Hey everybody, I'm Alan.
And I'm Brent.
And we're here for episode, are we on,
what number are we on, Snowman?
Eight, I think.
Eight, I call that number Snowman.
I understand.
All right, when I used to golf a long time ago,
when I was younger and stupider
and had way more free time,
and every time I got an eight on a hole,
instead of crying or feeling bad,
I just called it a snowman and I felt good.
Random Alan Trivia.
I have nothing to say to this.
Random, random, random, random.
All right, so, you ready to get going?
I am.
Well, let's look at the agenda for today.
We have a bunch of stuff,
or maybe not much at all, we'll find out.
In our last podcast, I cut Brent off
because I didn't want to hear about his IRR thing.
But this week, maybe I want to hear more about it.
So I thought we'd just start off
and let him finish his thoughts on there
while we are guaranteed to have some time.
So one of the problems,
let me start off with the problem.
As we move into this new world,
one of the issues that people are facing
is we have this new review model
where we're kind of judged on three different things.
One is how awesome we are individually,
how awesome we were at listening
and incorporating other people's ideas,
and then how awesome we were around taking our ideas
and helping others with them.
And we, me, as of course, Microsoft,
and I wonder how much, is that the HR guidance?
It is. Those things.
Well, maybe with a little less awesome.
Little less awesome sauce.
I haven't heard that as much.
I wonder if it's as transparent
or as clear across the company.
Just a side little editorial comment.
Just with the people that I've talked to.
You saw from my values a couple podcasts ago
that when we talked about those,
is I'm really big into transparency
and let people know exactly what you care about.
And I think if we could get, that's the right mix.
We get that into everybody's head
and they kind of get it, the right things will happen.
Because in the past, as you know,
it was all about being, the rewards
was all about being awesome yourself,
no matter who you crapped on along the way.
Right.
And as long as that awesomeness you did
was something that management remembered.
Peak in May, he used to be.
Right. That was exactly right.
So Alan and I have talked about one thing
that one of our big competitors do.
And that is every week on Friday,
everybody in the company writes a status report
that gets submitted into this giant index
that anyone can read.
So it, it, it.
Not only can anyone read, but it's searchable.
Right.
I wonder if anybody else is stuck on this same,
you know, linked to SQL issue that I am.
I mean, and here, here's four people working on this.
Oh, cool.
And so what, one of the things that that does
is it really makes it easy for people
to find other people who have similar passions.
So if there's something, so Alan mentioned a problem,
but let's say there's something big.
I want to create a small little niche book site.
I wonder if anyone else in the company
might be interested in working with me.
He gives me the ability to kind of search through that index
and then find a name that I could reach out to.
Okay.
Now, one of the, one of the things that I realized
very recently, because my strategy to try to influence
this company to do something similar
was basically talking to any and everybody that would listen.
And then I realized just a couple of weeks ago,
wait a minute, we already probably have that asset.
Just no one's using it in that way.
I will start.
This is where-
Trailblazer Brent.
That's right.
This is where the IRR idea came from.
What it stands for is an individual retrospective report.
Okay.
And then I just communicated it with my team.
Give me a moment to ponder.
The name sucks.
But what I'm trying to do is this is something
that I want every week and it is not a status report.
Do you go to them and go, yeah,
we're gonna need your IRR report.
Yeah.
And if you could bring some donuts on the way
and that'd be great.
Yeah.
I don't know about our four or five.
How many listeners do we think we have now?
I think we lost a couple.
Anyway, go on.
Yeah.
I just don't do passive aggressive very well.
It's not, not winding back to a nutshell.
Okay.
The biggest value of our competitor,
putting all their status reports
into the central store that's searchable.
When you mentioned status reports at this company,
what it generally means, it's pain, bureaucracy,
and some jerk wads somewhere is trying to use this
to create a paper trail so that they can hold me accountable
for things that they don't understand.
Yeah.
I fricking hate status reports.
I had to write, you know, the story like three months ago,
I was interacting with this team
and they wanted everyone to write on this sort of
virtual team to write status reports.
So people would write pages.
I would write two bullet points.
Like one of them was.
Done, not done.
The first one I did, one of my accomplishments was,
wrote my first status report in 15 years.
Actually, Alan forwarded that to me.
It was a great giggle.
You see why we didn't talk about this last time,
why there wasn't enough time.
There was plenty of time.
I was on a roll at that point in time.
Now I'm, now what are you, now you're like,
I'm like coffee's not working.
You're like a square wheel trying to roll down the hill.
Trying to roll up a hill.
On its own.
An IRR's purpose, and yes it will undergo a name change,
but in the short term it's not a status report.
Go on.
Its purpose is to fish.
What I'm trying to do with it,
is make my team easy to find for people who go in search.
And the type of people that I want
to reduce that friction towards,
is the ones where they have a solution
for a problem that we're facing,
or we have a solution for a problem they are facing.
I don't have a problem on my team.
My entire team is awesome on individual contribution,
but we do a lot of collaboration,
and we spend a lot of time talking about,
man we know that this expertise exists,
how do we find them?
Well one way to do that is make yourself easy to find.
Yeah I think as a side note,
the editorial comment is,
almost every problem I run into,
I stop and think surely someone has solved this before.
Then the challenge is,
how do I find that right connection?
Especially now I'm not working with a lot of
widely used tools.
Yep.
So right now we will iterate over it,
and when I laid it out to my team,
I said I laid down a baseline in terms of the content
I wanted to contain.
Just four items,
it's essentially what sorts of things are you working on?
What problems are you facing
that others might be able to help you with?
What sorts of things,
what sort of solutions do you think you've now done
in this last week,
that others might be able to capitalize?
And then are there any critical learnings
for knowledge sharing?
Hey I learned that this is a really bad way
to try to solve this problem.
Things like that.
And that'll be our first baseline,
I told the team.
Have you done one yet?
No.
Oh.
This is all theoretical.
It's all.
Unimplemented.
Not yet fully started.
The first set.
Half baked idea living in Brent's head.
No, it's already rolled out to the team.
All right, it's fully baked.
It's already rolled out to the team.
They will start this today.
No, I'm teasing you,
but I like the idea.
And I think as long as you keep it short,
to the point,
it's almost like the stand up.
Let me see if this analogy works.
The status report meeting is to the scrum stand up
as the written status report is to the IRR.
Yes.
Oh, I'm good.
So the other thing too is,
I've already told the team,
I don't know what this prize will be,
but we will reward people who figure out
the right format that decreases the time it takes
for people to find us.
Right?
It's, I mentioned it's like fishing.
Well, we got to find the right bait.
We can't just throw empty hooks out.
Probably won't work.
The other thing too is,
I want the team to figure out how to adjust this format
so that anyone can do it within 15 minutes.
It-
I was going to ask how long it should take.
I would,
I would expect it would take less than 15 minutes.
In fact,
Yeah, but you're a brilliant writer.
What you take 15 minutes to do
generally takes me four hours.
The point is,
regardless of the brilliant or non-brilliant
level of the writer,
it doesn't have to be perfect.
It's learning.
It doesn't.
The point is,
if you are good at search foo,
if you are good at typing in,
figuring out,
you have to ask some really crazy question,
finding the right search terms to find,
to get the hit,
you probably are able to write a very good IRR
because what you're trying to write
is what you did in searchable terms.
Right?
Don't use big words,
use small words.
Use-
And use-
Well-known-
Well-known words.
World, you're right.
So there's a little bit of an art to it,
but it shouldn't be quick.
You don't want to write Hemingway.
You want,
you're asking for not very many bullet points.
It's for a week, so.
So the,
we're gonna,
we have a public Yammer group already in place.
I'm gonna follow your Yammer group.
Anyone can,
anyone can join it.
I've made it as easy as possible
for people to get aboard.
And the value of this,
at least me and my team,
is not theoretical.
I did a different version of this.
I had a community alias about a year ago,
and I let people join whenever they wanted.
And suddenly people who I had no idea who they were,
started joining.
I'm like,
okay, if they get value out of it,
knock themselves out.
Was this an email alias?
It was an email distribution.
Did you call it free beer?
No, I called it,
it's Power BI telemetry community.
Okay, so it's around.
Anyway, go on.
They worked as a-
People joined.
They did.
You know why?
People are desperate for information.
Because I used the T word.
The T word.
Software design engineering telemetry.
Yeah, it means everything and nothing right now.
Within,
once that event's out occurring,
people who I didn't know who they were,
started joining.
Within three weeks,
I got an email from a guy.
Hey, it seems like you're beginning to work on this problem.
Were you aware that me and my team
already have a fully operationalized data warehouse
for that exact problem?
To which I respond,
no, I was not.
When shall we meet?
And that ended up being a great partnership.
And it shrunk easily four months off of my schedule.
Yeah, I think one way to find that often,
because we don't have a good way of discovering
what we don't know, we don't know,
or what other people are doing right now,
I think often the best way,
at least in my experience,
at our company,
the best way to find out if someone else
is working on a particular project or item or a problem
is to say that you are working on solving
that particular problem or project.
And then the person who's,
people that are also working on it
will pop out of the woodwork.
Yes.
It's just funny.
There's got to be a better way.
So a lot of people,
what they try to do is
try to solve this problem proactively.
I'm gonna have,
Alan, you are now,
whether or not you are an expert,
you are now the expert on
natural language programming.
We're all doomed.
Just so that everyone,
so that I can send a mail out to the whole world
and let everyone know,
Alan is now the expert.
He will take care of all of these questions.
That doesn't help.
Really what I'm trying to do is say,
hey, proactive is one aspect,
but how do I shrink reactive?
I know I'm struggling with finding people.
I know Alan has this problem now and again.
Alan has a fantastic people network
and a lot of people know this and leverage it.
I think we've talked before.
I have a half written Think Week paper.
I never finished it.
I didn't know where it is anymore.
Gosh, I might have lost it in a hard drive crash,
but I've called on this concept of,
if only Microsoft knew what Microsoft knew.
Right.
So I like the IRR idea because I think it's a great,
it's a method for discovering
what you don't know, you don't know,
for discovering, for making those connections.
What, when Steven Johnson,
author talks about where good ideas come from.
One of the things it needs is a network.
You need great ideas or most often
a connection between other ideas.
And those ideas need a real network
to swim in and define connections.
So anything that provides that network,
whether it's searchable terms,
sorry, I was thinking through Yammer,
how do you filter through,
I guess if you're just searching that one group,
I don't know, I'd figure how to use Yammer
for this technology, but for a company wide thing.
You just go to the top and you hit search.
I know, but there's so much other,
there's technical groups and there's social groups on Yammer
and I'll have to see how search works
and I want to look for.
So one question,
because Alan is a much better Yammer-er than I,
so you said you're gonna join my group.
Do you know, I didn't give you the name,
does that block you?
I could search for,
what I can do is I can search for you
and see what groups you're in.
I could probably guess which one it is,
but really I was probably just gonna email you
to ask you for the name.
No, I was hoping that you had an out,
your former algorithm would be there.
Because again, if I have this,
if I have this obtuse name
that doesn't necessarily align,
then people are gonna, it'll be hard.
Certainly they'll associate with me.
My search foo is not bad.
I would probably try IRR,
see if that shows up.
I don't remember what it stands for, infrared something.
When that didn't work,
I would probably just search for you
and see what groups you're in.
Okay, good.
Yeah, the company is a-
A sufficient measure or a method exists
for which people can find out what they don't know.
Yes, yeah.
It's funny.
I'm sure a lot of companies are the same way,
but well Yammer is, it's funny.
Our company is in love with email.
Yes.
It's hard for them to get out.
So we have Yammer, they're part of Microsoft now,
and we're using Yammer internally.
And some people are into it,
but for a lot of people just haven't,
it's just not there yet.
I hate email and I worked on the email team.
I'm trying.
And now that we're part of this larger organization,
the operating systems group, even more so.
And it's not that phone calls can be intrusive.
It sounds like you need to walk to my office every time,
but I don't think people realize how much
what a black hole discussion lists are
for sharing information, email discussion lists.
Yeah.
You don't have threaded,
well you have threaded conversation, but it's lost.
If I join, if this was a distribution list,
I could put all your emails into a folder
and search from that folder, it'd be great.
But if I join it late, I can't find any of that stuff.
I can't make those connections.
And if there's a reply to one, that gets lost too.
There's a degree of persistence missing.
Yeah, I was talking to someone who's working
with the Yammer team on something
and they were frustrated because
they will not respond to email.
If I want to get a response,
I have to send something to them on Yammer.
Great.
And they were frustrated.
I thought, well, doesn't that make sense?
Come on.
So that's a hard,
I don't know what it is.
Maybe it's because I have a thirst
for discovering what I don't know, I don't know.
Where I want to, I would prefer to use Yammer
or some sort of archivable, social,
discoverable, open, public, transparent group
for discussing and figuring out my problems than email.
In fact, I just solved this huge problem this week
in some work I'm doing and it's all an email.
There's no way, you know,
we document it for our team in our OneNote,
but when some other team, and I guarantee you,
some other team will run into the same problems
I had to solve this week,
they have no way of discovering the solution.
Yeah, well, they do have a way,
but it's gonna rely a lot on magic and hope.
Right?
If for some reason someone has the idea
that connects that person's network to yours somehow,
then there's a chance they could do it.
Yeah, we have an archive.
My problem with email right now
is the signal to noise ratio is just awful.
It is, and email is a very good medium
for sharing announcements, it's information sharing.
It's not a great, email is not a great,
for a corporation, not a great discussion mechanism.
It is information sharing, not knowledge sharing.
I like that.
So we got a new boss,
and one of the things that I think is fantastic
about this guy, he has done now three different slide decks,
and one of the things he talks about is-
Wait, the other thing we do too much besides email
is PowerPoint, but go on.
No, no, PowerPoint is fine.
No, no.
What we need is more,
we need more communication and less babbling.
I'll let you, now I will rant on PowerPoint
for one second and go back to your manager.
So we are so addicted to it that I review,
I'm one of the reviewers for Think Week papers every year.
Which are internal papers,
people trying to write about their great ideas.
Every year there's at least one or two yahoos
who submit their Think Week paper
as a PowerPoint slide deck.
Sweet.
Guess what rating they get from me.
It's the same number of fingers I hold up to Brent
when I'm mad at him.
All right, onto your boss.
Yeah, I know how I'm gonna post my next one then.
All right, anyway, one of the things
that's really cool about him
is now in three different slide decks,
he talks about Google Alerts.
And I think it's cool
because he talks about our competitor
and what they're doing awesome.
And he subscribes to Google Alerts.
And what Google Alerts does
is it gives him a sort of an intelligent agent
sitting back behind the scenes
and he's able to customize and say,
hey, these are the sorts of things I care about.
Let me know when something that I care about
pops up and make everything else go away.
And I would love to be able to do that with email.
Tell me what I care about or should care about
and make everything else go someplace else.
I used to have a rule, in fact, I still have a rule.
A rule suck.
Well, I have a rule where only mail
or I'm on the tour CC line comes to my inbox.
But even with that, these days,
single to noise ratio is awful.
Well, yeah, because people will start off sending,
well, Alan needs to know about the noise level
or this monitor thingy
or the fact that his test case suite is...
Not so much.
None of this.
Somebody else decided that you need to know this.
And then they very quickly realized
that you're ignoring the announcement to the DL.
And so start putting the DL plus Alan Page next to it.
Right?
I hate that.
It's no, Alan needs this information.
And I will work through his wall of whatever.
Anyway, manager slide deck.
What's going on with your new boss?
No, the whole point was talking about Google alerts.
My new boss is completely awesome.
I am just...
He must listen to the podcast.
I don't think so.
Not yet.
Yeah.
I am just a tad shy of just blatant hero worship.
This guy's awesome.
All right, yeah, we'll talk about him more later.
Give me names and stuff.
All right.
I read a blog post this week.
It was said there's no such thing as agile testing,
which yeah, makes, I mean, there's, to me,
it's all just testing.
The post was talking about sort of what does the tester do
on the agile team?
And I want to talk about the post
because I thought the premise of the post was good.
I didn't, I thought the arguments the author made
were totally off the wall.
What primary argument?
It was a lot of hearsay.
But it made me think in relationship to we're talking
about with more and more teams moving
to being engineering teams, you know,
whether they're agile or not.
And agile is this label that means now means 850,000
different things.
So on an engineering team of generalizing specialists
or specializing generalists or specializing specialists,
maybe not the third one.
Well, it's going to start up.
So generally when I see agile testing,
it's when I've seen that deployed,
it's basically a group of specialists trying
to work together.
All right.
So let's reiterate one thing we've talked about before
is that if you try and make an engineering team,
you know, a team of, you know what I mean,
engineering team.
So it's titleless people.
If you expect everyone to do everything soup to nuts,
you're screwed.
You're totally screwed.
So that doesn't work that way.
You're going to have specialists.
So what is the role or what are some examples,
nothing about mine as well,
but I want to hear your answer first.
What are some examples of the test specialist role
on an engineering team?
So first and foremost,
I am very much against that idea in the first place.
Against having a test specialist?
Uh, yeah.
Talk about that.
And I'll argue with you.
I think I've talked about before that when I first went
into development, that I had a mix of folks.
Some came from more of a dev centric specialization
and some came more from a test centric specialization.
And when I started off, I'm like,
I will have none of that.
Everyone's going to work together and solve
the same problems.
And I viewed coding and testing as skill sets, not roles.
The team we talked about before where the team really
started to click with that.
And as they started getting better and better,
what we found is when I first put down and say,
everyone tests their own stuff.
What I found just in summation is that the code got better,
became a lot more modular.
We found less bugs slipping through the cracks.
And it became more modular because writing complex code
is a pain in the ass to test.
And once I said, go ahead, write complex code,
but you're testing it.
And then when I started harassing them about why
the hell is this thing that we estimated for two days
is taking three weeks, right?
It basically ended up forcing them to modularize
and make it easier to test and easier to validate.
But that same process of modularization ended up
making it easier for us to add new features
to the product.
I'm all on board there.
Well, so the punchline is once the team clicked
and was really going through high throughput,
I then started asking myself, at what point in time
would I hire a tester to augment this team?
And quite honestly, I really struggled with that.
I still don't have an answer that I'm very happy with.
So let me answer it.
So I'm all on the board.
I think there is no, on an engineering team,
there is no role for a functional test specialist.
So I think, absolutely.
I think the huge benefit of someone writing tests
for their own code is they end up writing better code
because they realize, oh shit, my code can't be tested.
So that's great.
But what I would hire a tester for is I need someone,
how do I evaluate this thing end to end?
Maybe through instrumentation, maybe through analysis,
maybe a data job.
Who's the person to figure out,
how am I gonna make sure we do adequate load testing on this?
Or looking at some of the, we call the NFRs,
the non-functional things.
Those are things where I see
where a test specialist fits in there.
Because I think the people from the old test role
who are good, are good systems thinkers,
they can look at the thing and figure out
where the holes are.
They're also process improvers.
And again, this is weird, because it's not really,
I'll talk about what I'm doing right now,
which is not at all testing, but it's valuable.
I'll get to it in a moment.
But I think what the test role is,
is not really a test role.
It's a engineering productivity,
and maybe a quality role.
There's some gaps that the person who's,
I'm developing the code, I'm running my test for it.
They may not be as good at thinking about,
now how does this fit into the whole system,
not architecturally, but how,
what does the threat model or security look like?
Maybe I have some expertise there.
There's a bunch of little gaps
that I think need to be filled in,
that may not be able to be filled in
by the traditional software developer.
So, couple of things there.
First off, when I first went into dev,
my team was around six, seven people.
And that sort of specialization,
there's really not an ROI for bringing in,
on that team, that small.
There's no economy of scale there.
The second thing is,
but we still had this integration problem.
And what we ended up doing very dynamically,
we ended up creating sort of a monitoring site
that allowed anybody on the team,
whether or not they had written that component,
to very quickly visualize
how the system was operating end to end.
And we got actually very good at,
one person within 30 minutes could figure out,
hey, our customer value proposition,
what we own end to end,
is in the weeds and it's because of this right here.
Yeah, I think on a larger team,
you're gonna find more need
for some of those specializations.
And for example, and I wanna.
So actually, and I agree,
but your question was,
what's the role on an agile team?
No, no, that wasn't really.
Not necessarily on an agile organization.
That was the inspiration for it.
I say, what's the role of a test specialist
on an engineering team?
So what I think actually,
I don't think they're test specialists.
I think that is a team,
a specialized team of these same engineers
who are focused on solving that security problem
or that performance problem.
They are, the one thing that they,
as a whole have in common,
is deep knowledge on this area of expertise.
And what I have found to be the most valuable
is what they do is they figure out
how to automate that expertise so that the other teams.
I think a lot of people worry that,
well, I don't know what to do on this team.
I have these areas of expertise.
I think there are,
I don't think we need nearly as many test specialists
as we have today, these large test teams.
But I think some of the attributes,
I'll give you my example in a second.
Some of the attributes of things
that make people good testers are very valuable
as a, almost a generalization to the team.
My superpower, if I were to probably have any of my last,
several managers describe it,
is I just can figure out how stuff works.
I can figure things out,
even if they're kind of outside of my wheelhouse.
So because I'm leaving on sabbatical,
coming up here a while, I wanted to take on,
but I wanted to have some work to do
that would have an end date that would,
but wouldn't be critical path.
So I've been working on a lot of work
getting our Git repositories moved to Visual Studio Online
and getting builds working
and on-prem build controllers
and learning all kinds of crazy stuff.
And the biggest one finally solved this morning
was the coordination of active directory credentials
with online credentials.
So anyway, some interesting things
and everything's working great now.
So we're gonna be ready to migrate before I go.
So I'm pretty happy.
But is that testing not even close?
But is it, did I learn a bunch of new stuff
and that I provide value to the team?
Sure, and that's my role.
So it's definitely not a test specialist role.
That's a very generalist role.
I was able to expand my field of knowledge
and learn some new things.
I think there are roles for people who...
I don't, so I actually gave a brief speech
to my team recently,
and I thought I talked about it on the podcast,
but because I can't remember,
I'm gonna go ahead and go ahead and do it again.
The testers, I don't think testing is what's valuable
in the way we've been doing it.
Like even from my own experience, as I just discussed,
there's better ways of doing it to deliver quality.
However, one of the things people are freaking out about
is, hey, does that mean I'm no longer valued?
And I've said, no, no, no, no.
Testers, they have four key things
that they are attributes.
I'm uncomfortable calling it a role,
but I'll say attributes that testers seem to have in common
from my experience.
Number one, they are very good
at considering code quality issues.
We're good at looking at code
and going, you screwed up right there.
I remember like yesterday, about 10 years ago,
the dev architect did an off by one bug in his if loop.
And oh, I mocked him forever.
What the hell's an if loop?
I'm sorry, if statement.
All right.
Would be a, yeah, whatever, moving on.
Code quality, we're good at that.
Finding bugs is how we think of it,
but that's not the value.
It's about getting code quality up.
Customer quality, we're good at that.
Considering how the customer thinks
and what sort of things would make them happy,
that's something we're good at.
Coding, we know how to code.
We're not gonna, I mean, the best of us
isn't going to be better than the best of,
say, the current development,
but there is a great deal of things
that we as a function, as a group,
are quite good at doing.
Large number of us could write a high-performing web UI
without batting an eye.
And then lastly, we're very good at systems thinking.
We're very good at thinking things through end to end.
And none of those four things,
no matter what our role is,
none of those, the value of those four things diminish
in any way, shape, or form.
Those will always be valuable.
Yeah, I can't argue with that.
I think what goes away is the,
give me your code, I'll play with it for a while.
I'll tell you where the bugs are.
I give it to you, you give it back to me.
That stuff's gone.
Good riddance.
All right, we got about five minutes left.
We better get to the mailbag.
All right, Brent, you have the first question
from the mailbag.
Yep, so I had a 101 with a guy I hadn't talked to
in a couple of years.
Found out, by the way, that in some regards,
our podcast is going viral.
Meaning he found the link and forwarded on
to several people.
Yeah, I don't think that counts.
Viral's viral, baby.
In our next podcast, I will teach Brent definitions.
Yeah, I look forward to that conversation.
I'm all about virality.
Anyway, what I'm saying is that we've clearly
have moved away from, hey, just people just listening
for themselves that are now at a point
where they're sharing with others.
Good, what was the question?
As we were talking through it, he asked,
hey, Brent, this is all great, episode seven.
However, one question I had is,
I'll leave it to you to answer this.
How will it work when we're in this world
where managers have 10 to 30 direct reports?
How the hell are they gonna scale?
How will my manager know what I need to do
at review time?
That was sort of the, how will he be able
to prop me up correctly at review time?
And how will he grow my career?
God, people are-
He says, asking the guy who's not a manager.
People, well, I will tell you that I think 30
gets a little bit hard.
I think if 10 to 20 freaks you out,
you're probably not cut out to be an engineering lead
in the new world.
I think when I talk to people about this,
I recommend The One Minute Manager,
which is, if you ever read the book,
it is about manager is overwhelmed
with how much stuff he has to do,
and the stuff's not getting done,
talks to the guru,
tells him how to be the one minute manager,
which basically means that instead of spending
all your time monitoring your employees,
you dive in and out.
You give them guidance when needed,
praise when needed, you get in and out,
and let them, and guess what happens
when you get in and out and get out of their way
and give them what they need to do?
They grow on their own.
Yes.
They figure stuff out.
One of the reasons your team doesn't grow
is when you spend all your time trying
to micromanage them.
It's effort on you,
and it hinders your employees' career.
What should the micromanager do differently?
They need to learn how to step.
They need to give your team a framework
they can work in and be successful,
give them the right coaching they need
to continue to achieve that success,
and then get the hell out of their way.
So, Alan, actually, there's a reason
why I wanted you to ask or answer this.
Yes.
Alan has stated over and over again,
he's super allergic to being a manager.
No, I'm super allergic to being a manager at Microsoft.
Okay, now, let's say you're a current team,
but you have no management chain now.
Is your team gonna go into the weeds,
and are you guys all gonna get bad reviews?
On my team, no.
Why?
Because we have a value of being super transparent
and a value of collaboration,
everybody on the team knows to do that.
Everybody knows what everybody else is doing.
Say that we got rid of all our managers,
and we all just reported directly to my boss.
I think we would probably rely even more
on peer feedback for, along those things
we talked about earlier, on collaboration, et cetera,
for how we're evaluated.
But also what's gonna happen is
you're going to have leaders pop up
out of that team of 30 people.
You're gonna have people who rise as technical leaders,
who rise in and out, World of Warcraft,
project management style I talked about last time.
Leaders pop in and out, groups form.
As a manager, you see those in your brief
coaching and monitoring sessions,
so you know what's going on.
And if you're not transparent,
and you don't value collaboration,
and you don't share with each other,
it is gonna be very difficult to tell
who I need to give big rewards to versus smaller rewards.
But I think, Chris, my manager,
mentioned having the whole team report to him,
which is about 35 people right now.
I think he's still gonna go to his senior people,
his technical leaders, even though they're not managers,
and ask them about people on the team
to get more information.
But if you have 30 people,
won't everybody go in random directions?
No, if you have 30 people and no leadership on the team,
but you have your engineering manager
who's in charge of managing the team,
coaching, make sure everybody has what they need,
people are going to do peer mentoring and peer coaching,
and you're gonna have leaders on that team.
We should move on to the next.
Well, no, because actually I wanna bring something up,
and we're gonna have to do the other question next time.
So one thing I'll just say on this is,
my answer to this,
and you just talked about it a great deal,
but we talked about the IRR earlier, and the reason why.
My answer to this, in this world,
reducing the friction around knowledge sharing
is absolutely the key to making this succeed.
Yeah, I think it's a huge part of it.
So I wanna bring up,
I was thinking about this topic since our last podcast,
and I remember Brent and I have been having lunch together,
meeting together for like five years,
and I remember one of our-
Feels like 10.
One of our first meetings,
we're over at a place called Saigon City,
having some Vietnamese-
They're closed now.
No way!
Yeah, out of business.
Oh no, oh god, I love that place.
In a moment?
All right, back in business here, wow.
It's a good thing we have a new favorite place.
Where am I gonna get a 21?
Oh man, the 21 was so good.
Black check table, please.
The number 21 on the menu.
So we're having lunch there,
and Brent's talking about, we're talking about Google,
and Brent says to me,
this is just a few short years ago,
Brent says to me, I could never work at Google.
I said, why not, Brent?
He goes, they expect managers to manage up to 15 people,
and there is no way I would manage on a team like that,
because I couldn't give my employees
the amount of career growth and coaching
they needed to be successful.
Yep, and ever since,
so I remember that conversation.
I'm glad you did.
No, I've used that over and over again.
But one of the things that I do do
is I spend a lot of time thinking through,
why the hell do they think they can?
What did they figure it out?
I've now learned that.
Yeah, and that's actually a good mode for anything.
When you see something you disagree with,
somebody says something,
what's their motivation behind that?
Why are they thinking that way,
and see if there's some value there for you?
And how do they do it?
How do they make it scale?
Yeah, that was, so back then in those days,
and it was longer than five years ago,
I had a rule of thumb,
and it's something that I even taught my leads
who reported to me, is that my expectation is
that you're spending around 10% of your time
with each of your employees.
So if you have 10, that's all you're doing.
Well, over there, it was common to have
20 to 40 direct reports.
And I'm like, I'm sorry.
I don't see how my current tool set
will enable me to scale that.
And people management is critical to me.
If I can't even consider a position
where I would fail on that.
Yeah, I would love to talk more about this,
but we're losing our room,
and I'm late for a meeting.
So thanks, everyone.
We're gonna get to the other mailbag question
next time, and I'm Alan.
I'm Brent.
And we'll see you later.
Bye.