Hey everybody. Hello, it's Alan and Brent and we're back again for the final AB testing episode of
2014 yes number 15 and last one for the year that reminds me and it's at 1415
episode 15 15 last of 2014, right so I
Have a question for you Brent not on the whiteboard, but that's allowed in AB testing. Yes to you. Do you prefer to say?
2014 or
2014 I'm 2014. I'm a 2014 camp to we got and this it's actually a little one of these little anal peeves of mine because we called
it
1990 milk you with Colin 2000 2000 because we called 19 1900. Mm-hmm, but we're in 20s now not
2000s is that over the top over the top? No, it's
like I was so happy when we got through the
the first 10 years of this millennium and
I didn't know what the what is that first decade? Yeah, I think you're even okay there cuz we call it
Night. Well, I wasn't alive then despite popular rumors in history class. It was like 1907 so I can go
2007 anyway, is it the what's what's the decade? Listen people the odds. Ah, we're in
2014 soon to go into 2015 if you could all please join me in my crusade to stop calling at
2000 and I'd be really happy. Thank you very much
This has been a public service announcement from the A B testing crew will now resume with our normally scheduled podcast
You really cannot guess what will happen on this podcast you never know
What's new for you Alan? Hey, I just did I'm glad you asked Brent this week. I did a little
Interview that wasn't like an interview in person where they actually talked to you with the microphone
They sent me some questions that hey answered these and we'll put them on our blog
I did this for the a1 QA blog. It's at a1 QA comm slash blog
What does it stand for?
A1 like like really good like steak sauce like quality assurance like steak sauce quality assurance
I gotcha, but they've interviewed a lot of people. They have some good blogs up there
I'm some good articles and posts and I answered some questions and I answered questions
That you would expect the angry weasel to answer
What were those may you ask? I don't remember. No, I answered
There was a question about combined engineering is at the end of all testing and I said yes or no
You'll have to read to find out. I also answered questions about data-driven quality
The future of testing and whether testers should actually have engineering skills whether it makes a difference and what it makes a difference and
My un bashful opinion appears at a1 QA comm slash blog
Yeah, I'm looking at the title right now. I cannot wait to go tear this blog post apart
So the title they they took a quote out of the out of my answers and made the title of it said test
specialists are essential members of software teams and not sure let's tear it apart right now because
We the gauntlet has been thrown down for Brent and I to finally have a little more in-depth discussion
About generalizing specialists or specializing generalists and what that means. Yep
So the con I'll give my context then we'll go into that topic
So my context was I was talking about generalizing specialists
And I think people that have a specialization in test in testing skills and those kind of tester DNA big picture
How do things fit together?
Will remain an essential part of software teams regardless of whether they're called testers or not
Sure, the the only dispute I have with that is that I don't think they'll end up being specialists
I think they'll end up that will be a
More of a generalist talent and that it will spread out throughout the entire team. So let's
That's that for a moment and we'll come back to it as we discuss because sure
today on today this week on Twitter I introduced the
The term lost it
Okay, and I did not see that did not see lost it
I did not see lost it so after reading Twitter and people making comments about you know, I
Don't like what you're saying isn't testing
What I proposed was the law of software testing discussions lost it and you could reference lost it
Anytime a discussion is bogus because the definitions of testing do not match and then someone asked this morning
If we could extend lost it to match term general terminology terminology in general non matching terminology
so let's apply that rule to
Generalizing special specialized in general what is the law the law the law is that I can claim
It's more of a motion. I can claim lost it and
It immediately invalidates a discussion where we're not talking about the same thing
Okay, all right this this sounds analogous to my test is a four-letter word sure
Right. Yeah, exactly. Exactly. It applied the test. Yes. Yep
Let's see if we can come to some clarity on what generalists and specialists and specializing generalizing generalizing specialists means to us
So Brett, what's a generalist a
generalist is
someone who has a
Talent in
Most things needed to get software engineering done
they do not have
The way I would phrase it the difference between a generalist and a specialist is I would say
There's multiple skills that that an individual needs to have across three dimensions
In engineering they'll have process skills. They'll have technology skills. They'll have people skills a
generalist is someone who can
do all of those
with sort of a
50%
speed in
That's a that's a weird definition. I wouldn't get so complex on that. I would just say a generalist is
Can do a little about a lot of things
It depends right the little about a lot of things. I would definitely say a
Generalist is someone that you would classify as
Here's my jack of all trades sure
Let's go with that
Okay, because your other when we went with generals to specialists getting generalizing specialist is gonna get super complex
So we can't make that more a little bit more simple. So general's is a jack of all trades good
I'll say a specialist is someone who goes really deep in an area
I know for example
The guy that does the memory management stuff for Windows is a deep specialist there
He asked him to do the UI or an application. He would just
Laugh at you. I will generalize that and say a specialist in my worldview is someone who has a deep
deep knowledge
because I do think the the important distinction between a generalist and the specialist is what knowledge they have and
A specialist has deep knowledge in some
skill
Okay, so now you specified an area it may not be an area right it could be a skill
I'll say a skill very good. I agree. So now without getting too complex. Tell me
What is a generalizing specialist in your opinion your words?
generalizing specialist
Is someone who well again?
So I think of it in terms of more of a
Data science II way
No, so you asked me for me to simplify it
Yeah, um a generalist blah blah more meat a generalizing specialist is
Someone who still has really deep knowledge in a a particular skill
But they have
other
They have knowledge and other aspects
To the degree where they they can they can handle multiple different skills
but not to the degree of
What they have on the skill that they have mastered so that the difference I would say between
I haven't asked for a difference as for definition
Okay, I can see from your body language my definition sucks. What is yours?
So blah blah blah blah blah my definition if I were Scott Amler, I'm gonna read his definition
Okay, a generalizing specialist is someone who one has one or more technical specialties
For example, like Java programming project management. You talk about you know people or yeah, that's more concrete
That's kind of what I was least a general knowledge of software development
Has a general knowledge of the business domain in which they work and actively seeks
Here's the important one especially if people attest
They're good at this actively seeks to gain new skills and both their existing specialties as well as in other areas
Okay. All right
Any and Scott am was articles like when I come out 2007 8 it's pretty old. So what he's saying is
Similar to what I was saying is that?
As one or more your words one or more technical specialties
The one problem I would the one tweak I would have with that is it still would be a limited number of technical specialties
a basic knowledge of how to do stuff
basic knowledge of the goals that they're trying to achieve and
Learns good. So what's a specializing generalist is a term that's not used as much but you like it a lot
So tell me what a specialized generalism
I don't have a fancy definition from someone important to read for this one. So we're gonna have to trust Brent stay tuned
It's it's the reverse of this
so they have a general knowledge of
All or most of the technical
Skill, so they're broader. They're broader. Okay
And they're actively seeking to gain new skills
Deeper in a new specialty
So so both both sides if you were to run them as sort of an iterative loop
I do think you would see both generalizing specialists and specializing generalists
Converged to a steady state. I okay. I think we're more in agreement which sucks for our listeners who wanted to fight
But I read I tweeted about this as well and Jim Holmes
Because at first I read Scott Ambler who later in the same article says there's a lines of something like
What then what the heck is a can there be a specialized in generalist and he says basically I?
Guess so just a different path to get there. Although he says it's rare. Maybe it's not so rare
but you're saying that the specializing generalist is
Mostly a general to specializes and the generalizing specialists mostly a specialist who can go a bit broader
But eventually yes, which those will converge as you go as they both go
Because they're both have to share that attribute of wanting to learn new things eventually they sort of converge
Yeah, so the way we could we could discuss this further like if if we both intuitively
intuitively
Believe we had a couple beers before we started at 8 in the morning, so your friends having a hard time
That that they would likely converge
to
the same whichever it may be
right
Then really the discussion is
If you were to start a new team
What should it be?
Where do you start and in most of the blogs that I've seen that the advocate for?
generalizing specialists
My perception is the the battle that they're solving is they're trying to
they're not trying to solve the combined engineering problem that we are but they're trying to
essentially get pure dev orgs
to stop being stupid because pure dev orgs at least in the world that we're coming from is
Is a world of pure specialization? Yeah, and that doesn't work no
So I tweeted this and asked if there was a difference because I read the Scott Ambler article
I thought well, you know and I kind of got to that convergence point that you got to I thought maybe they're the same
But until they're the same they're different until they converge they are different and Jim Holmes who's an awesome, dude
I met him a couple years ago to peer conference and that he was organizing and hosting. He was part of Telerik
I
Said he wrote an article again six years ago
Talked about being a specialized in generalist and and I kind of got that there is a difference and
He's a generalist first and dives deep where needed. So let's play a game. Okay
I only have one round of this game because I just made it up right now tag. You're it
so my role
What do I do at work? I?
Am kind of a consultant for the team
Okay, my boss calls me that I look at what's going on
I figure out where holes are make sure they're gonna make sure they're getting addressed make sure we're not
Letting pieces fall through the cracks. I also spent a lot of time on this team because we don't have anyone managing in charge of managing
our builds
tweaking a lot of our build configurations making sure people get help with
Get and source control when they need it because it's new for a lot of people
optimizing tweaking
Set up some new static analysis tools for the team
Got those up and running so we can you know, I'm big on code hygiene and code sanity in the past
I've done similar sort of things and also written some
infrastructure tools
but at the same time kind of did a lot of
leadership things making sure that whether there are virtual teams another conversation what virtual teams or
Directives that we need that the team needed to follow we're taking making care of team-wide communication, etc
Kind of the things I do is I'm big on community. I'm big on learning from others. I'm big on sharing. I'm big on
Enabling people to do a better job
What am I am I a generalizing specialist or specializing generalist I
The way you just described I think you're specializing general. Yeah, that's it's interesting
That's the realization I came to as I began researching this which is weird because I've been going to a specialist and
and
And I can I give him a tiny Python flashback right there Oh
Time out I'm going to it's probably too young at almost 11 years old but over one of my goals over
Winter break is to have my son watch money Python on the Holy Grail for the first time
Maybe not entirely appropriate, but I think he's silly enough that he would enjoy the humor
I think my youngest son as well
And I absolutely feel like I have not done my parental duty by introducing them to flying circuit
Yeah, so that's gonna happen. That's that that's gonna happen. We'll see how that goes
My daughter may just roll her eyes and leave the room and go play with makeup or something
My daughter is just about to turn five
She would yeah, she would immediately bit flip and leave
But I think if I my old my youngest son would be all in and I think I could get I get it apply social pressure
I'm gonna give it a shot. You know we did this weekend and we're off in the weeds
I'm gonna come back to the specialized and generalist is
There's a school of rock wreck a mile from Microsoft
And you know that's a great movie and I made the kids watch the movie in fact
My daughter had a friend over we called her mom make sure we could watch a PG-13 movie
And it was it was like barely PG-13 and and yeah
It was I forgot how awesome Jack Black is and that whole movie was great
I would say how awesome Jack Black used to be perhaps
All right, so I came the realization that I was a specialized in generalist so by your own definition
You are suboptimal. I right. No, I've changed my definition
once I realized that I kind of what I do is more of a I
Yeah, I know a lot about a little little about a lot
I do always learn new things and go as deep as I need to to help the team
So here's not usually a lot deeper. Here's here's the realization
just so that you don't
Feel alienated or lost out or where did I go wrong?
Yeah every day as I cry in the corner. I think those things so
As I guess just got through those who grew up in particularly at this company those who grew up in dev
Are used to being a specialist it's still whenever I introduce teams to agile that is the number one
conflict I have when I introduced this to
We'll call them dev teams who grew up in dev even though everything's combined engineering now
Tess is the reverse
Right. We've talked many a times that when when we had these separated roles
Test was the guys trained to fill in the blanks. So we got talented at blank filling
Yeah, our friend Jim Moore who listens once in a while says that you said the job of test is the remainder
Yeah, I
Love Jim don't like that. I I like it. I I what you just said in different words. No, no, it's a it's a hundred percent
Right and I still hate it
I
And then I even wrote a blog on on that topic. Gosh a year ago
Do you blog anymore? I will get another one out
In the before the end of this into this year actually ideally this weekend stay tuned. Yep
But one of the things that that I have
done
is
I've
Watched I've I've owned teams that came from both backgrounds
Okay
and when you get into the the agile process that they're
Let me take a step back
You you from a technical standpoint, I would definitely classify you as a generalist
however
You are a specialist in certain things. So I definitely think that for example learning knowledge sharing that is a specialty
You have beyond the shadow of a doubt, right?
New tech
You're you're not afraid to go deep and you are able to go deep
Just about any time the business needs it the difference
From from my point of view between a generalizing specialist and a specializing generalist
a specialization in the agile world as we've talked before is another name for
Team bottleneck. So the challenge comes into play is when there's a specialization
We're the only specialist you're the only specialist and the worst case scenario is you're the only specialist in a
specialization that the team no longer needs
for example
let's say
You are work. You are working on a UI database product and you're the database specialist and
they decide to go a different direction and
We no longer need that database. We're gonna outsource that database to a third party
What do you do get a new job? That's exactly what you do
Yeah, but if you're a specializing generalist, what do you do?
You pick one of your other general areas and fill in or find another area specialty you find another area
That's true for a specializing generalist as well
the anxiety is
Significantly different I guess so there's that sort of a lot of people have mentioned. I know Lisa Crispin has I'm not sure if
If it's hers or she got up somewhere else. Sorry, but the tree shaped persona where you have the T shaped persona where you're broad
You go deep, but then somebody says well, there's other places that go maybe not quite as deep
Yeah with my hands you guys can't see it, but I think
Yeah to be successful in software
You can't just be a trunk of a tree need some breath and you need some branches and vines dangling down areas where you know
Where you can dive in what I would say is the this is actually an interesting discussion
The oh my gosh, it's actually interesting. Thanks for telling everyone Brent. Sorry
every now and again
Alan
Pull something useful out
So if specialization can turn into a problem around bottlenecking
then then is it true and I believe it is the generalization means a
generalist might be a
specialist in adaptability
Yes, but they do have the week is like discussing mutant powered strengths and weaknesses
you need
Know when you have a complex performance problem the generals can't help you you need the purse
you need somebody with with strengths in performance or or
Specialty and performance as part of their tool bag to help with that. I would argue the generalists can help you
But it may not be in an effective time frame. Yes, okay
Because and I would say the generals may help you as they ramp up specialty in that area in order to help you
That's maybe why the time frame is long. Yes, okay. Yeah
So all that said I don't see a test specialist
So this is a and in context of the article, it's a a test special someone who's a generalizing specialist
Where there or a specializing generalist? Let's talk about me for example, and but I still consider myself a test specialist
I know a lot about approaches for testing
I help our dev team a lot and how they're writing their tests now. They're executing their tests. I'm actually I shouldn't say our dev team my team
that happened to be programmers who are purely specialists in programming to
Broaden their ability to write
Unit functional and acceptance tests to journey that is a test specialist a team is always going to needs
I'm stopping you there. Is that a test specialist or a test specialization?
It's a test specialization
So I guess I think I get the part so if that is all you did that you are taking offense that is because I call
It test specialist. That means that that is just a specialist and not a generalizing especially when you say that I
immediately go
Team bottleneck and in in in in the year that dude screwed
Because he has anybody knows how to do it, right? Yeah, so
Yeah, a test specialization. I have several areas of test specialization
Because test is more than just one area helping them write better tests is one thing
Helping them think about how their components interact with others helping them helping them think helping them think
I'm a thinking I have I'm not a thinking specialist. I'm a specialization in thinking we haven't talked about test zombies in a long time
But yeah, we're not going to yeah
Do we do we reach critical mass on that so it doesn't let me let me see if I can let me try and summarize
What I got out of this conversation
You can tell me where I'm wrong and then we'll try again. Okay, so there is a difference between
Generalizing specials and a specialized in general and it comes in the second half of that word a specialized in general
It's more of a general to specializes and vice versa for the other one
But eventually as these people one attribute they share they share multiple attributes one they share. It's important is this
They're grasping new knowledge and bringing it into their tool back. Yes, and then eventually as the specializing
generalist
Gets more specializations or deeper specializations and it's a generalizing specialist
Gets more broad they kind of converge on being the same person the same type. Yeah. Yeah. Well, obviously, yeah
Yeah, and science fiction here
They the the same balance and
It'd be interesting to discover where that converges anything and and the path to get this Scott antlers
right the path that gets you there is
is kind of what
Makes you one of the other for example if I were to
I have a couple areas I go deep in but
Let's in anyway without rambling about how I become one of the other
Because I don't care as long as I'm valuable to the team or if they don't fire me
Can I also extrapolate beyond there that?
That's the kind and this has been written 150 times in different articles
I think I'm safe saying this that a good engineering team a whole engineering team an agile team a combined engineering team a discipline free
engineering team is made up of
those types of people
Primarily how much room is there for the dev specialist on the team of the future?
the programming specialist
Don't they need some generalization to remain relevant guy?
I think I think that when you say that I'm like, okay, what would be the the dev specialist?
and
My initial gut is that's that's what we call the architect. No, I think the architect is the generalist
The good architects I've known are actually some of the best test minds I've dealt with in development
They get how the pieces fit together they know how to think about it they know they know
Well, no so questions to ask it's interesting. Maybe you've had shitty architects
This is why I think you brought up the the losted conversation
because what I think of a good architect is that they are a
specialist in in
Architecture which is sort of an abstract concept right almost a general concept
Just messing with you, right? Yeah, I think I think architecture is a deep
It's a deep
Concept but it's at the high level
Right it it whereas you brought it up. Yeah
The
So a a dev specialist from going back to your question a dev specialist from your concept is
What then someone who knows?
The database in and out not to pick on our company which I'm gonna do in the next segment as well
But we have a lot of developers who are good at only
Tell me what to code. I'll code it and then I'll check it in. So what is that?
That's is that a coding specialist? That's I guess C sharp specialist. I don't know. Yeah, it's a language specialist. I'll implement that
Yeah, but then from a coding standpoint
If they're a C sharp specialist, are they a coding general? No, I guess so
I guess so because I think are we are we now like
Are we now?
The question coming to the opinion that it doesn't matter and everybody's the same. Let me rewind. Oh god
I don't know why I invite you only because your B is in the yeah, you I can help you find another
The question was oh god
All right, the question was Brent
Yes, Alan the question was is let me ask it differently so I can try and reel you the heck in
Good luck with that. I know
Go for it. I'm ready describe
Take a team of 20 people. You have a 20 person engineering team
Are they specialists generalists generalizing special specializing generalists? What's your mix generally at the start or at the end?
God no, cuz we just got through talking about they're just hired. Okay, you hired a team
You have a brand new product. You're gonna build a fizz banger which fizzes bangs or bangs physics
I'm gonna have I'm likely
in today's world, I'm likely to have a team of generalists and specialists and
I will need to kickstart the process
that creates the learning loop that gets them rolling to a
Converge center so you're gonna start with generalists and specialists and that and let them turn into specializing generalist and generalizing specialists
Yeah, then become whatever the hell we haven't needed. I'm already a specializing general so you won't hire me because I'm not like a
One of the other in that case. No, what do you hire me as a generalist?
I would hire you but in the class you wouldn't hire me, but you know it theoretically
I would so hire you I would I would love for the first three months the the one-on-ones I
Don't do one-on-ones. Oh you would no
Sorry, I'm busy
Making your product work. Yeah
All right. My ideal world would be to start with
Again specializing generalist people because I would want to optimize for adaptability, but the specializations I would try to
Diversify so that there is a lot of opportunity for knowledge sharing to run amongst the team and their specializations are aligned with
What my product needs? All right. Okay, I'm gonna put a
Nice bed out with a blanket and a pillow and put this topic into the bed and tuck it in for a nice rest
What do you think? That's up to you. I'm not done with this. You're not done. Nope. Oh god. Okay
Just to let people know I got an earthquake get out of bed
Know what's happening with the no no yeses in the SG's so just to share
So I tweeted on this that I believe I have a mechanism. I think we I think we've hypothesized what will happen
For those I think we talked about that I've gone back to school and I just completed a class on
Modeling and simulation so I'm gonna model and simulate this and see what actually happens
I
that may be my
Play toy exercise for the next
Couple of weeks. No one wants to know about your play toy exercises. I
Do you think to get this? I do think we've converged on
Something we've already converged on like it it really doesn't matter if it's
SG's or GS's when you begin what's critical is this this learning?
Adaptability loop and over time we I think we both believe that they're gonna come to some happy center and
What is that happy center? We don't know
Correct. We don't know when I'm done with this. I'll know. All right now now can I put it to bed?
You may it's in bed. Okay. All right one more topic. No mailbag this week. Sorry no
Cuz it's not happening because nobody asked me questions that I recall
But I was thinking just the other day. Did you ever read microsurf the Doug Copeland book? Yeah long long long time ago
I remember liking I was
Before I started at Microsoft. I
Like one chapter of it was in Wired magazine
I thought this is pretty cool and then I started at Microsoft and I got the book and read it
There was a lot of it was interesting. There was a lot of
Microsoft II, you know little quirks about Microsoft. This is written in, you know, pre Windows 95 pre calm it had a lot of
Sort of inside information funny things about Microsoft ease and and and it was a different
Microsoft it was a lot different and that book came out right when I started and
We talked last time Brett and I are both approaching the 20 year mark and Brent's bizarre internship story
Listen to the last podcast for that the previous one
But I was thinking and I don't know if you have many of these but I've
There are things
People do at Microsoft that I kind of want to feed to Doug Copeland see if I start like a follow-up
but for now, I'll just feed them to the
They're not enough of them yet for a book for sure
But let me fun to discuss maybe we'll make a segment out of this we're gonna think talk about things Microsoft ease do
What would be the title of this book? I don't know. I don't know. I haven't thought that far ahead yet
I don't think any of this anything regarding the topics of this podcast do not get thought of in advance
So don't ask me like things like that. All right, so what's your what you have me? Do you want to mind? What's your nuggets?
There's an interesting phenomenon. I see at Microsoft more than anywhere else and people will
To exit the bathroom. They'll basically wrap their entire arm and paper towels to pull the door open
Yet they'll eat anything you put on the kitchen counter. I don't get it. I
could put turd cookies out there
I could put like
Lasagna directly on the counter on a plate. They all is on ya. Yeah
But they cannot touch that stainless steel door handle this this
So Alan Alan wrote up the topic
And I'm like, okay usually when Alan wrote safe topics, I'm like, all right, I'll be able to swing with this
Yeah, I was like, okay
So you have you found some weird OCD specialists that you're hanging out with check it out. So Microsoft employees
What do we pay I don't think it's like a 59 total compensation like a fiction. I was like an entry-level person
They get good amount of money and they get great benefits
We take care of people here and we have a lot of long and tooth people like me and Brent not poor
We're not zillionaires or we wouldn't hey hey podcast Brent maybe poor. Yeah, it depends on it's a relative discussion
Well, anyway
You can get like an email from an admin saying hey, we're giving away free $5 t-shirts over here
Everyone will stop working like autumn deadline smedline. I'm getting my free shirt. Yes
and it doesn't be a shirt it can be a you know can be a shot glass or a mug or a
Little card that lets you have a badge for your avatar or whatever that the little teeny things people will I know I have a deadline
No, this build broken and I'm responsible to fix it. But there's a free t-shirt two buildings over. I'm going to get it
You ever read free? No
So one of the the topics that I'm hugely fascinated by is this thing called behavioral economics
and
The word free is just powerful right? Hey free stuff it it it doesn't even matter
I don't think this is a Microsoft phenomenon
Perhaps not yeah people we have free coffee and free soda people just grab when they go by it
Oh my god, the soda is free
If we're gonna say like if you like sodas free only on Fridays people would stockpile they go crazy if they changed it
Hey new t-shirt one nickel. Oh, yeah, I guarantee you would see a totally different behavior
So I was noticing that there was a a division wide t-shirt giveaway and I'm walking
I'm watching the throng and you know, I'm the ever the efficiency
And and wait, I hate waste and I'm watching
Thousands of people walk over to get their t-shirt and I thought you know
We have work to do and they're waiting in line
I know there's so when you said the microsurfs and so do the differences between the the
How called the decades like we are?
Definitely knee-deep in a new transformation
Right. I
Haven't I I can talk about the first decade. I was here in the second decade. I was here and very distinctly
I'm not gonna do it today, but the next decade
It's going to be very different like the one thing I found out yesterday
I didn't know about this and I'm still thinking through what are the downstream consequences?
Apparently we've stopped the ship it program. Yeah, we have. Yeah, right and I'm like
Interesting. So we're moving towards stopping the ship it program where we were
Microsoft as a whole was moving away from sort of a
Office space lifestyle more towards an open space lifestyle
And it's really for me hard to predict what this is going to be at the
end of that particular
Journey. Well the ship it program for those that don't work at the evil Empire is every time you ship a product you get a little
Decal to go on this that little metal decal to go on this plaque. Yeah
Yep, and I have two of them full of products that some I'm proud of and some I'm not
in
the
We're moving to a world where we may not have
Any products at Microsoft have major releases anymore. Maybe all incremental
Yeah, and then from that from that point of view, I totally agree with the removal the ship it program
But one of the things that I've used that ship it program when I go and I meet a new person
That's one of the first things I go look at
because
Right there is a stalker. That's like someone's Facebook history
No, what is listed right there is a set of experiences for that individual set of products a set of knowledge
And I find that I'm like, oh
Hey
You and I worked on the same team. I did not realize that well on mine
You would see I worked on Windows millennium and you would think less of me
At this point in time that's a challenge
Oh
Hear that
Right just didn't hear he worked on it. And as we heard earlier, he's a test specialist and yet millennium still happened
It's a law I could talk about windows. It's me. I don't know the millennium came from I thought it was Windows marketing edition
Millennium edition. Yeah, I was that was that the fix for y2k? No
I'm still puzzled why that thing ever went out
You know why it went out because that was before we companies were distributing applications primarily via the internet and Windows
Was the only ship vehicle for a lot of applications?
So we had to put a new version of Windows out in order to ship a bunch of things that people wanted to have shipped elsewhere
at Microsoft. Yeah
Sorry world. Yep
We broke the world. Do I have any Alan broke the world? I haven't matched the trend yet
I'm gonna make a list of these
There is a weird vortex around campus and I can't now that we used to have parking passes we stuck in their window
I never put one in but you can always tell a Microsoft driver because they had the same little pass hanging from their window
Yeah, but now we don't require those so I can't identify the Microsoft drivers
but I can say there is a vortex around the campus of
Really aggressive bad driving?
yes, but I haven't found the pattern yet to to really make that a
An observable trend that I can predict
Six years ago
This was like all throughout our internal like news sources that it was a huge problem
And I haven't seen any sort of um, I I
People ignoring pedestrians and oh they do completely I yeah sometimes if I get up late
I will go for a run in the middle of the day rather than I usually run in the morning and
I take a path that has me crossing the fewest streets as possible yet. I still
Pretty much I'm in fear for my life every time I cross the street. Yeah, I just let the car go by I try to
But then yeah, it's it's it's a crazy
It's crazy and I think part of it is do you think that so Microsoft has these streets that go through campus?
But they're they're public streets technically I think but the police never watch them. They are public streets. So yeah people drive
That shit crazy. Yep, and yeah, so
And even around blind corners and and
one of the
One of the things that I tell people on that because I get every so often
Oh my god
I was just about to enter the crosswalk and this guy went anyway, and I'm like, okay
Well, you didn't enter the crosswalk. So by the legal they can still go once you step a foot in there
Yeah, they have to stop and that's the other thing the the Microsoft pedestrians
They don't slow down. No, they
It's idiotic the approach of my lights green I'm going if you hit me it's your fault. Yes, and you're going to die
Yeah, that's the thing that like with the pedestrian even worse
I have a longer story for this. I'm not gonna go into it today. But the nutshell of it is
Look guys
You walk in the crosswalk and you and you get hit
Yes, they are in the wrong
They'll go to jail
You'll go to the graveyard. I
Just don't get your perspective, right? I was on a run one morning at work and
a guy was on his bicycle on the
On the sidewalk and he wanted to there's this turn
There's this place for people coming off the freeway and they want to turn right and it's really hard visibility
They want to turn right on the red
But they can't because they can't see there was a guy on his bicycle and he was like one foot in the street
Ready to go the second that crosswalk turned green
Pedestrian sign turns green the same time the traffic light turns green the guy
Started turn right slammed on his brakes
He wasn't going very fast and the bicyclist because he wanted to make a point just stood in front of him
He stared at him and stood right in front of his car. Just I mean like an aggressive bicyclist and I
Don't get it. Anyway off of the weeds here a little bit
But we'll look for I'll look for some more and it isn't just like one isolated thing. I'm looking for some more trends
There's a new pattern going like one of the things
Like the open the open space model
Here in Xbox, I think it's done rather effectively. I'm moving to to a new
building where it with a different design it's sort of the
The the corral people in like cows about to get milked a model that you'll see you that the Skype team has
Oh, I hate that but but the thing is that we've been told is that it's all open space and it's collaborative
but you go walk in those buildings and it's like
Entering a library during the middle of a funeral. I love team rooms. I love them
When they max out at 10 people at the most
Yeah, when you shove in 30 it it turns into a library I was yeah a whole other conversation
But there's there's a there will be
Pattern consequences to that model. All right. We'll look for things to happen in the next decade. Yes, we will stay employed that long
All right, everyone have a happy happy and safe holiday and a fantastic new year. All right, I'm not Brent. I am not Alan
All right, we'll see you in 2015
Ciao