Hey, I'm Alan.
I'm Brett.
And if you remember us, we're part of the AV testing podcast.
It's been a long time, right, Brett?
Guys, how long has it been?
Well, we...
Last time I saw you...
Three months?
Last time I saw you is the beginning of July.
We recorded episode number nine, which means...
Big double digits!
Woo hoo!
Well, we were in double digits if you used octal.
Never mind.
Yeah, true.
Okay, using a 10-based accounting system, we're in episode number 10.
And man, I leave for one little summer and Microsoft goes haywire crazy doing all kinds
of wild stuff.
Yeah, there is a saying around here that at least there used to be that we work in dog
years.
Maybe, maybe.
I used to say that Xbox, my two years on Xbox, was the best five years of my life, but
I think more time may have passed by since that shift.
Yeah, you know, the last two months, I think we lost...
We progressed a couple of years.
Yeah, and speaking of the last two months, for those of you that don't recall or don't
even know who I am, I took the summer off.
My last day of work was around July 9th, and I didn't come back to work until just after
Labor Day, week after Labor Day, somewhere in there.
I spent most of time in France.
Shouldn't you do that with like a rich, sweaty, sweaty person's voice?
I should, but you know what?
I was on the beaches of Provence.
I was in the south of France, very laid back, drank a whole lot of rosé, spent most of
our time in Exim Provence, did some traveling around the southern coast of France.
Because we were so close, we were in Nice, we took a little day trip along the coast,
went to the Museum Ocean d'Agráfique in Monaco, where Jacques Cousteau used to work.
It's fantastic of aquarium, nice museum.
And then because we were so close, we drove across the border, had a nice, huge pasta
dinner in Italy.
Where?
South Italy?
No, I guess it would be North Italy somewhere.
Excuse us, while we have a geography lesson.
I don't think there's a bridge.
We took a spaceship.
Anyway, it was a great summer.
People joke about the way I put this, but we stopped on the way home in Japan for a
week and visited some friends.
So I made it all the way around the world this summer, took the kids to the Pokemon
Store in Osaka.
Oh, I bet you they had a blast at that.
They had a good time.
Our friends gave them some money to spend there, and they spent three hours trying to figure
out what they were going to get.
My daughter is all into Hello Kitty, and I'm sure that that would be one of the first
places I would have to go.
Anyway, good trip.
A lot happened while I was gone.
Maybe...
Yeah, so if you guys remember, back in episode nine, one of our closing discussions was,
hey, what do you think will happen once you come back, Alan?
So let me ask you, how far wrong were we?
You know, we weren't far wrong, and there were other predictions I made that even were
crazier.
So, just fill me on what's going on.
I'm going to look at some technical things here that are kind of bugging me with our
podcast while Brent talks about what's going on.
Well, so one of the...
I would say the biggest prediction that we seem to be off on, just slightly, is we didn't
think Windows would begin the big change.
Well, what changed...
Tell me what big change Windows made, because I'm in Windows, and I didn't notice it.
I noticed it less than Windows than other parts of the company.
So while you were out...
I'm still catching up.
This is my second full week back.
While you were out, quite a few of the Windows orgs, my connections in those Windows orgs,
reached out to me and said, holy crap, Brent, we're starting that change.
For example, one of the comments was saying is sort of a rethinking of the quality orgs.
We shifted to a quality-based system, I don't know how long, four or five, six months ago.
But yet, even though we rebranded this quality, and some groups within the Windows org, it's
kind of still viewed as sort of the test org.
And we're seeing, I think, a stepwise sort of dismantling of that towards a combined engineering
role.
Well, let me tell you what I saw.
And without digging myself too big of a hole here.
And maybe I should go back and talk about some other predictions I made at a community
event that you weren't able to make it to.
We talked, probably, I'm sure I mentioned, we do this soapbox event every year for
one of the communities we're involved in, where everybody gets five to seven minutes,
I can't remember what time limit we used, on stage to rant about whatever they want to,
the wilder the better, and there's some entertainment going on.
It's a good time.
And the theme for this year was if I were CEO, and I got a little, we gave everybody
a little name sticker that says Sachi Nadella, and they got to talk about whatever they
wanted to.
And I talked about revamping management at Microsoft.
I made three big points.
And one was self organizing engineering teams.
And do that with a flatter or structure, where you have engineering managers that are in
charge of 14, 15, 16 people, and people that are capable of leadership of organizing and
orchestrating that team into something that can, you know, into self organizing teams that
can fill in gaps, etc, etc.
And those two things, there's actually a memo from Sachi this summer saying, hey,
we're doing these two things.
I thought, hey, maybe he said maybe he saw my talk, probably not, because this is all
this is not me inventing something.
This is me paying attention to what works in the real world and goes, oh, that kind of
makes a lot of sense.
That's something we should probably do.
But here in A.B.
Testing, we're going to get full credit talent.
Yeah.
So the third thing was it's like, how do you find those engineering managers
capable of orchestrating a larger team and doing the right thing?
And one thing at Microsoft we have is moving from position to position at
Microsoft is you have to go through a full interview loop just like when you were
first hired at Microsoft.
And I think it's sort of silly.
And there's a lot of restrictions around managers could put up, well, we're going
to need this person's mission critical.
We're going to need it for six months.
And it's, although it's certainly, it's not totally difficult or completely
difficult to move from position to position around the company, it's much
more difficult than it needs to be.
So my third premise in that was to make that as easy as possible.
So you'd be in agreement between the current manager and the hiring manager.
Hey, they're going to move over here.
You know, minimum transition times.
You can work half and half if you want to for a while, just help with the
transition, but people want to move, let them move.
And if you make that easy, and then some of the details that I won't go into today,
but if you make that easy, the way you identify your poor managers is they
don't have anybody working for them anymore because it's so much easier
for them to lead.
I think, believe it or not, my prediction is we will get there very soon
because there was a hint in that memo that said something coming up around
internal transitions.
I'm hoping we make that super easy.
I think it's going to help solve some other problems as well.
That would be so fantastic.
In addition to that, we should be able to make the EMs, the engineering
managers, move as easily.
Like in the world that you're talking about, right, the EMs will likely end
up having to have two big skills.
One, the ability to successfully execute on whatever their domain is, but in
an empowering fashion, in order to do that, they're going to have to cleanly
understand the value proposition of what they're doing and communicate down
the value principles versus sort of micromanaging command and command.
Yeah, came up with a friend of mine, sort of a metaphoric.
I spent a lot of time in France eating some fantastic food.
I was thinking, we have managers, and I'm going to be blunt here, we have a
lot of managers at Microsoft who are very good at turning the crank at the
sausage factory.
They make awesome sausage, but they turn that crank.
They've been turning this crank for 20 years, and they make some great
frickin' sausage.
The problem is the dishes we're making are much more complex.
Sorry for the metaphor, but it really needs a little of this,
little of this tasting as you go, letting it simmer, kind of just...
It's a much more complex...
What we need our leaders to do is much more complex than turning the sausage
crank.
It's a transition we need to make.
Honestly, there's a big chunk of our managers at Microsoft who only know
how to crank the sausage and don't know how to do anything else.
Your metaphor got slightly weird, but there was one thing I'll attempt to do
to add to it.
What the hell?
The other thing too is our competitors have learned, hey, wait a minute, we can
automate sausage cranking.
So then their people, instead of focusing on turning the damn crank, are
more focused on what kind of sausages should we make to enhance these more
complicated dishes that you're referring to.
Whereas we're spending all of our time going, no, we must turn the
crank.
Now we must take time off in order to maintain the crank.
Whereas our competitors, they've got the whole factory figured out.
The second thing I was going to say in terms of what engineering
managers then would need to focus on is I'll say customer delight, but in
a different angle.
This is employee delight.
One of the things when I introduce myself to my employees, I refer to
myself as their MSP.
They are my customer and I am their management service provider.
I'm fully aware that them choosing to leave the team is a big portion of
them choosing to fire me.
I make that part of my active practice because I don't like to be fired by
anything.
We need more managers think that way.
When somebody leaves, this works with my comment before, but let that
movement happen freely.
When I decided to go work for the manager, I fired you.
I like thinking about it that way.
One thing I mentioned before because I'm a huge fan of Pat Lincione,
the first person I actually read this in writing from, but direct
correlation between organizational health, how much do I love my job
and a bunch of other things around there, and product quality.
Those things are not completely independent.
They're very tightly related.
All you got to do is spend a few months in a team that has poor
organizational health.
The quality of the product will directly correlate it.
You know what's worse is when is this blind oblivion.
I see teams where they do because they never look outside their team
for anything.
They don't realize that their team's unhealthy.
Often, those are the same people that don't realize their
products unhealthy.
They're on a dismal team and they're making a mediocre product,
but they don't know any better and they're happy.
It hurts me to see that.
I shouldn't say they're happy.
They don't know what happiness is.
It's even worse than that because they do know better because
they have an engine typically around self-justification and
they are well skilled in going to look at those feedback
sources that affirm their subjective bias.
They go a more tortoise of ignorance.
They know what they know and they have a whole lot of that.
I've been talking to a couple friends of mine who were part
of the layoffs this summer.
Brett and I are somehow still employed.
I know a lot of people and I get good, good people who got
laid off.
Actually, all of the good people I know, I think most of
the found jobs, most of them, not all of them have found jobs.
We went through two layoffs.
All the good people I know from the layoffs that occurred
a couple months ago, the beginning of your vacation,
they've landed in great jobs.
Still have a few more from this last layoff.
Guys out there, we're very approachable.
If you work in a company that's looking for data science guys
or data pipeline guys or testing type guys, reach out to me
on Twitter because I know a bunch of really good people
right now that are looking for a new home.
The reason I brought that up.
By the way, I don't think it will take long for them
to find it.
No, no, no.
I think there's a couple things people are finding.
A lot of people that got laid off have been at
Microsoft a long time which is both good and bad.
It's good that they get a really nice severance package.
They're paid for quite a while.
What's bad is everybody I've talked to, to varying degrees,
is sort of blown away by the shelteredness of being
in the Microsoft walls and a lot of people don't
pay attention or haven't paid attention to what goes on
outside of Microsoft.
It's been very eye opening for them as they look around
at the rest of the software market and go,
oh, this is kind of how things are going.
My group was kind of hinting at going this way.
It's weird this team is full on doing this.
Or they're blown away by how much software tech
is in the Seattle area.
How many companies have offices and the number
of positions available.
They can actually be a little bit selective,
which is good.
But the main thing is, oh, there are other ways
to make software than the way I've been doing it
in my little sausage factory for the last 10 years.
Yeah, no, the people I've talked to on that front,
a good portion of them were very much anti-everything,
not Microsoft before they left.
And now some of the folks are coming back and going,
wow, I did not know what I could have had.
It's one of those things when I'm fighting the big fight
to getting people towards agile here within the company.
When I can get a couple of teams executing the rules
as they should be laid out, and they go, holy crap.
Now I completely understand why you were saying all that.
When I first walked through it and heard it,
I thought it was this hugely complex thing.
But once I got the muscle memory,
I don't ever want to go back.
Yeah, and I think the meta point to make there is,
and of course, if you listen to this podcast,
I'm preaching to the wrong people,
but it's really important that you actually pay attention
to what's going on in your profession worldwide.
You don't have to memorize the engineering practices
and organizational structure of every major software company
out there, but you should have an idea
of what their approaches are,
what their engineering values are.
Those are freely available.
We know that you want to think about flat org structures.
Let's look at how Zappos do it work.
If you want to think about who does some really cool stuff
with data science, let's look at what Netflix is doing,
especially with reliability and their chaos suite,
their simian army.
So everybody needs to know,
I mean, these are basic things that everyone should know,
but if I were to go to,
I can probably say the majority, man, that's a little harsh.
Maybe the majority of engineers I know at Microsoft
and ask them about those things, they go,
I don't know.
And this kind of goes back to,
this is not a Microsoft civic thing
I want to pick on our company,
but this goes back to DiMarco.
What was the darn book he wrote?
He found in his research that some high percentage
of the people had never even read a book
on software engineering,
since they got a professional job.
And that same sort of principle is true.
People, I just can't imagine being happy with my job
if I wasn't constantly learning
and trying to expand what I know,
what I've discovered throughout life.
And I wouldn't even be here if that wasn't the case.
I wouldn't even be employed at Microsoft.
People aren't censored by different things.
Yeah, I totally get that.
But I think one of the reasons I'm still employed
is because I'm learning and I'm adaptable
and I'm flexible and I can be put in a lot of different
situations and be successful.
And you're one of those guys who do pay attention
and bring it into the organization
to help enhance their forward progress.
And unfortunately that makes you a differentiator.
Why do you say unfortunately?
Because a lot of the things that we're bringing through,
this is a common discussion between you and I.
A lot of the things that you and I
are trying to bring to this company.
I've been teaching people Agile stuff for three years.
And I'm just like, it's making a small chink in the armor.
But my sense is if we don't figure this out as a company
within the next three years,
there's not gonna be a following three years.
Well, we've talked a lot at length in the past
on organizational change and getting people,
there's some sense of wanting to need to change as well.
And I think I'm kind of excited
with Satya's leadership on this.
I think we're definitely heading in the right direction,
but there's a lot of resistance even,
I would say even among the higher up executives,
because again, they've been making sausage.
They've been making some darn good sausage for decades.
And it's hard from top down to make those changes.
The other thing in terms of not only looking outside,
like you were saying,
people should be spending some time looking outside.
There was a study I read a few months ago.
The basic study, it must be true.
And basically what the study concluded
is that if you read one hour in any topic
that you have an interest in,
if you just read one hour a day for seven years,
you would be an international expert on that topic.
Sure, sure.
And the stuff that we're talking about,
I don't know that we need a ton of international experts
on all these variable topics,
but it doesn't take much time
to stay connected to global best practices.
The first thing you gotta do though,
is careful man, you use the best practices.
There's people that will freak out about that.
Yeah, it is.
I'm one of them.
So you mentioned this polling of engineers
and some of them would go, no, I don't know.
What's even worse is if you take that subgroup,
I'm willing to bet the majority of those people
who don't even do it, you ask them why they don't,
is because, wow, that's stupid,
because a chaos monkey is stupid,
because how are they gonna keep track of all those bugs?
Right, that's just gonna generate bugs and cause interrupt
and how are we gonna move forward?
And it's sort of a zero sum game for them.
When we hit one of the challenges about a year ago,
when we were talking about the changes coming up with test,
you and I both knew it's gonna happen.
All the forces are in place.
This has got momentum that is unstoppable.
But yet I would still go and talk to directors
and say, hey, all of this work still has to be done.
So what's the difference if we have a test discipline
versus a dev discipline?
They view it as a zero sum game.
They wouldn't acknowledge that tests are dead
doing their own testing
actually increases sausage production.
You give for a lot of inefficiency.
Right.
It's nice to look at,
I don't wanna send the metaphor anymore,
so I'm gonna stop.
What do you wanna talk about next, Mr. Random Order Guy?
Are we still in the changes category?
Let me talk about the third sub-folder.
So one of the things that I'm seeing now,
there's a new change of questions
people are coming and asking me about.
We have a lot of these new startup
data science groups throughout the company.
And as a-
Oh, wait, actually, let me go back.
Have you yet heard about blended engineering?
Is this where I used the metaphor,
the little, I threw it from my mouth thing?
Yeah, this is possibly where Alan Beeps himself.
So one of the more innovative groups in Windows
has decided that combined engineering is stupid
and that they're going to enhance it
with this topic of blended engineering.
And blended engineering, just in a nutshell,
is where the test team still exists
because the same level of testing still needs to occur.
Try to, I mean, the quality team.
Anyway, go on, I'm gonna shut up.
Yeah, they do testing.
But blended engineering means
that team now reports to the dev manager.
Huh.
Do you need to take a sip of water?
I don't know what I need to do.
I think I don't wanna comment on that.
All right.
I need to write, and I've started this
and I haven't finished it.
I need to write my thoughts down
on how an engineering team works
and why people over-complexify.
Is that a word?
Sure.
They make this, they decide, okay,
I recognize the inefficiencies
of passing stuff back and forth from dev to test
and back and forth and back and forth.
So my solution for that is to create an engineering team
and I'm gonna implement it in this amazingly stupid way
that ensures that I can never, ever have success.
So there's, as you can tell, going down that path,
write intent, wrong implementation.
So I think, or I don't even say wrong implementation.
I think it's okay to be wrong,
but it's not okay to not think through,
it's a systems problem.
There's many moving pieces.
Let's think about what this change is
before you actually implement it.
And that's where I see a lot of teams fail.
Yeah, I do as well.
The challenge that I'm facing a lot lately
is I do spend a lot of quality time on system thinking,
but the challenge for me is being able
to take the conclusions from that process
and then simplify it in a way that's consumable
by those who don't have that strength.
Yeah, this goes back to everything we've talked about,
about organizational change
and letting people know what's going on
and let them see success quickly, blah, blah, blah,
et cetera, et cetera.
Those things all apply.
You need, it's not a single crank.
It's not a single thing you change.
You have to do a lot of things differently.
It requires, as you mentioned before,
a different style of leadership and management
to make this work.
It requires just a lot of pieces to move at the same time.
And if you miss that, you're just not gonna be successful.
You're gonna think it doesn't work.
And it really can work.
One thing I wanted to mention, as I mentioned this,
I might've mentioned this before,
but worth bringing up again is the team I'm on.
I'm on a very small team, so we're a little unique
in that we have our quality team
and we do a lot of analysis, data pipeline,
make sure we can get the data back from our
flighting, et cetera.
My manager is the quality manager.
His peer is the dev manager.
But in a lot of companies I know outside of Microsoft,
because I actually pay attention,
my manager would just be another dev manager
and his team owns infrastructure and data analysis.
They would call him a development team.
They would be seen as a peer
to the other dev organization.
They could report up through a dev director at the top,
but in a way, in a slightly contrived way,
we have a combined engineering team, an engineering team,
but we do have a separate, on paper,
we have a separate dev and quality org.
I think I'm not gonna lie and say we're an engineering
team that works together like an engineering team,
but we're closer than the old back and forth,
back and forth of the past.
We don't really test stuff for the developer.
And we look at scenarios
and a lot more customer experiences
than on product functionality or feature functionality.
I don't wanna, that's just not what we do.
So the team that I'm on now,
very similar to the way you describe your team.
We do, everybody's title is engineer something.
I report to an engineering director.
His peers are all engineering directors,
except for the PM org.
I am an engineering manager, my ICs are engineers.
It's one of those things.
A rename doesn't change the perception of your role.
And that's the largest challenge.
So a lot of the folks in my org,
so when we did a recent reorg,
we took a whole bunch of testers
and we integrated them into the dev teams
and then reframed them as product engineers.
My team, we don't have a tight framing,
the way I communicated,
we kinda own the the horizontals of the org.
System testing, perfs, stuff, data pipeline analysis,
very similar to how you described your role.
Something is still holding the majority of the org
as a view of this is the place
where we can push quality downhill
and they're the ones accountable.
And it's been a non-trivial amount of me,
my peers and my manager's time going,
guys, you gotta stop this behavior.
Yeah, at that stage, it really comes down
to a leadership issue and making sure
that everyone knows what you're doing
and why you're doing it.
So a couple of new problems that have been popping up.
The situation that I described for my team
is a common situation throughout the company.
There's a lot of people in these quality orgs,
so they're sort of facing those same things.
A specific new problem that's popping up.
So when all of these data analysis teams came into being,
there was this belief that their role
is to feed the PM org, to help the PM
do usage analytics and really firm up
the type of features that are valuable
by the customer and help to create differentiators.
But the new problem in a nutshell,
you should be leading a horse to water,
but you can't make them drink.
So not a new problem is the PMs are like, great.
Like, where's my report?
Where's my answer?
Right, so there's a problem right now
where the PMs don't wanna give up sort of intuition mode
and they don't see the benefit of a fact driven.
It's a system.
And one thing, if you're gonna change,
we're not just changing what test or quality does,
changing what development does.
And it's not just change for change is sick,
it's change because we think we can get these efficiencies.
So the system or the model goes that way in direction,
but every engineering discipline involved,
the role changes.
And we're starting to see the PM role,
the program manager role at Microsoft begin to change.
I think it's gonna begin to change very rapidly,
almost what you call an overhaul of the role
as part of the system.
Ideally, all these things would move at once,
but any of you familiar with systems thinking,
no, it's really difficult to get all the pieces
to move at once in the right direction.
You can get all the pieces to move at once
in the right direction.
If you do it one step at a time,
what I'm seeing happening is we're changing one piece
all the way to where we wanna go.
And the other pieces aren't changing.
And to me, I'm bringing back the sausage metaphor.
It's like we decided the sausages aren't good enough,
we're gonna start making calzones.
And so we got one team manufacturing calzone cranks
and everyone else is still over there
trying to figure out how I stuff sausage meat
into a calzone crank.
Yeah, and what I've seen, and to be clear,
I'm bullish on Microsoft.
I see from Sotis leadership,
he knows exactly what kind of, it seems to be,
he seems to know what kind of food factory
he wants to build.
And it's a challenge for him as well.
He has to get his leaders,
people that have been at Microsoft a long time,
making sausage.
And he used to say, look, maybe sausage
isn't the right thing to make.
Let's make a boogie base.
Like, I don't know, man,
can I make that with a crank?
Cause I know how to use the crank.
This requires pots and fish and shelling and things.
And skills I'm not comfortable with.
I don't know how to make broth with a crank.
Yeah, exactly.
What do I put in?
Do I put in pork, beef, come on.
Yeah, so my limited exposure to the Satya,
my perception of what he's doing,
is he's actively paying attention to those teams
that have figured out a process
that helps rapidly convert the culture.
Yeah, and one thing, I'll go ahead
and I won't be in trouble, no one listens to this podcast,
but we have three listeners.
No, we have like nine.
I think only a couple work at Microsoft
and they won't report me anything,
but he sent a memo around flattening org structures
and a bunch of other things.
I thought this is fantastic.
This is gonna help the larger organization I'm in.
And one of our engineering leaders sent mail to the org
saying, I read, sure you're all right, Satya's mail.
He says to do this.
We're good, don't need to do that yet.
He said to do this.
And it makes sense.
We're in the middle of a,
there's been a lot of change already.
It's a very large org, a lot going on.
It'd be difficult to make it.
On one hand, I understand that,
I understand the logic.
It's like, we've had enough change going on.
This is gonna be very disruptive.
The size of an org,
very difficult to make some of these changes now.
So I think those will happen later.
But my druthers would be, let's do it now.
Let's make it happen
because I know about the efficiencies it would bring.
I've seen the inefficiencies that are caused
by a very squished, heavy, heavy middle management layer
and organizational structure.
And I would love to see that go away.
My problem with, anytime I see a messaging like that
around later, the opportunity later in one aspect
is beneficial, right?
Because you have an opportunity to then stepwise progress
towards making later happen
and you can hit the ground running.
But no one ever executes it that way.
It basically ends up, in my experience,
it ends up being a deferral tactic.
And it gets deferred, deferred, deferred, deferred
until it can't be anymore.
And then it's the ripping of the band-aid
in a way where the band-aid yanks the person's arm off.
There's so much dysfunction that you could have,
dysfunction and pain that you could have mitigated
by leveraging later.
Yeah, we'll see what happens.
I do think, so I do think anybody who thinks
engineering flattening is done is wrong.
Oh, definitely.
Definitely.
Anybody who thinks PM is safe is wrong.
Matter of fact, I think PM's up next.
And I think we're gonna see, my prediction here
is we're gonna see the PM ratios impact PM by 50%.
50% of the PM's will be looking for a new way to add value.
And I do think the high order bit for those PM's
are gonna be the ones who have successfully
and proactively figured out how to use
the new data-driven engineering culture
to differentiate themselves from their peers
in a way that adds business side.
Hey, we are getting low on time.
This is one of the things I wanted to talk about today.
Did you see on the news the iOS update?
I have not.
So what happened was iOS did an update
and for some segment of the brand new iPhone 6 phones
caused cellular to stop working.
Oops.
Being a Microsoft guy, fantastic.
They should ship more of those.
So it's interesting.
Every time, what I find interesting is that
almost every time there's some major bug,
I see some tester pop on Twitter or 50 of them go,
oh, maybe a testing problem at Apple.
When healthcare.gov came out,
actually, these are two with their issues.
Like, oh, maybe they should have tested more.
No, that was a software engineering problem.
So let's talk just for a second about,
so if you shipped a bug that-
Subjective bias.
Enough users that it would hurt.
I have my own answer.
I'll see if it matches with yours.
But if you were an engineering director at Apple
and you had this new update rolling out,
what do you think you may have done differently
to have avoided a bug like this?
So did it happen across the board?
No, it did not happen across the board.
And that's very important to mention
because I see the comments from the people that don't read
or something saying, well, they obviously didn't test this
because it wrecked phones, but didn't.
It was some, but many.
And did it wreck phones?
No, no.
People could go into iTunes, into a restore.
They'd lose some stuff,
but they'd get back to their factory settings
and then not update.
Apple ended up pulling the update.
And I think they have,
I haven't paid attention since the issue came out.
But anyway, I think it's all okay now,
but you had an update that broke cellular
on a significant number of your brand new phones.
All right, so here's a couple things.
So Apple, they have a product people love
and is all over the world.
In terms of risk, there's a non-trivial chance
that if you do make a mistake
because the product in general is loved,
that the majority of the audience will still bounce back.
Like there isn't, with Apple, because it's a love product,
although I haven't paid much attention
to Android and Samsung.
Those are climbing dramatically.
In addition to that,
like the one thing I'm thinking through,
my normal practice would be, you know what?
Do some due diligence proactively.
You should have some bed of machines.
This isn't like creating the end all be all system test lab
that you and I are used to from the old days.
I don't wanna do that.
In fact, I'm gonna interrupt.
I think this is a perfect example
of where flighting circles are being able to deploy,
that was the next thing.
I do think-
I think that's the key to this
because you wanna deploy this new update.
You're not gonna deploy, can't take any update
when you have enough diverse ecosystem of carriers, et cetera,
and deploy it to the world at the same time.
What I'm saying is that before it goes out,
there is some small element of preventative testing
that you should do.
Absolutely, and they obviously did that.
Most obviously did-
If they didn't, they'd see them on them, right?
Because there's a complexity around the options
and different providers,
and I'm certain that they get hardware
from different places.
I know they had tight controls on their hardware,
but flight control is the answer here.
Absolutely, it's like we deployed this
to 1% of our users and you look across the board
because this is not just for iPhone 6,
this is for some previous versions as well, the update.
Hey, there is a percentage of our iPhone 6 clients
that we've sent the update to,
and they've never sent a phone home after that.
The only challenge with this strategy,
the only challenge, this is why I brought up
Apple's domination in the customer love world,
for lack of a better word,
is even with the flight control,
even our exposure control with the flighting
of these updates,
if it hits a couple people,
if you did it right, it will be affected, right?
And it's gonna be a challenge to figure out
how to turn the crank and turn it back.
But the question is, if you don't do it accurately,
and when people get impacted,
is it a case that even two people in Apple
hitting this issue will be a PR nightmare for them?
I wanna be really clear in bringing this up
because I get annoyed when I see people do this
elsewhere on the internet, is I don't work there.
I don't, you know, it's completely possible
that they did all this and they just couldn't recognize it
in the analysis of the data.
So this is, it's like armchair software engineer
is a lot, is very easy.
Thought it was a worthy topic of discussion.
But the thing that I would love
if I were engineering director,
like the thing that I would try to do,
is how can I do seamless continuous updates
with an exposure control?
Because a lot of these problems happen
because they changed so much
that you really don't know cause and effect along with them.
It ends up being another systems issue
because there's carriers that say,
no, we only want updates at this frequency.
And the way carriers, with their radio stack,
there can be a lot of different things can go on.
So it's, anyway, it's interesting to talk about,
but I'm always blown away every time
there's a public bug of any company,
you know, it always comes out,
what bothers me is that a lot of people think,
what was the testing issue?
And maybe this one was, but quality issues aren't,
or frequently, or most often not an issue of testing.
The people we hang out with,
or the community we're associated with,
right, a lot of those guys are gonna go,
it's a testing issue,
as an, primarily, cause we still live in a world
where they're trying to create arguments
for why the old ways are the better ways.
Right, and it's time to move on, actually.
And if that's true, like,
Apple had a major update issue,
what, three years ago?
Where they were brick and phones?
Like, why didn't they change their process?
I mean, they probably have, but it'd be interesting.
I wonder if they have an exposure control program.
Yeah, again, our armchair software engineering is easy.
Doing it from our seats here, we'll figure it out.
Great, I'm gonna, I'll get back to the mail bag next week,
cause we're about out of time,
and someone's gonna come in here
and give us a dirty look.
Yes.
So, it's good to be back, I'll say that,
and thanks for listening this far,
and I'm Alan.
I'm Brad.
And we'll talk to you soon.
Yep, see ya.