Everybody hi, I'm Alan and I'm Brent and guess what we're back for episode Brent tells me 14 13 14
No, it's 14
episode 14 of a be testing
We had to take we missed a week
You may have noticed we usually get something out about every two weeks
But with holidays and things and we had to skip a week. It was kind of a bummer. Yes, it was but we're back and
I guess we have some things to talk about so you're ready to get started. Yeah. I have one thing that's not on the board
No, not on the board feature. We have podcast creep. Yes, we do and that is
very recently
My partner in crime has gotten older. So happy belated birthday
And before all of you send him a Twitter
He did not turn 50 in no way shape or form should you send him a Twitter?
Congratulating him on turning. I did not turn. He did not turn. I am one year away from a ARP
I'm a nice square number
Anyway, that happy birthday you geezer. Yeah, I'm
As they say down at the dog park effin old
All right. What were we gonna talk about besides age and forgetfulness?
so
Microsoft has gotten through just recently a bunch of layoffs
Without commenting anymore on the good or bad or both of those
One of our the guy I really respect
Was it wasn't it was given sort of the layoff package were you?
Here's a couple must find a job. You're still employed and he just couldn't find a good fit
it was tough because he's a really smart really well respected guy and
He sent he sent a mail saying
Two things I thought it was things we've hit on here before I want to kind of just bring him up again
He said there I'll paraphrase a bit two cultural traits that are holding Microsoft back
He said the first holding back from what?
Making faster progress making you're doing being as successful as we should be okay
One I'll go in reverse order of his one is something we talked about
At least a few podcasts is the non invented here syndrome and and Brent's team is working on breaking that congratulations, Brent
Yes, and I think that's awesome. I I I
Might without its own trials and tribulations
Yeah, and what was worse? I should come back to not event in here, but so I will okay
the other one was and
I'm sure Brent can relate to this because I certainly can is the
Valuation the the value we put on heroes and individual
Versus team and collaboration. Yep, and something we're trying to break
But it's sort of the the long-standing culture here is you know, we want
we value the people that come in and stay late in and
Fix the bug at the last minute that they created in the first place
That's one way to put it
We value highly
So the one thing that you didn't mention is also the the evils of command and control
I would add that to the to that list. Well, it wasn't in his list. So it
falls in there a little bit. I I
Agree with that. Let's just talk a little bit about those two points. Well, no, so so
right, we have we have
Heroism we have not invented here
We have command and control and we also have our review process and I would argue all of those things
Work together to increase this behavior. Yeah, I think it's a system
Heroes, why are the heroes coming in working 40 hour days over the weekend?
Right there. They're doing it because
Their command and control structure because they don't have the data
Came up with a bad plan and this guy's coming in and saving the day
And why is he doing it because he he perceives he's going to get a better review likely likely
Um, I do believe it's a system
I think I'm sure we've mentioned like all the things that have to change it wants to make it to kind of get that
Culture change to happen
What do you what do you think how what what sort of things could Microsoft do to?
Eliminate that value on the hero and put more value on the team
Peer-based reviews
Okay, something we talked about. Yeah, I've didn't that we spent a good amount of time last time
The the one thing though, that's that's sticking in my head
So Alan puts together all sorts of
Presentations you're like the chair of sasquake right? No
And I'll put it out here cuz I know those sasquake members are listening, but I'm looking to kind of back out of that role
Okay, but you currently are or no. I'm I'm I just I'm on the steering committee. Okay, that's it
Well, so one I was it you who put together the Jim Benson?
Yeah, yeah, I put I put together most of talks. Okay, so one thing that I went to the Jim Benson talk around personal
Which is interesting. This is under a topic of agile and one of the things he brought up that has has stuck with me is
teams need heroes
Teams need those people who are willing to
Dive in and just get it done through brute force if worse comes to worse
But the difference that he proposes is if you're a hero
That's your job
It's not going above and beyond your job
Your job is to firefight for the team. And so when you
Every two weeks end up spending
40-hour days
Well, thank you. And I I
Might is very hand wavy as a manager. I don't know how I would
Manage that or track how whether or not my hero on my team is exceeding or
Achieving their job, but I do like that philosophy. I do like that perspective. I have found
On the agile process that that I run which is sort of a hybrid between
Kanban and and lean agile
It's kind of allergic to heroes
The team is working together. So kind of heroes get
Not suppressed but pushed down in some regard
The the process doesn't like people
Going their own doing dark matter exercises
There's a perspective that the hero on the team ends up being a bottleneck
eventually
Yeah, did you ever read the Phoenix project? No, it's a it's
Took with the bottleneckers. I forget the guy's name. I used to have it memorized for but anyway book Phoenix project. It's
Three of constraints if you're the goal. Yep, so it's sort of the goal written as a
Little novel about this IT shop and
They have this guy who's basically the hero on the team. He's the bottleneck
He is the constraint and how do you you know?
What are some things you can do to make it so you don't rely on the hero and maybe you're right
That's okay. You can have a hero on the team and it's his job
But you don't you can't be a bottleneck. You can't rely on him like you can't be in a stage where
Well, it's okay that we suck because the hero will bail us out
Yes, and then what happens? I think his name may have been Brent. I gotta think about this
I totally forgotten now just popped in my head, but great book on on figuring out how theory of constraints and and and heroes
Relate it's really cool. It's called the Phoenix project. It's been a good
gosh
ten years since I was
Content being a hero on the team and yes, I've done my time. I'm totally motivated by
Not just me, but the team getting crap done. I like seeing progress
And it if for me, I don't know when the team does it
When there's no heroes I I feel like the team did something when the heroes did a little work
I feel like the hero did something. I don't know what
So it reminds me of a story. I was one of the last test managers for the the Zune
PC client what's a Zune?
And
For those who I think it has a look at that from the Windows 7. I think it has a Wikipedia page people can look it
up. Yes, you can
Zun e yes, thank you. Go on you totally put me in the weeds again
And there was an individual on that team who was sort of a old-school
STE
alright, and
She was a hero in in the in our vernacular we're talking about today
And it was it was interesting a calibration
this individual
was someone who I
Their manager was saying
Oh my god, all the devs want to work with her. She finds every single bug possible
and it was someone who was trying to go get into the senior band and
The the challenge I had with that is
in the senior band I expect people to
Get trained in leadership be showing how to help others grow and
and
this individual
wanted nothing to do with that and
It turned out that it would be it had the cause
was
There was a fear that if others got taught
then
She wouldn't be special anymore
And there was I have a story very talented tester
I'll say I'll share a story when you're done go. She was a very talented tester and one of the problems that I had with
with with with that approach is
So I remember one day I was talking with with their manager at over over lunch
And I said her existence on the team is actually heart
harming our
Organization and he was like what she comes and saves the day. I'm like, okay. Let me ask you a question
Are you saying that the whole rest of the test team is?
so inept
That if she weren't here
We wouldn't deliver the same degree of quality and he's like
Well, of course we would okay, so but we would be late. No. No, we wouldn't be late and I said well
What are you talking about? If?
What's the difference why what do you if you just got through telling me that she's coming and saving the day and
You also said if she weren't here
The team would still hit the same dates in the same quality bar. So what's the difference? He's like, oh well in that case
If she weren't here
Then what we would do is we would train up the rest of the team to be better testers and I said
How is that anything other than her presence is causing harm?
Right. The what had happened is is that the management had taken the lazy way out
relied on on the over relied on the presence of a hero and
it had gotten to the point where
They were a review based bottleneck
And what I mean by that is is that there was a huge fear that if if well, we got to do everything to make her
happy
Because she leaves our strategy is screwed
Because we didn't invest in the rest of the team and they're not prepared to pick up the slack. I think it's
really easy too easy and
for a lot of managers and management teams
to
put so much emphasis on the product and
You know the date and the features that they forget about the team that makes that software
I'm a believer that a healthy software team makes good software quality software. Mm-hmm and
Dysfunctional ones make good software, too. Um
Rarely, I think that's I think that's luck when they do that. I think I think it's a lot you
You'll generally find
20 to 30 percent attrition after they ship
Yeah, that that's great. That's good. The biggest the biggest thing I find that when you when you actually
Get agile working
What ends up happening is people's intrinsic?
motivation and their
extrinsic motivation like the
End up being aligned. They're one in the same the challenge now is it's sort of the carrot and the stick
This is why I'm saying dysfunctional teams will do it because if you don't I'll fire you
Right. Okay, so I'll get it done
but it's way more powerful and
It'll go a lot faster if people are doing it because there's some internal
Motivation
That's driving them. I believe that good management good leadership especially of a larger team is this I call it
Orchestration because I have this music background, but it's figuring out how to best utilize your generalizing specialists
recognized where your bottlenecks are and
Actually that second step something we forget about maybe step one is okay
I'm using my team effectively and I have this hero. They can only do one thing
I got one place to plug them in and
In then taking a step back and recognizing the next step is recognize. Okay, this person could just do this one thing
I'm sort of bottom up to them. How do I how do I relieve that and one thing is to you know?
Find people that can shadow and learn from them and whether it's the whether the woman you're talking about or something
somebody who's here's the only person knows how to configure our our
Our network switch in our data center or whatever something specific. You know, that's kind of bad
Yeah, the thing that ended up being super dysfunctional and in that particular team, right?
Is the management news she was a bottleneck and kept on sending people to her. Yeah train
She wouldn't yeah, and that right the story I was gonna tell earlier is on my very first team at Microsoft
I tested networking on Windows 95 and
and
One of the reasons I got the job was that at my previous company. I was the network administrator. This was in mid 90s
I knew a little bit about network. We had a network server that was not even around anymore
Really, but we had a network server. I knew some basic administration. I had to set up some we had some accounting software that
Only ran on a network system. So I knew a little bit about it. They needed they needed
kind of my match of skills plus some
Networking a network experience was perfect. We also had a guy in the team who was a network expert
he knew tons about it and
Our manager asked us asked him could you just spend an hour going through?
There's some details that Alan and so the guy don't know about just kind of give them an overview. He said no
And he said why says well, I've I've taken classes on this stuff and this is my value to the team
I'm if they know this then I'm not as valuable anymore
He actually told the manager that and then the manager told him okay, and then two days later. He was gone
He was walked out of the building
No, you're wrong
You're not so so even then 20 years ago
It was I guess I have to give some credit to our management chain for saying
Alright, you know we do value teamwork to some extent and sharing was that was that guy a full-time or
We're but we were all contractors. Oh, yeah, I'm my manager wasn't so why so you don't know my history
I started at Microsoft as a contractor
almost exactly 20 years ago. It was January like 4th 1995 and
I was hired full-time after five months by June by 20th official anniversary is coming up in June
I was 20th. Yeah, I'll be 20 years at Microsoft in June my official ones coming up in February
I didn't realize we were that close. Oh
This February see you're hired six months before me. I started at Microsoft in in fab of 95 December
94 I did six months as an intern then eight months as a
contractor and then saw
That's weird. That's a weird progression. Yeah, usually we hire our interns. We don't put them in the the
A-dash you not heard my intern story
Um
Did you like intern in marketing or something legal? No, what'd you do?
Once again a be testing often the weeds, but this is how we get the good stories out of branch. Yeah, so I got hired as
As an employee, okay
Guy came to my school
Pasty interview got flow flown up
went through a whole bunch of interviews in December and
and
Got the offer. Okay
When you come in your first day you go into this thing called new employee orientation. Mm-hmm and
the
The printout they gave you just says new employee orientation now I had
So I came into a building
It was actually
22 21
Came into a building and the room that it told me to go to was to the right and
There was another new employee orientation to the left and I was
Confused because the room it was sending me to
now on that placard said
intern
or orientation to the right and
To the left was full-time and I was confused
Because that was the first time in the entire cycle. So Microsoft was not quite as
So you could then you thought you were coming for a job. You're coming for an internship. Yeah, and it wasn't until the day I was there
Now the thing that was handy is HR was there as well that their offices were in the same
And they just laughed you and said silly boy. No, no, so I went I went and I went and immediately went and talked to
My my HR person because back in those days
HRs people were assigned to people as opposed to there was like one assigned to a group or an organization
So I went and talked to my assignee and I said, I'm confused. Why is this telling me to go to that room?
not the full-time room and
She gave me a well-practiced speech
She back in those days they done this before
So not this she gave me a well-practiced speech that that so
Back in the day and I think it's still true today if you come in for an intern
one of the problems were people weren't going back to school and
And Microsoft had a commitment with the school that they would send them back
So that they would finish the degree. So she's like Brent
We're not gonna offer you a full-time position because we want you to go back in and and
Finish your degree or get your degree. And I had just graduated in December
With two degrees and I said I I just got two degrees
How many more do I need?
And she's like, well, this is Microsoft. Two's not enough. Yeah, she said bring you graduated
I'm like, yeah
Just a month ago. She's like
You're not even supposed to be here. And I'm like, oh
I guess I'll go to my meeting now. So I found out the very first day that I was an intern
And that was that was the first time I had ever been made aware of that
And I went back
Talked to my manager. I'm like
Hey, what the heck?
When does this thing in I'm moving my my fiance up here in a month, right?
I thought I'd landed a job not not an internship and
Back in those days. They were very flexible. So
You could have an internship I think up to nine months. So they extended it as a six-month internship and
Then once that was done that the team
suffered
They ran out of their head count
so
And the we never ran out of that's a line in those days. We never ran out of head count
Head count grew on trees. So the other thing that ended up happening
Was I learned a new lesson
which was
Back in those days if you spent six months as as a tester and didn't know how to test
That immediately damned you I went through actually at that point in time
I went through 14 full-time interviews and I failed every single one of them
Because the team did you fail a little better each time I did. I good good at the team at that time
The team that I was on they were actually using interns as even cheaper contractors. And so oh
I then
one of my final full-time interviews and I I
Wish I knew who this was but I've gotten pretty good at reading people's body language and I I basically
Said okay
My last interview. I said it's clear that I'm not passing this interview
I've gone through a series of these no one's giving me any feedback. Can you tell me what I'm doing wrong?
And he said he walked through
three things and that those three things
I
Just snapped my head. I'm like, oh my god
I totally get this now and after that I went through a series of contractor interviews and I passed every single one of them
Ended up lending an exchange which ended up being one of the
Best places for me in my career. I wish I could go back and I wish I knew who that guy was
I could go back and shake his hand and thank him
But
Yeah, funny story that one, but it really as a manager. It wasn't an after a contractor
I think it was a year and a half before I was a manager
So I started as a contractor in a year and a half later I was a manager and
From then on out. I was very passionate around how to use interns
I'm like look at the end of this internship
Whether you know whether or not you want to come back into a test position
You will know how to do it
Anyway, that's that that's a cool story
I promise to touch a little bit on on non-invented here, even though we've talked about that in the past and yep
I do see
Us getting better. Not only is it non-invented here, but
We'll take like we're gonna have a Microsoft solution that could work said no the Microsoft solution doesn't work
We'll we'll write our own, you know test harness and
Or whatever and for those who aren't clear we didn't clarify it
Alan and I are both on the same page
That not invented here is awesome
If we can bring a solution that was not invented here and it solves a problem
Fantastic correct
For those who who aren't familiar with it or maybe
Just started listening to the podcast. All right, not invented here is in essence
People rejecting other other people's tools or solutions that because it wasn't invented here
The typical reason is oh if we do that it'll be much more complex and we'll have to maintain it
And that'll be harder or we'll take a dependency on the team and that'll slow us down
Well, let me give you just one quick example of them. We'll move on
My team uses get for source control
one
Massively huge advantage is a learning curve. It's new for a lot of people and but
What's great is that so many people use get is that any question I have?
And this is even happen what I've been often the weeds doing crazy things
Stack overflow and the internet in general has answers and when you're using your thing you built
Here's another theory of constraints using using something that's used widely is
is
Scalable when only the guy down the hall knows how to use a certain system or tool
He's a bottleneck and you get stuck trying to learn things and how many times have you used an internal tool for something you get stuck
You have to ask a question. You don't get an answer. So then you just okay. No problem
I'll just write my own version of it or I'll fork it this
It's just ridiculous. The the bottleneck theme is coming up a lot and it occurred to me that when you go with
agile
like one of the biggest things you really need to have is
Kong or visibility to a concrete team-based goal that individuals
Resonate with and they know how to
Influence it and drive towards it
For example the Kanban method will use Lytle's law Q theory and say hey I
Ideally you would have some sort of customer validation some way to say this is the number of value points that this feature
Realized but failing that you can use throughput as a goal
And you use that as a team-based goal and you say how fast are we getting?
tickets to done
And I've been doing this for for four years now and all the training with with lean
it
really makes you
aware of where bottlenecks are and
It's sort of a mix of motion because you love to know it's fantastic when you know where your bottleneck is
So you can go squash it because it also makes you hate bottlenecks
So this conversation is reminding me
once again of my love for the
Business fables of Patrick one's Yoni and one of them. I've read them all I forget the name
I forget which ones which but
One of the things he talks about one of the rules one of the tools
I use a lot in what I'm in my own leadership is I believe a team needs a rally and cry something that
That helps them figure out what their focus is and in the business novel what he uses is
teams in in
Peril like oh my god, if we don't get this figured out. We are gonna be out of business
They get that rally and cry then and they rally around it and either they fail or that usually they succeed
it gets the everybody on one page and the premise of what Lencioni says is
You should have a rally and cry no matter what something the team can center around. Mm-hmm
and here's a famous example of that is I
Don't know if it was the CEO or who it was at Flickr who said all right everybody
we are going to release and we're gonna be able to release every single day and
As he told me oh, you're crazy. We can't do it. We have for this and this and this here's all the reasons
It won't work, but that was the rallying cry
Our goal is we're gonna release once a day and his goal was we can just get like once a week
I'll be happy and they got to once a week. He said he was happy
I said no the rallying cry is once a day
We're still working and they got there that they do like twice a day and it's pretty much continuous
The speed doesn't matter don't jump on that part
But the idea is the team together the organization had a rallying cry they could work around and I believe that's true for a company
It's true for an organization. It can be true for a team. Here's what we do
Here is the number one thing
We you know make your decisions based on this rallying cry is the work does the work I'm doing does the work
I'm doing
contribute towards this goal which is so much part of the what I think about when I come to work that I can't not
Think about it. And if it isn't
You know
Do I need to do it?
Do I need to how much effort I need to put into it?
But I'm a huge believer in a team having that that
rallying cry that
Goal that everyone knows what it is and what it looks like and what how their work every day contributes towards getting there
I think it really helps the team. I've been on teams that have had I mean, I was just thinking through that
been on teams that have this rallying cry, but
There's more to it and I'm trying to think through what what that might be the the you could have this rallying cry
but it has to
It has to resonate with the troops
It has to be something that so that the carrot on the on the stick and the string that's just out of reach
Versus the one that's a mile away that you feel well that that's that's the leadership. Yeah challenge of this
You said a goal that here's what we're gonna do has to be attainable
Even if you know you be perceived as attainable
Yeah, and even if you know, it's gonna be hard and so people that don't believe it's going to be attainable
You have to believe as a leadership team
That that goal is attainable and then you need to live that too
I think one of the best ways to lead a team and to communicate these rallying cries to a team is
Celebrate examples of it. We cut off
Two hours off our build time. This is awesome. Let's celebrate this. We're on our way. Let's keep on working
There's there's I don't know if if if Reese is the one who started it
but there's a lot of wisdom in in
His book when he talks about the one metric that matters because the yeah, I think it's highly related
Yeah, I think I think one of the issues is that becomes a rallying cry it does exactly the same thing
It I'm thinking in terms of the the opposite of experience when you see teams
That have their four page long exit criteria filled with
numbers and
Right and it becomes diluted the one thing the driving towards the
Convergence points you need it a few number of things that are actionable and matter
Yeah, so
Let's move on Brent Brent gave me the hand signal that says let's move on and
And and I think we just created
surprisingly the perfect segue mate perhaps and our
Board says that Brett wants to talk about the difference between bean counting today and yesterday
So bean counting describing me by bean counting real quick and then just go on so I've spent a good portion of my career as
a test manager
right on for on pen products
I'm sure you've you've attended more than your fair share of ship rooms towards the the
The last period of shipping week the love of my life. Yes. Yes where everybody and their mother
presents again these massive spreadsheets of
Test pass rates and bug counts my eyes hurt just thinking about it. Yes, Em
What what this idea came to me is there was a
Individual that I was interacting with over the weekend on a blog post and he was talking about
Metrics and statistics and how how that will
I'm I'm exaggerating but how that doesn't eliminate the need for
testers in
It real I realized that there's a huge difference like I recognized the world he was describing
It was the world that I would had been in. Mm-hmm. Gosh even six years ago
But I wanted to see what you thought in terms of the use of
Metrics today versus yesterday. Would you describe it as as
different
Getting there. Okay getting there. What's the difference?
I think the difference is and you're gonna correct me when I'm done
But in the past I saw a lot of metrics about measuring the process of making software
bug counts
Remaining work items left a lot about how the process of making the product was going
These days as we moved more to what we're calling data-driven quality a lot of the metrics we look at come from
How customers use the product
Mm-hmm. So get idea of download rates and download success and installs and they come back to Xbox
We could see what errors people were hitting using which applications
So that gives us a better insight and sort of not an entire insight
But a better insight into what was happening with customers in the field help us identify real hot spots
and
we all know that as
An engineering teams we have found bugs that no customers really would never find we fix them because it's a bug
Or we don't and then as much as we do customers will find bugs that we never found. Oh, whoops. Sorry miss that
So I think using the data from actual customers helps us a lot in getting in that direction part of his article was talking about
again, that's stats can't
replace testers
They can't
Why not? I think there are some things
Well, a lot of it depends on context. I think you know when I look at
What testers do I don't stats can replace well, I could go off in the weeds here
but I think some of the things that
Testers or test specialists on a as I prefer to think about it
Some things about looking at performance and reliability and some of those
more complex
Non-functional attributes of the software
Even before it's the customers hands are a valuable thing for a tester to do and also looking at things end-to-end
To anticipate some of the problems customers write it might run into I think while it's okay for you to use and I've preached this
In the past that hey, let's just let customers find these issues and as long as we can fix them quickly
But I do think there's value in
Having your software good enough in the first place where people will come back
And that's gonna require some testing or test special specialization up front
Yeah, the the I agree with that the the biggest difference though that I that I walked away with is
Statistics to me now means something different than it did ten years ago
Ten years ago when I was publishing this this stupid spreadsheet and I've I've I've spent hours
producing these stupid things
Versus my view on it now is is fundamentally different like you and I have both been proponents of shifting
Reducing the head count on
Tester specialists. Yeah, right towards more of a data-centric
culture and
To me the reason why I'm a big proponent of it is because I now have a more of a data science II view on
on what statistics
Mean and how they should be used and how to use them correctly
Whereas before I would go
We're at 97 percent pass rate and we need to be at a hundred
We can't ship till we're at a hundred and all the bugs are fixed or you turn those tests off
Right
It's don't do that
That my point is is I think
If we're gonna drive towards data driven
quality, right
view
statistics as as a means it's still not the ends and that there's all
Alternate we've talked about this a bajillion times before right exposure control if you just did statistics
If the only thing you changed was you got rid of testers and you added statistics
I will not work on that team because they're
They're not necessarily using the stats
The the way they need to be in terms of driving towards the goal of creating quality
and if you realize that your goal is is is quality and then you have
one or two metrics that
Mad matter that it's gonna force you into alternatives for dealing with risk
That we used to solve with an army of testers. Mm-hmm
and just that whole talk just reminded me that so many and
so many attempts at
Organizational change or change or you know restructuring of a team
Fail to look at the whole system of things that need to change how many teams, you know, that said, okay
We're gonna do agile. So we're doing scrum
Like what this there's more there's more to think about
But not scrum scrum, yeah, we read the first chapter and yeah
We we recognize it either won't fit or we're really smart and we're gonna tweak it. Yeah
All right. So I think before we're out of time we should go on to
the
Okay, Brent, what do you got today in the mail that was pretty good
Reach your reach your hand deep in the mail that it's not in the diaphragm
Well, I had to stick my head into the bathroom. Let the echo happen, but it was I'm back now. All right, so I
Got a I got a comment on one of my blog posts over the over the
last week
Alan you have more exposure to this. So I'm gonna shoot this question out to you
So this was in my blog posts around shifting the tester mindset if you recall that one
We're how very aligned with what we're talking about
Remember what I have to dinner last night, but yeah
It was very around how we can take these testers and turn them into more quality oriented
Yes, add reactivity to their regimen. I do recall in the the individual
called out that
Large companies like Google and Facebook and Microsoft
Right. They have all these resources and they could potentially get away with
Removing testers but smaller companies still need them and any he mentioned this term of
PM focused testers
Which resonates to me sort of a combining the PM role and a tester role in the single individual sounds like a generalizing specialist to me
Go on and then I'm gonna add a third
Characteristic because he talked about small companies. I'm gonna add just a peer startup and go
What do you think about that? Do you think that there are in terms of the needs?
for for having testers does it differ based off the type of company you are I
don't think so when I think of
You know our small arm our Microsoft small team is a huge huge company to anybody else at about 200 people
We definitely need test specialists. I think
At that size we do rely a lot on data
But we do need people thinking about those non-functional things and end-to-end how things work
We need that test specialization on the other end if I think of a five-person startup
Let's go with five. That's pretty that's a pretty good small size. Would you have one of those people?
Dedicated to testing. No, I don't think you could afford that. Do you need someone that kind of it doesn't have to be a
When I think of a tester, I think that tester mindset that systems think of the big-picture thinker knows how the pieces fit together
Often it's the architect
You know one of the best test minded people actually several of the best test minded people I've known in my life are dev architects
They know how all the pieces fit together. They go. Well, that's gonna cause a problem there and and these things aren't gonna go together
Again going back to generalizing specials. I think out of that team of five people you definitely need
It can't just be all people that know how to write code and write unit tests for it
I think you need somebody kind of thinks big-picture and can figure out how those pieces fit together
So the that's the long version of my answer is yeah, I think it's the same
From a startup to a large company you need people that kind of you don't need
You don't need one tester for every developer certainly which Microsoft had in the past, but you need people with that
traditional test mindset as
Part of their toolbox on any size team the thing that that so this individual explicitly called out
Sort of the evaluation of the user experience
Which I don't know if this is what they meant but it resonated with me sort of the old-school STEs. Mm-hmm
for the thing that I found interesting
Is he kind of called out that his view was smaller companies because their research resource poor?
have a stronger reliance on these type of
testers and
It that resonated with me is just wrong
Right because in the larger company that the problem you have there is that you have this pain in the ass bureaucracy
You're dealing with you have this huge command and control
It's a lot easier to remove my both beliefs is a lot easier to remove command and control from smaller teams
Can't have it there. Just think for a minute. So I'm in charge. I'm this I got this five person startup
We're making something, you know, super cool
if it's
Actually fun five first start up today. I'm not making I'm making a some sort of app or web service
I may have every architects. I'm gonna take big picture. We're going to
Invite fun evaluate that user experience and that five person company probably gonna do a friends and family
We're gonna take their feedback seriously. You guys try this out. What is this working?
Then you do these scenarios, etc. I might sort of crowdsource this amongst the same way
We do at Microsoft these or a lot of companies these concentric circles of deployment, you know, 1% 5% 20%
I might do friends and family. Okay invited beta you guys try it
We need feedback or to incorporate it so by the time it gets to any substantial amount of people or press
That the user experience has been evaluated by users. Mm-hmm
I think there is no better person and and I'm sorry testers who you're you you're your personal rallying cry is to
To be the customer is you're not the customer and the best person to evaluate
Really what that customer experience truly is is the customer. Mm-hmm
So the better the better you can get at finding a way to get the customers to do those things in a way
That's not damning for your product or effective. You just roll this thing out to a million people and go it's done
Better you're gonna be I think that's gonna be part of your business plan in a small startup
Have you read Steve Rose blog on this topic? I have read Steve Rose blogs in this topic
You where he was talking about one of the problems when that he noticed is when we have these these
teams of specialists called testers is
They believe they're advocating for the customer, but what they're striving towards is
Approving that the product matches the spec that PM wrote
They're driving towards the requirements, right? Not necessarily what the customer actually wants. That doesn't actually work
Yeah, all right. Um, we are out of time
Thank you, everybody. Yeah. Thanks. I keep your questions coming and we'll be back in a couple weeks with
Another installment. Yes, all right 16 or one of those numbers. All right, he's Brent. I'm
Well, thanks for listening see you next time