Everybody hi, hey, I'm Alan. I'm Brent and we're back again
For the a B testing podcast what episode are we on here?
Well, I actually had to look up that this time Alan and we're 16
You had to look it up because there's a number too big for you to count
It's too high for me to keep in my head. That's that's excellent
Excellent job there Brent and our first episode of 2015. Yes
Look at that. Hey, happy new year everyone. It is it spent a month
We took the holidays off and what you doing your holidays Brent? I
did
very proactively
Nothing. I was very forcibly doing nothing
It was fantastic
Wow, I'm impressed. I was hoping to draw a little bit more out of you. No, no
I did it was hard to do like family wanted to do things
Did no work. I'm on my couch work my lazy boy recliner
You know
I've actually thought about going out and buying a lazy boy recliner
We want to we want to upgrade the the our living chair
We want it well, we want to upgrade our living room, but that would have violated my principle of doing nothing
So it was fantastic. It was um, so we had a big release just before the holidays
Power bi is the the team I'm on we have now
several new features and
Those features are all free. So if those who are interested in the the power bi space you can go create
use our new set of features and
Go create your own account for free and start messing around with power bi dashboards. It's a fantastic product
But it took a lot out of us to build it and so by I shut up
Matter of fact, I had to do a password change
You know, you know how our past
Data with the bifurcation double ginger of the globe. Yes. Yes. Yes. Yep. We can do that in a whole bunch more
That's awesome. I did a lot of junk and did nothing we didn't
Try well, gosh, we did travel. I ran a 12k
The 12k is a christmas run. I finished without puking. That was nice took me just over an hour
So I was happy with that
Okay is five miles six miles eight miles eight miles. I was and in fact, it was so much fun
that I
In a fit of stupidity that I will sure i'll hate myself for later. I'm gonna do a half marathon in march
Um around this march this march around murse around
You have support staff?
No, you have my phone number. So if you
I'm eight miles in and i'm doing fine. I just need a beer. I got your back. Alan. I'll be right there
And then sort of on uh, we had a nice holiday at the house and
Sort of a little bit of a whim the wife and I
Took off on new year's day for a quick trip to vegas
Oh, we saw oh the night we got there next night. We went to the final show the justin timber lake tour
And then and flew back the next day. So are you a a beat a big jt fan? My wife is
It was a good show though. It was it was done really well, but I was listening to the radio the other day and he is
Uh last year he was the number one or number two
um
Number one artist in terms of bringing money in I believe it. Yeah, like like and he's funny too billion dollars
one bajillion
Um cool. All right. So
Those of you that haven't turned off the podcast yet
Let's actually talk about software and this week because we've been gone so long and we actually had some feedback
Let's go right. Wait
So so actually before we begin there's there's there's one shout out I wanted to do
Those who are listening to the podcast
uh as well as a
blog post
Um, you guys have known that i've gone back to to school and i've actually surprisingly i'm halfway done with it
Not really certain how where the time went
um
the but one of my
professors, uh
Uh just recently passed away
So I just want to basically shout out and say this this this man has been a key part of my
Uh personal growth towards my career trajectory
Very sad to see him go and I I really do hope that um
He rests in peace
It was actually very sudden. It was my my last class my last semester. He was my professor
And we were doing this conference call and he does a video call and he suddenly started coughing
And he and he mentioned just sort of uh at a hand that
He was gonna go see the doctor, uh the next day and
Turned out he ended up having uh lung cancer. He had never been a smoker. So it might have been a genetic version of it
And the word had been that he was coming back this next semester. Matter of fact the the class i'm taking now
He was supposed to teach. Uh, but um
January 8th, he passed on so
Uh professor, uh, if you are able to hear thanks
Uh, you have at least one student that appreciated what you did for him. Very cool. Yeah
Well, not cool, but thanks for the shout out. Yep
uh
so without further ado
Let's go right on to the
Mail
Wow, that was fantastic, you know, I I work on these so yeah we have and
by definition
Obviously, no one sends regular mail anymore
So there's no mail bag and people don't even send us email and often they don't even actually most the time
They don't post any comments
On the blog site or on itunes or stitcher or wherever
they usually tweet
Random things in the hallway. So the mail bag for us is anything any sort of interaction you have with us is the mail bag
Yes, anything that we can spend a half a second
And turn into an interesting question is a mail bag and we appreciate it
And once again those youth haven't turned everything off although we did have actually a mail from um,
Jinsung
Oh internal this last time. So yeah, well that'll come up for that area
Yep, so first off I want to give a shout not a shout out a shout back
Uh, it's really cool. Um
Back in december just after our last podcast came out michael larson
Did a post on some of the podcasts he listens to and mentioned us pointing some people our way pretty cool
I think we were number one on the
I don't think it was I think it was alphabetical
Number one
That's why we start with a we're a a a a a b testing. We are number one podcast
In the in the so so anyway in the category of culture change for software testers starting with
Starting with the letter a
So so anyway, um, I got to meet michael four or five years ago at uh, um briefly at
Pnsqc conference down in portland and then i've been reading his blog for a long time
He did a great review of how he tests software at microsoft when it came out on his blog
But then just recently last month I had the blog post here so I can pull up the date here
Uh, he did a post on a on december 19th. No, that's actually the podcast one was on december 19
He did another post that i'm not going to look for right now, but but it was on
Now i'm gonna horribly paraphrase this but it's it's it's interesting
It was something like organizations of horror vacuum
and the story he told
was
Somebody at their company just left and they're the person owned all the vm stuff and he said well
I have some background there. I can I can jump in and
And sort of the moral being hey, you know, if there's stuff you can do go ahead and jump in which I fully believe in
So much so that it reminded me when I read it that the week before
There was some work that wasn't being done and and I love learning new things and jumping in on things and my superpower is I can learn
Things really quickly and I figured things out really well. So there was some work that needed to be done
And that'd be really interesting. So I lied I said, hey i've done something like that before I can help out
I said, oh great and I I
Did never done anything like it before but I knew I knew I could I knew I could learn it
It depends on how you abstract it. Yeah, I guess so i've worked on
products before yeah
I've i've
Yeah, yeah, i've uh, i've read words in english before I can do this. Yes
Now I mean
There's a sense of fearlessness that actually alan and I both share
um
I think we've been testers for too long to believe that that code is is anything
Even remotely resembling magic
It's just another bunch of lines of code put together to solve things
Yes, it's not hard to figure out what it does and how to make it do the right thing. It's hard for some people
Not for me, it just takes diligence
Yeah
Anyway, I I related a lot to that because I did that all that post especially but from the recent ones because I that's exactly
What I do. So I
I like to
Uh, I like to be a generalist wait, which oh
Let's not let's not go there again. So anyway, thank you. Michael, uh his website
Uh mkl test head.com
Uh, and he's I believe mkl test head on twitter, but if i'm wrong, you probably already follow him
Anyway, so um, yep, I I I do follow, uh, michael and read his blog, uh quiet ops
Cool. Yeah, he's a great he's great
All right, let's get into oh, oh twitter conversation was this from gear in norway?
Yes
About he thought it was we were talking about, you know, one-on-ones and coaching and mentoring and
He mentioned that in his workplace or in his culture
They the managers that just managers didn't do that
Yeah, the he he sent us a tweet and in his feedback was after listening to one of our podcasts
And I think it was some comment that I had made around um, the frequency in which I I talked through my guys
um
And he he found it, uh odd or befuddling i'm i'm i'm
paraphrasing here
uh to have management
that
syncs up with their employees on a weekly basis and in the even when as far as to say
uh
He found that like culturally odd like he was he was going to talk or ask around and see if any of any of his friends or co-workers
Experience such a phenomenon
All right. So what do you think?
I
The the opposite to you and I the opposite seems weird and it's not like you need and yeah
And this is one of those things where it's really easy to get the pendulum the wrong way and I see managers
who
Are so busy because they have these eight or nine direct reports
Want to meet with each of them for like an hour every week and sometimes the weird thing happens
Like we'll do an hour one-on-one a week and then you won't you just won't see them the rest of the time because you're
doing other managerial stuff and my
I'm not a manager, but my management style when I choose to be a manager is
The even more frequent shorter kind of check-ins. Yes, you have to have longer discussions around
Career and kind of what's going on when you need to dig deep
But i'm really big into the one-minute manager give get out of people's way
But dive in and find out what's going on and see if you need to intervene there was um
There was another on that same thread. There was another reach out
uh, or another
Another person I forget the name at the at this moment in time reached out and sent a thread
around sort of the role of a manager
and a belief that
A manager who holds on to the idea that they remain technical
was bad
particularly in the in the feedback context
And and I think the way to really address this feedback
problem
And I guess the third thing I would I would
Bring into play for those who have heard of it or not. Uh, there's there's this new sort of um
software engineering model
The way I'll wait till you're done. Sorry. Yeah that that
Zappos is really
What did they call it the holacracy? Yeah, it's holacr the holacracy
I was saying zappos is the primary example leverage throughout the but holacracy. There's no managers at all. So
Actually, and that was the thing when I first saw gears
twitter he's like
He was uncertain about this world where managers have one
Have weekly one-on-ones with him and I wasn't actually certain which direction he was talking from was he talking from the old school world where where
Basically managers get promoted because they're super technical and they suck at that actual job
Or more of the future world where there are no managers and he doesn't have sort of a command and control of or a head
He's expected to get feedback from when you look at we're gonna be all over the board on this because I have a whole bunch of ideas
on this yeah, that's the way, you know zappos is
Sort of famous for that holacracy culture and but
They don't have managers. This is I don't know which direction to go somebody signs paychecks
Somebody signs, you know off on purchase orders or whatever. So people do have authority to do those things
People don't report to each other
It can kind of work and I always thought I always
It's a great thought experiment to walk through. How would this work?
I'm going to talk through it when I think about any sort of complex concept
It helps me to think about extremes
Like what would it be like if there's no managers and whether I work at zappos not I can think about it
Well, somebody's got to step up and you're gonna have people
Now in a leadership role, I'm talking about
No, you already you brought up zappos. I'm going this direction. Okay
When you don't have any managers
People will still step up to lead you you're gonna get
Self-organizing teams. Yep, big believer and those are going to happen and
Want to force them to happen don't have any managers. Yep
They'll absolutely have to happen. You'll see that work out
And there are companies that have very few managers very flat and the same things happen
And there's not a lot of difference between a company with
Very flat company with very few managers, maybe 10 20 reports. I don't know that the employee counted zappos
Where you're going to see that because the org is big enough
that manager's job
As the org gets flatter ends up being a lot more just kind of
Keeping overhead under control and I wonder if in I love the thought experiment because I don't know any of this
I wonder if in an organization with no managers where you do have people that kind of end up
in that same sort of role, so my you know
for example
I may
Be on the self-organizing team where the strength that I give to the team is kind of keeping everybody organized and
making sure the work is moving forward and
That people have someone to come talk to when they have a question around anything from how to do something to career
In many worlds. I would be the manager of that team, but i'm really sort of the self-organized will say leader. Yeah
The whining it back to to feedback though
So you pick you are are organizing the process
That the challenge in that world that in terms of exploring your thought experiment
is
How do you improve?
How do you?
How do you get better at doing that role?
Let's say that's something you go you sit back and you reflect and you say man
I am good at this
But now you have the challenge of how do you get better?
You go. I want a special I want to become a specializing generalist and this is where i'm going to spend my
specialization time getting better at
How would you do you look for opportunities where you can do that?
You look for challenges look for challenges. Sure. Say I want to I want to add performance, you know testing performance analysis to my
To my specialties i've never done it before but it seems really interesting and a friend of mine does and he's pretty good at it
the so i'm going to look for
Opportunities, you know, let me let me shadow you. You know, somebody else is doing this. Let me shadow you on this
Nobody else is doing it. I'm going to take some time to go read about it and and cope with some ideas
I can try on my own and i'm going to try things i'm an experiment and then as I get a little farther
I realize wow
I can do these performance activities, but to really understand what they mean
I need to understand a little bit more about statistics and how to analyze this data effectively so we can make choices
So i'm going to dig in a little bit there and if you want to get better at something
um
You need to learn it right you need to learn and practice. Yes and deliberate practice
So you need to grow your ability towards those challenges. Yeah, and and
the only thing the only
Advantage having a manager
Gives you if we're still talking about that thing. Yep
In that situation is
If you don't know where to go
You can ask your manager where you can go, but there's a weird there can be a weird code dependency there
Because you can ask anybody that doesn't have to be your manager. You can ask anyone that you need
You need a suitable means to discover what you what you don't know and what you don't know you don't know
Correct and that you need to leverage your team for that more than
You know or at least as much as I don't know where a manager the person you work for provides any additional advantage there
Let me let me ask you
One additional question. Oh, yes. I love you. Is this the bonus round?
It is. All right. You did well in the first round. All right
How would you know?
That you're not just blowing sunshine up your ass
That you are actually doing good versus
You thinking you are
The work I do needs to provide value to the product
Okay, and how would you know if it's doing because what you just described is that you're now
Uh, the way I kind of envision what you described you are the world's best as far as you concern
Are we making?
product decisions that improve the customer experience
and
Depending on your definition of customer. Yep, but are we making product decisions that improve the customer experience?
Based on the work that i'm providing to the team. Let me um, let me let me be more precise
Because like I believe you can do that and be good at organizing the process and still be pissing off everyone that you're working with
Yes
And that feedback I get where you're going. Probably important
Yeah, so how do you find out? Okay, so I I can figure out the work i'm doing is helping the product
But you're asking me. How do I figure out if I am doing it in a way that is?
uh
I was gonna say socially acceptable, but how am I a good team member as well?
And we've talked about the things I value, you know on a team I work on i'm pretty straightforward, you know, does the work you do provide?
Value to the product. Uh, do you have what's your output?
Yeah, are you getting a reasonable amount of that work done and do you play well with others?
Yeah, those are when I look at someone I want to think how well you're doing I look at
Those things yes, and so how do I know if i'm playing well with others?
I always do no. I this is this is tying it back to awesome. I just know
Um, you can well in absence of a peer feedback system, which we've talked about before which I which I love and and sort of an ad hoc
Uh, if you can get people to really use one and rate people it's great. But ask people ask
If you don't have
A way to figure that out
I would ask people i've done that before
Um, i've asked someone to ask someone else about me if you're afraid to get that feedback directly
uh, but I really would prefer a sort of either
a
Feedback system could be anonymous or not or maybe even both
Uh, do you have an answer for that? How do how do you find out if you're pissing people off the actually you're always pissing people off
So, how do you find out when you're not pissing people off?
Uh, i'm also uh turns out i'm not pissing people off. Whoa, I'm pissing people off. Yeah
Particularly the times during the day where i'm sleeping and everyone else is nope pissing off
No, or hardly anyone at that time. Um
no, so
You just did a great thought exercise and and I think you kind of concluded that in a holacracy world
In order to to really succeed and not only as a team and a project
But when we're talking about a feedback system, we're really talking about the role of the individual
Mm-hmm and and how to help grow them
um
You you you have to have
Some sort of peer feedback tool and it turns out
holacracy acknowledges that
and um
You have to reduce the friction
Uh to enabling people to give
their
uh feedback
um
uh in a in a way that's actionable and uh nearly immediate
The the other thing most I have not seen
any article
That discusses holacracy in sort of a waterfall context
Right, uh, mostly most oftentimes you'll see holacracy. I'm going to say most currently i've it's all that i've seen
Uh are doing some sort of agile process
And agile, uh, one of the great benefits is it really tugs out
Transparency everyone knows what everyone knows
The in a holacracy world you really have to have collaboration
collaborative teams
Really helps to instill trust and that really helps to light up the sort of peer feedback mechanism
Going back to the other extreme though. Um talking about managers
right
I am a technical
manager, um
I I have gone through several years. Uh, i'm actually surprised honestly surprised when
My manager feedback scores are below. Uh 90 percent and it hasn't happened in
decades
the
the main reason why
I think most managers when when they go into that role and they stay super technical
It's because they don't understand the problem that they're trying to solve
Their their job isn't primarily to get the project across the wire
They have to do that
But it's it's more medium term long-term thinking
and and
Um, you cannot just do that without paying consequences. You will see your people going
Um stymieing you'll see your people getting to a point where
They're not getting support from you and they've kind of run to the end of of their ability to create a method
To get additional feedback and they move on
and
You can't do that. I I think you can't do that as a manager period but you absolutely can't do that in the software world
Because the number one asset
Is the knowledge that's between their ears?
And if you let if you let that go and you don't invest further in that you are short
Shrifting project acceleration. Did you say shrifting? I did I said short shrifting. What is shrifting?
Uh, that sounds like something that happens in a jail
I wish that's shiv shrift. I'm sure that I don't know
Uh short changing then all right, i'm gonna go with shrifting to make captain synonym here happy
Although you if the knowledge that's in their their heads and and allen's in another podcast he he's he's done
multiple
Discussions around the the importance of recognizing that we're not in the software
Industry we're in the knowledge worker industry
That we just happen to be using software
So the knowledge is the the primary asset therefore you're you're best motivated
to
Motivate and challenge and grow the person with that knowledge
And if you failed to do so, uh, you you better have a plan
For dealing with that knowledge leaving your team
And far too often I find these hyper technical managers either
uh
They they approach this as they're the guys that are going to do that
Or not. Let me give you a particular one
Quick story and then I think I think i'll end this topic. No, no, I I have more once you finally shut up. Okay
um
a manager
Years ago the best manager i've ever had
He shared with me his number one rule of of management
Okay
He's like if you do nothing
If you do nothing
You have to do this
and that is
Your task as a manager is to earn your team's loyalty
number one earn your team's loyalty
uh
You don't you can either be a technical manager or you can be a um, a people manager or you can be like me someplace in between
but whatever it is
And you can do this in any of those styles if you're a technical manager
Then that means you're helping them grow by look doing code reviews and in helping them think of other algorithms or or other
ways to solve the the problem via an architectural stance
But it means you can't just fire and forget
You can't say
Alan you will do this by tuesday
And then come tuesday go why haven't it been done? Although alan would get it done
um
Loyalty is everything
now
and i'll i'll just
years ago
Michael hunter blogged on this
For those who I think it's actually his last blog still
Um, he asked me to write up about the best bug i've ever encountered
And the best bug I ever encountered is when I completely screwed the pooch as a test manager
We had this product
We had these test plans of all the operating systems that we were going to work on
I had a team of 40 people
Uh, the dev team had a team of 20 people
Remember the days when test outnumbered dev?
And that was so stupid and we had like five pm's and we still couldn't test quality in no
um
So we had a team of like 60 people
And long story short our product relied on dcom
and
We were going to ship with office
And they were on windows 95 or 98 that did not have dcom
And we didn't discover until after office greenlighted
That we didn't work
on on that os
And we never did
So we had gone through a series of interrupts and changing plans and in that whole process. We had forgotten to test on that os
Okay
As the the test manager involved and the one responsible for quality
If I had been my manager that day, that would have been my last day of this company
Think thankfully I wasn't and I was on my way
Um to go have a conversation with my manager because he needed to know
one of my
uh
Managers that reported to me knew what I was about to do
And he interrupted me and he said brit
Do not do what you're going to do. He's like, I I don't know what what are you talking about?
I was trying to own the message what what i'm not doing anything
He knew better
He said before you do anything
Go home sleep on it and if if what you are what I think you're about to do if you still want to do it
I won't get in your way
I said, okay deal
I came back the next morning
That guy came and talked to me
um
But he was still wearing the same clothes
He and my entire team
had done an all-nighter
Working with dev they found they fixed the problem. They did an entire month's test pass
in one night
And it was entirely
Because they didn't want me
to um fall on my sword which was
Absolutely what I was about to go do
um, oh yes
now
The thing I would say
When it comes to to giving feedback the most important thing is everybody needs to know
What actions to take next and it and it doesn't matter if it's um, if it's a poor performing employee
Or it's one of your stars
everyone wants to have
Ideas and thoughts of what's the next thing I can do to improve myself
and a lot of the times
Managers, even if you have a manager doing weekly 101 so that doesn't mean it's going to be good
A lot of those managers all they do is adjectives
Right. Uh, oh, you're great. You're excellent
Uh, or you suck or you need to improve or any of these type of things
And it's not concrete enough
um
that's
My secret to success as a manager is you got to give them
um
An action you got to give them action ability you have to earn their trust so that you can actually tell them the truth
And they'll hear it
Anyway
You have more to say I I got so lost in there
So what is I think I figured out I had a question on what a technical manager was and it's
But I think you answered that part way through so that's good
Um, I think most managers
Yeah, we're kind of mixed
At least on the test side with whether managers are technical or not
But most I think most managers these days have are technical to some level
I wanted to jump on another extreme because what we're talking it reminded me of
Sort of the well, let me ask you this see if it gets where i'm going if not we'll see we'll all adjust
Okay
So we talked about holacracy and uh self-organizing teams. What's the opposite of that?
What's the other end of the spectrum describe the structure and just briefly of what would be the other end of an extreme on that?
uh, the the one that
The one i'm thinking of is is kind of when I was introduced to to management
I was told this rule of thumb for each employee you have you should be spending 10 of your time
uh working with that employee to improve them or to to
Talk with them is good. Even back 10 of your time is invested in them, you know
Yeah, looking at in some hand wavy thing is is basically that's communicated
Which basically means if you had back in those days if you had a team of 10
That's all you should be doing
Um, so I think that's that's the opposite extreme
Someplace where you have due to some team size and your accountability
That's all you do. Yeah, I wonder if so my take on that is if that's your and somebody may have that
that
Idea still in their head, but I wonder if your team really grows
It's kind of like you gotta set them free and my whole my one of my principles around
management is
Give people a framework they can work in and then get out of their way and then I combine that with uh,
Sort of the one-minute manager concept. It's it's a nice little business parable book easy to read
I suggest you fly through it, but you just need to know when
to dive in and and when to intervene and and you do that by
Knowing what's going on in your team doesn't need to be uh,
You know a constant monitoring and sometimes people more monitoring than others, but it's it's not hovering either
It's getting out of their way until you need to be
Need to know what's going on I completely agree the
One of the speeches that I give often to my teams
Is in order to learn and grow?
You have to take on challenges
And you have to make mistakes. Absolutely
Um a lot of managers I've talked to when I when I say no, you need to let your team make mistakes
They look at me like oh my god, they're too afraid. My project's gonna fail blah blah blah too afraid
And you don't and but they don't understand that
The reason why you need to make let them make mistakes is so that you can help them learn from it
Yeah, I just wonder if you are the overbearing, you know 10 percent of your time
Dedicated to each employee if they have that room to grow and you sort of develop this
Dependency or codependency where as an employee i'm not sure what to do unless my manager comes by and gives me that
You know invest that hour a day and I didn't do the math. They're not that much but you know, um
Diving in and telling me, you know what I need to be doing. I need to figure things out on my own
One of the things with my current job Microsoft is I mentioned this a lot and someone asked yesterday
How do you figure out what to do?
I said there's always work to do and i've had a good track record of being able to figure out
What's the most important work to do? But I haven't had a manager tell me what to do in
Since I can remember it's been since like late 90s since I had a manager actually gave me assignments
That's I think that's
Positive I think so too. That's not a bad thing
I'm not saying negative things about my managers with with they trust me to figure out what needs to get done with one possible thing
Is like you only know what you what you are capable of knowing and I do think
Um, the only weakness to that is it would have been good
uh
At least annually a manager assigned you something
That's somewhat out of your
Comfort zone and not your wheelhouse or something that you would normally choose to do because that helps you grow
I know but as going back to my comment on
uh, michael arson's blog and and and my uh
Relation to that is that I do pick things that are hard. I do pick things out of my comfort zone
Alan is an active learner. So so yeah, I don't say yeah, I this is not a
A a path that's maybe automatic for everyone. Yeah
The the other thing uh, the last thing I think i'll say on this topic
I thought you were done already I was and then and then you said something that I liked
I don't know if you have figured out how this podcast thing works. We like talk and bounce the ideas off each other. Anyway
We'll work that out
Maybe maybe that can be an action for you to take. Hey brant. Take take this action
Alan yet again indicated that brint is number one
One thing I think these technical managers because you you you did say an insight
Around that they're afraid they're afraid to do this
And one of the things I think these these super technical managers need to get over or or hopefully it'll give them some some help
And hope to experiment
But the reason why you want to let you
uh
People make those mistakes
Actually, why do you think why would it be valuable to that technical manager to let those people make mistakes?
Valuable to him valuable to him. I don't know tell me
it's it's primarily because
Learning is what causes an acceleration
If you don't let them make those mistakes and you don't give them the the the ability to actionably grow
Then you're going to be dealing with a static world from exactly. Yeah, right
You don't have the ability to accelerate this forward progress. You don't have the ability to scale
And quite honestly for those managers growing your team and getting them to to do that ability to scale
Is important to your career growth. Yeah, I i'm a also a big believer in the learning organization and yeah singe's work there
Absolutely with the 100 and not enough that happens
uh, the last thing that reminded me of as we continue to babble around this is
uh
In holo in a holocracy
Where does the decision making happen?
It rotates it happens at where it needs to at the closest point to where it needs to happen
and I believe in that for a team too, I
Uh, I think a lot of managers have you shared your world of warcraft story on podcasts yet. I'm sure I have
So yeah in brief I believe a lot in the world of warcraft theory of project management where?
You form a group
You know to accomplish a specific task
You work on that task together share the rewards then you either disband or take on another task
Yeah, and and who's the leader in the the world of warcraft model it rotates right? It depends
I think that model is all about holocracy and you know, i've done this dungeon before i'll be the leader
great
I've rode this pony before. Um
So, where was I going? Oh so decision making in hawks and in a self-organizing team in general it happens where it needs to
Many managers I know and i'm going to tell a quick story here
Uh want to be the single point for that decisions for their team
Slows the team down a lot
Now think about what happens and as microsoft people going oh god
I have stories for you and I will tell you the same story you're probably thinking in your head. I worked on a product once
where
our vice president
Not my favorite vice president at microsoft, but you can't don't know what i'm talking about because they have like 150 of them
But you know, I I think I mentioned this to you right at apple
They have like a cto a cfo a couple vps and that's it
I'm trying to guess the vp and we have 150. So anyway, is this a vp? So anyway here? Yes
Okay, not the one I was thinking of
Anyway, I better not say the name because um, yeah, it'll be obvious to some
And if I say his name i'll just start going off on him and this will be my final podcast recorded on the microsoft campus
but anyway, but anyway, but anyway, he was
He wanted to be involved in every decision and talk about a technical manager. Here's where you can go too far to the extreme is
We would be in he would show up to uh, like a ship room meeting we're going over bugs and he would dive in and want to discuss
Everything down to which reg key we are going to modify to do
You to make this work
At some point as a manager you can be you can be I mean even if you i'm a technical manager of a team of eight people
uh, I
There's a point, you know, i'm I can see myself fairly technical beyond the line. That's like way
I know on the line like
You need to trust people to make decisions and get out of their way and at some point
There are bigger problems you need to worry about than minutia implement minutia of implementation
When I see managers at that level like the first thing
um
I go
This guy seems like he's being defensive like yeah
And and typically people who aren't being defensive
In this case, he wasn't defensive. I really think that he
In a way, he sort of validated himself. It's like yeah, I can i'm a vp
But I still dive in here and you know if I had to I would write this code
I will tell you a a
Different story the best vp I ever worked for and i'll even mention his name. It was bob muglia
He was highly technical
I I remember, uh very fondly a day he and I spent three hours
uh
Bullshitting, uh outside
Talking about uh his exchange server deployment that he did all by himself
At his home now why a vp needs his own exchange server deployment at home
Doesn't matter
He did he had his own domain and pop wasn't enough, but he um
He at that time was vp
uh of server and tools division
right, so
That was his
I would I would say what he was doing and the reason when he went through those actions
He was highly tech the most technical vp i've ever worked for
But in terms of the space that he owned
I would argue what he was doing and why he was doing it was more so around customer empathy and helping his business grow
Not I mean he never got in our business. That is
Completely different. Yeah, I mean that's passion for technology which is completely different from
Diving in way too deep on day to day implementation details. That's a great example of get the you know, get out of their way
I'm just i'm just imagining your your last vp going through like a code review and going hey
Hard-coded string that shouldn't be there
My last vp. No, he definitely wouldn't have done that
He was the one you were talking about. I don't know that's the last one. Yeah. Yeah. No, that's the last one the last one's actually
Um, I you know, I like him
He's not my vp anymore. I have a different vp
I can't keep track how many different vps have I worked for? Oh my god
I don't even want to count. Yeah. All right, even certain which you're talking about
I I don't think we have time to dive into our last topic. So I have to shelve it
We will and I think actually
There's going to be some more interesting things coming up over the next two weeks on that topic
So let's shelve it and yeah, and there's so much to talk. There's so much going on
But it's been fun to be back
Yeah again. Happy new year
Yeah
And I apologize that we didn't actually talk about anything
But we did get a few nuggets in there about management and structures and holocracies and other cool words
I can put in the summary when I get this posted short shrifting short. I gotta look up shrifting that sh r i f t
ing. Yes
All right. And another word for you to look up is
G-o-f-f-o
Okay, we're we're gonna call that good i'm alan i'm brent and we'll see you next time see you guys