Hey, I'm Alan.
I'm Brent.
And we're back for another episode of A.B.
Testing.
What number are we on, Brent?
28.
God, how did that happen?
Cool.
Yeah.
All right.
Totally.
Apologies for anyone who has sat through all 28 besides us.
We've gone through 28, right?
We have.
What's worse is that?
We might have gone through 40.
What's worse is that I go, not only do I sit here
through these, but I sit through it again while I edit and take
out all the dumb stuff Brent says.
Not all of it, obviously, but most some of it.
He does a fairly good job at that.
And I said this on Twitter.
Last time, our tech support team turned around
and seemed like just in two hours.
I think there was a long weekend coming up.
I can't remember.
I think it was the Friday before that Labor Day weekend.
So I thought, if I don't get this done today,
it's not getting done for a while.
Well, again, the tech support team did a fantastic job.
So this is weird.
We use, for those of you interested,
I used to use Audacity, which is a darn nice program
for recording as all the features I need.
For the first time ever, we have a debut in episode 28.
Something we've never done before.
What's that?
Well, normally, I'm track one because, you know,
and Brent's track two.
But today, Brent's number one.
Woo hoo!
That was purely a mistake.
That'll be fixed in the next episode.
And when I mix down the mono, you'll never know.
But for me, I look and see what's going on.
And I'm speaking in the wrong place.
So I just wanted to share that with the audience.
So this podcast is going to make you feel uncomfortable
the entire time?
No.
Being in the same room as you makes me uncomfortable.
You're not the first, nor likely the last,
to give me that feedback.
Yeah, I read the report.
It's awkward.
All right, let's get going.
We got our list on the board.
And we'll get through it here and probably get to none of it.
Let's try and see if we can get to at least one thing.
So Strata Conference, we talked a little about last time.
You're going there.
It's in New York next week.
Yes.
Holy crap, Batman.
It's next week.
It is.
So me and one of my employees are going.
We have a goal of recruiting like monsters.
Got for the first time in like 15 years,
we talked about this last time, got new business cards.
And I intend to come back with none of them.
All right, we'll see what happens.
Are you going to tweet?
Is it like fishing?
Are you catching release?
Or like you hook them and you bring them home with you?
I mean, did you book like one ticket there and 50 tickets
back?
That.
You know, I don't know what the limit is on my end
of my card.
But I am agile, so we'll see what happens.
And the other thing, so last time I issued an offer out
to the three.
If you want to connect, I'd love to meet you.
I did get one of the three to reach out.
So we'll figure out some logistics there.
But you remember Percy from several episodes ago?
He's like a guest member on the show.
Yeah, and actually on the way in, I was thinking through,
hey, since we only have three listeners,
it probably wouldn't be hard to meet them all.
It's great.
And then, yeah, I like to think of anyone
who submits a mailbag item, or we talk about,
they're part of the show.
Absolutely.
Actually, that was a stretch calling this thing a show,
right?
Yeah, let's just roll with it.
All right, cool.
Speaking of like things and conferences and things,
we talked, I'm not going to recap them going to Eurostar
for the mobile deep dive in November.
But in between now and then, I'm
going to go give a short talk at the GoDaddy office in Kirkland,
which I think is open to the public on October 9,
Friday night.
The talk is?
Yeah.
OK.
So I'm doing like a half hour.
And normally, I talk about very broad things.
So I asked for suggestions, and they gave me a,
what do you want me to talk about?
I'll talk about anything.
And they gave me a list of very specific things.
Such as?
Well, I don't remember.
I only remember the one I selected.
I said I can do that because I work on one of those, which
is strategies for testing a single page web application.
OK.
But I will turn that into one of my sweeping generalizations
full of opinions.
But I'll talk about it a little bit.
It'll be fun.
And then I haven't worked out when yet,
but I mentioned last time the wonderful people at Riot Games.
And Trey McRae invited me to come to a sort of a night
of beer and appetizers they were having in Seattle.
Brew-ha-ha.
A brew-ha-ha, something like that.
What was that?
Three or four weeks ago, I had a good time talking to people.
And he contacted me and said, hey,
our people like talking to you.
You're fun.
You should come talk to more of us.
I'm going to go down to LA sometime for a day
and hang out with them and kind of see what they do
and talk to them.
Of course, I don't know when yet, because my calendar's
been cray cray.
So I got to get back to it and figure it out.
Because I have my, I'm like, he said in the next few weeks,
I'm looking at my calendar and I said,
I think I can make this.
So I got to look at my, sorry, I'll try and email Trey
before I post his podcast, because I haven't actually
replied to him other than the first one saying
I check my calendar and figure anything out.
Does he listen to the podcast?
Yeah, he does.
He apparently, and he's kind of a cool guy,
so I don't know why he would do this,
but he kind of stalks me.
You're kind of a cool guy too.
Birds of the feather thing.
Yeah, maybe, maybe, maybe.
I think there's a lot of, I mean,
you have a lot of relevant skills,
a lot of relevant knowledge.
I wouldn't be at all surprised.
Fake until you make it.
Amen, baby.
I wouldn't be at all surprised if TreyTray
tries to convert this into a move move.
No, no, no, that's not what it's about.
He's cool.
We've talked about that.
That's not in the cards.
I am, yeah, long story there, but you know,
at some point after 20 plus years of Microsoft,
20 plus being 20 years plus three months,
retirement, actually, you know what?
I don't know if you know this.
It's September, less than three months,
I qualify for AARP.
So, you know, I'm as young at heart as I sound.
I'm fricking old.
You know, I was having this conversation
with one of my mentees just the other day.
In a couple of weeks, I will have a 17 year old
and I'm just like, whoa,
where the hell did all the time go?
Because when you go into work, right,
we are surrounded by 20 somethings all of the time.
Or people that act 20 something.
Both.
Microsoft is a little like Never Never Land.
You come here and sometimes you never grow up.
You never grow up and certainly physically,
there's this overwhelming perception,
except for the few times in the day
you actually look in the mirror,
where you sort of feel like you're the same age
of all the people you work with.
So it does kind of befuddle me that I'm getting to a point
where I'm gonna start having friends who are in AARP.
I'm not gonna, I'm said I'm eligible,
I'm not gonna join, except for, you know what?
I think I get free dinner at Denny's on my birthday.
So I don't know.
I think everyone does that.
Ah, crap.
But the thing that's gonna be weird
is when we start going to lunch,
you're gonna go, hey,
do you offer a senior discount here?
What's wrong with that?
Nothing.
It's just gonna be a slap in the face of,
wow, I hang out with old people.
Yep, I do.
Because I'm in a crotchety mood now.
Get off my lawn.
I'm gonna skip ahead to the fourth item.
We'll come back to that other one
because that's really a proper order.
So it's been a long time.
It's been a long time since we've had an installment
of Stupid Things Microsoft People Do.
Otherwise known as Allen's Soapbox.
Get off my lawn.
So this one, I drink my coffee black
like it should be drank.
This is like the preview.
This is like the trailer that comes for the real peeve,
which has nothing to do with coffee.
So I'm not gonna complain about.
But black is the way God and the Colombians intended.
One of the things that annoys people other than me
is people will add milk to their coffee.
They'll open up some milk in their refrigerator
and they'll leave this half carton open
and the next person does the same thing.
By the end of the day, you have like 12 partially opened
cartons of milk in the refrigerator.
So that-
If they're in the refrigerator, what drives me next
is they leave it right next to the coffees.
I don't like milk.
At all?
I think milk was invented to make cheese and that's it.
It has no other usage.
It's not for drinking, all right?
That's gross.
Ick.
What about chocolate?
Yeah, chocolate.
And not necessarily milk chocolate, dark chocolate.
But chocolate milk?
No.
No, gross.
That's disgusting.
Milk chocolate?
No, sometimes, but no, dark chocolate
only because it goes well with wine.
Hot chocolate?
No.
Wow.
Hot cocoa a little bit.
No milk.
Milk is gross, all right?
Not even the right soap box.
Let's get on the other soap box.
Nothing to do with milk.
That's just a common complaint about people.
So I work in a building, I've worked in buildings
with elevators before, but I'm a stair person.
Now that I work on the 20th floor, I'm not a stair person.
Although I do take the stairs down,
if I have to go down to reception,
five floors below, no problem.
I take the stairs down from 28
where the cafeteria is to 20 all the time.
But if it's more than two floors when I was three,
I'd use the elevator.
And obviously coming into work in the morning,
I take the elevator.
I don't even know how to take the stairs from the lobby.
So anyway, because our elevator
goes to Microsoft floors, you have to use your card key,
little click thing to use the buttons.
The buttons don't work.
Unless you swipe your card.
Unless you swipe your card key.
So everybody knows this,
because everybody's on Microsoft.
Yet, yet.
There's only a card key reader on one side of the elevator
in front of the bank there.
And inevitably, every single day, every single ride,
someone will step on, swipe their card key,
press their button, and stand with their waist
about two inches away.
From the card keys.
Yeah, like I have to stick my hand in an HR unfriendly zone
in order to scan my card key.
So I think, so hopefully, which I have refrained from doing,
we're all introverts.
You're like, excuse me, I need to stick my hand
in front of your, I scanned my card key.
But usually I just hope that they picked a floor
that's a little lower than mine,
so they'll get the hell out of my way
so I can scan my card key and push the right button.
If you're lucky also, there's buttons
on both sides of the elevator,
but the ones on the other side are useless.
Unless you have a card key.
But there is a window of about two seconds
after someone swipes their card key
where the buttons will work everywhere.
So what I try and do is sort of tailgate
on their buttons.
But the point is,
that is like, that is access to the,
you are blocking access to me getting to work
because they're not guarding it.
They're just not thinking,
but it's just the weirdest thing
that they all scan my card key.
I'm gonna stand right up here in this corner.
It's like, dude, you're weird.
And I wonder, do you think,
this is probably inappropriate for the podcast,
but I wonder if there are some people
that maybe they just do it to get,
see what the reaction is from other people.
That's art.
I now suspect you do.
But I don't think these others do.
One of the things I studied in,
I'm a music composition major.
So I studied not just classical composition,
but modern composition and some of the modern art approaches
where the music,
they said the performance, the music isn't the art.
It's the audience's reaction to the music.
That's the art.
Sure.
So when you do like John Cage's four minutes
and 33 seconds,
so you can look, which is four movements of,
three movements or four, I can't remember,
but just silence.
But the point is,
as I got off of my tangent is,
somebody could look at that on the surface and go,
well, that's stupid.
I could write that.
And yes, you could,
but the music is how the audience reacts.
And I've not only seen that piece performed,
I've actually performed a percussion ensemble arrangement
of that piece we did.
We did a whole year of John Cage pieces
and the audience reaction,
there is something to that.
It's not all fluffy, fluffly, artsy, fartsy,
is the audience will react and it's interesting.
I've lost you.
Percussion ensemble.
Yes.
I didn't know you ever played any sort of percussion.
Oh yeah, I was primarily a woodwind player,
but I did play a lot of percussion,
enough so that I actually faked and lied my way
into the percussion department during grad school.
What instrument in particular?
We had a professor that didn't know everything.
So mostly, I mean, everything.
I'm versatile enough.
I could do,
I totally fooled him into thinking I could play everything.
And going in, I was mostly keyboard percussion,
so marimba, xylophone, vibraphone, et cetera, et cetera.
So I did a bunch of stuff there
and then we did some snare drum stuff,
which I can totally kick butt on
and I could fake my way through it.
And then, and he gave me some really hard timpani stuff
and not on my fourth tape,
but I just, you know, I'm really good at,
again, fake it till you make it.
I practiced a lot and learned something
and looked up some things.
In the library, didn't have the internet back then, I'm old.
And anyway, faked it through.
It wasn't until,
one of the things you have to do
when you're in a music program is,
play.
I'm gonna smack you so hard in the head
that something funny's gonna happen.
You have to do things called juries,
which are the end of every quarter.
Three or four of the music staff members,
usually from your area, plus a few others,
it's, you have to perform a piece for them
and they critique you.
Like this is like your final.
Like you imagine, if you're taking lessons
for a quarter in college,
your final is you have to perform something
to show that you've actually learned something
from your lessons and you're applying
and you've been practicing and stuff.
Kind of the musical equivalent
of defending your doctoral thesis.
Yeah, at a smaller scale.
I had to defend my master's thesis,
which was,
again, I got so lucky.
At the long story, I got so lucky.
It's like, they showed me a score.
So tell me about this piece.
Like a score, you know, a score is like all the parts.
And I'll get back to the other story in a minute, but.
Score contains how many measures usually?
Oh, the score is the whole piece.
Oh, the whole piece.
For every instrument.
Oh, got it.
And tell me about this piece.
And I'm looking at it and,
and they don't care if you know what it is.
They want to describe, like,
you look at how the, what the instrumentation is
and how the instruments are used and chords.
And from that, you can actually do some
pretty easy forensics and figure out kind of
have a good estimate when the piece was written
and maybe even who wrote it.
I happened to recognize the score.
Cause it was, one of the things I did
when I was bored in the library,
is I flipped through scores
and I actually knew exactly what it was.
So I played stupid and said,
well, we got this and that and this,
and this is going on here.
So it's probably Stravinsky.
I'm fairly certain it's a soldier's tale,
but this, you know, I think you'd ever.
Baa!
Oh my God, he pushed.
No, no.
The only person I impressed with what they do
for the master's thesis defense is
they have three people or two,
three people from my department,
plus one person they grabbed from an unrelated department
to make sure they're not BSing me through.
So I blew him away.
So the other part of that story was where was like...
Alan, the walking music genome project.
Oh, I remember.
So spring quarter, I had already done my thesis.
The only thing I had my juries to do
and my professor was there and somebody else,
the band director and director of bands,
sounds more exciting.
And then the old, old percussion guy
who was on his way out,
but he knew me from undergrad school.
And I play my piece and I go,
he goes, he goes, he goes, he goes.
And he said, you play percussion pretty well
for a clarinet player.
And that's when I let the cat out of the bag.
I said, my current professor,
progression professor said,
so you play clarinet?
I said, yeah, actually I was a woodwind major in undergrad.
He goes, why did you, how come you ever told me that?
Because I said, I figured if I told you
I wasn't a real percussionist,
you wouldn't let me into the program.
And he goes, oh yeah, you're probably right.
The, your story, you ever watched the movie Drumline?
Yeah.
It's one of my favorites.
Oh, good, so bad.
But your story, oh, I love it.
It's always been my-
How can you love that movie?
I was, Drumline two sucks,
but Drumline one was a good movie.
But your story kind of reminded me
of the competitions they do to see
who gets to be in the first string
or whatever the hell they call it in a marching band.
The other thing, so we went to Walt Disney World
the other day, and you know the,
I'm sure you know the name,
but in the Epcot Center, the Japan area,
they often had these women come out
with these sticks and these large kettle drums.
Okay.
And I could watch these guys forever.
Love that style, love anything you do with the big ass,
what do they call it, are they kettle drums?
Are they horizontal?
No, not the horizontal like marching band things,
but they look like-
Are they tuned?
Yeah.
But they're gigantic.
They're timpani or kettle drums.
Okay, those are cool.
You played that?
Yeah, I played that.
You're slightly cooler now to me than you were before.
That's great.
So does Evan's thing count as a MB item?
It came in mail.
All right, so we got a mail from Evan,
and we're gonna talk about it in a minute,
but you know what has to happen first.
Mail back!
Wow, there was a little bit of lounge in that one.
That was fantastic.
I live for the lounge.
All right.
Wait, I was gonna go into Copacabana for a minute,
but I'll reel in the back.
Reeling it back.
Okay.
Copa.
What did Evan say in his mail?
Oh, I remember.
So we got a mail from...
Mail back.
...young Evan Lehrer.
We used to work with Evan.
Actually, I remember Evan when his career was just this tall.
Now, when I first met Evan, he was freshly minted IC
in the test organization.
He's now grown into leadership.
He's left Microsoft years ago.
He came from X...
Four or five years ago from Xbox, went to...
Amazon.
They sell books.
Yes, everything else.
Oh, by the way, I used just to see if it worked.
I had Amazon...
We have at Amazon, same-day delivery, bring me some beer.
It worked.
Got like an hour.
It was kind of expensive.
I just wanted to see if I was bored on a Sunday.
Neat story, Alan.
Okay.
All right.
Somebody has to come in handy.
You can go to 7-Eleven, get it in 15 minutes.
Yeah, no, actually it'd take longer.
There's no 7-Elevens that close to my house.
But I could have gone to the store.
But if you're already two hours in and running out of beer...
I could have gone the thrift way.
I just wanted to see how they...
I was kind of curious how the process worked.
It was a purely exploratory order.
You know, one of the problems with the current room we're in
is that we don't see the clock.
We're good.
No, I know.
It's 8.30.
And it reminds me of some feedback we got in the last podcast.
Did you see that Twitter or tweet?
Oh, yeah, after the rambling...
After the 20-minute rambling, you guys got to a great point.
I think that was mentioned a positive way.
In my head, that was said positively.
Oh, it was.
And the fact that we actually made a point...
Because usually we have to ramble for 40 minutes.
Sure.
Then improvement.
Wait, go with that white net improvement.
So anyway, Evan sent a mail.
Evan's at Redfin now.
Fast forward to the...
Oh, look, they made a point.
Evan's at Redfin and he asked...
He said, AB testing Roadshow.
Yes.
And we said, Roadshow?
Okay.
So his mail was to...
Hey, guys, it has been a while.
I hope it's all as well with you.
Thanks for asking, Evan.
It's going great.
It is going great.
Alright, keep going.
I recently joined Redfin as their Seattle QA manager.
The company is at an inflection point moving from three-week waterfall releases...
What is that?
That's like a Scrummerfall thing, right?
Yeah.
Yeah, okay.
But at least he knows that it's not Scrum.
What ifs?
Yeah.
To a continuous integration model.
However, there really isn't much expertise in the company on how to navigate this transition.
By the way, Evan, if we're releasing NDA stuff, I'm sure Evan's the only one at Redfin that listens to us.
We're probably fine.
You know, I don't think there's anything...
It's not like he said, and we're moving...
We're doing a special new project.
It requires us what it does.
It allows you to blah, blah, blah, blah.
So he has questions.
Yeah.
There are questions going around like, so do all devs need to write tests now?
Yes, next.
And can we ship code to production without QA involvement?
It depends.
Next.
And as a QA engineer, do I have a place in this new world?
It depends.
Let's talk about that.
Yeah.
While I'm trying to help guide, it may be helpful to have some outside experts give a tech talk to the engineers.
Oh, I missed the part where you wanted experts.
I think we're out.
Fake it.
What do you guys think?
I have a question.
What's a QA engineer?
He doesn't say QA engineer.
I thought you said the QA engineer.
Oh, that's right.
You're right.
As a QA engineer...
Of course I'm right.
Do I have a place in this new world?
Well, the first question's easy, but we should probably give it a longer answer.
So the first question was, do all devs need to write tests?
Do all devs need to write tests now?
Can we ship code to production without QA involvement?
No, dude, learn to read.
Read that first sentence again so people understand it.
So do all devs need to write tests now?
The long answer...
I give the short answer is yes.
The longer answer is yes.
Or affirmative.
Okay, yeah.
That is absolutely because...
Well, you tell me why because.
I don't tell you why because.
Let's actually give a real long answer.
If not, who's going to write the tests?
And actually, we've pounded on this forever.
I think for many tests, especially unit functional, making sure your stuff works,
there is no better person to write those tests than the person who wrote the code.
At some point, there's a line in where that's no longer true.
And let me give you an example from my team.
Our team, I wouldn't call myself a QA engineer.
I'm just still a software engineer, but on a team that doesn't have any testers.
So I guess I cover some of that, but our devs are starting to actually get good at writing tests.
What?
How is that possible?
And not just unit tests.
We have our unit test suite is growing and becoming very valuable.
But they're also writing what we call scenario tests,
which you could call user journeys or whatever.
But some end-to-end-ish tests.
And they're getting better and better.
The tests are getting less flaky, and they're covering more of the product.
And they're running all those, which is great.
And then we had a weird bug come in last week,
and we thought, well, how do we miss that?
And then it only took me a few minutes to go, you know what?
Our devs are very good at writing tests that test the happy path of the product.
And we are actually, we have a good, comprehensive suite
that we make sure our product works as long as you stay in the rails.
If you start doing those weird things that testers think of,
like what happens if I do this 100 times?
What happens if I, you know, blah, blah, blah?
Those things can cause problems.
So my job as a, I'm still a common software QA engineer,
but part of my job is to help them get better at that.
And also for me to do some of that myself,
and I'll spend some time with them.
In fact, I have some meetings set up next week with each of the feature teams.
Kind of spend a half hour sort of brainstorming through the,
sort of how you look at the edge cases.
We'll call them edge cases for now, but the nonstandard scenarios.
So, oh, by the way, Brent and I, Brent's taking notes.
Yeah, Brent's taking notes because we're actually putting together
the outline for our presentation as we cast.
Yes, we skipped ahead, but we agreed to go and talk to Redfin.
Yeah, so yeah, we did.
So I think the first thing we talked about is developer testing
and a little chunk on that,
and we'll have some stories and anecdotes there.
And if you want to, you can add something to that,
or I'll shut up and let you talk about the next question.
Well, there's one of the framings that I'll put on this one is,
anytime you're trying to do this change management,
you have to consider, and I've said this a billion times
on the podcast, you have to consider three aspects.
The people, how they need to change, the technology,
what needs to change, and how do the processes,
the bridge between the technology,
how we expect the people to use the technology in a new way.
All of these questions, every time I have gone and done
any sort of talk on these topics,
the primary issue comes down to, wait,
so you're saying that the culture I'm used to is going to have to change?
Yeah, yeah, that's what we're saying.
The other thing I think that we'll have to cover in this,
certainly what, why, and how.
Usually the why is what seals the deal
in terms of getting them to go forward.
And this is not just, we should understand from Evan,
maybe even beforehand, why are they making this change?
Maybe, usually there's a good reason for it, right?
When you might make a change?
Like there's a reason they want to do continuous integration
and have high daily quality instead of good quality
once every three weeks.
They want to make that transition.
They don't have to.
There's a reason for it.
Some teams make these changes because they heard from some other team
that it had some benefit and they don't want to be left out.
I've got to imagine that a company like Redfin wouldn't do this
for that type of reason, that there's probably some business goal
that they're trying to achieve.
But it's important if the team needs to make that transition,
they are much more apt to make that transition
if they understand why they're doing it.
Yes.
Unless, you know, because there are probably people that
absolutely see it's going to be better.
Some that think, whatever, I'll go along for the ride.
And some that think, screw this, we were fine before.
Why don't we need to change?
This is true for any sort of cultural change.
Yeah.
Yeah, those three camps.
But the way you loop in and get momentum towards making the change happen
is make sure everybody understands why you're making the change
and what it's going to get better as a result of moving in this direction.
Yeah, and set up the right training, set up the right, for example,
continuous integration.
They're going to want to go from moving three-week waterfalls
to a continuous integration model.
I have yet to see a team that is able to do that successfully
without some serious architectural investments.
Well, I mean, we can talk hypothetically about this,
and we will for a moment before we get to the rest of the questions and notes.
What would I do?
You make sure, so they have a build server.
Sure.
Because they're building, I don't think they're building once every three weeks.
They're building and testing.
And if I'm going to imagine a three-week waterfall,
they do some planning for a couple days.
They write code for a week and a half, then they stabilize for a week.
That would be what I would do with a three-week waterfall.
And some people are thinking, hey, man, that's how my team does Scrum.
Well, that's a three-week waterfall.
No, I don't know if you know this.
I have a bunch of slides on this.
They've done studies as to what is the best sprint size.
Two.
It is.
Two weeks.
What's the worst?
Three.
Because it's screwy.
It is indeed.
Three is worse.
Well, three isn't the worst.
The point is three is worse than four.
Three is worse than four.
But it's actually three, one, four, two.
Really?
Yes.
And that's interesting because I've done one-week iterations before,
and they're kind of fun, but two feel good.
I like two-week iterations.
So do I.
I've been pushing our team for that.
I haven't got there.
The main reason why three is what they have found is any team who tries to onboard
onto Scrum pure but pick a three-week sprint, it is the forces of evil.
We'll turn that into two weeks coding, one week stabilization.
And I don't remember the numbers off of my hand,
but it's over 50% of the time.
Interesting.
So back on topic.
Yep.
And by the way, number one or one week is the second worst because the typical
Scrum overhead becomes too costly in one-week iterations.
It might depend on the size of the team.
But anyway, as I said a minute ago, back on topic,
I don't want to dive too deep in the technology stuff,
but they have a little bit of a walkthrough as an overview.
They have a build server that have to figure out if it's configurable to run
automatically on check-in.
And CI means you have a rich suite of tests that run as part of check-in.
And this can be depending on what they have already.
Jenkins is very popular, but we use VSO for CI as does a chunk of Microsoft
because we make it.
It's good for us to test it.
Anyway, there's some technology things we've got to figure out how they can
do builds on every check-in.
You have to look at the size of their team.
Maybe they can't do a build on every check-in and they have to batch.
There's all trade-offs through there.
But the idea is that every build that goes to the CI server is at a min bar
quality level defined by the suite of tests that run.
And hopefully that min bar is very high.
And if not, you add more tests.
The other thing too that you, like I actually think every one of these
questions we could do a whole hour tech talk on.
Yeah, so that, yeah, especially you.
Because you babble.
All right, what was it?
Let me put it this way.
I think you could do a whole hour tech talk on.
There is cultural stuff.
And there's a good story, you know, the Flickr story of, I'll dig it up
and share it.
Because there's a story where they're, and I'm going to horribly
paraphrase this, like I've horribly paraphrased all my stories that I
read and forget most of the details on.
But I'm 90% sure it was Flickr where the CEO said, or some other
high ranking person said, I want to be able to ship every day.
And his team was doing sort of this three week waterfall thing,
you know, or something like that.
And they said, you're freaking high.
And, but that was his rallying cry.
And the rallying cries were important.
And they got better and better.
And they got to shipping a high quality product every week.
And he had a big party and celebrated.
People said, why are we celebrating?
We need to get to every day.
And it's like, oh, I don't, you know, it's one of those
things where I set the goal of every day in order to get to
every week.
And the employee said, screw that every day.
This is fun.
The other thing too, right?
Waterfall to continuous, not only continuous integration,
in terms of like the infrastructure,
the technical infrastructure, but it also implies a shift to
Kanban.
Or something you want a shift to high daily quality.
Yep.
A shift to some of the things that have to happen is you're
not going to have, you're not going to think of features of
things that span three weeks.
Nope.
You do things in small chunks.
And you have to have monitors.
Like, I don't know if their technology is that big enough
that they need to worry about exposure rings,
but they do need to have the ability to do detection on
prod and quick reverb.
Right.
And when you think about it, and he doesn't necessarily say
they're doing CI to prod, but CI.
And you can make that choice to promote the prod.
Moving from three week waterfall releases to a
continuous integration model.
So there's a bunch of knobs to turn there.
Yeah.
If they're, if, you know, maybe, let's talk about this
for a second, and we'll, I don't want to, we don't need
to do the whole talk here, but if they had, say,
I assume they have a week of stabilization built into
their three week waterfall.
That means it takes them a week to stabilize their
product.
That would, how do you do it?
How do you stabilize that product now in a day, so
you can release it in a day or in an hour, so you
got, or continuous.
One, you don't mess it up that much.
You have to automate a bunch of that testing.
You can't, you can't let bugs linger.
There's a whole bunch of knobs you have to turn
slowly, and they're not going to get there.
They're not going to go, okay, we finished our
three week sprint today, tomorrow, we start, we'd
start releasing CI.
It isn't going to work that way.
So there's a build, like to me creating the right
branch integration strategy is key here, and having
a principle that your main branch is always RTM-able.
Yep.
So changes as best as possible.
Don't integrate into main branch unless it's passed,
but you want to evaluate on the change by change basis.
So we have our model, we use Git, and our model
is develop branch is equal to our CI environment.
So this goes through CI, goes to the develop branch.
Master is our, currently our dog food, but our
production environment.
Perfect.
So we just do emerge from when this develop build
is good.
But do you have a check-in based integration model?
Yes.
Or is it a batch integration?
We do both because we have, we have actually,
it's a weird, ours is complex.
We have multiple gates, but we're actually moving
from batch to check-in.
Awesome.
And the check-in, per check-in runs all of the
unit tests, a subset of all of our longer scenario
protractor or selenium tests.
And if any of those fail, it's rejected.
Otherwise they go in to develop.
We know they're pretty good.
And then we immediately run a much richer suite
of tests there to make sure there are no other
integration problems, other people's checks going in.
Yep.
So those are going on all the time.
Continuous testing, all the time on that develop branch.
We also have monitors running in our, both our
pre-production environment and our dog food environment
that find out if any of those things begin to fail.
Actually in our, we have those monitors running
in our CI environment now too, to find out if anything
gets like slower or fails.
So we have lots of checks and monitoring things
which are really pretty good.
So I don't know.
Again, those are knobs we're slowly turning
because we're not, unfortunately, we're not to see,
we're not to high, we don't have consistent
daily quality on my product.
But we're, so we're kind of along the same journey
a lot farther along than Evan's team is.
Yeah, no, I think you guys are exactly on
the same journey.
And I also think that turning the knobs slowly
is what makes sense.
Boiled frogs, man.
Boiled frogs.
That's right.
Because again, you have to turn multiple knobs
simultaneously to get this word.
If you shifted, if you were to say,
hey, tomorrow we're all can-ban.
And you don't have the people trained up,
you don't have the technology in place.
I don't know.
It's an exaggeration, but you probably won't
have a company in a couple of months.
You have to bring people along for the ride.
We got on this tangent by the QA stuff.
We're not on tangents.
We're right on time.
By definition, we don't tan.
All right.
What else are we talking about?
As a QA engineer, do I have a place in this new world?
Oh, haven't we talked about that a whole bunch?
We could argue that was the whole reason
we started the podcast.
It is, and I think, oh, wow.
That was nostalgic.
My head really wants to go off on a tangent,
but I have a whole other topic that I'm going to stay right.
There are no tangents in A-B testing.
We just covered this.
Okay, I'm not going to go there.
But I guess it depends, but listen carefully.
If the only role on the team is to write software,
implement software, and write happy path functional tests,
there may not be a role for a QA engineer.
No.
But that's a really horrible way to make software.
You can't just implement code and write happy path tests.
You need those generalizing.
I think the former QA engineer is the generalizing specialist
or specializing generalist that helps the team accelerate
productivity, applies systems thinking to make sure
the edge cases and corner cases and things like reliability,
perf, globalization, et cetera are all addressed.
They look at the product overall to find out what is the,
because you're doing CI, how do we get better every day?
Most of your engineers aren't thinking of that,
but QA engineers I think are uniquely, former QA engineers,
are uniquely tuned to do that sort of thing.
They are.
They're also helpful in terms of training up the other dev.
My ideal scenario when we're seeing this,
now, Evan, there's nothing in what Evan's talking about
that suggests that they're considering unified engineering.
That's correct, but even if you're not,
let's say you have a test team and you're doing it,
but again, I think unified engineering is almost irrelevant
to this conversation because this role is going to change
regardless to more of an engineer role to do CI,
if you're going to have daily high quality builds.
You're not going to be running a test pass every day.
The one issue, so let me ask you this,
because we've talked about this in the past,
but we've now had more experience,
the statement that I've said in the past is still true today.
Any team that I've seen where they're trying to move
quality upstream and get dev doing more testing,
if they have a low to medium level,
even just one QA engineer in their scrum team,
the model doesn't work.
I've not seen a single situation.
I've seen situations where there was a 10 to 1
dev to low to middle level QA guy,
and those devs are like,
I don't know what management's thinking.
How is one guy going to get all of this work done?
The culture shift is just not going to happen.
The dev seniority at minimum will overpower this one low level guy,
just as a strong man to defend.
Evan's not a low level guy.
He's not.
But we're talking about his team.
I guess so.
I think what you're saying is that if the lower level QA tester guy or girl
is going to have less,
not going to have the ability to have the influence on the dev team
to teach them how to help them write better quality software.
Is that correct?
Yes.
And even further,
and we've talked about this what, two, three episodes ago,
once the codependency loop starts?
Yes.
I think you've got to eliminate that no matter what, right?
Right.
So let's talk about that.
And we'll maybe give a little bit of information from Evan first,
but you don't want to put them on the scrum team to be dev's bitch.
Right.
So what is their role there?
And Evan can help.
Any leadership can help figure that out.
I've obviously done this for a long time,
but in my team I'm totally comfortable being the one sort of test guy
for 70, 80 devs.
Yes.
I don't go to the...
Your experience, right?
So I got to think...
You're like, no.
That is not what I'm paid to do.
Right, absolutely.
And in fact, we have...
I have five vendors here that do some testing for us,
and I've embedded them in the feature teams.
And it's even less than that.
Not only have the one tester in these feature teams,
I had them span multiple feature teams,
because only five of them.
And they are very well trained.
When someone says,
hey, can you do this test pass for me?
Can you do this for me?
Their answer is no.
That's not what I do.
They say, what are you...
But you're a tester.
I say, what?
And they're very much a liaison and a consultant.
They will brainstorm with the Scrum team on how to do some testing.
These are fairly junior people.
But the model, I think, works.
Imagine Evan is a senior guy with a bunch of junior people.
That model sort of works.
As long as he facilitates their role in that Scrum team,
you can have the more junior people there.
And be successful.
Yeah, I think the insight we just got on here is,
if you pay active attention to making sure that co-dependency loop
never, ever, ever starts, then there's hope.
Yeah, I think so.
And the plans work them well, because not only do they...
And I talked to the engineering managers,
who are massively more senior from these testers.
They still seem as really valuable,
because they provide that different insight.
Testers just look at the product differently.
And then also, they take...
Because they look at the product collectively as a whole.
In fact, those five vendors probably know the product
end-to-end better than anyone.
But they'll go to their different feature team meetings
and bring that information back to the collective.
So that little bit of that plugging in is super valuable.
So I think if you...
I don't know, that's the only model that will work.
But for me, having those five vendors
get connected with those...
We have eight engineering managers,
who own...
I'm totally estimating here, let's say 15 feature areas
of our product.
And so far, it's working out pretty well.
They're a little stretch thin, but again,
it's my job to make sure that if they need to...
It makes sense to spend a little bit more time
working with a team on this feature.
I'm going to make sure they're ramped back on other things
so they're not stretched too thinly.
I just had another idea.
Let me interject that and love to hear what you have to say.
All right.
I'm reminded back to the old days when our friend James
was still at Google and he was describing...
What was his name?
James White Watson Whittaker something?
Whittaker, whatever.
Yeah, that guy.
He was describing...
And Google's changed, right?
I don't get the sense that the principle they used to have
of if you want to change teams tomorrow,
you just notify the right people.
I don't think that that's...
I think Google's gotten a lot more command and control-ish.
Yeah, I have no idea.
Get to your point.
Okay.
So back in the day, QA guys could pick and choose
where they wanted to work.
So if they were engaged with a dev team
and that dev team was trying to do some of this
dev bitch stuff, that dev team lost their QA guy
because I don't like working with you.
I'm going to go work on that thing.
It doesn't work.
I mean, yeah, it's harder when you're at a smaller company
because your option is to quit and apply for other jobs.
Yeah, I guess it depends on how many choices you have.
But if you dramatically short the dev to QA ratio,
if there's only one QA per dev team of, say, seven...
Even that's too high, I think.
But go on.
Then you could potentially start up a process of,
hey, one of your QA guys comes to you and says,
hey, I didn't like this.
I need your help.
You don't need my help.
Tomorrow you're going to work with that team is set.
I don't know about that model.
We can explore.
So you should...
You understand what the benefit would be of that?
Yeah.
Okay, good.
You want to keep them engaged.
I think we have enough information for an outline.
And Evan may listen to this podcast and go,
all right, guys, I'm good.
You don't need to come.
I doubt it.
I'm good.
We talked about what the themes for...
We didn't even...
I don't know that we even really covered...
It's done, man.
Presentation's done.
We're good.
Okay, awesome.
I'll put together a slide of some sheep and a balloon and...
The Avengers slide.
I like your Avengers slide.
You should put that one in.
Oh, we should do that.
We should do some of that.
So it's P...
Yeah.
And the one that goes after that whole sequence there.
Perfect.
So what do you think?
I think we better call it a day.
All right.
All right, everybody.
I am not Brent.
And I am.
See you next week or next time.
Again, Strata next week.
We're done.
You don't get to talk after goodbye.
Reach out to me on Twitter.
See you guys.