Ladies and gentlemen from the Palatial Studio D at Microsoft in Redmond, Washington, I'm Alan.
I'm Brent.
And we're here for episode 30 of A.B. testing.
The big 3.0.
You know what? Big 3.0. I'm going to be the big 5.0 like in two weeks.
Really?
Yeah. I'm ready for a midlife crisis.
I did that 10 years ago.
Grew my hair out long.
You were 50 10 years ago? That's about right.
No.
Here you're predicting midlife is 50 for you?
Oh no. I'm over the hill.
So, f***. Oh, I can't.
Edit coming.
So this episode, we have our little list up.
And it's all about this episode is called Stuff Alan and Brent Did.
Yeah. It's all about ketchup too.
Like the number one item on the list.
God, what was that? The end of September?
We haven't recorded. We did the live episode.
We'll just talk about it in a little bit.
But we haven't recorded a studio session.
In a while.
It's been a while.
Life happens and we apologize.
But you know what?
I talked to somebody. I'm going to jump ahead here.
I talked to someone in Europe.
There are a lot of one of the three in Europe.
Just saying.
I met like seven of them.
Yeah. Similar experience.
We have a lot of folks now.
Yeah.
It's fantastic.
No. There really are only three.
They just trade off.
But it's funny.
Someone told me that they like our podcast,
but they can't listen to it while they do anything else.
I thought they're going to say because you guys are so idiotic
and stupid and unpredictable.
But it turns out it's just because we talked fast
and English is their second language set to stop and actually listen.
Oh. That's my anecdote there.
So back in.
I was going to assume it was ADHD.
So they have to take.
Oh, we should do.
That's the subtitle ADHD testing the print and Helen show.
Hey, you went to in the end of September conference called Strata.
I did.
It was.
And on to the next subject.
Sorry.
Tell us a little bit about Strata.
The two coolest things was went to Strata.
First and foremost, it was my first trip to New York.
Second Strata was extremely interesting from the perspective of seeing
how the rest of the world is viewing the data science problem versus say
Microsoft.
And then lastly, had dinner and drinks with one of the three.
Which three?
Percy.
Percy three.
Actually, it's one of my favorite one of the threes because he's the one
that kick started the one of the three hashtag.
Did he I thought I did he did it.
He did it.
He's awesome.
He is winner.
I don't know what's interesting there.
I don't know.
So you thought the rest of the industry is doing.
What is the rest of the industry doing?
Is it is it are they just doing math on Abacus or they actually doing cool
stuff?
I'll tell you what I walked away with first and foremost.
Microsoft today in a lot of our internal problems were still under
transition right to this as we gear up and train more people on the
data science world seems the type of problems that we're trying to
solve today.
The rest of the world solved two to three years ago.
You know, that's you know, it's a parallel there.
There was a time in software testing back when it was much more
relevant when the problems that the industry was trying to solve
were problems that Microsoft solved a few years ago.
But so that parallel happens and it's good for us to notice us
as an industry and us as Microsoft to see when to one
one cool thing is you see happening a little more now than
happened you know 10 years ago is people actually look outside
the walls of the board and see what's going on in the world.
They notice these things.
If I understood what you said previously that there was a
period in time which there was a period of time when on the
test front Microsoft was ahead of the rest of the world.
I believe so. Yes.
I you kind of saw I kind of saw them follow.
I agree with that for better or for worse.
I also think like a lot of other companies have followed
Microsoft's review model.
Amazon still uses our review model that you and I suffered
under 20 years ago.
But I actually wonder if there's a correlation there.
Right.
Because we were busily heavily investing and leading the
world in terms of how test is done and the rest of the
world moved into the frame of hey we don't need test and
they invested sooner and earlier than we do into the
data science world.
I think we were slower to something just even the science
part.
In many cases we were slower to realize the power of
measuring customer data and telemetry in general and all
that.
Yeah.
We kept investing using monitoring as testing versus
trying to test everything into it from before it went
live.
Yes.
I get it.
Yeah.
So cool.
You met Percy.
You learned about some big data.
Biggest takeaway.
Big data as it gets bigger and bigger.
You need to work towards massively parallelizing how
you grok the data.
And the biggest takeaway the biggest aha for me is that
in that world polynomial time is absolutely too slow.
N squared is way too slow and it's even getting to the
point where O of N is too slow.
So we need faster more effective ways to parse
massive amounts of data.
Yeah.
It's very fascinating.
This is where we've talked about it before.
When things what you know can't scale to your
needs this is where new ideas start to form.
So it's going to be really exciting to watch what
comes out of this space over the next couple of
years.
Yeah.
It is interesting.
I was worried at the beginning because it sounded
like you're going like tautology mode only.
Like you're going to say as big data gets bigger
it's bigger.
I'm going to try to avoid pure tautology today.
All right.
Or not.
So you got to go to New York.
So did you do anything New Yorky while you were
there?
Yeah.
Went to this great Brazilian Russian.
How many what?
A Brazilian.
Oh I thought you said a Brazilian.
No Brazilian.
Brazilian restaurant.
Okay.
Yeah.
You realize Brazil is not in New York.
I know.
Okay.
Just checking.
Yeah.
We went to Sal's pizzeria and we also went to
one of the hole in the wall pizzeria places.
Sal's was sort of hey it's famous place we got
to go.
Okay.
Hole in the wall pizzeria.
Way better.
I know.
I think the Sal's pizza I could get here.
I was not impressed.
There's nothing like a slice in New York City
late at night after about 17 beer.
Three two beer.
One beer.
Sufficient beer.
Yeah.
Alright cool.
And then Times Square that was an experience.
So my hotel room was literally right over Times Square.
It was fantastic that the blackout curtains actually did.
I think they have to do that there.
Cool.
Alright.
So then in between there we went and recorded the live show at Red Finn which you heard
in episode 29.
Hopefully.
At least three of you did.
At least three well the three heard it.
Interesting to marry a live show with the A.B. testing style.
It was fun.
We got a chance to babble on a lot of things people had heard before.
Little interaction.
In most cases we remember to repeat the audience question.
And in some cases you had to infer the question from our answers.
But all in all an interesting take and we should we should do it again sometime.
Well think about the format of that so we get that find the right marriage there.
Yeah I don't think based on the feedback.
See I don't.
Here's the deal.
Alan doesn't read the feedback.
I don't give one flying you know what about feedback.
Brent however is slightly below feedback.
Can you explain to me again how just as a complete and total hypothetical aside.
I'm forgetting it.
Can you explain how learning organizations work again.
Anyway.
Yeah we do need to tweak the format so what you guys what you guys don't know so we had
the audio.
I wonder if it's worthwhile to release the video.
If if two of you.
Brent there's there's a reason we're on a podcast.
That guy good point.
Yeah people don't we're gonna.
They don't need to see that.
We'll go down to two listeners and they're both blind.
If we decide to show our faces.
What we did for the presentation is we decided to do it as as we as you saw podcast style
we told them up front.
We had what a hundred plus people in the room and we didn't we didn't bring a slide deck.
Yeah which I think is fine.
I think if there was one thing I would do differently I would take your little sheet
of notes and crumple it up and throw it away before we started.
Yeah you said that in the podcast and I'm still denying that it was in the way man.
Yeah in the way from my experience is in the way.
No I think so that one the great news is we got the first ever our first ever live album
for something like that.
I'm gonna need the out of net.
I'm gonna need the outline or else I'm just gonna get in the weeds also I think for this
format reel in the topics like way more high level and then stop earlier for questions.
I think the most where so I don't look at feedback because I look I observe the audience
look for engagement and it was Q&A where you start to get the engagement.
Yeah I think better last time so we spent I was roughly when I re listened to it I
was roughly counting how much time we spent talking about our prior experience.
I think when you go into that setting up a expectation of credibility is important but
I think we spent too much time on that.
I agree with you that if we had just gone through very quickly the breadth of topics
and just a little bit of depth and then open up the questions making it very clear
hey we can go wherever you guys think is most valuable let's start made it much more
interactive I think that would have been a better presentation.
Have we done a podcast since I did the talk at GoDaddy?
Yes.
Okay because that was they wanted me to give us like a half hour presentation so I prepared
a couple quick slides on testing a single page web application which I happen to be doing
and just I just all it was was sorry if this is a repeat I just made some basically I started
with the bullet points of like five or six or seven of the things that I thought I had
learned that are most important.
I talked about them a little bit kind of how our team was doing it and then we had
questions that for a quick little half hour talk that worked well and also it's because
something like that you could go super deep on and go forever but I find that even
when I do conference talks I value the Q&A more than you can't really do a Q&A on a keynote
but I if I if I do a track session or even a workshop I really try and make it interactive
in fact once I gave a many many many years ago I give a keynote at star and Lee asked
me to give a track session and Whitaker our buddy the infamous the world famous James
Whitaker was there a good friend with James but I don't want to come to my talk but we
finished by I finished by thing that goes because being goes I can't use the exact words
he used because they're not PG appropriate because something like holy Alan you didn't
do anything you made your audience give the whole talk for you there's a quote I used
in my the segue into I went to Eurostar a few weeks ago and there's a quote I pull
a lot into a presentation once a while but usually I'm talking about some you
know bit of innovation innovation maybe even this stretch something some new idea
talk about the Heinlein quote which I will badly paraphrase as I usually do
but you know the future is paved by lazy people trying to find a easier way of
doing things and that's what I do I don't want to get a whole talk I don't
want who wants to listen to a talking head for an hour those people that they
paid to come and do exactly that I know I don't and I I'll talk about Eurostar a
little bit but I as an audit both as an audience member and as a speaker I think
it's just much more value when you're doing a track session with 30 40 50
people to make it interactive versus have them listen to you read bullet points oh
did you which yeah I had a I had a nightmare at star I had this like
really vivid it was like it wasn't quite all the way a sleep dream but
it's kind of laying in bed and I visualize like the worst presentation ever
I wrote it up I wrote it up it's basically every bad thing I've seen like
people reading bullet points and turning their back to the audience and slides
with nothing but text it's all yeah yeah I'm just like oh hey and they never
stopped talking they never get to a point you know okay I go damn it damn
it oh it's awful so I like that and there I saw one cool talk it was it
maybe went a little bit too far I won't throw out any names because I'm being
critical but maybe went a little bit too far on the audience participation could
be a little bit more roll up in it but it was a lot of fun I like engagement and
the audience was engaged so even though I would like to see a little bit more
wrap up a little bit more facilitation around the audience discussion during
this talk I think the audience still got a lot out of it so I can't really
complain from my perspective I would like you know and I'm super
hypercritical on on talks and there were plenty there were some really good ones
and plenty of like come on stop and am I upon a soapbox again you are when you
go to these often too often it's a consultant trying to drum up business
versus a practitioner trying to share knowledge with the community oh so it's
strata that one thing that was interesting is that they they
separated those conferences they were different tracks and the consultants all
in one session only one track Oh Lee Copeland if you're listening all
consultants get their own unfortunately for star conferences I think that means
that there's like one small track for non consultants I could be wrong I my
demographics would be wrong so I'll be quiet but so I went to those tracks a
couple of times and those are the ones where I left after 15 minutes it was you
you pick up very quickly I am NOT going to learn anything here except for this
guy's particular tool in what it costs often I think and not to pick on you
know it's really easy to dump every single consultant into one bucket but
in my experience I can qualify this I'll weasel word my way out of this in my
experience the vast majority of consultants speaking about software
testing at least is a lack of practical and recent knowledge or it's it's just I
just can't find it relevant I think that problem so several of these companies
also had their engineers come and do presentations I had a great long chat
with the engineering team from eBay and it ended up those type of things are
really adored it ended up being kind of like a in-person stack exchange
conversation they asked questions of me I asked questions of them we both learned
together but the people who are presenting this consultant stuff I
think they're bringing in their marketing team I'm like you know if you bring in
do the same presentation but have it presented by one of your low-level
engineers it'd be a much better presentation for that audience it kind
of comes back to whether you're you know I'm a big fan of storytelling in in
general and in talks and often if you don't have that practical experience you
don't have the story that helps drive the point home and if you're telling a
story it's sometimes irrelevant but I think really those anecdotes about how
concept X was used and what it did and what you learned are super valuable so I
know we're not I'm I'm we are doing a patented a B testing tangent so I want to
wind back in I think we can close I was gonna fine then I'll do my tangent okay
as usual brain gets to finish one of the things that was also different was
our rhythm I don't think our are you're in my rhythm when we do the podcast it
wasn't clicking at redfin and I think one of the reasons just looking at you
right now right we're we're looking at talking in the microphone we're reading
each other's by language we can kind of tell whereas and you're reading that
stupid piece of paper in front of you I was that thing is my memory now I
think you're right though that if we had if we had just briefly I think next
time right that sheet has to be no more than five items something that I can
memorize and kind of memorize the flow so that I don't go off tap it topic and
start talking about individual the color of your underoos that was really
embarrassed I cut that out that was edited out it's blue though yeah Superman
the but that's something I think from so I did read the feedback and I do think
that that awkwardness of our rhythm got picked up by the audience so let me talk
about before we get to I'm gonna talk a little about my experience at Eurostar
but I've been thinking for a while I want I go to all these conferences and
I watch talks and see different styles of talks and I want I need to run a
conference no let me finish Brent put your sock back in your mouth and let me
finish I'm shutting up because I want like I think hour-long talks are awful
I want 30 minute talks maybe it's 20 minute talk with 10 minutes of questions
I don't know what how it works I'm working out the details I think I I
just there's very few 50 to 60 minute talks that I've enjoyed if they're
interactive you can you can go that long or longer but just a talking head for
that long is just 90% of the time in my experience a total waste of time there
are logistics around that you've done that before and it went well but let me
go on another thing I'm gonna marry some ideas have been bouncing in my
head right here at 835 in the morning and a be testing I've also thought some
of my favorite conferences have been peer conferences for there's just a dozen of
us 15 of us in a inner you know hanging out for a couple days or a day talking
about stuff seeing where the conversation goes imagine a be testing
with more people and smarter people and Brent now and shut up and listen
there's potential there I went to one for teller ik that Jim Holmes hosted a
few years ago it was just a great experience I did the Chris McMahon
writing about testing peer conference fun good camaraderie great ideas some good
learning out of that and but organizing hosting travel stuff I could do but I
don't know so what I've been thinking of doing for a while and I don't have a
timeline for this and maybe we get one or two of the three to join in is a
virtual conference a virtual peer conference we pick some topics get invite
10 15 20 people everybody has a topic they're going to talk about for anywhere
from 15 to 30 minutes or some time for question and answer and interactive it
wouldn't be like an eight hour a day thing you do it for like we're gonna do
it for a couple hours over a couple days I don't know how quite it works
yet but bounce around in my head I don't have the details figured out but
I'm throwing it out here to the masses for feedback and thoughts and planting
the seeds and and maybe what would be awesome if it happened if somebody else
just took it took it by the the reins and made it happen and etc etc so I went
to Eurostar in a mastic where in the Netherlands okay so if you those you
that haven't memorized European map there's a little spit of land at the
bottom of the Netherlands that goes kind of scorched itself in between in
between Belgium and Germany and there is a town there called Maastricht and
that's where Eurostar was this year and I went there flew into Amsterdam took a
train about two and a half hours get there I walk in I go I get to my room
put my stuff down hang up some things that are wrinkled I beat it's been
like you know 20 hours of travel at this point I walk downstairs I'm gonna get like
a something to eat and go to bed and I see great guy I haven't seen since the
last year I went to three years ago a great guy Alan Richardson he's Alan
number two I'm Alan number one we were labeled during one of the keynotes
he's a frequent speaker but he's Scottish Scottish he's Scottish so
he's a fun guy I like talking to him I met a lot of people who were one of the
three saw some good talks I I got it in Tuesday night Wednesday night we had a
dinner in a cave that was cool I sat with a servant caves mushrooms I don't the
dinner was you don't know you were there it was good not great there was
some some food I don't eat I kind of I mostly drink the wine didn't eat much of
food at a fun table James Lindsay was at our table he won the whatever the
European tester of the year award is or something that was fun next night
however was a dinner just for the speakers from the I was only there to
speak on Friday at this deep dive on mobile testing and we ate in there's
this restaurant that's made in an old church so just beautiful and the food
there was just fantastic oh so good and then I became back and believe it or not
usually when I got to these dinners I worried that I'm gonna come home like
full and plastered and not sleep and but it was nice to came home fairly sober
not too full and got a good night of sleep and got up and gave my talk the
next morning what's the best European country for
aquitarian to Eden I know it's not Germany I can get around anywhere
Germany's at the cheese you can get around anywhere I think so give the talk
how to go I think it went well what was the theme of your star this year the
member I just was there for the mobile deep dive so the theme was mobile
testing so I talked about application compatibility I talked about it from the
angle of the thing I worked on to make Android apps run on Windows and talked
about how we got data and really turned it into the importance of using data and
telemetry and that really stuck home and there was actually I was thought I'd
scare people with that but there's some other talks on that as well Julian
Hardy went deep into data analysis etc mm-hmm so it really kind of helped you
know it's tough being first it's fun being first it's tough being first but
what I like to do when I give a talk at a conference is I'll tie in like
previous talks so I feel like I set up my peers very well to tie in their
subjects so there was that next morning I took off I like a two and a half hour
train trip to Amsterdam I got at the airport early than I've ever been to the
airport like three hours early but there were such long lines I still barely
made my flight it was ridiculous so then I get to our plane ran out of gas
that ever happened say we're running all on fuel we're gonna need to stop a
little early and top her off so we stopped in Albany New York and got some
extra fuel get to Philadelphia in time for me to miss all my connecting flights
home spent the night in Philadelphia flew back the next day and that's pretty
much it I was home for a week and then I went to this I went down to visit riot
games who make a League of Legends hey before you start talking about riot
all right um you have your star questions I do you want to know where
Netherlands are you geography lesson you just did that this is actually the
first time I think I've heard you say that there was sort of a deep dive on data
analysis which I think is promising that that the rest of the test community
is beginning to get with the modern times what based on what you observe that
you're a star what sort of things are still active in the test community that
shouldn't be and where do you see the test community moving I think there's
still a lot of people living in the test last world where testing is this thing
that happens after the development team is done with the product that's
unfortunate that's unfortunate for us it's fortunate for the consultants
that's where they make a lot of their money so that part is inefficient but
for many companies they just it's it's good enough there are most
companies doing any sort of web service or a web page anything in the cloud have
figured out that data that gathering data and analyzing it and you know turning it
sideways is the right thing to do are you seeing that as well as test first
starting to be highlighted at these conferences no I'm seeing more and more
sort of Agilish integration of the testers quality person into the
development team but it's and again I don't know what the right direction is
but more most often the tester in these agile teams is just doing all the
testing tasks versus coaching develop and helping developers on how to write
better tests in the first place so these conferences are helping to teach
and optimize for the world that people shouldn't be in is that what you know
I'm not saying that at all I'm saying people are sharing their experiences on
what they're doing and this is in a vague summary what they're doing I think
people are figuring out how to ship software faster and they're trying
different things to see what sticks okay and that's for the practitioners for
what I see from a lot of consultants is there's a separation between development
testing if you look at this I forget is this ISO 2 1 1 9 I might get the
number wrong but this there was a big hull blue last year about this the new
ISO software testing standard and is that the thing you quizzed me on a few
that was the IST QB thing okay thinking about this testing standard is
that it fundamentally from the very beginning assumes that testing is a
completely different task from software development so there's just it just
doesn't work in my world and probably for the world of a lot of people it
just assumes that testing is this thing that's done after development is
complete and that's just not a world that I don't I do know and I've realized
and acknowledge that there's a chunk of the world that lives there and that's
fine but that's not the way I ever ever want to make software there's a role for
say final validation final quality assurance right there's there's a lot of
people throughout manufacturing throughout software that have the the QA title
happened then no in it in it the amount of work there really should be what at
most 1% of total time spent on the product I'm making up numbers of course
but it should be much smaller than it is true that 43.7% of all statistics are
made up I heard it was uh it's rising oh well yeah all right so you traveled
for 40 hours it took me a long time to get home maybe close to 50 hours to do
an hour presentation and then you came back and plus a bunch of free food in
Europe then you came back and went to riot I did I was invited down to visit
riot who and I don't know if you've played League of Legends no I played a
little bit and I've played it like ten times since I've been there because it's
I'd and I'll tell you why in a minute it is crazy I'm sure at least one of the
three have played League of Legends I got to go on a tour of their facility I
don't know how much of this is top secret or anything but I'll take my
chances I had met them a couple people down there a while back and I just
wanted to kind of check the place out because it's it's the most popular game
in the world I think they have they have world championships where they can
fill a soccer stadium full of people watching people play this video game it
is just crazy they have their own arena trying to figure out what rock I've lived
under I've never even heard of this game you're not helping the cause here
man yeah so they have their own arena across the street their place is built
on their new place is they got from Fox Studios so it's on the set of the
old 24 so like Jack Bowers old office is still there cool images is
it's a it's basically a world of Warcraft competitor then ish but not really I don't
want to go all the way into explaining and check it out but it's really well
thought out and I think just done really well then there I love their
business model where they don't have ads you can't pay to make your to increase
your ability of winning like you can't like buy a bunch like you can't money
won't make you win the game only skill will but you can buy it people they
make them money people buy skins and and things for the overall there's a
rotating list of champions you can choose from if you want to have one
always available you can buy that one but and they make good money doing that
and they're massively popular it is just crazy how wild the world is for
this thing and I was asking about monitoring and the cool thing was I asked
him all my typical questions like I was looking for like what's something they
haven't thought of yet and they're pretty much you know they didn't I
couldn't really surprise them with anything I'm talking about monitoring a
little bit oh come check this out and I see this like this route looks like
NASA where their operations team works is like showing like stuff all it's
really cool I don't want to give I don't want to give away any secrets or
anything but it was I was impressed with the facility I already violated my
NDA but I think I'm I think I'm probably in least in the great I'll be
vague but very recently have you have you visited one of our data centers have
you done that trip I've done the Queen Sea data center trip yeah just did
something similar and yeah I totally understand like the the NASA monitoring
yeah it's really cool right I was impressed just to monitor electricity yeah
check me out the dinner metal but some cold people there it was it was a fun
trip was worth it to go meet those folks down there and get an idea what their
place looked like it's pretty cool we're either to give a talk or a field
trip man most of sort of a field trip okay just meeting some people to quick
take a Monday off quick quick trip to LA to and it was cold in LA was a bummer
it was windy cold in LA is what 70 no it was like in maybe maybe less than
60 ah that's a spring here all right we don't have anything from the mailbag do
we we had something from Percy but we didn't write it down right so I want to
ask okay so we'll do an episode of stupid people at Microsoft I got two to
cover one is right you have a big truck right I do a big red truck all right so
we call it Clifford Clifford the big red truck that's fantastic I have a
so I don't understand is people with these here's my my wonderment people with
these hundred thousand dollar SUVs your truck isn't that much but no these
massive you know they're like guys before wheel drive which is made for
going off-road yet they slow to like one one hundredth of a mile an hour to
go over a speed bump that I don't understand okay is it and I have to
imagine help you with every single one of them has a coffee cup filled to the very
very brim with my truck I do not even pause for speed bumps I fly bumps in my
frickin Prius there there's one you know what I'm talking about right so I'm
gonna stop I'm gonna ease the front tires over okay okay I'm gonna go forward
yeah I just go I don't actually I know I'm the way here on the way here this
morning there was a guy in a truck you know the ramp down to the parking lot
ramp down to the app so there's this four-story ramp to an underground parking
lot near the building that we're in right now and they have speed bumps and
there was this guy who was in a three Ford 350 which is a bigger more heavy
duty truck than mine driving over the speed bumps in the way you described and
I'm just like oh my god move move what are you doing yeah all right hey we talked
a lot on this podcast about systems thinking did we we managed to have a
point this podcast not in this one previous oh right episode yes we don't
have a point this is the stuff Brett Naland did but I was thinking about you
when you have a challenge when you want to whether it's an organizational change
or a or any sort of change you want to do at work or a project or anything yep I
find it important to at least take a little bit and whether it's a my map or
some notes or sketch or some conversations I don't believe in analysis
paralysis like thinking through every possible plan B and plan C before going
but I do believe in thinking at least a little bit in advance about what are the
implications of this let me kind of walk through this in my head this would be
a long process so recently and so I I live my life so I'm fighting a little
battle right now where someone I work with wanted to make a big change that
let's go ahead and do it let's make this change okay everybody's on board let's
go go I'm thinking there are some big implications here that you haven't
thought of and like huge like the part he wanted to do is all going hello about
by far the easiest part it's like the tip of the iceberg he wants to take
care of and I'm looking at and every time I think about what's underneath I
go we got to do this it's probably not that bad oh you have this part oh
shoot and that connects to this and now we have to do this so it's just
fascinating to me how and again I don't want to get stuck in like thinking
through every possible thing but and I'm being very abstract about this in case I
know he's not one of the three it's interesting though this isn't like the
first time in my career I've seen someone who should know better push for
change without thinking through the implications of it I think the reality is
is system thinkers are rare I don't think they're that I think I don't really
don't think they're that rare especially in a tech company I know not
everyone is I think they are I think I think you have people who go all
right we needed we need a abstract strategy and they gloss over the
details I think there's a lot of people who are very deeply detail focused
who often just execute and execute and they don't actually even know what gold
they're trying to achieve and I think the people who can bridge those two are
extremely rare that's my experience yeah and I guess and I see a lot of the same
parallels I talked a lot about with the right guys about teams moving to unified
engineering and agile and you can't just decide that okay we're gonna be
agile we're gonna do this and this and this you need to think about through
why and what does it mean and what does it change and how do we function
differently and there's just a lot more pieces in there than deciding okay we're
agile now we're doing scrum and we're not writing in word documentation yeah I
mean it that started up what 15 years ago and it's has led to you inventing
fragile right I think that any I think there's Alan's I need to make a list of
these along with you used to automate 100% of the tests should be automated
little bit of just a teeny bit of a tautology there but there is something
else that I think every team needs after define team but needs a systems thinker
to be successful you need someone who can someone whose job it is to think about
how all the pieces fit together what the implications are of any sort of change it
was one of the pieces of feedback that we got from redfin is one of the
questions that didn't get asked apparently was why is Brent suggesting
that we hire an agile coach and by the way it's exactly for that reason it's you
need to have someone I mean he right and I would I would if you want to bootstrap
just hire one further hypothesize that if you look at any successful team at
any company in the world they have that person that can that is looking at the
big picture thinking other pieces fit together and that may be someone on
the team may be an architect maybe the leader but I think success requires that
someone is at least ongoing success requires that someone is looking at the
big picture of things it's the the desire to bounce from fire to fire is
seductive right it is hey Alan I don't have time to think through this whole
thing this is something that I need to do right now and then they don't
realize that that causes a chain of events that the new thing that they're
going to be asking you to do six months from now is not only directly caused by
that thing that they didn't think about but actually reverses that thing I've
seen this happen over and over and over and over let me close with a story yeah a
parable if you will so Alan's parables guys walking out to the river and sees
someone drowning it dies into the river to save them and then there's two more
people drowning in the river so two more people run out and run out to save them
and it and there's more and more people floating down the river people the
people are running out to the river to save them bring them to shore and they
see someone walking upstream they said where are you going we need your help
I'm going upstream to find out who's throwing all these people in the river
I use a similar metaphor I talk about if we're busy putting out if we're
constantly busy putting out forest fires maybe someone should move ahead and
find the three-year-old who's been given the lighter I like my story back
all right I think we're out of time and we should call it a day what do you
think sounds good I am Alan and I am Brent good thing we know our names all
right thank you for listening to episode 30 of A B testing we'll see you next time