Guess what what it's episode 26 of a be testing Wow
Holy cow, what are we doing?
And yet again, we have a list of things that we don't know what we're talking about
But we're gonna talk about them and see what happens
Yep, every time we come here with like that looks like about five minutes of material, but somehow we stretch it into
Longer. Yes. I wonder how many people play our podcast back at like a faster speed so they can get through it quicker
How do you do that? Like the tools that I have playback tools like on YouTube. I did that all the time
I watch talks on YouTube at one and a half speed
Sure
So YouTube is very handy
Maybe no, but maybe if you just if that's like your thing and it's if all three listeners say like we listen to you fast
I will maybe I should just make like two
versions of the podcast one at normal speed for the noobs and
Then one like at one and a half or double speed so you can get through
But this time if people want to get through the podcast fast
We're helping them out. Yeah, we started a little late here cuz Brent got lost. Yes, Brent has come to the lovely
confines of
Lincoln Square
Yes, downtown Bellevue as I've mentioned before I used to work in Bellevue. I love it here
From where I'm sitting right now. I can see two different lakes
If we had gotten here a little bit earlier, we would have seen the sunrise
This doesn't help for the podcast but the sunrise in that direction
Yeah, my office is right under the side of that wall that my view is that direction to yeah 20th floor here
not bad my last building I would
Wake up and get to watch the sunrise over man
Only it wasn't so darn busy here. I would look out the window more. I guess so. No, no, I
What have your office facing the window
Work is fun, but busy. It's it's it's a good challenge
Yeah, it's also really cool that when I walk the other way to get coffee
It looks out over Seattle. I see like little tip of a space needle sticking up that way. Oh, yeah that way
Yeah, all right. Wait, maybe I got a better idea for getting people through the podcast quicker
I'll just cut out all this boring crap
Episode 26 three minutes
The three minutes where Alan and Brent actually talk about testing. Oh, yeah, and that's Alan and I'm Brent
So so speaking of talking about testing
Starting this one off. Well
Look, I'm starting it off. Well, I'm sorry. You're not along for the ride. I'll follow. Okay, so
Yesterday I was I have like an hour at my desk or two and getting some work done
Take a glance at Twitter and
I see oh, there's a cast talk going on
I said and I had no idea what it was about but I'll just listen in and see what's going on at cast
Oh, I'm guessing our listeners. I think one thing about people to listen to a podcast
Is that you actually pay attention to the internet and if you're listening to our podcast
You're probably a tester who pays attention to the internet. So you probably know that cast is the conference
The Association of software testing it's the context driven schools conference they do it once a year and
bomb bomb
Yeah, so anyway, the cool thing is that they I don't know
We've done a rant on the context school testing on this thing. I don't know, you know
It'll probably have the number of our listeners, but it could it could I have nothing against the context driven school
I just think it's entirely
Redundant perhaps perhaps
Yes
Anyway, what what was the topic of the cast talk? I was getting to that
I thought but anyway, the cool thing is that they they broadcast
Some of the talks all the talks. I don't know. I only got a chance to listen to one and not even all of it
I jumped in halfway through it was a woman
You wanna sermon
Don't know the name. I I followed her on Twitter because it was actually a good talk. I
The tweet I said about it
I'm gonna give the punchline then I'll get a little about the talk and then we can talk about that and then we can do something else
And then this will all get cut from the the non boring version
So the the last my punchline was it says I hear so much I can't from testers
and it was great to hear her message was just just ask and go do it and
It was and it was wrapped in some really cool nerd geek
Dungeons and Dragons role-playing game plus, you know plus 10 agility kind of you know
Things it made it a good talk. I thought it was very well done
but the point is beyond all the fun part that actually made the talk interesting as opposed to
95% of the talks I listened to receive is
The core message was very good. Also. It says look if you
You want the keys to the castle as a tester?
And you and I take it for granted that we can that we see source code we see
We can look at the the database is supporting our product in the background and see how they're
Put together and how the schemas work, etc. And a lot of touches go are very much
I'll be blunt here. They play the victim role. Well, we're not allowed to see the source code
If we see the source code, they think it'll mess it up and and I'm making the really windy voice here
But you get the point. Yeah, and she says screw that
If you want to see the source code ask to the source code they say no
Tell it ask them why not and say look I'm not gonna wreck it. Just give me read-only access
I want to know how things work
And say thing about you know the databases and deployment is well, you don't even know how to play more shows. Yes, I do
What if I want to make my own test environment for some really invasive destructive testing?
Whatever you want to do do it and the cool thing was is she and I'm gonna get this wrong on the details
Cuz I was kind of working while I was listening. Sorry
She did this eventually got the keys to the castle at her old job
It took like two years or some long just cuz she was new and learning and once you realize the keys to the castle
we're powerful being able to have you know access to everything as a tester and
To abstract as we do and and go off on tangents here
We've talked a lot about that that that it's what generalists do
We want to know a little bit about how everything works so we can know where to dive in
Right and it was good. It was so whenever I see somebody doing that
I really I get raw raw behind them
But she joined eBay a while back and took her about two and a half weeks to get the keys to the castle
Cuz she knew she needed him
But she knew how to ask and she had all the techniques for asking and and being persistent
So that was pretty cool. What exactly does the keys of castle here mean keys to the castle?
Oh, I mean escaping out of the metaphor. Oh
I'll leave the metaphor. I can make a little like Keith key motion with my hand
So keys of the castle are you have access to whatever you need to?
You know how to deploy to environments you can look at the databases you have access to source code
You know whatever else so what I met details you need to know that a lot of it is yeah
So respect maybe trust I think and you and I
Have seen this but it's a lot more prevalent at other companies
Especially smaller companies probably not as much as eBay where the testers are you're just you're not respected
You're the just you're you're on a different level than us because we're the ones writing code and making money for the company
You're just slowing us down
right
there's
That's the one thing that I was thinking of a lot of the times
and again, it's been a while since I've been in a test role, but
Every time I went to a new team, I would always find a large pocket of my new employees
who had firmly established themselves in a
Dysfunctional codependency relationship. Oh
Very similar to like domestic abuse. Have we talked about codependency on here before in testing because I bring it up. It's like I
Don't think we have actually
Maybe I tweeted somebody asked what do you mean codependency and testing once and I said well
Tell me if you've seen this
Developer says here's my code. Please test it for me tester says I found bugs in it
I feel validated because I did my job has to go. Thank you for finding my bugs. That was very nice to you
Please find some more. I found some more. I feel validated and this loop goes off like
God, give me a break
Yeah, but that loop also
Not only does the developer happy because he doesn't have to test his own code because he feels that as the burden
The tester is happy because hey, I did something useful
but that loop as it repeats over and over and over and over again, it
solidifies the perception that
test is non-technical or
test is
There was a comment I heard yesterday where one of my mentees went to a team and the and the head holy of that team
Didn't like tests. He's like I'm just gonna hire
High school interns to beat on the product right? It's it's viewed as
Something non-scientific. Yeah, and and that enablement
Just re solidifies that and once that role was in locked in
Yeah, it's the victimization of tests will persist. So let me
This is weird how?
This conversation comes to something that just happened yesterday
I wanted to share with you and just for context for people that have been paying attention to me because seriously, why would you?
I'm on a team
engineering team
Really no testers, but the asterisk I'll talk about in a second about 70 people. I'm in charge of quality
I we are not completely without testers. I have we have half a dozen vendors we use for testing
Mainly helping us get promoted to our dog food environment a lot of other tasks
They do have actually do a bunch of things. But one thing I did recently was
Yeah in the old days, you know, you had the one-to-one tester ratio here. Here's your tester great
I'll put them under my arm. Okay, wherever I go probably a Dilbert cartoon in there and if you look at what's the ratio here one to
12 am I so it's you your personal tester is
That's not the way we do it
We are testers do a bunch of different things and they do some really great testing as well
One thing I did just late last week was I figured out a map of feature areas to testers and dev managers
so I could kind of plug them into standups into
spec reviews and
Etc. Just a little bit as not as their tester but as their liaison
So that the tester the vendor tester that works for me
Will work with a feature team here
It'd be sort of a liaison and bring that information back to the other testers
Just so we could know when new features were coming in because we move very quickly and new features are coming in all the time
This is spy so it's it is the ease of communication
They're figured they were losing about 20 30 percent of their time of the day just tracking figure out how things are working
This is supposed to eliminate that make a little more connection one thing. I was worried about
Was will these dev managers now consider this person to be their tester code opinion?
So I got unlocked so yesterday
I got some mail and it was from one of our one of our DMS and
Said hey, I'll paraphrase here to protect the innocent because I didn't have a chance to sanitize
Say so-and-so is working on a major refactor over the course of this week and a bit of next
The plan is to phase check in the work to avoid a huge change set with a lot of aggressions good approach
And the question is can we get an affinitize tester to work with them and run through a set of scenarios?
I'm thinking oh
This sounds like they want yep
Yeah, yeah, so I
Very asked a clarifying. I asked a clarifying question. I did I said, what's the plan?
Are we gonna check are these in like a local branch or by check-in? Do you mean they're going to dog food, etc?
then I said
our tester can make sure there aren't huge regressions, but we really expect that you guys do the testing and
They're applied back with the answer that I have that that was okay with me
They said this is good. This means that things are there. They're figuring it out. Mm-hmm
Says we're already doing a bunch of testing internally including writing a lot of automation and we're doing manual tests from these are developers
They're doing manuals. I go. Okay
Yes
Now that the CDT guys are listening because they heard us like say that all testing is context-driven now
They're going oh man. It's not manual. It's it's something anyway. They're doing stuff. It's not automated. Whatever anyway
Said I still want to dedicate a tool with a good I'm paraphrasing here
So with a good st. E mine to do some exploratory testing and it's like, okay, that's that's a service we can provide
Brent making a little face
But it's like in war wait wait in Will Robinson warning
My and look the testers that that half a dozen then they they don't work for me
They work for a vendor company, but the they're very good at exploratory testing and I work with them on it
And they're very good and I didn't get the very important part. Can they do exploratory testing for an hour or so?
Not warning. That's actually I think that's a reasonable request and commitment. I think
That is like they've done all the work except put the little candle on top of the cake
and what I can do is like it we have a little candle on top of the cake is
These testers find a lot of really good bugs. So if they're if yeah, anyway, I think it's an opportunity there
Like in terms of you know, why I I set off the warning alarm. I thought you had gas. No. Oh
no
Right here you're you're in
You're on a walking a tightrope. You're on a
balancing
You're doing a balancing act and several other
appropriate metaphors I
Know you're aware of this you've done this enough and I know you won't let it cross a certain boundary line
But this is definitely a place where this snug they're gonna be snuggling up close to that
Boundary line. There's also an opportunity here though to
Sure
Sure, dude. I'll have my guy do
ETA
Making the exploratory test analysis
Xt ET
for an hour
under under one condition
Your two pests your two best test centric developers are with him in that room at the same time
In other words, it's an opportunity to teach that team how to fish
Absolutely. And one thing even short cutting that is we had one of the dev managers come to me last week
And say hey, we should do a bug bash
And I said hey, let's not
So but but they're great at finding bugs. I said we're good at finding bugs already said
so I have a different and
The bug bash is you know, everybody sits down and tries to find bugs and I've done those John Bach
I think he's once already about session based testing
Which I've been doing for actually years before he wrote about I just didn't actually have a good name for it
Let's do a bug bash but with a small number of people or
Set a small not a whole team and with a specific theme or charter in mind
Like we're gonna look at just this area, but I want to bring up session based testing because I don't have to explain
I think it's a better approach to the bug bash so people can go look it up. Whatever
What I'm going to do it's already planned is the part of this conversation was let's do a bug bash
No, it's not why not because
Lots of reasons
But what I wanted you is the bug bash isn't for me just about finding bugs
It's a lot about learning about testing and learning about the product. So instead of doing a bug bash the whole team
I will do a bug bash with a feature team
I'll take a group of developers and we'll sit in a room like Brent and I are sitting in right now and
We'll use that big screen and put the product up there above some laptop so can have some interaction etc. And
We will walk through testing and we'll test out loud. I've done this before on many teams. It's always very successful and
We will simultaneously
Find really cool bugs and teach everyone in the room how to be a better tester
Yes, same outcome same approach slightly different implementation what you're talking about. I was trying to think through because
When you said no bug bash like
This early I felt the same way
I'm like no bug bash evil and then I was trying to think through why did I feel that way number one, right?
It's generally. Yeah, you find a crapple of bugs. It's generally inefficient percent
Are the ones that matter it's generally inefficient to have a large team
And caveat if you're a small software company of six or seven people by all means all get together another bug bash
Yeah, but that's kind of my limit a scrum size a scrum team size is about the lip out the max limit
I want to get involved in a focused completely a session based testing bug bash, etc. But the the
the other reason why?
bug bashes bothered me is
because it's it's also a
Precursor to a stabilization period in my
Bashes and stable let's make the bug back by the bug list go up and then we'll yeah, I get it
I get it. Yeah, and it it I will feel equivalent. I'm drawing bug lines in the air. Yeah, and I'm wondering
Is there a way to fix bug bashes by instead of it being?
the focus on the bug bash
But it's a focus on
It's sort of a process bash. I would never call it this but
Because the bugs aren't the problem
the problem is
Something's wrong with how we delivered software that allowed the bug to get in
That's the value and maybe do the RCA
but as I sit here and reflect on the times I've done this sort of thing the
the sort of the focused bug bash is what I've called it before is
I'm actually usually more happy about the learning of
The people in the room that I am about the output of the bugs and we always find like one or two
Really cool ones. I did some of these in link and we had and you talk about the 2%
We would find like 30 bugs in an hour on a product that was pretty well done and and over half of them are things
We'd fix before we shipped. So it was pretty pretty high yield for that sort of activity
But regardless of that I didn't care about that metric at all
I cared like people were having fun and learning which is way cooler to me. Yeah, but you can do fun and learning without
enabling an old-school
See I see why a
freaking
Bug process that's the whole thing with the stabilization periods the whole thing with the bug bash like the the thing
I think is critical is the learning and in addition to getting people exposure to
The product like if you do the feature team
one thing that I think would be an interesting experiment is a bug a bug bash with the feature team on their own code and
That feature team on someone else's feature team code. Yeah, we should
all look in yeah, I have plenty of room to experiment, but we put it that way of
Figuring out why we miss this bug and improving that
Yeah, there's a lot to go here. It's and again. I don't want to rehash on our team totally, but one of the fun things is
just being part of this transition of
Teaching developers they can test and we spent a lot of time talking about last time talking about whether
Developers could test and they certainly can they've just a lot at Microsoft
Especially a lot of the developers never had to but some of them are actually really good at it
They never had to and when they've been here a long time
They they they realize that the prevailing belief is that's a lesser job. Well, it's a safety net
It's which winds back to actually what started this topic what sort of this topic this nice lady
Talking about the phrase I can't well. I know that was my paragraph. She didn't say that she never said I can't so
Let's not put words in her mouth. Okay, but the message that came out was she talked
She didn't talk about the negative side. She talked about everything
she was able to do because she asked and and the value it gave her and in my mind I I
Heard the opposite that all the times I see testers whining complain about well. I'm not allowed to do that
I can't do that. We don't do that here. We're not you know, I don't get to see this
Oh, though. We don't do that here drives me
batshit crazy
The one of the teams I was on
I've talked about this before there was a team that I was on when I started it I found out that
That
BBTs hadn't passed in six years
BBTs they have they had shipped three different releases in the city
BBTs hadn't passed a hundred percent in six years now. That was a problem. I was very interested in because
That's extremely rare. You don't normally I that's the only time in my career ever encountered that situation
But there was an element of complacency
That's that's the the culture in the org is that they just accept that
That's how things are done. They the team had long since given up
I eventually fixed that by analyzing it and realizing what they had done wrong they had put
In essence all of their in the instant areas in the BVT suite
Right the the suite
number of possible failure points
Was what they had placed into their BVT. Well, that's just stupid. It was a brilliant I
Thought I'm just they were like yeah
But if we can get them the pass and keep them stable then our quality will always be high and we'll move quality upstream
I'm like, yeah, but here's the deal you can't
I do want to move on a little bit, but it's interesting. I have one
Dev manager I work with is very much that side of the fence
He says why don't we just run all the tests as part of CI?
and I said well, that's
good
Well, you do them in phases and and do the simplest to debug first
Sure. Sure. I gave a talk a
Webinar as part of STP's does like these day-long
like series of
Webinar the webinar which is series of talks. I forgot I gave her like four or five years ago
I gave a talk on the simple powerful BVT
And the idea is the BVT the built the basic verification does build verification test is out
super short
But powerful set of tests just all this you know is is it worth investing any more time in this build? I
have I
Have that I've my principles on BVT's are twofold number one if it's
severely broken fail fast
Very similar to yours the second one though is there's there's a quality guarantee
And the thing I said is what I want in the BVT suite is that the BVT's give us an 80% confidence
That the next suite will pass
only 80% and not not
100% I don't that I don't want all of that crap in the BVT suite
But it's it's is it worthwhile running the next week?
Yeah, you can actually that's an easy one to just prove to yes did 80% of the time or more did we
Did the next set next round pass?
there's
To close off. I don't I have two more things
I want to say on our crap thing and then I'll close it I'll leave the room and come back when you're done
I'm gonna go quick first and foremost if you're ever
Feeling like you're a victim
This is this is something I tell all of my mentees when they come and go I can't or blah blah blah blah blah
Yeah, one of the things I think mentors responsibility is is to help the individual take back control of their own life
Okay, so the speech I use often you
You it is not a choice whether or not you're going to be victimized. That's the definition of victimization
But being a victim is a choice
Absolutely. So yeah, you got dealt a
bad hand
What you do with that hand is up to you now some people
They're happier
Having having the label victim they will of course if you confront them on this they won't agree with that
But if you look at their behavior, they go yes, this is now part of my identity. Okay fine
Nothing if that makes you happy, that's fine
Just stop talking to me about this topic because it's not something you want to change
the the second thing when it comes to
this this I can't stuff and in this dysfunctional circle of
Dev and test one of the things that I have always been very successful with
when I go to a new test team and some
some
Dev is trying to test me on this
Right the speech that I use very often and I make sure that my actions and my follow-up words line up with this
Dude
You're just writing code. It's not magic
Right. I turn it back. I'm like look dude
I'm actually the guy trying to figure out and make quality out of the system. You're just a freaking code monkey and
if you if you take
Maybe not as abrasive approach, but if you take that similar approach, you'll find that you converge towards something that's respectful
Very quickly
Sure, I'm done. All right, I'll cut that out of the boring part
so
One thing I wanted to cover I mean to bring us up for a while and we'll do it in about 10 minutes here at the
Most because well actually it's not we're not gonna fit it in because you're gonna go all rant crazy
So it's interesting that we brought up
CDT those folks are also very much against
certifications
not really get certifications in general I
Don't have a
Strong opinion because those don't really affect us here at Microsoft or even in the US that much
And there was a big thing about there's a I won't go into the hole the new testing standard
Which is just idiotic because it it just assumes that test endeavor completely separate completely separated
It says it starts there. It's like not going anywhere, but I I wanted to form my own opinion
So I went and grabbed a couple sample test questions from the Istq B
Okay, and the great thing is there multiple choice now
I thought I'd just give you a few Brent and see how you do and see how and I know you won't see this in
Podcasts lamp, but I want to see I will let you know how red
Brent's face turns and what kind of weird faces he makes as I asked the questions. So this is gonna anger me
I'm no these are legitimate questions. I grabbed these randomly. Oh, I got to do that one second. Okay
No, wait, I'm the context of this test is software testing. Yes. Software testing is the basic generic context
Yes is to get your base certification so you can get a job in a lot of places in Europe
Okay, the main focus of acceptance testing is a finding faults in the system be
Ensuring the system is acceptable to all users see
testing the system with other systems D
Testing for a business perspective or e testing by an independent test team. I'm gonna say B. Oh
so sorry
Apparently the main focus of acceptance testing is D testing for a business perspective
alright
We don't need to analyze because I
Let's go on to the next question. Oh, this is not gonna anger me
Greatly test managers should not a
report on deviations from the project plan B
Sign the system off for release
C
Reallocate resource to meet resources to meet original plans D raise incidents on faults
They have found or E provide information for risk analysis and quality improvement
I would say should not all of the above except e
No, apparently
Test managers should not reallocate resources to meet original plans
Friends making a constipated face
Wait, wait, I got another one
Ready what a bizarre?
How bizarre
At least one more
unreachable code would best be found using a code reviews
B code inspections see a coverage tool
D a test management tool or e a static analysis tool
What's the best way to find unreachable code? What the hell's the difference between a code inspection tool?
Say code inspection so a code review or a code inspection. Yeah, what's the difference between all the code inspections a formal inspection
Faking title inspection where you have a bunch of people in a room and you have like pre-work to do and then there's one person
Just takes notes and it's very formal process. Okay, so I'm gonna guess base off of what I view is the stupidest answer in the list
Clearly a test management tool should in to do this
Tell me that's right
Unfortunately code reviews apparently are
Although
They say the most effective
It's just all it says unreachable code would best be found using code reviews and I would say no that's wrong
Their answer is wrong. It's static analysis tools static. I'll stools are great
There's compiler some of the compiler warnings to find unreachable code
Yeah a code review like static analysis tool. I see I see unreachable so weight much better
To identify unreachable code code reviews I can I have
Seen unreachable code, you know that thing
I could you could find that in the code review certainly not guaranteed it depends on on I mean if the code is really friggin simple
Hey, dude, you have a method here that no one's calling
Okay, I have one more which is the punchline from this cut this should have come up last week
Ready? This is actually part of one other test question. And this is a certification. Yeah, you ready?
I'm finding a new thing that I agree with the CDT school
Decisions are stupid
Absolutely, right. What would by getting these right? I don't know what you'd prove that you were extremely lucky guessing stupid answers
No, let me put it this way would you hire someone that passed this?
All right one key reason why developers have difficulty testing their own work is a
The existence of a testing
What's the option of self-fulfilling be a self-duming prop prophecy once they realize that testers aren't I
Don't say aren't needed some little freak out, but aren't always needed but on you know, you know, I mean you listening
Maybe not Brent in the room does
Testers are not needed in the context that this thing's implying. It's like the guy the guy that wrote the article that we reefed on
Last time yeah ripped on last was reefed on mean anyway. He's runs a test consulting business. Of course is gonna say that anyway
What was the question one key reason why developers have difficulty testing their own work is a lack of technical documentation
B lack of test tools on the market for developers C lack of training or D
lack of objectivity, I know the answer that they want
You know the answer they want on this one is D, but the actual answer is C. You're absolutely right
Yeah, it's absolutely lack of training. It's this idea that oh you wrote the code you can't possibly test it is I said it last time
It's stupid. It's just really stupid testers. I'm gonna take a deep breath
It's funny it's on the test but you you gave the perfect answer so I want to fill in the blank
It's like I know you want the answer to be D, but it's C get over yourself
So going back to data science and and getting into that training right there is so much
literature on
Keeping yourself objective like because it is the there's a large series of biases that is
Very easy to get trapped in yeah, but only only testers know how to think learn biases
And hadn't thought about that that's that must be why I'm went into data science it's obvious next step
now it's
It's lack of training for sure and I would say there's probably even opportunity here like TDD
Very successful, but there's probably an opportunity here for someone in
graduates looking for their PhD in computer science and trying to think of what their thesis should be
how to formalize a listing of biases that devs go
that devs can get trapped in and the solutions and
The way to create discipline so that the devs can avoid those biases
Objectivity is a problem for sure
lots of
scientific
Disciplines have created means such that the individual can succeed and stay objective
Because they they acknowledge
That that can cause harm mm-hmm
But the issue here is sort of the industry years ago is taking the easy way out well the easiest way to be objective
Is to get someone else independent third party right the thing is
Test is never independent right it's a stupid mantle we put on our head
There's I can't tell you how many testers that I've seen
They get the same PM spec
That the devs get and that same PM spec
influences the
The same wrong assumption that dev implemented is the same wrong assumption that test is validating
Yep, right it
Anyway, I thought you'd like those. I'm so now I've now
Formed my own opinion
That last question isn't that that's that's the kicker you fail Brent. You cannot be a certified tester. Oh, uh
So it's funny that I
And to be fair I don't pay attention to all the rants against certifications. I
View them from afar. I see what's going on there
I haven't seen anybody list the absurdity of the questions before if you have I apologize if I've missed it
You know I'm sure somebody'll point me to something
But I've never actually looked at like sample test questions and pulled some out and and realize that oh my god
These really are really bad. I would actually if there's any of the three listeners
That's a hashtag one of the three right if if any of you guys
we we pretty much mocked every single one of these questions if you actually have a an
objective and logical reason why
We shouldn't have done that I'd love to hear it on
I think that I think the biggest reason for certifications is a lot of companies especially in Europe
I don't know of a ton in the US who require certifications as part of their for whatever reasons they
I wonder if companies that require certifications for employment actually know what's involved in certifications because like it like you're right
I don't think I want to hire someone who has one. I'm a little afraid of them
I'm actually thinking it would be interesting to sort of see the correlation of companies that
hire test teams that are primarily certified and companies that don't that are in similar industries and
to see if you can correlate
that certification either adding value or
detracting value
That would be interesting. I don't know if that exists in fact
That should be something that people that run is TQB and I've met Rex before he's a nice guy Rex black
who does a lot of this stuff and
but he's
He runs a lot of training programs to train people to pass the test and cetera
But I think really what I'd like to see him do is show that that data
Do you are these people people have certifications actually provide more value in the long run to the business to the yeah to the business?
Right because my fear is that these companies that that do fundamentally do the certification
Number one, they're gonna be slower my hypothesis. They're gonna be slower than their competition and
It's gonna cost them more
Yeah, all right. You know what? I think we're about done. We are there was something else I was gonna say crud
I don't know what it was though. Do you remember?
Sorry, all right. My memory is worse than yours
Whoa, whoa. All right. I'm Alan. I'm Brent. Hey, we got our names, right and we'll see you next time. Yep