Hello, everyone. Jesus Christ.
What the hell was that?
I am going to leave that out there just for you. Hey, everybody, I'm not Brent.
And I am not Alan.
And together we make A B testing as Alan Brent. Get it? Alan Brent,
for those of you that haven't figured it out.
Right.
Because we haven't really talked about experimentation A B testing, have we?
No.
So I was thinking on the way here we should have.
We should talk about that someday. But even more importantly,
maybe there should be like an A B tester persona. It's just like a total dick and
gets on the Internet and says funny things. No, maybe not.
Sure. Oh, speak.
I'm like, why do we need the persona? We have the two of us.
Right. We have two of us already. Hey, I don't know if you follow the the
Swift on security on Twitter. No.
Oh, it's hilarious. There's somebody with way too much free time and way too much
computer knowledge tweeting as Taylor Swift as an I.T. and security specialist.
They are great.
How do they do it as Taylor Swift? Like song quotes or something?
Sometimes. Sometimes lyrics rewritten.
I mean, it's really easy to impersonate any celebrity on Twitter.
Absolutely. No. And she is really adamant about saying this is not a parody account.
I am Taylor Swift.
And I care about security and software in general. And there's this underlying theme in all of
her posts about end of times due to computer computers taking over the world.
Yes. As as we continue with the data science stuff, one of the things that I often tell my team
is we need to treat this very carefully so that our robot masters look look back upon us fondly.
Exactly. Anyway, just thought that thought I'd bring that.
Oh, and speaking of which, like HoloLens. Oh, yeah.
Sign up. Have you tested that yet? No, I'm I'm I signed up to go do that.
Check it out. I am. Thursday, I think.
That's going to be cool. The only thing I mean, obviously, we can't speculate too much, but
I just hope the price point isn't too outrageous because it's going to be pretty cool.
I don't know. But you know, there's nothing like that out there.
I have to hide it from my kids because they find out Minecraft is available.
Oh, I already showed my kids. My kids were like, you're doing really.
You do. And so so Alan and I have friends.
We have to buy three pair. Alan and I have the friends that work in that that group.
We do. And I sent one of them a mail after I'd looked at the YouTube marketing PR piece.
And I said, dude, does this thing even do half of what is on this video?
And he's like, Brett, it does it all. And I'm like, done done done.
And then he said, this thing is absolutely going to change the world. And if it if it
does do anything close to that, I think it absolutely will.
Yeah, I think it's just like when the first PCs came out, I think, you know, my hunch is and again,
don't go Murray Joe Foley quote me. My hunch is the price point is going to be a little high
at first, just like PCs were at first. Like 3D printers.
Like 3D printers. Yeah. I read somewhere that as we go off on our 80D tangents,
I read somewhere that the primary output from 3D printers are parts to fix your 3D printer.
Is that correct? I haven't actually.
There's a friend, another friend of ours. I don't know if you know Matt, Matt F.
No, I don't. He's really cool. You work with them on the Xbox team. He's over on that team.
And he has three 3D printers. So I asked him, so did you use the first one to print the next two?
But no, no, he's just really into the technology. And I haven't played with that. I really,
really want to. My son has actually gone through a class last year.
What was basically a whole semester long just on 3D printing. He actually taught the instructor.
It was a brand new class and the instructor was like, I don't know. Here's the manual.
Good. We value people that can figure things out. Hey, just for the heck of it,
do you want to talk about software? Sure. Or people or something like relevant to our
limited audience? Our topic. We don't have topics, come on.
So the one thing... We have three words in two bullet points. Actually, there's three
bullet points, one of them is blank. And we have three words in the backlog today.
Yeah. Let's start with whatever your first
thing is that you wouldn't tell me about. Yeah. So Alan doesn't do this, but I do. So
on my blog, I often go in and I check the stats. I'm very interested in
where people are coming from. It's the primary...
Like country or attitude? Website.
What folks are linking to... I think my number one referring site is Twitter.
But you know what's fun for me? Twitter and Facebook.
Nah, I don't do anything on Facebook. I'm thinking of just deleting my account. I never
go there. I go there once in a while just to snark. And to look at what losers all my
friends from high school are. Sorry if you're listening. Sorry. Not you, the other people.
Yeah, not you. Yeah. And then this link showed up just this week. I went back to see
how people were linking to my site. And I found that the folks over at testbuffet.com
have put together the top testing blog sites for 2014. And my dear partner is number 10 on that list.
He's looking at it now. I'm so excited. I brought it up. I brought up testbuffet.com.
Which you know, these lists, I don't know how they come... I mean, they're kind of ridiculous, right?
He actually has a criteria, although the criteria is essentially says things about testing.
And well, cool. Sadly, I should actually blog about testing.
Actually, so I'm ranked 76 in that list. You're on the list.
I am on the list. He believes, I think he said that there's a total of like 200 testing blogs
that he was able to find. And it was interesting. You just made a snarky comment about, hey,
maybe I should blog about testing sometimes. What me, snark? Never. And it's interesting.
And we also talked about A-B testing. And I'm starting to view not only the podcast,
but definitely my blog as beginning to shift away from the testing concept and much more towards
the quality concept. Yeah, mine has too, if you haven't noticed. And yeah, we've talked about this
before, so I'll shut up there. Yeah, I think it's a natural progression as sort of we and
the industry kind of change how we make quality software. I can pretty much guarantee I will blog
more about testing. So then what? Testing activities. What? You said you'll blog more.
That means you have at least one more testing blog. Yeah, there are lots of testing activities
that go into what I do, what my team's doing, what I care about. I am giving, did I tell you I'm going
to Star Canada? No, I didn't even know there was such a thing. Yeah, there's a Star Canada. This year,
it's in Vancouver. Oh, when? June, middle of June. Interesting. So check it out. I'm going to give
Lee, Lee asked if I give a keynote there. So and he saw my post, my last post about
how I test software at Microsoft and how we've changed a lot. He goes, I think it'd be
interesting to talk about some of the big changes that have happened over those six or seven years.
So I'm going to do that. It's going to be fun. And then he also asked if I would do a tutorial.
I thought, no, I don't want to do a tutorial because I don't really want to talk about.
I do want to talk about some stuff. So there's a lot of that. And I couldn't figure out what
to talk about. So this was my thought process over a week. I'll rolled into 20 seconds for you or
the way I ramble 10 minutes. So you are going to do a tutorial? Yes, I am. Would you shut up
and I'll tell you, please do. So I was thinking, well, I could talk about that. I look at the
tutorials and I go, you know, I don't want to give a tutorial like these. I want to,
and I really valued the generalist, you know, and being able to have a toolbox of things and cool
things you can do. And I said, heck yeah, that's what I'm going to give a tutorial on.
And I am going to fly through stuff. You don't know that you should know for a tester. I'm
going to go through probably 45 minutes to an hour on security testing. I'm going to go through
some ideas on performance testing and then also a little bit of statistics because you can't really
do perf testing without understanding how to apply mean, median, average, and a few other sorts of
analysis beyond there to figure out what's really going on. So I'll get to put a little bit of,
I'm not going to be so bold as to call it data sciencey stuff, but a little bit of statistics
for testers, things testers should know about how variant. Interesting. So again,
a little hodgepodge data enhanced testing. I don't, don't, don't worry about it because I don't
like your words. So anyway, I thought I could easily feel I'll do like a half day thing and
it'll give me room to be flexible because I, for tutorials, I've had to be with you for four hours.
I really can't can exactly what I'm going to say, but I'm going to give myself some rails to go on.
I'm going to make sure I talk about these things and about this much time on each thing. And if we
go off on some tangents, great. But the goal of people walk out of there going, you know,
not knowing one thing pretty deeply, like you get in a typical tutorial, but walk out of there
going, wow, I have like five things I can go do on my team and, and provide some value. And then
as I get more interested, maybe there are things I want to dive deeper on and become that,
that specialist in that area. That's my goal. So Lee said it sounded great. I think I'm doing it.
Unless something better comes along for Lee and then he'll go, Alan, you're out.
I think it's a good idea. I'm, I'm thinking through. So Alan's done these type of things in
the past. A lot of times his testing tutorials. I've done a lot of dark things in my past.
I've never actually attended any of the stars. So I've never experienced the,
or done the Alan Page testing experience. Oh, the Alan. Yeah. It's actually going to be a
ride at Disneyland. I'd like to announce, no, sorry, Disneyland is copyrighted. I can't say that
probably, but go on. But yeah, I should do, I should not say the thing I just said. Quit my job
and do a tour. Like I'll go, I'll go to every city in the world and get it like a hotel room.
That fits like six people. And we'll call it the Alan Page testing experience.
I can't fill an arena. I can't fill a conference room, but you could probably fill a bathroom in
most hotels. Probably fill a motel six. Yeah. Yeah. Let not the whole motel. Like, you know,
a room, right? Small room. Well, I'll put the PowerPoint on the TV and I'll, I don't know.
How do we get here? Test buffet. No, no, I'm not done on the other one. We didn't know where we
are. I did. Although, no. Yeah. Yeah. So it's, it's interesting that you're, so his typical,
Alan's typical tutorial, as I understand them, were in the past, much more related to a pure testing
discipline. And I would say in a nutshell, it was kind of like testing one on one. No,
the only, actually, I had to think here's how to, the only tutorials I've done at a star before
have been the, I did two Alan page on testing, AKA the Alan page testing experience. And I,
what did I do for those? I, well, the first one, here's what I did. The first one,
I just did total, uh, lean, lean coffee style. I took a bunch of quite, what do you guys want
to talk about? To that for about 10 minutes, took a whole bunch of questions. I gave them a
five minute break. Why organize them into buckets? And then that's what I talked about. Then I got a
bunch of some feedback said this was great. And I love those people and you gotta take the good with
the bad. And I don't, you know, I don't, I read all the feedback and don't get too high for the
highs or low for the lows. But some people said, didn't really have any structure and he didn't
follow the slides. I thought, okay. So then I had to do this. I did the same thing. I can't
remember which one was first. I think I did it at star East first. And then I agreed to do two
in a row. So I did it at star West the next year. But what I did then was they can tester testing
audiences. Don't really change. So I looked at my groups of questions for what I did at star East.
And I made up some slides that kind of aligned that. And then you, you group the questions
and made up slides in five minutes. No, no, no. So I, I went through the thing at star East is
done. I look at the feedback. It says, some people say, great. Some people say no structure.
So before star West, I had six months. I used the output of how the star East presentation
went to kind of make structure and slides for those that like those things. And then I did
the same thing where I asked a bunch of questions at the beginning, grouped them. And I said, okay,
I think I covered that in my presentation. And I went through my slides and we talked about that
stuff worked out very well. Oh, interesting. It was the exact same presentation. I just,
I just cheated a little bit and use the data driven presentation. I use the data,
the feedback data from my star East presentation to manipulate the audience and to think I was
magically prepared for their questions for star West. So you did that. And there was a lot of
ad lib in there because I can, as you can tell from the babbling going on in this room,
I can sit and talk about a subject and usually more interesting than then because the audience
honestly is usually more interesting than Brent, but we do our best. Anyway, it was, it was fun.
So if I had, I am not doing that sort of thing. I'm actually preparing a full, a full new sort of
smorgasbord, which is like a buffet. I'm going to call it a buffet. I'm preparing, preparing a
buffet of cool tools for testers, not just like tool tools, but you're like, you know,
here's what a, here's how to do SQL injection. Here's that. Here's how to get a free book from
your mom and pop website, that kind of stuff. So tools and techniques. Yeah. Anyway,
star, how did we get there? Well, I don't know. We rewind a little bit.
Sprinkling, sprinkling in data stuff.
Figure out what you're talking about. Yeah, some data stuff. Yeah.
Um, wow. Uh, a little plug there. It might be interesting. So let's, let's, let's sync up.
I don't know if, if, if this is something that's viable, but, um, do you think there
would be some advantage in doing a podcast up there? Uh, why are you thinking of going up?
It's not that far of a drive and I have six months to plan. Uh, yeah, yeah, definitely. I,
in fact, even if you're not there, I'd be, if any listeners are going there and
Brent can't make it, or even if you can, maybe we should just, uh, yeah, we should think about that.
And I'm thinking, sorry, my head is going three different directions as usually does,
but yeah, if you're there, we should do a podcast right there in the fricking lobby.
And, uh, cause I'm not going to your hotel room. And that is not where the Alan Page
testing experience happens, but it'd be fun to, uh, if somebody wanted to get on the show,
get a little plug their own stuff, talk about what's going on, ask us some questions and
see what kind of, I know it seems like an obvious place for a mailbag.
Oh yes. Mailbag for the mailbag. Anyway, guys, we will, uh, that that's an interesting possibility.
We, we will work those details and, and, and, uh, get back to you. You want to go on to topic?
Two. No, no. Um, you got me thinking about how you bring people to your sites. I brought up my stats
and yesterday there were three search terms that brought people to my website. Those were,
and this is that we're not going to talk about these. One is dichotomous key for dummies.
I don't even know what that means. Alan Page testing. I think they knew what they were looking
for. And then I'm not sure if I helped with this or not, but the search for false negative
app Microsoft job interview. Uh, I don't know how to look, I don't know how to look back farther.
Otherwise I'd look for some really cool ones. Click that link. Because once in a while,
as you guys with blogs know, uh, you get some just awesome, uh, search terms. I'm gonna look
over 30 days and then we're going to get back onto the next topic only because this is fun
and I, this is totally unprepared. I don't know what to see. Um, I'm going to skip the ones
that seem obvious. I'm a thank you for all you that search for Alan page testing because you're
finding my blog apparently. Um, somebody searched for Alan in parentheses, the weasel.
That's funny. I do that search tear down the wall. Hillsong United. Probably not what they're
looking for. Hey, Brent, someone looked for Brent Microsoft blog testing and found me.
Sorry about that. I stole one of your searches. They probably found me through you. All right.
Anyway, nothing, nothing too weird in there. Once in a while you get a really crazy one, but, uh,
I don't really see any trippy ones to share. In fact, I should probably do this offline and
find the good ones and, and then actually I'll be a board. I'll never do it again. All right.
The, the referrals, the, the referrer sites is the one I find the most fascinating. Yeah.
I don't really have time for any of it to be fascinating. Um,
when will the 2013, 2014 Australia pool finish and they got to my site? I'm hoping they used
Google for that one because if being brought me there, that's that's I gotta talk to the, yeah.
Okay. I'm closing that site. Let's move on. Test stuff. Oh, one more thing about test buffet.
That's interesting. That list is there. I got some mail from the guys over at appletools
at what appletools. Yeah. They, um, they had game, Apple L tools, no APP, Li tools. Okay.
They make a pretty cool. It's I'm not a big fan of record playback, but there's,
it's actually pretty good for, for what it is. I got, I got a demo online. I thought it was,
it's pretty neat. It was, if I was ever into that stuff, I would use that. It has some interesting,
uh, uh, features that, that gets rid of a lot of the things I hate about recording playback.
Although it's still recording playback. Are you talking about recording playback
automation? Yeah. Okay. So anyway, they are, uh, they're going to publish a blog post with a list of
the top. And this is the guy that wrote a book, um, sort of, well, I didn't, I made a book from
a series of blog posts about, you know, all the things wrong with automation kind of yet they're
on February 18th, they're going to publish a blog post with a list of the top 15 thought leaders
and test automation. And they're one that was okay if they could include me on that list,
but it's okay to include you. And I want to say, well, it depends who else is on the list,
but no, I'm going to let it go. And what's my ranking?
Well, I hope they go alphabetical by first name. I know. I, I bought one of those books and I
advertised it on my, um, on my, uh, blog post. All right. So can we move on? Yes. Let's move on.
Now, is this a male bank item? No. Okay. Then I won't do the song for you. No reverb this week.
Yeah. We didn't do our research this morning. Sorry guys. We Brent, this has been carefully
researched. I spent six hours last night and researching this and probably 28 hours the day
before putting in the preparation and research for this show. So don't, don't, no, there was,
don't try and sandbag and let them, then let them think that we are not ultimately prepared
for everything we do. So the next, the next topic item on, on the list today, uh,
I actually think did come from mail bag, but I no longer remember enough of the email to really,
give the person the right credit and, and move forward. The topic. So it's kind of
related to, uh, my most recent blog posts. That's, that's how I'm thinking of it. Um,
we've gone through a transition around getting to combine engineering where by no means done.
But combined engineering and most of that concept is, is viewed as incorporating test into the
development practice. Um, we're also on the way of flattening the org. Um, yay. I was, uh, at a meetup
last week at, um, an external company and it seems they're kind of following the same practice.
I don't know if they're taking their, their leadership from, from Microsoft or if it's
just a phenomenon that's actually starting to go everywhere. Yeah. I, yeah, I, I've seen it
everywhere. So I don't know if I don't, I really don't think they're following Microsoft, uh,
because it's happening. I know. It's an area where Microsoft's really following a lot of other
companies. So if they're really weird to say, it's, it's, it's kind of circular. I know up here
in the Seattle area, a lot of the companies, for example, Amazon, um, they took our review
process from 15 years ago and that's what they do. Yeah, that's too bad. It is. And yet they still
managed to succeed. So way to go Amazon. Um, the, depends on your, what's your def? Well,
I was going to say, it depends on your definition of success. I don't want to go off on an Amazon
tangent forever. So, uh, I'll let you finish. Oh, by the way, I'm not going to let you finish.
Um, as you know, I really don't like the term combined engineering. I do know that,
but I hear teams use the word, the phrase unified engineering, which doesn't grate on me as much.
Just FYI go on. Okay. Anyway, in all of these transitions, um, PM has essentially been left
untouched. And PM is program management at Microsoft. We call them program managers,
which is funny because they don't often program and they don't often manage.
They're very rarely managers in general. Uh, from my experience, you'll see, uh,
PM supporting an engineering team roughly at the rate of, um, two to three PMs per manager of an
engineering team. So the PMs themselves are often viewed as having the same sort of scope of
influence as a, as a manager of an engineering team. Um, but they are not managers. So let's
talk about, um, just for context for people that don't work at Microsoft, sort of maybe the
traditional role of a PM at Microsoft. What do you, what, what if PMs, what do they do traditionally,
not now as we transitioned, but traditionally what's their role? Uh, I've seen PMs go into two
distinct phases. When I first started here, the first decade, I would say they were highly
technical. Um, it was very common for the PMs to own, for example, the API definition,
uh, documenting the requirements and then handing off to, uh, engineering to execute those.
That's very waterfowlish.
It was, but that's what it was 10 years ago. Nowadays, I actually, most of the PMs are,
there's a PM, a GPM I worked with, um, years ago that he described PMs as essentially the guys
who do all the crap that engineering doesn't want to do.
And that's a bad definition. It is, but it's not, I mean, it's not an honorable definition,
but it's not inappropriate. What you see PMs nowadays mostly are doing scheduled driving,
um, uh, setting up meetings, owning communications, but the technical aspects,
uh, not as strong as they were the first decade.
That's not entirely true. That may be a little bit of sample bias. Look it up.
Maybe on your part because, um, uh, Birkin's book, which has since been renamed, but Scott Birkin
used to work at Microsoft. He wrote a book called the art of project management,
which was modeled a lot after what PMs are doing then. He left Microsoft at least 10 years ago,
if not 15. So what's your, so what's your subjective bias on this?
By the way, I don't care what your role is. If you care about, you know, any sort of influence or how
to, uh, make things happen. Actually, the book has been retitled as it's called, it's called
making things happen now. Okay. It's the same book with a little bit of edits and things,
but it's a great book on how to manage a project, whether it's a scrum team or a, or a virtual
team, Brent, um, or any sort of thing we have to organize people and get them to work together.
So I think for a long time, um, and PM sort of a catch off people that aren't,
you know, diving in the code every day sometimes. So, but I think for a long time, some PMs, uh,
their job has been to make sure to manage communication between dev and test and
customer and marketing, et cetera, the liaison, uh, schedules, yep. Uh, getting, making sure
the right people are in a room when you need to get, when you need to have a discussion in
a room to figure something out, um, sort of all that sort of overhead that helps the team
work together to make software. And you can see where that's leading, right? That that's the,
that's the positive, positive spin on what I just said. So I don't disagree.
Don't be a negative Nancy. So let me go ahead and I led there. So I'm going to start and let
you jump in, but you can see if that's been the traditional role of program management,
what that kind of means now, because if we have a unified engineering team and again,
there are generalizing specialists, not everybody's doing the same thing. There are people that are
doing more testing than more testing activities, then development activities. So that we're doing
more development activities and testing activities, but the right thing happens and they have
the right standups for communication. So they know what's going on. They know what the
roadblocks are between them. A lot of those traditional program management jobs are now
handled by the team. There's no reason to be a liaison between dev and test. Cause there is no
dev and test as an engineering team. Yep. As far as schedule goes, teams are working off back,
prioritizing backlogs and you may need somewhat a traditional program manager to help, you know,
either to be the product owner or to handle with the organization of, of grooming the product
backlog, some things like that. Sometimes the team may handle that a traditional PM.
It's often a very good role for them, but you certainly don't need as many, I think.
You don't. And even on the, the backlog grooming, I think initially you'll see
PMs take on the PO role, but as we see the data coming in and as we ship more frequently, and
Alan is messing with my mic. Yeah. I like how Brent like puts the mic in front of him that
looks at me and talks. It's really creative. Okay. They talk like people talking out the
side of their mouth, but it's really not possible. The trying to put myself out of the weeds.
So PMs will take on the PO role for, for due to prioritization, but as people get more
accustomed of doing MVPs, continuous deployment, as well as light up a solid feedback stream
from the telemetry. I even think we'll see PMs as the PO role kind of disappearing. It's not
necessarily going to be about what are the next tweaks that we need to enhance. Right.
What about that?
I think the agent itself will be able to optimize the current local product. The thing I think that
we'll be missing, actually, what do you think we'll be missing? What will be the role?
Let's imagine the world where the dev team has communication, collaboration has gone up. They've
actually gotten accustomed to a lack of command and control. So they're doing what's right versus
what management tells them to do. Hopefully those two are aligned, much more empowered.
There'll be some weakness in terms of like cross team dependencies.
That's exactly where I was going. I think a couple of gaps, when I was thinking of going,
the obvious gaps to me are everybody talks about scaling agile and there's things like
safe, which are, Brent's gone through training on that.
I am the first certified safe professional for Microsoft.
That's great.
It's cool.
But whether you use safe or not or something, I think there's a big challenge. We have companies
as huge as Microsoft and product teams. I tell people, I work on a relatively small
team at Microsoft. It's 200 people. I think there is definitely room for people to make sure
coordination happens, especially around dependencies between teams working together
to make those things happen. That's a great role for that big systems thinker P and make
sure the right pieces are happening and getting that communication going.
I think we don't really have very many technical assistance at Microsoft anymore. Definitely not
at levels lower than some of the VPs or presidents.
I'm not certain. I'm not used to that title.
We've had technical assistance in the past. Bill Gates used to have a couple.
I was in engineering excellence. I interviewed three different teams. Basically what they did
was they made sure that any time there was any sort of roll up to executives, that their job
did not waste executives' time was to go talk with each of the teams that was presenting and
making sure they had their ducks in a row. Last time he gave you feedback that said,
do A, B, and C. Let's make sure you get those done before you come back. Otherwise,
it's going to get mad. That grooming there. I think that sort of role is obviously valuable
for an executive, but even as you're communicating up the chain, sort of that person to coordinate,
the coordinator of coordinators almost. I was just thinking about TAs yesterday and how
one of the VPs in my chain, actually the only VP in my chain, now I've given that away,
could sure use that because there's a lot of chaos, I think, in what he hears from his team.
Someone needs to kind of organize that. Then I was thinking as you were talking there,
that sort of role, and really these are all coordinator roles I'm talking about,
or sort of the future of PM, but that's something that needs to happen. I guess that needs to happen
today, let alone in the future, but I do see a lot of value in people that can do that.
That's not typically someone who's come up through development or testing. You need somebody who
this that can figure out, get to the crux of the issue, ask the right question, get the right people
in the room, and get the right conversations happening, so as to not waste people's time.
I agree with that. The other thing that I thought you were going to go to is a role I foresee in
the future for program management. So now we have all these sort of disjoint teams,
empowered teams. Command and control isn't really as strong as it is today.
One of the principles around empowering a small team is you basically are trying to push
decision making down to the people who have the best information available.
Yes. Let's pause there, because that's important.
It is.
We both know leaders who insist on being involved in decisions way below where they should be.
I believe that decisions can be made as close to the product as possible.
That was a repeat. Go on.
If you have these empowered teams and you have little tribes in a large org,
let's imagine you're a 200 person org, it's somehow split into 18 to 20
little teams of 10 or maybe even 10 teams of 20.
So the coordination becomes critical, but if you do it in the command and control
model, that's going to be less than optimal. You want to empower these guys.
So how do you do that? I actually think it's the PM role that will fill in that blank.
More from a business aspect, as you just got through saying, one of the biggest
things that ends up being lacking is where to go next, how to take our current assets and
build a better business. I actually think that's where PM is going to end up going.
Business focused.
More business focused. And then I believe that we still need coordination,
but at a much higher level than the providing today.
And I think we'll have a couple of coordinators. I think that's probably where
the release manager type role will probably migrate.
Yeah, I think there's other things too. I think there's a definite skill there.
There is a talent.
It almost goes back to that, I don't want to say project management, but I'm reflecting on,
I've read making things happen a couple times now, probably three or four times actually,
because it's actually it's really good, even if you're not a PM. And some of those things,
I should go highlight which chapters I think are really relevant in the future,
because some of those those core issues are going to be important in the future of PM at Microsoft.
I agree. Do you agree with my point in terms of these guys being the business owners?
Yeah, but as much as I hate to agree with you, yeah, I think that's important.
I think I agree with that.
But in a different aspect, I don't think these are going to be the guys
that are triaging bugs.
No, I don't want them there.
They are going to be the guys.
Too many people in the room already.
Looking at the market, looking at our current technical assets and saying,
hey, I think there's an opportunity here.
Let's let's call cobble up an experiment or a prototype release it out to that market and see
what comes back.
Now, let me ask you, with the current PMs in our in our organization,
I don't want to answer this question.
How many how many of them do you think are going to make either of these two bars that we just laid out?
So I don't I don't think any PMs listen to our podcast.
No, no, we're just.
And actually, I don't think any PMs at Microsoft listen to any tech or software podcasts.
But here's one email me if I'm wrong.
No, here's one thing to be aware of, though.
Shinsung, yeah, took my blog post about PM and sent it to the Yammer group PMs at Microsoft.
That's oh, I have to go look at that group.
Yammer, the big echo chamber of Microsoft.
Yeah.
I thought about this before.
I think there's a couple of factors.
Hold on.
So I understand why you're cautious.
I'm not.
But think of it as we care about our brothers in the PM org.
And this is how we can help differentiate those who actually listen to us to be in the right place.
So this is what I would say to anyone, you know,
in PM or thinking at PM.
So I'm not going to be too cautious.
I think it's I'm going to be frank.
Definitely.
We're going to need fewer PMs in the future than we have now.
For sure.
That that I think that's a given.
If you disagree with that, please think again.
I think of the current PM population.
Just to be clear, I actually think it'll be much fewer.
So of the current population, there are a chunk.
We do have some that would work fit in just fine on an engineering team
doing some of the design stuff, some of the, you know, as a regular software engineer,
not a P.O., but just jump right in.
We have some of those around.
We have some PMs.
We have a PM on our team who's fantastic at data science stuff.
So I'll put it, you know, that's that would fit right on the engineering team.
Yeah.
They've other PMs.
I don't know what percentage.
We have some PMs who get that business focus.
A lot aren't though, as I think through, I'm just thinking through not just my current team,
but the PMs I've worked with over the last five years or so.
And a lot of them are feature focused.
Feature focus.
Gantt chart monkeys.
Yeah.
So boy, boy, I think, I think a small chunk can fit in.
Another small chunk will adapt to the changing role of what PMs will do at Microsoft.
And then that other chunk, I'm a little lost.
I don't, you know, I don't want to say fear for your, necessarily say fear for your job or anything,
but I'll put it this way instead.
If you're a PM and you don't, you don't get what your role would be as a coordinator
among agile teams, or you don't get, or you're not interested in relating what your team is doing
to the world and having a business strategy.
Or I guess that's it.
If you're not on board with those things, or if you don't think that your skills transfer to
what engineering teams are doing or will be doing in the short term,
those are skills you're going to want to ramp up on in order to continue to be valuable at Microsoft.
Yeah.
That there's one other aspect that I've noticed in a couple of teams, and I wonder if this will
turn into a tipping point and have it be common.
I see design teams, which have generally been rather small at the company, beginning to strengthen
and bolster.
And I wonder if we'll see many more people shifting over to the design aspect.
And in CPMs.
I just thought of something else when you said design is that one reason to keep a few more
PMs in one other role there is I would really like to go ape shit crazy on experimentation
across our entire product lines.
There's our reference to AB testing, but I think that's a great thing for PMs to figure out,
to design and drive and figure out, okay, we're going to do this treatment and this treatment
is what we're going to expect from that.
And then people can do the work.
I don't think your typical dev and test are great at figuring out what those treatments
are for an experiment.
That's something, that's a great role that someone needs to do.
And I want to go just like I said, just crazy trying things out.
I love experiments.
I love them, love them, love them.
We should definitely use some of our resources to invest in that in the future.
In my team, I've been very deeply engaged with my design team on this same space.
They're all about hypothesis testing.
They generate a series of different hypotheses and a different set of experiments.
And there's actually two problems.
Number one, the technical assets aren't there yet.
And partially, a lot of orgs are having challenges towards shifting up and building those technical
assets to light up experimentation.
And the other thing too is they have a sense that there are so many hypotheses that are
important for them to test and generate that they even are short on people in terms of
thinking through these aspects.
So they're not able to scale from a people front and from a technical front.
But they have the process aligned of what they want to execute on.
Yeah, and I wonder, and this is a good topic to ponder, but I talked about PMs,
but really for anyone, you need to look at where engine, it's pretty easy if you're
at Microsoft or whatever company you're at.
How are we doing engineering today?
And predicting the future is hard, but you have an idea what it's going to look like maybe
six months or a year, what direction we're going in.
And am I, you think to yourself, how valuable are my skills going to be in that model?
And either if you're lacking things, great opportunity to learn.
Yep.
This is really true for anyone.
You need to be adapt, I think to be successful in software or actually to be successful in any
knowledge work, you need to be adaptable and willing to learn new things.
Yeah, there's only, so you just said they need to look at what direction they're going.
I'm going to clarify that because I don't think it's the direction that matters as much,
but the goal that we're trying to achieve.
And we've talked about this over and over again.
The goal is amping up the speed to building a solid stable business.
And I think PMs can play a very valuable role there, but they need to understand that's the goal
and make sure that their direction is intended when that goal is achievable,
that they're already prepared.
Right?
The, I think one of the competition is we're going to find, so I've gone back to school,
I know that academia is actually teaching kids this sort of skill set.
So there's a lot of college hires coming in.
They're going to be already 50% the way there.
Yeah, be cool.
Yeah.
All right, man, we're out of time.
We are.
So I'm still Alan.
I am Brent as well.
All right.
And this was, by the way, episode 17.
Yeah, prime number.
We're very good.
Woo hoo.
All right.
Thanks, guys.
See you later.
Bye.