Hey everybody. Hello. I'm Alan and I'm not
Because how could you be what I'm Alan that's Brent Brent is looking as beautiful as ever
That's sitting next to me here in the room in studio a Microsoft main campus. We're in a different room today
We are cuz I it's it's only vaguely
Disturbing because we normally meet at 8 and 8 was too early for me today
So today today, we're meeting at 9, you know, we have an Audi and oh by the way
I'm gonna get back to that story. This is a B testing episode number 18
So if you're listening to the wrong podcast now is the time to pause this and and switch to the one you meant to listen to
No, no, no, this is a better podcast than the one you were planning
Okay, so
We have an Audi and
Audi apparently is in translated English means every repair is frickin expensive
Is that the acronym like I think so I have to figure it out. I'm sure all
Let me just give you an example
Just so happened both of our cars a Toyota and an Audi both needed service this week
Audi needed it. Sorry this the Prius needed its
95,000 mile
maintenance
Go in there. They check it all out do everything. I'm out of there for 40 bucks
Nice
The basic maintenance on the Audi starts around to something
Yeah, and that's just like to change a gasket right that that's like okay
It's gonna be a hundred to open the hood because need a specialist for that
It's a great car, but man man when it needs work done it
Hurts. So anyway, I'm a huge fan of so I had to leave it overnight because they had to clean the carbon out of something
Fuel injector sure sure whatever
Anyway, so I had to get a ride to work so I couldn't get here by 8 so I'm here now and that is a long intro
You know I had I've been experimenting with playing with a bunch of different podcast
Players, I finally found like one
I like I need like a really simple podcast player most ones I've looked at are like super complex with all kinds of features, etc
Too much too much. I'm sure if I listen to podcasts all day the kitchen sink podcast player would be great
But I wanted one that was simple, but there was one that I used for a while
until it pissed me off where it an option to
Skip like the first n number of seconds or minutes of any podcast
so if you know that a particular podcast doesn't get good tell say the
Third or minute or the lake or the 30th minute. You can just like set it up. See you skip all that
Testing and software and quality stuff
I think yeah, I I have a feeling I have a hunch
I have an inkling of an idea that Brent has a bit of an announcement to make
What do you think about that?
Yeah, and and the fact that it's written up on the can bend board certainly helps a great deal
Look you are breaking the third wall of podcasting
Talk about your little now what happens in the podcast stays in the podcast apparently
No, so I'm very happy to announce
This is the the first place I'm doing in a public forum
I'll probably be writing the blog post the obligatory blog post on it over the weekend
But I have a new job
Today's will be cleaning
bathrooms in the studios
No, if I go on sorry if they're willing to pay my salary to do that
No, they would
They'd still have to pay me more
The
As an aside
The because we never do a side. Yes. Yeah, the the you know the
The in California that which is that that's my home state the guys who hold the signs
That say slow and stop. Do you know how much?
They got paid 20 years ago 20 years ago. Did you do that job 20 years ago?
No, how much do they get paid 20 years ago?
$50 an hour
Should just flip song. I have an announcement to make I will be resigned
Yeah, and then when I share that with people they go what the hell
They just sit there in twist signs all day for 50 an hour
But you know what their day goes by so slowly remind goes by go crap
I still have work to do and it's six o'clock. Yes, the that's that's back then
That's the rate they had the charge to solve the attrition problem because the job is so friggin boring. That is interesting
Yeah, I think there's a whole
My head is spinning because I read a lot of psychology of how the brain works kind of books and and what affects
You know motivation like the Dan pink stuff
I want to think maybe there's some way to change that job up and give them
I'm not gonna brainstorm the whole solution here, but I think I could come up given some time and some brainstorming a way to
Make that job interesting enough for people who didn't go
Batship board doing it
Come back next podcast for that solution will solve we will take suggestions and we will solve that and many other
Construction union problems all the next podcast sir. All right, so
Job in your job is at Microsoft it is. Oh good. It is. I hear they're a pretty good company. I am
They hired you I
Will be going into a full-time
Data science job
My title shortly will be data scientist manager. They can't see the air quotes you put around that data science
What does that mean? What does a data science manager do?
Manage data science II people that's great. What do data science II people do?
So the they use the data to help
Create actionable decisions that that in essence is what every data scientist is doing
What's the difference between sort of business intelligence like we there's data
It's very obviously we do and data science or they related are they overlap how there there's an overlap
business intelligence is
There's an overlap in terms of the technology used data science team will often go
deeper in in sort of the
Technical aspects you can kind of view it sort of the difference between
This is a hyperbole but a difference between a PM and a and a dev in a in the software engineering world
They're both working on technology
but
one is focused on
You'll say executives and communication and
Visualization and the others more focused on processing the data
Turn it into something actionable now. I intend to sort of do both
Much like we've said here before
in the services world
Building the most reliant or reliable service that no one uses is kind of pointless
and it's the same thing a lot of lot of data science stuff you can spend months working on it and
Then discover it's a non-problem
Yeah, right and
Something you want to avoid so I was reminded and again because in this podcast we never go off on tangents
I came across a free ebook from Microsoft on data science in the cloud, which I haven't read yet
But and I'm too lazy to probably look up the link and put it in our our
Podcast but you should put it in the pocket
It's I will I will make an attempt now that brand has put pressure at minimum
You should send me the link but it's data science in the cloud with Microsoft Azure machine learning and are and I'm a big fan
Of our I don't know if you caught this announcement. Did you know Microsoft bought our we bought
Yeah, I don't know that we bought our we bought a company that was doing a bunch of stuff with our no
Let me look it up. Hold on. I'm but I do know a guy who's going to that team
You know a guy who knows a guy. Yep. So on the revolutionary analysis comm blog
The company revolution revolution analytics who make our were acquired by Microsoft on January 23rd was the announcement was made
Yes, that I was aware of that's pretty cool
Our is fun. I think I don't think you have to be data science II
I think I don't know that's such a that term
I think the term data science reason I asked you the questions about it
I think data science and data scientist are
Words and titles that are still evolving into something that can be commonly understood
We are likely to go through the typical Microsoft process on this
You mean where we swing the pendulum madly until it lands somewhere in the middle?
where we
So there was a slide I saw a couple years ago that compared
Data science to to sex in high school
Warning PG section of the podcast starting now. Yeah, you rent in essence
everybody
Wants it
Everyone claims they've already had it and no one actually has
In terms of the fun things that we've talked about here a couple times on on the podcast and and
We have not talked about high school sex before on the podcast. No, but in terms of the there's a there's a
Couple podcasts ago you were talking about unique things about Microsoft. Oh
Yeah, yeah, and one of the unique things I at least I think it's unique is
Microsoft will
Will pick up a term that's commonly used out in the world and then
Once they find a term like data science that they're very fond of
Completely ignore what the definition that the rest of the world uses. Yeah. Oh
May I peeve for a moment? Go ahead. I don't know if we ever ever brought this up
I may have peeved about this before our podcast series ever started, but there's a team at Microsoft who makes a
Development environment and compiler
It won't actually name the product name. You can probably figure it out
They have so many of those compiler team. They were really excited about
Making some tools for exploratory testing. Yeah, they can exploratory test and they wanted to
Blog about this and write about it and get the industry all excited about what they're doing with exploratory testing
so I don't think you need to
Have read every magazine in the world or paid attention too much to the world
But you've looked at all at testing outside of Microsoft at all
When people talk about exploratory testing and they want to abbreviate it Brent, what did they say ET?
They say ET not as an ET phone note home, but ET exploratory testing this team
It this is this by the way doing the Microsoft is a challenging algorithm
It's the wait what how should we really this?
How about the the third letter?
No, the second the first letter of each name of each word
Anyway, this team was going off calling it all their other articles called XT and I looked at it
My jaw dropped and once I got a crane and pulled it like up to my face. I sent an email
Actually, I didn't send the email right away. I screamed and swore and laughed for a while and then I sent them email and said hey, um
So there's this term
That you're using
Everywhere in the industry I can find example example example example example
Exploratory testing is referred to as ET
Why don't you guys use ET also and fit in with the industry? Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait
reply Oh reply good
I
Looking forward to common sense. No all our documents already use XT and we have customers that we've said that too
So we're gonna stick with XT done done done
Yeah, you know sometimes I can't make this stuff up
I should write a book about stupid things people do but and people would think I was exaggerating. I
Really think that could go in Doug Copeland if you're listening you want to write microsurfs to I will give you ideas
All right. I'm just gonna leave it right there. I
As many as you want you want little side plot ideas great
I will fill you in with trivia Mary Jo Foley. I don't have nothing for you. But
Anyway, you want to write some good fiction about Microsoft to help you out
So an executive here at Microsoft, it'll all be okay. He won't disclose anything
you know what as long as I work hard and
You know really apply myself. Um karma will take care of me
Okay. All right. Hey, um, oh I remember we're doing a podcast we are
totally forgot
So congratulations on the new job sounds fun
I'm sure we will hear much more about it in upcoming podcasts
You talk about what you do and I make fun of data science. I can't wait
So you wrapped up then on your old job?
The way we transition jobs at Microsoft. Oh, did you want to talk about how you went about getting that job?
Yeah, so this was my first
Time through the interview process you got to be kidding me. How long have you been at Microsoft? No
No, since we changed it. Oh
Did we change it we did tell me about what's changed because sometimes it's changed less or more than others but tell me about it. Oh
So have you experienced a thing called a feedback only?
interview, um
I don't I've done a lot of interviews for internal candidates. We've I'm not sure how it's different than before so so so the team
that I went through it says I
Believe I haven't fully asked my manager of my new manager. Is this exactly what's happening?
but
I've now seen the interview process from from experiencing to myself versus are as well as
Seeing other people go through with my employees for example
Alan's team just picked up one of my employees
His last day is also today
That's right. I saw him in the hallway a couple times this week. I'm checking in
Yeah, hey, we're already talking about how how he can come and help fix your guys to stand up
Anyway
It's very hold on a second Brent put your face over here. Oh
All right, go on the it's very different
So a feedback only interview process as I understand it is you you
You go talked with a couple people
They don't give a higher no higher
They just write up their feedback in the decision still on the manager who can then no
I have not seen that before even for our internal loops. We're still making higher no higher decisions
So I can't wait to hear more about that. Yeah, I'm gonna get
more in-depth and on this
To understand what's going on because I have been harping for a long time. I'm sure in this podcast too that
One thing we really do stupidly at Microsoft was we'd interview internal candidates often the same way
We interview a brand new hire and it's just idiotic and I hate it
So this is a good trend if this is happening more across the company. Yeah, so
We like the process
But so far I'm really digging this process the other thing that I found out as going through this
HR
You know the no poaching rule
Thou shalt know is that an unwritten rule it is not you're kidding me as of now
I I think that's a very good thing. I think go to the HR portal and
There's
I'll send you the link later. There is a there is a readers. He's talking to me. Not you listen, right?
Yeah, no, sorry guys. This will not be going out to the podcast, but there is a there is a detail
Page on there that explicitly says
the no poaching rule
No longer exists if a person comes to your team and they wish to leave in one day
They may
Yeah, and there's a recommendation around staying like six months
But yeah, but you can like oh wow not what I expected that you can't get stuck with the bait and switch and
managers
They explicitly call this out
there is
There is no no poaching rule
It's basically it's it's very much around empowering employees. Well to be clear
Maybe let's make sure our definition is approaching or the same poaching isn't just leaving your job within a day poaching is me
You know typically in the past a manager would have to you could drop hints maybe be
Someone have to come to you looking for a job
But the for poaching would mean I could you know, I'm not a hiring manager, but I do a lot of recruiting for our team
I could email
You know so and so and say hey, I think he'd be a great fit on our team
You want to come talk about it which used to be kind of frowned upon majorly frowned upon
But it was easiest get caught. It's the easiest thing on the planet, right?
But the thing is hey and then the rules you send email to a BCC list of people that may include only one person say hey
My team has some openings if you know of anyone who may be interested
We don't take it. Yeah teams managers totally cheated. There was all kinds of things. I don't know anyone besides me. Hey, thanks
all you had to do is
Let's say I wanted Alan on my team all I had to do is call Alan and say hey Alan
I want you on my team here's what we do and
Alan goes oh, that's fantastic
And I'll say great. Here's the career position
Can you send me an email saying you found this on career and you're interested in chatting with me and Alan would say why?
Yes, that will take five minutes of my life
Now I have evidence that Alan talked to me first
Done great
And then I have to go through a six-hour interview loop on your team where they asked me like how to reverse a string and and
And silly things like that. Yeah, so
As I was going back to so the interview process. Oh
And on the HR web
The at the very end of this paragraph it explicitly says
the only control
managers have
to
Keep people on their team is make your team more attractive than everyone else. Yeah, you know, this is I love this big
And I'm gonna take full credit for this because at last year's we have talked about this before I give a soapbox talk on I
forget what it was actually the topic was but one of the things I mentioned in this talk this little five-minute talk was
That
People should be free to move around the company whenever they wanted. Mm-hmm that happened. Thank you and
The way you tell the good managers from the bad managers the bad managers don't have anyone reporting to them anymore
So does that although that's not actually as as as I've discovered from little pockets throughout the company
That's not entirely true. Yeah, I don't think I don't think we've all the way transitioned over because this at all. There is a I
know several managers
Who who can keep people on their team?
By scaring the crap out of them. Yeah, well, we'll find
No matter what systems in place
People are gonna game the system. So if people are gonna game the system, I'd much rather have a less restrictive
system that at least
encourages
Good behavior. Yeah
This awesome. I'm glad to hear examples of that. I know
For every example you give I and probably many of our Microsoft listeners can give counter examples
Well, that's not happening or managers are saying
No one no one can leave the team until you know, we ship I guarantee it's happening. It's happening and
the
like these are the easiest things on the planets to work through because
The problem is is that there's a lot of employees when their manager says this doesn't do their own research
This is again another one of those
Very similar to the XT phenomenon where where people internally don't research the truth
And in this particular case, right?
All you have to do if you have a manager just telling you this
All you have to do is go talk to your journalist and say hey my managers told me this is this actually true and
Most generalists will go your manager can't tell you that I know
But
Honestly, and since we're pretty frank and open and no one no execs have yelled at us yet about what we say about Microsoft in this podcast
My experience in my coming up on 20 years of Microsoft has been that
HR is much more concerned about
Not breaking rules that would cause lawsuits than actually in enforcing rules that would help employ growth or freedom or
Coming aligning with the handbook
It can depend on the generalist I know
But I feel like HR in my experience is there to make sure lawsuits don't happen. I
So I make it part of my business to get tight with with HR
And I will I used to do that
But every time I got tight with one they get fired or leave for another job
And I will tell you that there's a lot of turnover there
I will tell you that every single one of them that I've talking with is
Really is really focused on on
getting the right candidates and getting in making great teams and
and
They do have to obey constraints around legality
but
the
You can influence that good. Well, I hope then that that becomes more of the norm for those HR generalists
That would be great because I think we definitely need support of the whole company for some of these team and
Job movement things to work in a way that benefits Microsoft
Yeah, there's still so I ended up with a four-week transition
Still a little long. It seems like it right. Yeah
Although the guy you you took I think ended up with a two-week
So yeah, I would like to see this as a good way towards the journey. We're by no means at the destination
Yeah, and let's talk about that briefly. No, I have other stuff to talk about but I think
often two weeks isn't the the ramp down cost much as it's the
the price you pay to
Just through bureaucracy of getting like a finding an office for this person and etc. Etc
I would like to see transitions be two weeks, but
With a sort of graduated like I may spend two days or half of every day
At least that second week or maybe working through those weeks
working on both teams
So combining the ramp down with the ramp up. I always commit when I whatever I'm getting a new employee
That's always what I offer to the guy
Because what I want is the date and I'm like, hey, let's set it for two weeks and
If if you guys can't close
In terms of the transition by that two weeks
All right. I talked with I talked with the guy
They think they can get it 90% the way done in two weeks. Let's set that as the date and whatever remains
I'm happy to have them continue to do that
Yeah up to another I've had I've had I've seen that happen quite a bit where hey, you know
I'm starting work on x date, but I have this other project here to finish up. I guess fine. I have no problem with that
Yeah, the the one thing about the interview process that doesn't appear to have changed though is
the questions, ah
Right. So so
There there still appears to be
the the formula
right, oh you
You look at their resume and you you ask what's what do you do the passion question?
Then then you do the group fit question
Yeah
You do the coding question and the coding question is always a useless function that and then you do the puzzle question and and
Yeah, I push my team hard not to do that
especially for especially for internal candidates, it's almost all about fit and
And if for me
One of my unofficial titles on the team that I give myself is chief morale officer
I honestly believe that if people like their job, they will do better work at it and get more done
So I'd spend a lot of time making sure they're going to like
Trying to figure out if they're going to like working on the team working on what they're working on working with the people
We have I think that's for for an external candidate. I got to find out a lot more about them
So I'm gonna go a little bit different direction, but the internal people
Often even people external who are returning to Microsoft
I will spend at least my interview we do multiple interviews so we can aggregate things together
but my interview is a lot about figuring out are they gonna fit in and do well here and
And like working here. I know other people focus on other things, but I I
Yeah, I we need to the questions need to change to the way we interview an internal candidate needs to be
Quite different from the way we interview a brand new hire at Microsoft. I agree with that
Of course you do because I'm right you are right the one thing I'm seriously considering though is
What would actually happen if we as for internal candidates?
If we just simply banned coding questions, well
What like how much risk would that put us at? Yeah?
There's a one of the managers on our team
Is in love with the coding question and
They're gonna be an internal candidate who's written these really cool. I look at the portfolio the resume. Okay, he's done this. That's awesome
I use that okay, it's fine
And then we'll get through the loop and say did anyone ask a coding question?
I'll say do you have any reason to believe?
That this person can't code
No, but it's part, you know, I yeah, it's I push back. I I am still fun of the
Design questions because I find that that's yeah, I think that's good. How would you architecture design? Those are good discussion things
because
Honestly, because I think the way you design an architect in a our meeting because you do that in a brainstorming meeting as well are
Very similar the way you code at the whiteboard versus the way you code at your computer
Remarkably different hope wholly different wholly different and the reason we do that for new hires want to make sure that
You kind of want to make sure that they haven't
You know, they do have a clue about what's going on
They know how about how logic and program flow works and they have an idea
How programming languages work to make sure they have it? It's really just a resume checker
But for in an internal there's no reason to do it
I would much rather focus on design and architecture and and lot not logic puzzles
But sort of logical working through things and how well can we brainstorm together because that helps me figure out
Kind of how you think and that that gives me even more information even then
It's like I like what you were saying in terms of the fit, right? I'm gonna be working through. Okay
What are your?
Strengths as it comes to solving problems not problem solving in terms of like puzzles, but right every team
We have a bunch of crap. We got to get done, right?
What what strengths do you bring to bear to help me get crapped a done right, right and so much of our work especially
now versus
Years ago is collaborative. Yeah, I want someone that I can I
Feel if I can have a good conversation with someone about working through a problem and they're contributing a lot
That's it. I feel pretty good about that if I say if I give him a question ask him
So, how would you do blah? They go?
I don't
so
Maybe I would
Yeah, I'm not feeling less good about you for me
It's interesting
What I what I'm finding now is that there's really only two things at the interview process that I'm a highly allergic to
Right if if I'm interviewing for something because I have a gap on my team
For example in the new team. Mm-hmm
Then you can look for specific skills. I I am the first hire. I have a team of five opens and
Right now I gotta I gotta go
Reverse engineer this problem, but my management believes that I'm going to need deep machine
Learning skill set. Okay, and that's hard to find
Like there's a there's one team at this company that has a whole bunch of them and that team does a very good job making
Sure that those people are happy
So they're they're hard to poach
The
So if I'm if I'm missing a skill gap, I want to I want to test on their ability to sort of fill that gap
The other thing is I'm finding that that I am highly allergic to heroes
If I get the sense, you're a hero, I'll spend a half a second going
Okay
Do I have a position or can I construct a position where I need a firefighter and offer this person a role where?
Heroism is your job not above and beyond right, right?
And more often that I think we've talked about that heroes are okay if heroes your job
right it that's exactly right now you're
You are the team firemen and just because you consistently put out fires
Doesn't mean you're any better than anyone else cuz that either way is your job
Yeah here being a hero is your job, right?
The the thing is is though if you're a hero on a on a situation where I don't need a hero
And I need a team to work together
That's a problem for me
It really is it and I would imagine as you fill these five positions on your team
What you're looking for in a candidate changes as you begin to fill these positions
Yes, because you're looking for I imagine specializing generalists with specializations and machine learning
But those other skills you're gonna need as well. Yep, and that fifth higher each higher is progressively a little bit more harder
Maybe to fill as you start putting the jigsaw puzzle together. I want it
I definitely want it. I want specializing generalists and I want a diversity of
Specializations in my team. Yeah, right and then once I kick start that
The the the execution process I I do
We'll begin blending those guys
So they'll begin getting read of the bottleneck that occurs because of the specialization. Perfect. All right
Hey looking at the Kanban board. What should we skip?
Because if we have about 15 minutes left
Let's skip item three. Okay, do I talk about?
For the last project you did on your last team. Is that item two? Yeah, okay, so
One of the things that I'm also very excited as as I think we may have talked about this here
No, we you did last time. I think
Whatever. I am certified and an agile you are certified. All right as
Thanks. I am certified in agile framework known as this scaled agile framework
I got certified in this about a year and a half ago and last Thursday
I kicked off a planning event for my current team
because
they want
They've done a reorg
Where we are now going to go back to?
Shipping on prem products, so we have some very
High I didn't realize people still made on-prem products. Wow. That's cool. Well servers still on I'm just giving you a bad time
And it's a it's hugely all defensive. I'm not
Hugely popular. We also have analysis server
And reporting server and as the team sort of built up the cloud
we kind of
Use the majority of our resources to build up the cloud services and
It's kind of put these other
hugely valuable
products
Valued products from from a customer base kind of on the backburner. Yeah
We're getting feedback from customers now. That's basically saying hey, we love this on-prem ecosystem
We still want to continue to use it
We're not quite comfortable with putting all of our data in the cloud
Can you guys help us out so that we did a reorg and said will you pay us money will help you and
That's exactly what we're going to do
But the whole organization has spent the majority of their time the last two years
To doing services and in service is much more of an agile framework
So when we when we started thinking through the planning we're like
All right, what did we learn from the cloud?
Because no one wants to go back to waterfall. No one wants to go back to teams of test specialists
And so it was very exciting me being able to pull together
The scaled agile planning events set them up for an agile cadence even though it's on-prem and the
One really cool thing that they're going to to do is they're going to have an RTM mobile build every month
They're going to decouple
What engineering produces and its cadence from the release cadence, so they're going to produce a new build every month
They'll they'll let people know
What features are well and to be clear they're going to do builds daily or more often they are they're going to release one
Every month they will classify one is RTM able okay
And it'll be up to the business and marketing as to whether or not they are team
So the engineering team and this is one of the things that ends up being super powerful as I communicated the team the engineering
Team you guys you have no influence over the ship decision
Which kind of forces them to constantly have an RTM mobile product
Right now they're going to work towards doing this on a two-month cadence and then build it build it to a one-month cadence
and then one week
That's actually what they're talking about the puddle they probably won't go daily goals are great the
But the thing that's really exciting is that right now there is a team of 50
After I've walked them through the the planning event and walked them through the rationale
I would say 80% of them are like I see how this works
We can totally achieve those goals with this. It's very very cool cool
So then will you function as any are you done with them?
Will you consult with them as they move forward did you leave any leave any seeds there for them to?
When they run into a problem, what do they do without Brent?
That's actually the most common question is popping up this week again
Today's my last day on that team and I said let me what will we do without them?
He made it super clear because as Alan knows every time I leave a team
I usually set up a series of like lunch meetings with with people I've left behind
I stay in communication with with that team rent has a trail of bodies across Microsoft
He still communicates with and I I let them know look
Please do not let me find out
Two months from now that there was a question that you knew you could have asked me a month and a half ago and
You didn't and you went into the weeds because you didn't like
Use me as a resource
Don't go. Oh, I don't want to bother Brent and it's okay. That's another thing about job movement. We need to
Remember one company one thing about encouraging movement around the company is your old team needs to be able to ask you questions
I think it should be common in every case
Especially when you're in sort of a leadership position or there's special knowledge you have about how something works
I remember when I left the CE team Windows CE 12 years ago 10 years ago, whenever it was
I got questions about some of the things I was working on there for years afterwards years
Yeah, it's and I was okay to answer him wouldn't bother me
I said, okay
just
Sometimes just referring them to someone I knew was the new owner of something but offers like the it was just as easy for me
To answer answering questions. I mean, it's it's stupid simple. I'm like, I don't understand why people
don't just do that. I think this team will because I
Spent the better part of the last year really emphasizing and and
The value of collaboration and knowledge sharing
So I think if they get stuck they instead of said them doing the typical process of going to the internet and spending
Three days trying to hunt and gather for themselves
Well, cool, so like they're set up that's something it occurs to me that's something that's also perhaps a another Microsoft thing
Like we're talking about Microsoft. We're like, no, we'll do it ourselves
Well, that's a fractal you often see I see
Like no, no, I'm not gonna ask Alan this question that you probably answer in two minutes
I'm gonna instead spend three days and research it myself. Yeah, I have a three quarters
We don't have think week anymore, but I have three quarters of a think week paper on the title is
And you've heard this phrase before I probably mentioned on the podcast
But if only Microsoft knew what Microsoft knew yeah, and we just don't share well we function
I believe Microsoft size could be a competitive advantage
Because that shared knowledge, but we don't leverage it. In fact our size right now
I would say is a disadvantage because of some of the practices people are in about not sharing between teams and not asking
someone on another team a question I
Think within the next five years we've talked about it here
one of my entry speeches when I go to a new team is
Guys we are here to solve problems not right tools
Yeah
Not invented here
accordingly
kicks ass
Right, and I do think
Within the next three to five years. I think the me needing to do that speech
Is probably gonna die. Well, I hope so. Let's find out. Oh, hold on a second. Do you what?
What is that?
Hey, we have a question from the mailbag Brent I
Was coming up I have a mailbag question. Yeah, no it was I was a completely smooth
Segway, I could not see where you're going
But so in the last three mailbags you you've done a done sound yeah
What is that supposed to be? I don't know. Oh, yeah, I just look it's an I know you're making it your own
I'm making it my own. It's
Blues clues meets
It kind of ends the reverb pretty well. I think it does. It's fantastic. It's kind of what I'm into I kind of envision
Like a mailbox door slamming. Yeah, I'm not sure what it is
And I'm sure it's gonna evolve over time and in fact, you know once we get up into you know
I don't know how many mailbags you've done and I'm actually probably too lazy to go look through for all of them
But maybe I make like a little mailbag
intro
Compilation, I don't know. You know, it's really sad about our podcast is I never
Save what I cut out because there's there's crap on here that
We have a bloopers reel that you that could sell millions. I think not well not or at least get us lots of trouble
paces, yeah
So what's the mailbag Alan I don't know a Brett Hinton on Twitter asked
He said it really asked he stated he said every time I listened to a B testing episodes
I wonder what do test specialists on Alan and Brent's team actually do
So I don't have test specialists on my team. So Alan what do test
Did you have any on your last team?
The answer is lots of different things because the specialists are specializing generalists in in most cases
So we have on our team for example, we have
Some testers who are specialists in performance and security for example
Let's this first scope team. Are you talking about?
Like your boss's team. So on my boss's team, so we have we are not
despite what I've I hope I didn't indirectly leading one to believe this we're not a
Straight up unified engineering team. We have a quality team which actually doesn't do a lot of testing. We have test specialists
We do some of the longer tests things around reliability
Investigation we do a lot of data sciencey stuff and analysis and reporting, etc
So that could leads pretty well into
What the test specialists on our team do so my manager's team is probably best described as a team of test
Specialists you could even say test and data specialists if you include
Some of the work there, okay
So the pieces fit together it's for that jigsaw puzzle Brent's making a face of me
They do a lot of different things my specialty is in
You know, I'm sort of the big-picture guy. I'm my specialty is looking at everything that's going on and making sure the right things are happening
I also have a passion towards engineering efficiency
So I end up actually filling in a lot of work
I do as much work for our development team as I do for our team of test specialists
Let me ask
Going back to the scope question
Do you have any any recent visibility?
to a unified engineering team at the at the
Scrum team level that actually has an in place test specialist because I know I haven't had one of those
I don't know they call themselves test specialists
I do know of teams at Microsoft that have people that do
Much more big-picture thinking doing some performance testing or or
looking at
Things around acceptance testing or integrations a integration how it pieces fit together
That probably describes the specialist role in general more if I were to join
Some random Scrum team at Microsoft some team had a Scrum team my role in that Scrum team would be
largely around making sure a lot of the big pieces fit together that the
Teas were getting crossed and the eyes were being dotted and I would probably do it was me
I would do as much work around like I do in this team around engineering efficiency as I did around making sure that the product
Was high quality that's just that's leveraging my specialties. I can imagine and
If I were a hiring manager building a team
I would if I had someone who was really good at a test specialist who was good at actually
The way you describe your team is we have described test teams for many years
I don't want people that just can write a bunch of test automation
I want people who are great problem solvers and when needed can use code to solve those problems. I
Would say so Alan and I have both
I
Got it. What was it three years ago? This used to be a topic
Alan and I talked about a lot we were in shared communities and those communities talked about it a lot
This was before the unified engineering change and we were trying to help
I wouldn't call it change as much as a shift because
Probably I don't know what percentage of Microsoft teams are sort of unified engineering, but it's I
Think a large portion of the thing they think it's a majority now
I do think keep in mind windows is not for the most part windows is not
our OSG
Mostly is mostly is so maybe maybe half. I don't know the OSG the operating systems group is just so dang large
I think it skews
Majorities, but Alan and I and I don't remember the whole list but back in those days two three years ago
We we had a list of like
Seven five to seven different things that we believed test would move into as a specialization
that that the world around
Everything that the engineering team doesn't want to pick up
Which would kind of begin to dissolve and I kind of see
That is what's actually occurring that we see individuals
Sort of gravitate towards certain specializations for example. I'm moving towards
I
Wouldn't call it a test specialist. I'll call it a quality specialist sure and the way I contribute to quality is via
specializing in data science I see other people
focusing on the system as a whole
Integration testing and scenario testing let me describe a little bit differently cuz we need to get towards I think I yeah
Centered in on it is I think core and I wrote up this in a blog post a while back
But the majority of engineers at Microsoft are sort of that core programmer meaning design implement
Unit test functional test make sure my crap works right the test specialists do the remainder
I hate yeah, I know the remainder stolen from Jim Jimmo, but
It's what else needs to happen. That's contextual for that product
It may be a little bit more for an on-prem product than a service product
The services is going to be leveraging a lot more data analysis
What I'm saying is is as I absolutely do despise the remainder, but
If there was a team of test specialists, I think the team absolutely would own the remainder
But when you when you
Drill down into details
I think you'll find that the world where there are individuals on in the remainder is
rapidly dissipating
Yeah, well my role is more of a specialization occurring where I really thought Microsoft rules
But I was gonna be on that scrum team
I would be as much as a
software engineer as I would be the very technical PM on that team because I'm I
Can't do the remainder by myself on that team, but I'm making sure it all gets done. So I'm so and
Whether it's just making sure there's work items or for some of those illities or extras that have to get done
because I look at software from a
Lart from a higher view than many of my peers. I see. Okay, we're gonna need to do this
I know about this we need to do that or you need to make sure we apply this tool here blah blah blah
Etc, etc. So what I've observed from from from Alan
And I haven't
God we've known each other forever, but I haven't spent a whole lot of time
Like shadowing Alan and and I mean publicly
Around
How he does this day-to-day
But my understanding of it is that Alan in a scrum parlance likely has an affinity towards
The scrum master or the product owner type role. I believe that's more likely the the gap
You end up filling because these are more and I always evolved
So what you say today may be true. I may be different in three months or I was probably different three months on the specifics
But you still generally
Look at the system. I'm a hole filler and then you go repair the gaps
Yeah, I'm a hole filler and I use my breath to kind of figure out where holes need to be filled and prioritized
I've been very lucky at that. You know, I've I've talked about I haven't had a manager. Tell me what to do in a decade at least
They might give me some suggestions once in a while
But my job is to kind of figure out what needs to get done and then make sure it gets done
Yeah, and then one thing that you do that you don't really
Proselytize it well enough because I do think if others were to follow in your I love it when you use words like proselytize
That I have to go look up afterwards. You don't know why is it enough? No, I'm going proselytize fair enough the
Is
Alan is also talented at when he finds that gap are
Arguing the business value for it, right? I sees on the team if they were to just do Alan's algorithm
It would be just as likely to go. Well as it would bad for them, right? There's a focus on the business value
We are Brent full of great ideas. We are also out of time. Hey everybody
Thanks for listening this far in yet another episode of a be testing. I'm Alan. I'm Brent and we'll see you next time
Episode 19 next time. All right later. Bye