Kids, this is Alan.
And this is Brent.
Welcome to episode 31 of A, B, Testing.
Hello, everyone.
Hey, Brent, you know why I made that old man voice?
Yes, I do.
Because I'm an old man.
You know what?
I don't feel a day over 50.
Actually, I'll talk to you back.
I feel exactly a day over 50.
It's no fun if you pick on yourself
before I have a chance to.
Preemptive picking.
I had already planned to come in and announce
that a big event had occurred that I am now.
So two days ago, I was, you were only 8% older than me.
And now you're 11.
So as far as I'm concerned, I got younger.
Thank you.
So is this a chapter out of How to Lie with Statistics?
Which is a very good book by the way.
It is a fantastic book.
And I don't think it's in there.
All right, we'll add that too.
It's How to Lie with Charts.
Or maybe it's just Dumb Stuff, Brent says.
But yes, I turn 50.
I share a birthday with the infamous Ozzy Osbourne.
And someone else who came in.
Holly Marie Combs from Charmed and Picket Fences
and some other shows.
Oh.
She didn't wish me happy birthday.
I was hoping for a shout out, but nothing.
I spent some time on History Channel's web page on a day
in history.
I know.
You had these stupid things like, oh, that one's been around
longer than the door transplant.
Hopefully you're around long enough for a brain transplant.
I did actually, though, the one on the Vietnam War,
I did wonder, do you actually have any memories of it?
Yeah, I was there.
I was what they called the young.
So my dad, I don't even know if you know this.
So my dad went into the Vietnam War, right handed,
and came out left handed.
He got hit by a mortar shell.
OK, that's a trip.
This is a downer, I know.
But he got hit by a mortar shell,
and he had half of his body paralyzed.
Now, it's a great story.
I grew up with this as a father.
And one of the things my dad does,
which has always been an inspiration for me,
is he calls the rest of us two-handers.
And ain't no two-hander going to be able to do something
he can't.
My dad, he got dealt a really crappy deck of cards
and survived it.
This all happened, obviously, before I was born.
But I do know his timeline.
And I'm like, hey, wait a minute.
Alex, or not Alex, that's my son.
Alan was four or five during that time period.
I wonder if he has any memories at all of Vietnam.
No?
The answer is no.
All right, then.
Shall we do our topics?
We got some mailbag and some other stuff to talk about.
Should I just jump right into my rant?
Go ahead.
All right.
I'm going to offend someone.
But it wouldn't be the first time on A-B testing, right?
No.
Is it someone that actually listens to us?
No, I don't know, probably.
So for full disclosure, I get the difference
between checking and testing.
I also get that 99.9% of the software engineering world
uses the encompassing verb testing,
Vrjarand testing, to describe things
that are technically checks.
And when I looked and I went and looked this up,
and even the authors of checking versus testing
say that testing encompasses checking.
Checking is a part of testing.
So it just irks me to no end.
Don't ever do this one of the three, or two of the three,
or three of the three.
None of y'all.
Like when someone says, I wrote some automated tests,
don't freaking get on Twitter and go,
don't you mean you wrote automated checks?
I've seen these.
No, they wrote automated tests.
They happen to be checking something that's fine.
Just this incessant need to correct people's use
of the word test is not helping your cause.
It's not.
It's kind of like saying, hey, Alan, I just got a new puppy.
And you coming back with, don't you
mean you got a German Shepherd?
You're like, stop.
Yeah, it's worse than that.
It's worse than that.
And then it gets worse.
Somebody who doesn't even like me, I can handle it.
And I'll flip it a little crap once in a while
because I get it.
But somebody who doesn't even know what they're talking about.
They see just random person happens
to mention the word testing when it could mean checking.
And they get jumped all over.
And then they make the argument of going,
well, isn't this just semantics?
And they go, words are important to communicate our ideas.
Words, we have to use the right words.
And it's like, give me a break, people.
You knew what they were talking about.
It was totally clear to you what they were talking about.
But you insisted on changing it so that only 1% of the world
would know what you were talking about anymore.
I mean, ah, stop it.
Just stop being an idiot.
I am.
So I am one of the people who will state words are important.
And I probably have on multiple people.
I completely agree that words are important.
But what is not important is a Nazi-style activist correction,
an active spell checker.
Dude, now no one's paying attention
to the wisdom behind what you're saying.
And they're just going, how do I get out of this meeting
with you, Douchebag?
Did you see my tweet yesterday, the day before?
Must have been the day before.
But every morning, I load up Feedly,
and I read through all my blog posts.
And for some reason, I subscribe to people that piss me off.
But often, even people that piss me off sometimes
say smart things.
But anyway, I came across, I can't
remember who wrote it, so sorry.
Another article about automated testing
and how we aren't really automated testing.
You're automated checking.
And testing can't be automated because testing
requires a human blah, blah, blah, same argument.
And I tweeted, in the time it took me
to read an article saying that testing can't be automated,
I could have wrote some automated tests.
And most people got the irony of that,
but I did have one person go, well,
I think you're talking about checking.
I don't get what you're saying.
So please, just don't be thick about it.
If you're one of the three, yes,
it's good to recognize that there is verification
and investigation.
And it's important that you have
that discussion with people.
But randomly correcting people is just frickin' idiotic.
So knock it off.
Case closed.
It is.
My part of the case is closed.
I'm ready to move on.
No, it is.
And I'm off this topic, but you just said something.
So I saw your tweet, but it didn't interest me enough
to follow the conversation.
But that was almost hurtful.
The rabid wombat there.
Wombat!
What was their definition of testing then?
What gets lost?
And it's funny, I went back to the source.
Why can't I automate testing?
Because testing is a human activity
that requires judgment and intuition.
And that can't be automated?
No.
Of course it can.
Look, please don't make me go off into this hole.
I went back to the source, and I verified that.
And it's funny, when this thing first came out.
And me?
I said I always considered checking
to be a subset of testing.
And later they said the same thing,
which I don't think they listened to me at all,
but it makes sense when he's being logical.
So it's not one versus the other.
Checking is part of testing.
There's a part of testing that is simple verification.
Boolean verification.
But the followers of the model seem to think it's a versus.
And they go to all ends to, it's almost like it's an agenda.
It's just stupid.
There are much more important things
to have semantic discussions about,
agreeing that words are important.
Blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
It's a good thing we only have three listeners,
because I'm glad that we don't have
to deal with the problem of having polarized alkalite.
You know, it's OK.
Echo our words back to us.
If we drop to two, it's cool.
I'm just like, man, I would feel so responsible
if I had a bunch of, frigging, thoughtless disciples following
me around holding up this testing versus checking battle.
Yeah.
And it's from the same crowd that recognizes,
rightfully, the power of critical thinking
and how important critical thinking
is for good testing, investigation,
and actually for any knowledge work in general
to stay up on the soapbox.
To not recognize it in this case, it's hypocritical.
Completely agree.
All right.
So let's talk about something not from the soap.
Actually, everything's from the soapbox, right?
Drent and I just had lunch.
Oh, it was good.
It was fantastic.
Dintag Phong plus plus.
All right.
But we were talking over lunch about some of the challenges.
Brent and I, Brent has been on Agile teams.
He's helped teams transfer to Agile.
And he's back on the horse again,
helping a team become, do adaptive software development,
being able to react to change.
And we were kind of talking about the challenges that
happen, moving from a predictive or any sort of even
iterative software process to an adaptive process
or your data driven, you're driven
by the need for change versus needs for stabilization
periods, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
Ultimately, it comes down to, any time
there's an established system, it's really freaking hard
to change to a new established system.
True.
Right.
So the challenge, right.
I don't know if you've done much research on this.
But do I look like I do research?
No.
Yeah.
You're too old.
Even if you did, you'd forget it the next day.
I got to be all kids.
Did you see me tweet?
I got my application to apply for AARP in the mail.
Booyah.
Discounts.
Out.
Lunch is on Alan from here on out.
Yeah, so I have a bunch of friends
who are Agile consultants, Agile coaches.
I myself am a coach.
And we spent a lot of time talking
about how do we help people do this transition.
Because it is, quite honestly, almost all of these problems
come down to people problems.
It's almost always cultural.
Jerry Weinberg may have a quote about that.
He does.
The exact quote, actually.
So the challenge that, so my particular team today,
there's a new challenge I've never faced.
I have had the whole team running on a single board,
which I'm very successful at getting.
But in this particular case, there's also
five separate managers running.
And all of these guys, they don't have a business first
mentality.
They have a my business first mentality.
And it is hard to get them to.
Can you clarify what that means?
Or actually an example.
So I think I know what you mean,
but I don't want to jump down the wrong path.
I'll give you an example.
One of my peers today.
And none of my team, actually.
None of them are any of the three.
An example today is, so those who follow Kanban,
you know that there's this process called limiting WIP.
And we limit WIP, including what goes in the ready column.
So we do a backlog grooming process every week.
And we adjust this.
But we have this thing called a swim lane or a rail
that we call the interrupt rail.
So if something new comes up and it's not
time for the planning meeting, and you
need to get somebody started on something,
even though two days ago we just went through backlog
grooming, it happens in our space.
We're an analytics team.
So we have to operate at the speed at which decisions need
to be made, which is hourly at times.
But this interrupt rail's purpose in life
is to limit how, to create a limit on how much our time can
be interrupted versus allowing the plan to move forward.
Well, he had like five things he
wanted to put into the interrupt rail.
And he wanted to understand, because he
has all of this pressure from other folks
to get this bug done, get this thing fixed,
get this stuff done.
And he's missing the old days where he could just do bugs,
allow bugs to get deferred, have a stabilization period in which
he fixes it.
And the thing that he also wanted
was to increase the WIP on the interrupt
and be able to get his team.
And he's like, I have two projects,
and I have five people.
So I need to get these guys moving forward.
I have this huge urgency.
Well, the thing is, is right now,
the planning phase, its purpose in life is we have commitments.
So I think, do you follow the semester planning?
Are you in, if I said we're about to end sulfur,
does that mean anything to you?
Nope.
OK.
So most of CNE, and I believe also most of ASG,
do six-month planning cycles at a division level.
That ends in December.
So there's still several team commitments
that my boss has made that we haven't accomplished.
So what's happening, so I created a process
so which we could resource share and get
those goals accomplished.
One of my peers, he has five open positions,
but he only has one person in it right now.
And he's where things that we've committed
haven't gotten across the wire.
Well, this peer I was talking to,
he is more focused on what he has to deliver
versus what the team has to deliver.
This is what I mean by the business priority versus my.
It's like 17 on the list.
And we're back.
I made Brent stop partway through
because my audio equipment was being mean.
The signals are a lot better now.
I'm not sure how the first half of this podcast
is going to sound.
Yeah, we're good now.
We have normal levels now.
Brent was getting smaller and smaller and disappeared.
And we tried a bunch of things, and I just
plugged into a different USB port on my Lenovo laptop.
And we're good to go now.
Wow.
All right.
Were you testing or checking your equipment?
OK.
I am really worried now that the first half of our podcast
is going to sound like poo.
Because now I have actual levels that make sense.
I can always adjust them later.
You want to start over and just make this one a shorty?
No, I don't want to start over.
We'll make it work.
So I may just publish in the second half.
So when we last left off, Brent was babbling,
talking about transitioning from predictive to adaptive.
And take it away, Brent.
Yeah.
I'm not going to go.
Am I doing that all over again?
No.
OK, God.
OK.
Yeah, it's hard.
All right.
Next subject.
I think we've talked a lot about organizational changes.
I'm not going to dive deep into that.
But it's tough for people to see.
There's two things in play here.
One is that it's easy to go back to what
you're comfortable with.
Yep.
And that's one of the harder things, fighting inertia.
The effort that people see the value.
For me, when I see teams get to that stage where
they can truly be just adaptive, and it's fun.
Oh, it's fantastic.
I think it's motivating.
Because I go to the Dan Pink research on people
are motivated by progress, by seeing progress.
And you get to see so much of that.
And you don't, without a lot of the roadblocks
that come with debt.
But negative motivations almost always overpower positive.
And in this particular example, any place
where the hardest part for doing this transition for leaders
is to recognize that you will be happier.
You will have a more productive team
if you let go of command and control.
If you let your team decide, they're better suited.
They're better able.
And the facilities that we put in place
to allow you to prioritize or influence
what they have to choose between are enough.
Right.
There's a Steve Denning quote that I'm
sure I've mentioned to you 50 times.
But from his book, The Leader's Guide to Radical Management.
Give people a framework they can work in
and then get out of their way.
Yeah.
I love that.
I give them just enough one minute manager
apply, swoop in, and give them coaching when they need it.
But get out of their way.
Let people make decisions.
They're actually better right than you think they are.
It occurs to me.
It occurs to me just now what exactly is going on.
What's going on is there's a bunch of people
who are in leader roles, but there aren't leaders.
They're managers.
I don't know if that insight helps me solve this problem.
Brant, if there weren't hard problems for us to solve,
we wouldn't be employed.
I have plenty of other interesting problems
to solve than polling people from 1998 into 2015.
Yeah, that is a challenge.
We are in 2015.
One of the things.
For a few more weeks.
So for a few more weeks, 2015, we're
going to pull the team to a safe model in March.
That's right.
You're safe certified.
I am.
I'm going to take them to safe, which is for a team our size.
Safe really works well for 50 plus.
Again, we're half that.
It's overkill.
But I'm going to test because I suspect that the safe model will
strike a balance between how the managers want
to use command and control and create
a predictive environment.
This will allow them to be predictive in three month
cycles.
All right.
I haven't done this in a while.
And I don't know if I can do it in my second half
of my century on this planet.
But I'll try it.
Mailbag.
That was actually better than you usually did.
I was expecting the fact that we just came back from lunch
and trying to fight lunch coma would have slowed you down.
But it didn't.
No.
So Alan, we have at least three mailbag questions
and one handy tip.
OK.
I want to talk about the first question.
Alan sent out to the three, hey guys,
we're going to do two more.
Any questions?
And one of the questions that came back,
why are you guys so great?
And the answer is, is there an answer?
Because I don't think we're particularly great.
I said in Twitter, we're not.
Could there have been sarcasm there?
Perhaps.
OK, next question.
We do take all questions and address them in our podcast.
We don't always give insightful answers.
We will answer.
We will answer with something.
So I went to private school when I was younger.
Southern Baptist religious school.
And I remember my teacher.
So much is coming to light all of a sudden.
I remember my teacher saying, God answers all questions.
He either answers yes, no, or not going to answer right now.
And I'm like, magic eight ball at least has eight answers.
OK, now we pissed off two of the three.
Let's go on.
Did you see the one Twitter?
I heard the one hashtag.
Yeah, tweet one of the seven of the three.
Yeah, I thought that was cool.
That was from test.
Pappy.
Yes.
Who I met at Eurostar.
One of the seven of the three.
I like them.
So let's talk a little bit more about the I
don't think any team company outside of Microsoft
uses this term, but the term often used at Microsoft
is combined engineering.
Yep.
Meaning it's a software team without a dedicated test team.
So what is that?
And did you watch there was a talk at a local QA SIG
recently with someone who used to work at Microsoft.
Yep.
I don't know.
Jamie Campbell.
Yeah, I knew Jamie is worked in office.
And then I looked at the slides and I watched most of his talk
and I think there's some things we can touch on.
But did you do either of those?
I did both.
Look at you.
Yeah.
I would say in first ever dual prepared A-B testing podcast.
I'm so uncomfortable using the P word here.
Podcast.
Prepared.
Oh.
Yeah, so there was when I was going through it,
first I thought it was a challenge
because there was massive glare on the monitor.
Right.
I had to follow along on the slides outside.
I couldn't see the slides in the broadcast at all.
I was hunting around the QA SIG's website
and I was halfway through the recording
before I finally found the slides.
And then I just went, oh, sure.
That's what he was talking about there.
There was only one place where I thought
I was going to disagree with Jamie.
And then he came the very next slide.
You started talking about his view.
And I'm like, yeah, that's very much the lines.
Yeah.
And it was really more of his experience
on his team going through a move to combined engineering.
It's very similar.
Not only were they moving to combined engineering,
but they were moving away from predictive development models
towards adaptive.
And it's important.
And I said this before.
I'll say it again.
And one of the things I didn't like in his combined
engineering slides is why move because it's trendy.
And yeah.
I didn't get the Taylor Swift metaphor in his slides.
The point is you don't do anything
because other people are doing it because it looks fun,
because it's cool.
You want to, if you're going to make a change,
have it be for a reason.
And I think it's the other way around.
We want to be more adaptive.
And because of that, it makes sense
for us to do a unified engineering team
because it lets us be adaptive in these ways.
Now, we just talked about that.
Maybe I don't know if I actually got to a point on it.
Rarely.
Why do we want to be adaptive?
We want to be able to react to what customers want and need
faster.
Why?
We didn't have to do that before.
Why do we have to do that now?
Because now, if they're not getting what they want from us,
they have many other choices.
People are much more fickle in their choices
of web services, web providers, apps, et cetera.
If you don't give them what they want, you've lost them.
Yeah.
I can try out, pick any popular thing right now.
And I could try out free trials of that thing, 15 to 20 of them
in a span of three hours.
One of those guys are going to have the recipe
that I'm looking for.
Yeah.
You will lose.
Sometimes, even if it's something that they don't absolutely
need, like if they're a word processor,
I probably need a word processor.
And I don't like Word.
Used to be I could wait for the next version of Word.
Now I have lots of other open source and freely available
alternatives.
But there may be something like maybe a game
where they don't need it.
And they might not even be an alternative.
But if you're not giving them value
and reacting to what's working and what's not working
with them quickly, they're going to stop using your game.
Not for a competitor, not for another product.
People could stop using what you're making just
because it doesn't get them enough value or pleasure
or fun or whatever.
Yeah, some games have competitors.
Like we talked about League of Legends last time.
Some games don't.
But it's the second.
The point is, in the world today with apps
and the world living on the web, you
have to be adaptive to make software today.
This might be too harsh to say, but the world in general
today has ADHD.
They're fickle.
And if you don't keep them engaged,
they're not going to come back.
And we shouldn't say the world because there's
telecom and military software that doesn't need to be adaptive.
Telecom?
I don't know about telecom, but I'll
go with the military one.
OK, fine.
I'll do that one.
I think if the FCC lifted limitations,
what made it easy for people to switch from Comcast
to Xfinity to Frontier.
Isn't Comcast, Xfinity, the same thing?
It is, yes.
So maybe not those two.
Yeah.
But if it was easy to switch back and forth, people would.
Yeah, one thing, getting back to Jamie's thing,
and combined engineering in general.
So the mailbag item, to be clear, the mailbag item
was around, hey, what is the efficacy of combined engineering?
And to me, the biggest one, I'll
get back to Jamie's thing in a second.
To me, the biggest thing is what I call the,
I think I've acted on that before,
the ping pong game.
The ping pong game of, here's my code.
Here's a bug.
Here's the fix.
Here's another bug.
Here's some more code.
Here's two more bugs.
That back and forth and back and forth, very inefficient.
And I'll say it in a different light.
The world has ADHD.
Therefore, we have to adapt to keep the world engaged.
Therefore, calendar time, calendar time, not effort
calendar time, calendar time is one of our single most
competitive assets.
Things that waste calendar time, such as bug ping pong,
such as stabilization, throwing over the walls,
such as stabilization.
Particularly in the world, when there's
a whole massive community of people
who have successfully shifted and have
learned how to produce better software, in that world,
combined engineering is a necessity.
I think so.
Although I also hate the word.
I've always been fine with it.
And once you introduce me to unified engineering,
I like that better.
Glad I have an influence on you.
In terms of, well, go back to Jamie's.
One thing I did, one kind of orange flag, yellow flag,
he was talking about their move.
And some of the testers moved to development roles.
Some moved to data roles.
Data analyst, 50% moved to dev roles.
And he didn't say this directly.
But I was worried that in that transition that they lost.
One thing I think is critical in unified engineering
is that although the specific roles may go away,
the activities still need to happen.
And I was worried that he made it
sound like all the testing expertise was being forgotten.
And I think it's important when you do unified engineering
for that efficacy to work.
And I said this before, he permucated a million times,
is that you don't build a team where everybody
does the exact same thing.
Everybody owns quality and code soup to nuts.
Some people are going to be better at some parts.
And you want to optimize for the team you have.
To some degree.
And so your orange flag kind of backs into my orange flag.
Because one of the things he talked about,
his first slide, it was towards the end of his deck.
And I think it was titled, specialists are great.
And I cringed.
I was just like, oh.
But the next slide he was talking about,
but specialists need to learn.
So he delivered the same message.
He was dancing around specializing generalists.
And generalizing specialists.
He took it from a different angle.
But that's what he was saying.
Because the problem with specialists
is they're a bottleneck.
They can only do what they can only do.
Now, if they're in a business where what they can only do
is what's really valued, then fine.
It makes sense.
But the problem is when you get into a place where
what they can really do is not what the business needs
from them, then you end up, much like what
I was saying before, the problem on my current team,
you end up focusing on the local optimization.
And that's not what's valuable.
It's not how you bring out the maximum value out of the team.
In a world where you have to aggressively compete
for people's attention.
I like that you brought up bottlenecks in general.
Because when I think I go back to five minutes
in our conversation, going back to figure out
what you want to do first, and then figure out why,
figure out what you have to do to get there.
Don't start just by doing something.
You can even go back farther.
And if the goal is not never, should
be we want to ship every day.
That can be something you do.
The goal should be we want to get frequent value
to our customers.
So in order to do that, we're going to give them
a new build every day that has higher quality and more value.
So every day, every day better.
What is the most, I'm trying to reword,
what is the most value we can deliver every day?
Yeah, and maybe you do that.
So then you think, well, what are the bottlenecks that
stop the screen in there?
We can't do a stabilization period.
How do we get away from that?
We'll fix bugs.
There's a bunch of things you can do.
And don't optimize them all.
Figure out what's the biggest bottleneck.
Optimize that.
Figure out how to get rid of that.
And it could be the specialist.
Well, we can't ship until our performance specialist
gives it his once over, and that takes two hours.
Well, how can we spread that out?
Well, what does he do?
Yeah, exactly.
Maybe we can spread that out.
But there's a huge number of things that have to happen,
or that happened.
Figure out, and maybe that's fine until the day he's sick.
So there's probably a better solution there.
But I really like the idea of just,
let's figure out what's the biggest bottleneck.
Address that.
Then go on to the next one.
You don't need to do a bunch of stuff at once.
Figure out what you're trying to do.
Figure out what's the biggest detriment
from letting you do that.
Fix that.
And then reevaluate.
It occurs to me.
Thinking about what I just said,
where the single most precious thing on any team,
no matter how big or small you are, is calendar time.
Yeah, absolutely.
It's not effort, calendar time.
And what you're really trying to do
is maximize the equation, ROI per calendar time.
Yeah.
Multiple ways of doing that.
But bottlenecks, people who, you know,
single points of failure,
all of these things slow you down.
I have one guy.
So I used to be the scrum master of my team.
I recently hired a guy to my team
that he followed me from my last team
and he took over while it was there.
And I've said, you know what, I want you to do this.
I want you to fight broken window theory.
And I want you to stick to the rules
and be ever persistent.
My job is going to be to spend less time
than I had been, but to make sure
you're sticking to the rules.
Okay.
And one of the things he just realized, it's Friday,
and one of the rules he has to do
is the work always has to move forward.
And so he noticed one of the rails we have on our board
is out of office.
And it's that time of the year
where people are disappearing.
He's like, okay, there's this big machine learning
conference for two days here in Washington
that half of my team is going to.
He's like, okay, just a reminder,
the work still has to go even though,
move forward even though you're gone.
So either you guys got to complete it
or hand it off by end of the day today.
Why would he take that approach?
Certainly the work could wait two days.
Right?
Well, it was because no, it can't.
Calendar time is a single most precious asset.
The work has to move forward.
I truly believe in one of the mantras
I've done on this team is, you know,
we released to our production server
only goes to some internal people.
But we go through a nice promotion process to get there.
And it's like better, better quality,
more value every week.
Eventually that'll be every day,
but it's incremental.
If it's a little better every week or every day,
just a little tiny bit over the course of weeks
and months in a year, it ends up getting hugely better.
So I like the idea of always forward
even because calendar time doesn't stop.
Yeah, I get it.
I like it.
I will say, so specifically to the question,
like the efficacy of combined engineering,
much like Alan's favorite answer is it depends.
If you recognize and view it
and implement the change strategy
as if the change of combined engineering
is a system change,
then it will work and it's fantastic.
If you do it as, hey, all combined engineering means
is Dev and tests are working together.
So we'll just incorporate tests into the dev team.
And that's all you viewed the change is.
It's a living nightmare.
Yeah, there's lots of ways to screw it up, right?
Oh, it's very easy to screw it up.
You could say, I could do a whole podcast
to get a dumb ways to do it.
So we could say, I have a team of 10 people
on a combined engineering team.
And every week, half of those people will be the testers
and they're, we'll do a two week sprint.
And maybe, oh, I know, two weeks,
they have to be testers.
That's one way.
Another way was we do a two week sprint
and we'll develop features for the first half
and then test them in the second half.
And then we'll fix the bugs in the third half.
I don't know.
I have to think through these bad ideas.
Don't do those.
Actually, the first one I was thinking through.
So if you did, you had 10 people on the team, right?
And you find some way like,
hey, the last character of your name, mod two.
If you're odd, if you're a zero or one,
you'll rotate back and forth.
I'm like, that actually could work.
Yeah.
If there was some rotation.
Careful, careful.
If there were test activities, you wanted to, yeah.
Right.
But yeah, no.
The typical, the typical strategy that is happening
is big changes like this.
People are trying to minimize change
instead of trying to maximize the goal,
then minimize the change that achieves the goal.
Though what happens with these changes,
where it can go arise when you think
that the change is the goal.
Right.
Yeah, it's kind of what I was saying before.
Don't just focus on what the change is.
Focus on what you're doing.
You're doing these things for a reason.
And it's lost a lot of times in these changes.
Oh, we're being agile.
Why?
We're doing combined engineering.
Because it's trendy.
No, you're doing it for a reason.
Yeah.
And if you don't know what the reason is.
And the team has to know what that reason is
because otherwise you're never going to get them bought in.
Right.
And you even still may not.
Because people, and I think I've brought this up
on the podcast before.
People, there was a study done years ago,
people are more afraid of change than death.
Right.
It was change, death, and public speaking.
You have to push change forward.
But you have to acknowledge that there's a fear,
that there will be resistance.
And you have to sort of.
And that's the leadership part of that.
There's tactical parts of this which we talked about.
But there's that leadership part of making sure there's
a path that works for everyone.
Yeah.
And we've talked about the last podcast as well.
I stand by this.
I do think natural boring system thinkers are rare.
Perhaps.
I am a developer.
Why do I have to worry about training this tester?
I don't want to just be writing code.
You know what?
Yeah.
I get it.
Hey, let's give me back two of your ladder levels
and you can do that.
Fine.
Are they called?
They're not really called ladder levels anymore.
I don't know what the hell they are.
I think you're older than I am.
I think your birth certificate is wrong.
Let's do Vernon's tip and get out of here.
What was Vernon's tip?
Oh.
So apparently you didn't see it?
I did.
I was giving you a bad time.
So the deal is that, and it's too late now.
So now at the end of the podcast,
the tip of the day is when you start listening to this
podcast, keep the volume on low.
Yeah.
It's a little lob.
Maybe if you can hear that we have fire engines outside.
Because we're on the 20th floor with double pane windows
and we can hear them.
Yeah.
All right.
Hey, everybody.
I'm 50-year-old Alan.
And I am not.
I am 11% younger Brent.
See you later.
Bye, guys.