Hey everyone.
Hello.
I'm Alan.
I'm Brent.
And we're back for another episode of AB testing.
Whoo.
Uh, episode 21, right?
Episode 21.
What podcast can drink in the United States?
It's interesting.
21 second year episode one.
I don't think that'll work next year, but this time it does.
We'll see what happens.
Remember I took a couple of months off last summer, so, um, we'll,
we'll just see what happens.
We also have, uh, other strange stuff going on.
Traditionally we've recorded at eight o'clock in the morning.
And eventually after a year, I bailed on that and said, this is getting harder and
harder as I get older and older and I drink more and more.
So now we're here at 5 PM and he can't stop getting older.
I know.
And who wants to give up drinking more and more?
Right.
So, uh, anyway, thanks for listening and we're excited to have all of our
listeners last year, we talked a lot about our two or three listeners, but now
I think we have eight, maybe even nine, at least nine.
All right.
We'll go for there.
Number one on our list, but it's the three.
Those are the ones that we especially appreciate it because they've
been with us the whole time.
Yeah.
I appreciate every single one of our listeners, especially the ones who
send, uh, questions for our mail bag.
So we don't have to try and think of things to talk about on our own.
Yes.
It's okay.
We haven't, we have enough crazy things happening in the world of
Microsoft that, uh, we can find stuff to talk about.
Yeah.
Although, although we should ask for feedback because, uh, we haven't really
had a really good mail bag and a good while.
I know.
What is up?
No, I could, I could like yell at our listeners right now for not sending us
questions, but then they stopped listening and that would be the wrong thing.
Right.
But so, so they're getting what they paid for, for sure.
Well, we should start the subscription model.
But then if, no, we shouldn't, then we'll lose our three.
Yeah.
But you can send us gifts of, uh, food or,
I'm happy with gifts of tweets.
All right.
We'll go with that.
Yeah.
Even if you guys are saying you like, you guys bore the crap out of me,
please stop talking.
Well, that would be fine too.
Let's just, you know what I'm going to do?
I'm going to take half of this show on the road.
Are you?
I am.
As we've mentioned before, I'm going to be at star Canada in June, uh, in
Vancouver, uh, I'm excited there and I will talk to you there.
If there's enough, if there's interest in anybody, I will record some stuff
and we'll put it on the podcast.
Um, and then I am going to the Netherlands in, oh God,
November, I had to think when, uh, the Eurostar conference is there.
I'm going to attend Eurostar and then I'm giving a keynote at the deep dive
on mobile, which is, uh, the last day of the conference.
Okay.
So I remember, uh, I don't know, three episodes ago that you told
everybody about Canada and you said, this is probably going to be the only conference.
So, but I like, I like Europe and, and I thought it'd be fun to do.
And also because the build conference, Microsoft's, uh, developer conference
was this week and I won't go into a lot of details, but the product I've
been working on that I can't talk about was discussed at build.
Isn't build public build this public.
So you can't talk about the thing that was talked about publicly.
I can, but you know, I want to be very careful.
Did you ever watch Star Trek?
Yes.
Yeah.
Which one TNG?
Yes.
So data was what sort of was he human?
He was an Android.
Oh, he was.
Yes.
Interesting.
And wouldn't it be cool if data or his ilk would work on windows.
Anyway, just hints there for the crowd.
You could have like, Hey, and what if data notice that the, that he
couldn't see what might he go fix?
He wouldn't work when he was on the Klingon.
So yeah.
So, uh, where was I?
So I'm going to be talking a little bit about what, um, our product does at,
uh, and sort of the challenges and how we've addressed them at Eurostar.
I'm excited about that.
And I think that's it.
Did I tell you I was invited to give a talk in Portugal and I had to cancel.
I had to say no, no, you did talk about that last time.
Did we talk about it on the show or afterwards?
I can't remember.
Yeah.
It, uh, I actually don't remember.
I don't remember either.
Anyway, uh, I hope they invite, but I do know that it was soul crushing.
It was, but I'm coaching soccer.
This, yes.
Yeah.
And it's the last game of the season I'd have to miss.
And, uh, so I'm going to coach soccer instead of going to Portugal.
Well, you could just fly the whole, the both teams to Portugal.
Do both.
Yeah.
I know.
Wait.
Yeah.
Uh, no, no.
And it wouldn't even, well, way to be a dad in the coat.
The cost is one thing, but who wants to go on a trip that long with a bunch of
10 and 11 year olds?
Put them on a different plane.
Like houses are problem.
We'll put them on a boat.
Yeah.
I mean, if you can, if you can afford the cost and afford a temporary, uh,
nanny to watch them on the other plane.
Yeah.
Hey, uh, before we go into the real agenda, can we have a another brief
episode of things that piss Alan off about Microsoft?
Alan soapbox.
Dun dun dun.
We'll be taking user requests for the theme song slash sound effect for the soap
box for now, we'll just leave it as nothing exciting.
So early in my Microsoft career, very early, there was a famous event called bed.
Um, and bedlam happened because someone created a test distribution list.
I was in exchange when bedlam.
Oh, do you want to tell bedlam from your side?
No, you tell your side first bedlam was somebody noticed they're on this bedlam
alias and it's not the end of the world to be on an alias.
You don't know about, but they were curious.
So they did, but I will say it wasn't like, it wasn't the exchange
team that created this DLL.
It was someone in it.
Okay.
I'm just saying someone emailed the entire alias and said, Hey,
why am I on this alias?
And the, how large was the alias?
5,000.
No, it was closer to like 20, 30,000 people pretty much contained at that
time, the majority of Microsoft.
Yeah, it would have to have been well, Microsoft full-time was only, was
right around 25,000, I think it's 15,000 when I first started anyway.
Uh, a lot of replies me too.
And anybody that's worked at Microsoft for a second knows that you don't get
yourself taken off a DL by emailing the entire DL and saying, please remove me.
You go to the darn tool and remove yourself.
These reply all fired back so quickly around the whole company that it
pretty much brought exchange down.
Is that right?
It didn't pretty much.
Okay.
I was being nice cause Brent worked on exchange.
Yeah, it brought it down the, the, the, the everybody connecting.
So first it started off with, as Alan pointed out, someone trying to go
and clean up their, their own membership list.
And back in those days, so today we have a bunch of other tooling, but back in
those days, you had to administer it through exchange and the only person
who could administer the DLL was, or the DL was the owner of the DL.
I do remember that now.
Yeah.
So, so this person was going in.
You couldn't remove yourself.
You had to go beg someone to get you off the DL.
So this person went through, looked at, uh, their distribution lists.
They're, uh, I, I never actually found out who started it, but, um, I presume
they were like, I get all this crap email.
I want to stop getting crappy email.
And notice that he was on this deal called bedlam.
So it started off that mail.
Uh, then a bunch of other people came in and said, Hey, remove me, remove me too.
Me too.
And then what made it worse is suddenly everybody's mailbox, pretty much
everybody's mailbox at Microsoft was buried by me twos and then the next
phenomenon started happening, which I don't think you addressed, which is as
the me tooth train kept on going, a new train started up where everyone
was replying all to the thread saying, don't reply off.
Yeah.
So, um, and that one was amusing because how do you get people to stop
replying all without replying all, um, the, with all of this happening and
people coming into work and realizing that their inboxes were filling up.
So everybody, a large portion of people found that their, their inbox quota
gone within an hour.
Uh, the, the, the network at that point in time couldn't handle the load.
So people's emails were being queued up.
Um, so it created bedlam.
Yes, it did.
So fast forward almost 20 years later.
Yep.
And I got some mail this morning.
I'll, I'll read the title for you because it's called, uh, the title
of the mail was testing only please ignore group and blah, blah, blah.
And then the, the context of the message said, you are now a member of the
testing only please ignore group testing only please ignore because I
fancy myself as having an intelligence slightly above a rock.
I thought, Oh, this is a testing thing.
Someone's working something out.
They say to ignore it.
I'm going to do that by deleting it.
And perhaps I should ignore it.
I w I did that.
I thought it was very clear testing only please ignore.
It seems pretty straightforward.
But the next hour with my jaw dropped, watching the reply, all of people
sending mail to this alias asking why am I on this alias?
What is this?
What should I do?
And I'm thinking, I think you should please ignore it.
And luckily outlook has this, uh, feature where you can right click and
you just choose to ignore a thread, which I did, but I'm blown away.
Uh, and I think I was, whenever I see a problem like this, I think about,
you know, I do a little bit of five why I think about why does this happen?
Not why did someone create an alias?
This is a, is a legitimate business reason for doing this testing thing.
But why, why are we seeing this behavior based off of response stimuli?
So I don't know entirely.
Honestly, I think a chunk of it comes back to our heavily email culture.
I think people spend their time.
I mean, look, I was expecting from you and we wrote this up.
I was expecting a high quality rant and now you're going to go like serious.
Look, why isn't it?
Why isn't it just simply because you work with stupid people?
Would you put your pants back on and wait for the answer?
All right.
Wait for me to get there.
Come on.
I like to take it slow.
Daddy wants it.
All right.
He's ready.
Let's go.
Anyway, people spend their, their, I was watching these people reply all and make
cute little comments to about 5,000 people.
Wasn't the 20,000 watching my mailbox fill up.
Just idiotic, idiotic.
And some people thought they'd be clever or apply all with the special little DRM
tag that says don't reply all, which means that our client cashes ahead on
when it's going to look the moment you get near that male, it tries to load all
the DRM stuff and things slow down.
And I just drives me nuts.
And I'm watching people reply to this thing multiple times.
There's 5,000 people on this group.
I'm thinking a couple of things.
I'm thinking one, every person on there, I'm thinking, are you really that dumb?
Seriously.
And then I started thinking, I think there's probably a direct correlation
between your productivity in general and your involvement in this thread.
And that's what got me thinking, you know what?
Some people are so happy and feel like they're productive when they spend their
whole day with their face buried in email rather than actually getting work done.
You know what I actually get work done when I close my fricking email client
and get my face in the computer and do the work.
Get your head out of the email, you fricking idiots.
Well done.
That was a good rant.
Alan, as you've already heard from here, has a face for radio.
But he just got bright purple.
He feels it.
I'm the best looking guy.
I will freely admit that between the two of us, he is the A is not only
Alan, but the attractive one.
Absolutely right.
Well, in comparison.
Yeah.
All right.
So anyway, people are still, you know, I'm gonna have to actually empty my deleted
items because it's filling up with all the, all the ignored threads.
So let's go back to the, the, the, the, the, the serious Alan.
Well, the one that's really trying to decompose why.
Well, I think the decompose why is it, I really feel like people think email is
the most important, I shouldn't, I shouldn't generalize.
There are some people at every company.
I believe email is fantastic for information dissemination.
Unfortunately, and, and not so grateful out of other things.
Unfortunately, our culture is very much around doing everything over email.
And I think this is another symptom of that same cultural inefficiency.
I'm done with the subject.
Do you want to move on?
Do you want to say something else?
Uh, Dylan, I want to say something else, but it just, just lined up that what I've
written on the board lines up very much with what you're saying.
All right.
I don't see it.
So let's go on and you can tell me how to make this perfectly perfecto.
Here's the thing though, right?
This, this particular situation is absolutely the snowball effect.
Yep.
Right.
It, it, it, it progresses exponentially and everybody has their own little
personal tipping point, but once this gets to a tipping point, you have no
choice but to act because now some idiot someplace else is actually having
a negative impact on you.
Right.
You now have to spend a half hour unless you've created a rule or something like that.
It was five minutes.
And when I got the mail, I now have to do extra effort.
I didn't want to do because of a bunch of idiots.
I don't know.
Well, it really is distracting because I, I saw the first mail come in.
I had to Nord it.
Then when I saw the first reply, all I thought, Oh crap, here it comes.
And sure enough, I'm just staring at my screen, shaking my head.
Oh, people, people, people.
There should be a feature in, in, in Outlook.
There should be, there should be a lot of features in our, instead of
replying, there should be a feature where if things like this are happening, you
can click a button and say, everyone should ignore this and it gets aggregated.
It sounds like an exchange feature.
But it should be well, instead of replying all because they're trying to,
they're trying to shut down the noise.
So it should be just a button that says shut down the noise.
And if enough people do it, it just stops.
So when you do right click, ignore thread, if it's like that, but if, but, but
with crowdsourcing enough people say ignore it, everyone ignores it.
It gets ignored.
There, there is a, there is a, um, there's a feature in exchange that
we called the, the message torpedo.
So if you message recall is the official feature, right?
Oh, I love message recall that if I see one of those
in my, my inbox, I make sure I go to the mail before to see what was
recalled cause maybe something good.
Well, what I, so if you, if you, um, if you use rules, I don't know if they've
changed it, but it used to be the case message torpedo only worked against
messages that were in the inbox.
Oh, so one of the things I used to do is, is, uh, the way I cracked at my
rules is I moved the messages I cared about out of the inbox.
That is good.
That's where most of like junk mail stuff.
So inbox essentially eventually became just nothing but junk mail.
And I can just say control all delete an important box that comes like, yeah,
I get it.
Yeah.
Once you move it over, you're like, Oh yeah, I'll let you recall it.
Just as soon as I finished reading it.
Um, yeah.
So Conway's law is what I wanted to talk about, right?
The, the Conway's law was, it was written by a guy named Conway,
Martin Conway.
Uh, thankfully I looked him up, uh, on Wikipedia just before I violated a key
principle of AB testing and that is principles.
Yeah, we do.
We've talked about this before where I actually did some prep time.
We now here, it was only like a minute, but, um, he crafted this, this, uh, law.
And it's, it's a law where he noticed a cause and effect between system
architecture and the communication style.
And notice that these were systems and that he noticed that how an organization
communicated with people is how it's also how the architectures built by
those people communicate with each other.
All right.
Uh, is this kind of like, don't ship your architecture or is this different
than the structure?
I don't know that one.
I don't know who meant that one.
So talk more about this.
Give me an example.
So I get it.
Uh, it's essentially, have you ever noticed that, that at times it's back in the old
days, it is huge improvement sense, but back in the old days that it didn't
seem like outlook and exchange worked well together.
I may have noticed that.
Yeah.
Well, it was because outlook and exchange didn't work well together.
The team.
Got it.
So it's, it's essentially what it's basically saying is that the designs of
the, the code that's being built is going to follow a similar communication paradigm.
Okay.
I believe that as the people anecdotally, I believe that to be true.
Cause I've seen, uh, whether it's products that need to work together, or if you
have a panoramic operating system where the teams don't, uh, another word for
panorama, maybe a Vista.
Where the, uh, no, I understand.
Okay.
You gave me a word.
I was looking at me like, Oh, I used a big word again.
No, I got that one.
All right.
So, um, I know anecdotally, there were some, there were communication
problems on that team that could cause some of this.
Well, you've heard of, um, projects that, uh, you've heard the term
make the product seamless.
I've heard the term.
Okay.
Um, sounds like a marketing term, but go on.
No, no.
So several of our products and we still get feedback on this, particularly
with the windows asset, right?
Those who are, who are software junkies or spending a lot of time with this,
like what's the number one question that, Hey, SharePoint and, uh, I don't know.
Zune, these are both Microsoft products.
How come they don't work well together?
Or SharePoint and Excel or, or Excel and notepad or whatever.
Right.
These folks have a user scenario that they require uses of multiple products
in a row and the, and they do this day in and day out and they notice.
That they'd not integrated together well.
Um, and not only that, if you, if you spend enough time, you can actually
almost physically tell that it was an entirely different team that designed
this, particularly for, um, some of the scenarios.
I can't think of an example, but we have a bunch of them in this company.
Where in order for it to do it, you have to sort of navigate, um, your data
through, uh, multiple teams to accomplish your goal or multiple teams code.
But it feels awkward, particularly on APIs.
Okay.
I get conceptually, you brought this up for a reason.
Yeah.
So the thing I wanted to talk about today, that's sort of the theme Conway's law.
I will log that in the theme part of my data.
We have themes and principles and I think you sound so upclass, but we know we're not.
We're not.
Although I love the white shirt.
I mean, you look all like summary.
Yeah.
Dink.
So it is nice out.
Anyway, I thought I lost it.
I'm still the same low class guy, but you definitely upclass today.
Just, just keep in mind that is, this is the reason it's the podcast, not a video cast.
All right.
So today with the theme of Conway's law, like I want to talk about central
organizations, like what do you mean?
Um, are you familiar with the hub and spoke model?
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
What's your experience with the hub and spoke model works
fantastically every time, doesn't it?
Um, no.
Do you want to describe to our three listeners?
Yeah.
Um, I don't, I don't like spending too much of our podcasts talking about stuff
like, like just Microsoft stuff.
Hub and spoke is worldwide.
It's it's a known thing.
So in my experience, so the hub and spoke is you have a central org that works
with, um, smaller orgs on each team.
So the central org is the hub and you have this spoke swimming out to these,
these smaller teams do the same thing and they communicate back to the central
org, which does a lot of the heavy lifting and maybe the spoke team within
the team is supposed to do sort of the implementation and adaptation for their
specific product, uh, specialization for their product around the same
ideas coming out of the central team.
Right.
So the hub is, is, uh, they generally have a broad scope.
Yes.
Right.
Um, for example, the things I'm hearing all the time lately is, Oh, we're
doing this for the whole company.
Okay.
A very broad stroke and their mission is to provide some key resources and dependency
that the spoke team that enhances leveraging their specific business.
Oh, yep.
Okay.
And you said, and so you agree that these work fantastically.
Um, no, I did not agree that.
Okay.
I worked in engineering excellence, which was in a way, a central
organization for Microsoft.
Yes.
Uh, even it had its which no longer exists at this company.
And it's because they were so fantastic.
It worked perfectly.
And they said, just like I, I have all kinds of soap boxes lined up here to
jump on, but I kind of want to see where you're going first.
Okay.
One of the things that I'm seeing as a, as a problem with central
orgs, and I'm seeing this pop up a lot.
Um, and it is a potential problem where I'm at right now.
Uh, but although I know a solution towards it and I'm intending to improve it.
Uh, but a lot of the times the biggest thing about these central orgs,
because they have such a broad scope, they have, they approach their problem
solving as if they have a mission from God, meaning
just like Jake and Elwood.
No.
Oh, but they were on a mission from God.
They were, but theirs had dancing, singing and band cool like car chases.
Yeah.
But none of that happens here.
Oh, and beer.
Yeah.
What else needs life?
Um, go on.
Uh, money.
Uh, no.
Okay.
Um, so the central teams, they get this feeling of validation that they
exist because their version of God wants them to exist and therefore everyone
just needs to snap to how they intend to solve the problem.
Right.
That's I'm going to, I'm going to hold off till you're done, but yeah, I've
seen that, that viewpoint often.
I'm, I'm waiting for a rant.
Oh, it's coming.
Okay.
Building up.
All right.
Turn to purple.
So here's the situation that I'm seeing.
Um, we have a central organization.
Okay.
And I'm thinking of several, not necessarily any of them that I'm working directly with,
but this has always happened.
They get this mission from God.
They have a very broad stroke.
Now, because they have a broad mission, um, their mission is almost always not only
larger, but significantly larger than what they're resourced for.
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
And the way they tried to scale this down so that they can scale and sustain is by
limiting what the spoke teams can do.
How do they do this?
Because they often, depending on the size of how many spoke teams, they will
do this by saying, no, no, no, you don't know what you need to do for your team.
We do because that's the capability we're lighting up.
So they reduce those capabilities.
They don't ever actually come and ask the teams what they need.
Yeah.
So, and so then we end up having a hub team that's taking forever to
produce something nobody wants.
And we have the spoke teams who are getting pressure to, to actually
provide business value in a time window that's useful.
And so then they start duplicating it.
The hub team doesn't know what the spoke team's doing.
The spoke team doesn't know what the hub team is doing.
And then we end up in this crap-tastic world.
And it's because these guys aren't talking.
It's more than that.
It's more that it's communication as part of it.
Actually, communication is a big part of it.
It's the major part.
I'll argue that later once you're done.
Right.
I don't even know where to start, but this is exactly what I've seen in.
I can't think of a central org at Microsoft, at least for this
hasn't been the case to some extent.
The central orgs, they, you're right.
They feel like they're going to solve everybody's problem for everyone.
And the big problem I see is they get on a, they develop a charter for themselves.
They're good.
We're going to do this and then everybody else is going to snap to it.
Because we're doing this for everyone.
Yep.
And that is the exact wrong way to do a central team.
This brings me back to, um, there are, what I think of central teams and I
think of how they work, uh, I think about consulting and they should be
like a consultant for this area.
They are, I want them to help the other teams do this and they're going to do
a chunk of that work themselves, help them implement, but they're, that
viewpoint should be a consultant's viewpoint.
And when I think of consultant, I think of, there are two very good books
on consulting that talk about this.
One is the Weinberg book, uh, secrets of consulting Jerry, Jerry
Remberg, I might get the title wrong, but another one is great.
As I've mentioned before, I'm a huge fan of the, uh, uh, Pat
Lanchione business fables and his latest fable, which is a couple of years old.
Now he did a, um, this is standard business book in between, but his latest fable,
I forgotten the name, but it is about his consulting business.
Uh, and it's a story talking about how a guy was in a consulting
firm and told me that sounds familiar.
They started off, they did all kinds of prep work and they came into the client
and told them what they should do.
And they felt like they had to come in and be the expert because they
were the consultant or the central org, the, the, the, they really wanted
to be the expert where central orgs are.
And this other company was taking all of their business.
And then, uh, there was some weird thing where the guy had to got transferred
or acquired, he had to go work with these guys and learn how they worked.
And their idea was he couldn't believe they weren't doing prep because they
would take their first consultation meeting and they would go and ask
questions and learn and not try and be the expert, they would ask humble
questions about, well, how would you, what do you actually want to do here
and learn how they could help them?
And this is exactly how to, this is how, if you're a, whether you're a
consultant in a central org or just in sort of some sort of leadership position,
this is by far the most effective way to have influence and be effective.
And it probably ties down to communication as well.
I think too often our central orgs want to come in and be the expert and
solve the problem for everyone and go, we have figured this out for all of
the division or all of Microsoft or all the world.
But what you really want to do in a central org is figure out how you can
help everyone because I am honestly, I should probably not say never, but I
will for now, I've never seen that sort of push of like, we have the right
answer, we're going to tell you what to do work.
What I have seen work is when someone comes in or some org comes in and says,
let's figure out what you're, what you're doing and how we can help you.
We'll take requirements for everybody else.
We'll kind of figure out what everybody's doing.
Then we'll figure out a charter from that, what everybody needs and what
their problems are versus building something and doing the field of
dreams, build it and they will come crap.
Yep.
What is important.
So you talked about a couple of things and I, I don't see the expertise
things so often, cause a lot of times I find that people on the smoke teams
are on the smoke teams are actually better experts, but the thing is these
guys are in a role where there's, so I agree with that.
They're in a role where it's supposed to be, but when they, when under
conversation, what you find out is that failing that it doesn't matter if
I am or not, because again, I have a mission validated by God.
In other words, my executive says it's I win.
I like your consultancy.
Like there's an, there's an implied fix in there.
Right.
Fine.
Go ahead.
Have your mission from God, but the VP, he changed the funding structure.
No, the VP doesn't fund that team directly.
That team he's going to fund the spoke teams extra money and the spoke
teams fund that central team.
It's always weird in a, um, I wish there was a good system.
Maybe I was a better business person.
I figured that out a way to, uh, make those checks and balances work
by funding from within the org.
I think it's a cool idea.
Yeah.
I was talking to a friend of mine in a different group at Microsoft and
they're doing a big reorg and, um, they're moving to a unified engineering.
Um, and he was talking about, well, what do you do in that situation?
I want to go too deep into this.
We've talked about, but what do you do about some of the non-functional
things like performance and reliability and some end to end things?
And, and I, and I gave him a bunch of, you know, ideas.
Here's how you can, you know, incorporate this people use specializing
generalists and, you know, blah, blah, blah.
And he was really adamant about, I really think we need a central
org to run all this stuff.
And all of it.
No, some of it.
I think it makes sense.
Yeah.
And I, and the, there's sort of a hybrid and we're a little off the track of where
you were, but we can come back in a second, but I see how you got there.
I pushed him toward is, uh, he really wants that.
And I think there's, there is advantage in that shared expertise.
Being able to have those, like if there's four guys in an org of like
500 that really know perf being having them like we've done with tag in the
past, having those guys be able to share what's going on like consultants
would, consultants go out for their jobs to come back and they, they can
figure out what's going on or learn from each other.
So there's advantage in that, but you can, but, and you also want
to rotate those people around.
There is a big push in his org, for example, that, well, we don't need that
because every single feature team should have a perfect expert is, is
what one of the, one of the leaders was saying, and that's a nice idea
in concept, but you also need a, a reliability expert and an end to end
expert and a security and privacy.
And pretty soon there's nobody left to actually write the features.
Right.
And, um,
but the one feature that gets written will be great at per
flyability and, um, and security and privacy.
And compliant, et cetera, et cetera.
Right.
It's there, there is a, the decentralization is as
attractive as centralization.
Or it's unattractive.
No, no, no.
So people get seduced into, oh, we should decentralize, we should
centralize and, and there was a, well, it's, well, I read years ago
that it's, it actually is an infinite loop.
If you, if you pay attention to the system, if you pay attention to the system,
it's an infinite loop.
Well, it's interesting and I'm just going to bring us up briefly, but
it's interesting how many of these problems fall back into something
we've talked about probably in every single episode, which is idea
of specializing generalists, generalizing specialists and systems and systems.
Yes.
So it really comes back to that.
So rewind a little bit, uh, but now we were, I have some people.
So we're talking about centralized orgs and how we've seen them fail.
Yeah.
The, the, the, I like what you were saying in terms of, or I piggybacked
off of you in terms of, Hey, let's change the funding structure.
Because the, really the problem is, is that what the central orgs,
particularly again, the ones with the mission from God, who they're
trying to make happy is whoever's funding them.
Yeah.
And something I just thought of is this goes back to the, uh, shipping
your org structure part of this, which is say I have 30 people on my central team.
And somehow I get like, like some more head cat.
Now I have 40 people on my central team.
I'm going to be cranking out a lot of stuff for the whole org.
And maybe even so much that the spoke teams can't adapt to what I'm doing
or consume what I'm doing because I have, because they have like three or
four people doing something, uh, in a consultancy type model, you could.
That's almost never a problem because again, the hub team has such a broad stroke.
The spoke team always goes faster.
You know what?
We've seen that you're right.
The, the only place, the only place where I've seen the spoke team go slower
is when God comes down and says, no, you will take a dependency.
Yeah.
And then, and then the same God tries to figure out why we slip four months late.
While you're talking, I think in more and more about the concept of actually,
we talked about the model of consultancy and what I've learned about
leadership from consultant from studying consulting, but actually doing it,
actually having the hub team, uh, rotate people onto the spoke teams to actually
work there and help really understand those problems and implement and adapt.
And that would take care of the communication piece.
Cause they would have to,
it would certainly take care of the empathy piece.
The, but if you don't, it's much like what we've said in systems and, and
change every time we've talked about systems and need to change behavior,
right?
They're incentivized to do the wrong thing.
The other thing too, that's, that's, that's particularly in my new world where
there is a lot of hub and spokes teams in the data science world.
One of the common things that's also very frustrating for, from the central team.
Let's say you were on the central team and, and the team I was on before
my current one was a central organization.
They're doing all this great work, but no one's using it.
Okay.
And the reason why, of course, is by the time they completed that work,
the spoke teams already solved their problem.
Right.
Okay.
We've all seen that.
It was sighted, seen it over and over and over again.
Now the thing, so I had a conversation with a member of my central team today.
And it was a fantastic one.
And I'm on a spoke team.
They're on a hub team.
We have a similar thing.
I record, I told them, here's, here's how I see the system.
You guys have a broad stroke that requires you to go slow in order to get all of this
stuff in so that can be consumable at your scope.
Right.
It takes a lot of work to do that.
That's going to make you guys go slower.
I need to go faster, but I don't want to reinvent the wheel.
I want to use your data and help to converge on your system.
Primarily because they're doing data warehouse solution or data engineering.
I don't want to go into that space.
I could do it.
That's what I did to my last team, but somebody else is already doing it.
Someone is starting to do it.
I know the maintenance costs over the longterm.
This is their mission.
I'd rather help them.
So I had a conversation with them and I said, look, I don't want
you to view me as your customer.
I want you to view me as your partner and what I want to do.
And I completely understand that there's a very high chance that my priority on
a spoke team is going to be very low on your backlog, but I need you
to understand that I can't wait.
So what I would like to be able to do is when I encounter these situations,
I give you my developer, he works on my scenario and enrich your asset
so that I get what I want.
You get convergence.
What do you say?
And I've done this now three times in this last week and every one of them
was like, wow, what a magical solution.
Where did this come from?
The real world.
It's essentially open source except with a little bit of command
and control bureaucracy overhead.
But what do you think now applied Conway's law, once me and that team
are executing in that style, how well do you think my system's going
to integrate with theirs?
Cause they are actually two distinct systems, but I want to
take a dependency on theirs.
Well, it should improve.
It's going to integrate fantastically.
I'm sending one of my developers over to their team.
Maybe he's a horrible communicator.
Maybe he's a dick.
Uh, he can be a dick, but he's a great, he's a great communicator.
I'm just saying it's not foolproof, but it's definitely going to improve.
He doesn't listen to his podcast, but one of his better friends does.
It'd be interesting to see if this bubbles back.
Eventually someone who gives a crap is going to listen and then
we're going to get an email saying, Hey, it's, it's funny.
Like we've spent a lot of time, uh, picking on my kids on the podcast.
This is the first time I started picking on my employees, but you
know, one of the things he was giving me crap just an hour ago.
So screw him.
Yeah.
All right.
Did you have more on that?
No, I'm good.
All right.
Anything else you want to talk about?
No.
And we're out of time.
I guess we are.
So thanks for listening again.
Thanks all.
All right.
We will talk to you soon.
I'm Alan.
I'm Brent and we'll see you next time on AB testing.