I'm Alan. I'm Brent. I let Brent sit down barely before starting today, but we're back for episode
20-20-20-20. I used to know how to do it in
zwei one
wait ein zwei
Yeah, no, I've forgotten how to say it. Okay, the the multilingual version of A-B testing will not be releasing this week
We're on episode 22. I forgot for a moment, but now I remember and good to see you Brent
Good to be seen by you Alan
So we get shall we get going? Yes. Hey, I read some I got some mail this week
And I'm just gonna read the first sentence of it. I want to see what you think
I like reading mail to Brent dearest at no, we're sorry wrong one wrong one
The mail says with agile becoming more and more popular
It seems like everyone is running iterative development these days
It goes on from there. Is that it? No, it goes on from there. So but that one opening sentence
Kind of pushed my buttons in a way that probably isn't obvious to a lot of people
No, it's obvious to me it is but you are not a lot of people are you? No, you're not a lot of people
So what by body weight? I'm at least two ah
Shush
Shush shush what caught your ear there are mr. J
There are oh to do you have a doctorate not yet. I can't call you. Dr. J
You'll just be mr. B
So what was it that pushed to what what kind were actually two things that bothered me about that sentence
It was a short sentence. Please tell me that read the sentence again. Oh damn it. I mean, okay sure
All right with agile becoming more and more popular. It seems like everyone is running
Iterative development these days. Yes, the two things that bothered me is
this idea of
You should go with agile because it's more popular. Ah, yeah and
This idea that agile and iterative are the same thing
Yeah, the second one really it's funny
You mentioned both of those because the second one is what caught my my ear initially and said not of I cry foul
And we'll go into that in a minute, but it's interesting
I just polished up my keynote for Star Canada a
Couple days ago yesterday day before and we lose your submission. Oh the submission was a while back
this is a slide deck, but one of the things that
Kind of came to me as I was putting this stuff together is in the takeaway is you don't make changes like this because they're popular
Or because you know, they're interesting you have to have a reason why although it just for many many reasons talking about leadership
But yeah, really important agile is popular. Let's do agile. It's a really
Stupid thing to do and a great way to screw up agile and a great way to make crummy software. It's
So I actually just before here Alan
I I did another coaching session and so I have a variant of agile that I teach people
It's a two-hour training session and literally I finished another session an hour ago
Okay, the very first slide I spend 15 minutes discussing. What is agile and
These people who
Push it forward as a popularity thing helps to encourage it to becoming a fad and it makes it a lot
Freaking harder for me to get these people to understand that it is not a religious
Doc a dogma. It's not a fad. It's actually the scientific method in action and
And it is makes it so much harder to open
Minds when you already have a prevailing belief number one that it's a fad or number two
You have dumbasses in this company who read the first chapter of the scrum book and look at the first paragraph of the other
Agile manifesto and then come back and tell me it's about
Iterations well, it's funny
We're gonna we're gonna go way off from the weeds and come back and get on this
That's a very important point
But while you were talking I was thinking in doing some research for my talk
I came across this a couple articles sort of bashing agile, but for different reasons and some good reasons
I'm not but one started off very interesting
Interestingly said that my team's doing agile. I think it's effin stupid
But I want you guys to help me out. It's not an as some agile forum
Then he goes as I understand agile. It's this and he described scrum
Yeah, which I thought was interesting
Which you know again scrum is not agile
well
Implementing scrum and you know accurately is it is a way of implementing agile
There is a way of implementing scrum that is completely non agile. Absolutely. Yeah, exactly
the just because you did did
70% of scrum
Doesn't mean you're agile. Yeah, and the other thing I thought while you were talking was I
Would bet nine out of ten agile coaches are people that whether they're called agile coach whether they help their team with agile
not I would say nine of ten agile advocates wish there was a new word for it because the agile ward has been so screwed up and
bastardized well there
We we have got to have already talked about this
No, I don't know. I don't know that
Let's let's what the point I wanted to get to and the point I promise I in the strategy actually we could go back from
year one
Shut up, shut up. Yes. So yes, there is and I'm thinking through like the very first thing
the first slide
No, second slide first slides the goal slide second slide is what is agile?
Because I before I go and they talked about everything else. I want to get these guys out of their head that
Agile is iteration or agile is scrum or agile is some other thing that it's not
Okay
You're I really wanted to have like a big bang on what agile was I'm gonna let you give your get to the you
What is agile you have agile?
Well, um, can I has agile put in the macat sure
Not one with the cat meme. I've got actually real work to do
I don't I don't have the time to spin like you do trolling for anyway
Moving on
The first thing I do actually when I do these presentations I now have a I learned of a game called the penny game and
It's it's basically I put a simulation
Of the team through three different phases of how to improve their throughput and the first thing is I set them up at teams
I actually give them ten coins of different denominations and I
And usually I have multiple teams today. I had three teams competing against each other
Ten coins of multiple denominations and they put them in a cup. The first thing is that they have to
The output is every person on the team has to have recorded the result of a coin flip
But they have to execute that coin flip in denomination order
So quarters before dimes times before nickels blah blah blah. Okay. Now the first path I bike. Okay, it goes in the cup
First person has to flip all coins and record it put the coins back in the cup and then pass it to the next person
And you do that through the team. I call that waterfall mood. All right, okay, and it is
the
I've now done this several times and every time I go through the first phase
I will tell you I have done this like ten times and I I personally hate phase one
Today the fastest team got got through there were only four people got through it all in three minutes, but it felt like 15
It was just like oh this thing is dragging on
Then I
Modify it and I tell them
Okay. Now what you're gonna do is one coin at a time you flip a coin
You can then pass the coin to the next person and they can go through the chain teaching them flow like a combo flow
Okay, okay. Everybody does the quarter. Everybody does the dime. All right
First person starts he flips his coin records it. He can now pass the coin to the next person
They can flip and and now people are
Parallelizing and it goes a much faster and usually that takes about a minute and then the third phase what I do is I say
Okay. Now teams we're gonna give you one minute to discuss your strategy and then we're gonna do it same way last time
That I only care about these two outcomes
That coins are done in order first and everyone has a result recorded and
that third phase
everybody improved
another
20% off of their prior time now the three minutes went down to a minute
Like it cut it in a third and then there was another 20% off of that minute
and
that last phase is is intended to introduce them to
how you can prove things if you work as a team work together towards the goal versus
What we talk about all this time the the
groups of specialists
conveniently classified under the name team
Drives me nuts
the
That should be what I call phase two now specialists specialists under flow
now the next thing I do is I said
agile and
learning
go hand-in-hand and
agile is the ability to
adapt to
Adapt quickly to changing phenomenon
That's one of the things iterations doesn't do right? We've talked about it here before
I
Know we've talked about it because I called him out and then he talked to it was Steve Rowe and he talked about it
At our next lunch. He once told me
Windows is agile. We do iterations
right and and
It's and that was an important insight because with his and my conversation allowed me to understand
What is actually wrong with the word that there's power in well, I think two things happen one is there's this blind
Ignorance or belief that iterations
Equals agile but some people I know believe
definition of the word iteration has included well you you reflect and adapt at the end and
So it's they're still wrong. Yeah, but the point I like to bring up is I worked on I just got mail my
Invited me this September to the win 95 team reunion. They're having 120 year union. Okay, that's my first project at Microsoft
It was mine, too
Uh-huh
Would you work on it when 95 I was on the at work fax team a little Oh a little stupid come something. Yeah
Something nobody used I worked on networking
I made sure you could connect to network networks. So that is relevant today as your fax machine
Yeah
Anyway, we were we were on iterations
We had three-month milestones and sure we knew the work that was planned for each milestone, you know a year in advance
But there were iterations. Yeah
well, and the thing is
like
Kanban, which is in my view significantly more agile than scrum is I
agree
There's not an iteration in there. I know
It's a continuous flow
now
when everyone thinks of iterations like that they
Think of every sort of PR material you'll you have ever seen on agile, right?
I'm currently visualizing in my head Reese's build measure learn loop
Okay
Mm-hmm, and and I think what's happening to these people are just looking at this thing not reading the words not processing and just going
Oh, it's a circle must be iterations
Right and they're missing. Yeah, like learn
One of the ways I tell the story I'm not going to mention the team today
But I've seen situations where it's both basically build measure build measure build measure build measure
Right. That's a loop too it is but it's not agile
not adaptive and
What you're talking I thought of and hopefully even though we haven't actually directly getting kind of the point between iteration and being adaptive and adaptive
and learning and
Elizabeth Hendrickson's litmus test for agile and I'm gonna probably
Badly paraphrase this but I'll get close is something very close to
Agile is delivering frequent customer value at a sustainable pace
It's it's and nothing in there quite that but very close get close enough to know that that and I like it because that doesn't
imply iterations it implies delivering value and
Imply a sustainable pace, but the important thing that gets missed
it from her side
Isn't in her sentence, right?
That what you're gonna say it's implied. Okay, because what she says is delivering customer value
Not delivering code to customer. Ah
Yeah
Let's take a moment to ponder that how many teams you bet on the delivered value
Versus delivering features that may or may not be used how many teams have I been on? Yeah, I could think some I've been up most
of
Matter of fact
It's made a it's made me it
It's made me it
It's it's been a brand of mine
Because of that
People call me out and want me to come in and work on their team
because I they view me as having a customer focus and
And
There was a
buddy of mine that now works outside of Microsoft and he was describing a story where like I
wish you had been here to do this because this the project if you had managed it it would have been much faster much sooner and
People would be happier. Right? It's um, I mentioned this on the podcast before what the the variant then shut up
People can go back and listen to all the podcasts. They're not gonna okay fine finish you just finish you just did the stats for that
One of the key things that I have added to the variant of agile that I teach now is
After it's released most most scrum boards. It goes check in done
Okay, not mine. It's it's checked in and
Then it's released
Then it's validated by the customer
Then it's done. I'm not gonna call it done until I've proven that the requirement assumptions
Of why we built this code are proven true
We built this code because we intended it to add some value to somebody before we really progress further on the plan
Or maybe not before I'm not gonna necessarily block
But I want to get that out get that validation done
Because if that's gonna negatively impact the rest of my plan, I want to know now
Yeah, I like that a lot. I've worked with orgs where the
Getting that feature done
Was the ultimate goal?
Done and checked in and and not much beyond there. There was with it's done
And I know I'm gonna have to fix a bunch of bugs and make it work and add some fit and finish
But for now it's done and for me, it's not even close. I
have a
Litmus tests I use quite often and it sort of discusses
Three common software development paradigms that I see a lot
first and foremost
waterfall
What you see is that they're trying to constantly ask the question is the plan on track
It that's it all we care about. Did you get this thing done by this date?
I wouldn't even necessarily I agree with that and that's the iterative model
Yes, the only the only part I would question on that is
another thing pushing my buttons is waterfall and
Agile are not necessarily opposites and very few teams actually do true waterfall
But which is as it should be
Okay, but I but I get the point I get the point
Alan and I talks about this a lot
That particular topic right the thing is is
Waterfall true waterfall was written in this this white paper. I know Alan remembers the other yep
But no one actually executes it so so no in the paper
He's not a little dangerous and prone to error no, but waterfall today is whatever the serial
Fazed gated sure crap that people used to and it's gonna be very similar
Scrum in 10 years is not gonna be what Schwab wrote. It's what the society has turned it into. Okay, sure
But waterfall is the plan on track
Agile is
Focused on is the plan correct?
That the important thing there, of course
For I haven't had to deal with this a long time
But when I first started dealing with this people were saying Oh Agile is just about doing whatever you want no plan
no, it's about having a plan but not but building the plan in as lightweight as
Possible and a high ROI plan and building in that learning which is really important like we're going planning to we're gonna do this
And then we're going to learn and adjust and constantly
Evaluating that the plan is still correct and if it's not shift are we doing the right thing or are we building software?
That's wonderfully functional that nobody will use and there's a third one
which I
Call Jedi and this is the teams. It's an acronym JDI God
These are those teams that ask the question plan
Just do it
We don't need no plan for those in the software industry the the typical word
Is cowboy?
Jedi teams and cowboy they're one of the same. They don't need a plan
Not only the PM's all
Potential the next Steve Jobs, so is the dev team
We're always right. We don't need a plan. We're smart. We'll get it done. I have never met a cowboy dev team
that
Wasn't chock-full of five-star devs just asked them
Of course
the
Yeah, do we cover both of those popular? I don't know. I don't know where you're going with that. Oh
so the main thing I wanted to cover was
iterative and adaptive and with that and to me agile is adaptive that learning part is
Absolutely critical and just being iterative has nothing to do with agile
Well again, I hear that the groans from the audience that haven't heard this through the time machine through the internet already
Yes, just because you iterate doesn't mean you're agile
I've been on many very non agile opposite agile products that were iterative and you don't have to iterate to be agile
Yeah, that's exactly and that's the main point I wanted to make I think that main point is can you adapt and learn?
you do have to be iterative to be waterfall and scrum and
You don't have to be agile to be waterfall and scrum
All right, and apologies if you're listening to this and I made fun of your email, but it did lead to a good topic
So I know you meant well, so you can actually be agile in the traditional waterfall method as well
That's much harder to learn when you have phase delivery
But if you think about the example I said on the penny game, right?
So the problem is is that each individual?
Completed their all their work before they got it done if they broke it into the smaller pieces
Wait, they turn it into a food. You just said they completed their work before they got it done
I'm sorry each individual so I had teams of four and then no to answer your question
I didn't hear what I said. Yeah teams of four and let's say those teams are four were
I don't know make something up a
Design guy a PM guy a dev guy and a tester guy
Right what we see nowadays is you have design complete
spec complete dev complete test complete and
All of this work gets chunked as full completeness in order to get to done a simple fix
Cut that crap out do one small item
Design gets it done hands it off to PM
he works on that while the design guy starts working on his next thing and
Shift it through and if you do that you can turn turned waterfall into something significantly more agile and perhaps even
Agile that's what you described is very close to Kanban. It's exactly combo
Except even then like so did you just say Kanban is waterfall?
No, you can you got you can waterfall with but by letting I'm just trying to shove words in your mouth piss you off
But the other thing to also keep in mind
Based on the context that we're talking here, right? You can do Kanban and not be agile. Oh, yeah
I can see that right you can just constantly flow if you're not evaluating that if if what you're doing is correct or valuable
This is again why Elizabeth's thing is so so important and it's so easy to gloss over
Yes, I agree and I was gonna say something else clever and important, but I forgot what it was
So we're gonna go on to item two, which I don't know what it is. Why don't you kick it off Brent? Okay
If you think about it in terms of power and words
Like here's here's another phenomenon that I've noticed we've talked about in the past. So we've talked about
me joining the data science team
And we've also talked about
Data science as a buzzword. I think most listeners remember the high school
sex metaphor
But the thing that's interesting is even the people with the title
Aren't really trying to improve themselves
What you're seeing is a lot of people spinning up
Reporting only teams and saying oh well, I built a report that's data science. Yeah
It's an insight
no
They ever share with you my last manager one of the metrics one of the KPIs he wanted to judge me under
was TTI
Time to insight and I said wow
That's a fantastic one. I can
Completely understand what you're trying to say because he wanted me to help shorten the velocity of insight production
But I just need one thing he's like after hearing me being so positive of his feedback
He's like, yeah, what?
What's an insight? How do I measure it? How do I know if it occurred?
The
When when you get that little tingly feeling in the back of your neck, that's an insight. I'm
One of the things that's happening right now
there's there's a
So people are just producing reports and it's sort of the build it and they will come
Hope and then what they're discovering not very adaptive. It's not
Hey for those of you who are in this space, I'm gonna share with you a very critical
KPI that I've developed
That I suggest that you use if you're in this world where you're essentially doing report production and not necessarily doing
Analysis and helping to try to shorten insight
Value or insight production and tie together relationships between key variables if you're just doing reports
instrument your reports and
measure one thing and that is the number of people who are using your report the day after
The key executive review or whatever the hell you built the report for
Alright, because the fact that because they found it useful it would be your metric there, right?
If you finding yourself building reports that are only used the day before
Essentially for slide where then you're not really
Providing value. These are reports that a PM you need to figure out a way to
Those things done. Let me let me one up you or go a different angle here
I think the build it and they will come thing drives me crazy. I work with orgs that are
They love this they want to build the thing that's for everyone, but they don't unveil it until it's not ready yet
We got to do more here and my approach is if I'm if you ask me say hey Alan
Can you do a report for me that shows the food bars the fish bats?
But a bit of that I don't go yeah, and I'm gonna draw it on the whiteboard for you
You watch look something like this and you know, no, I'm gonna erase some stuff and I go like yeah something like that
It'd be good. That okay. I got feedback from my customer
I take a little picture with my phone then I go to the web browser and it gets them Excel and I mock it up
I don't even use real data
I make a picture of it and I and it's and maybe it's it's pulling like mock data from a database something very simple
I put it in a web page and I go hey brand is what we talked about. He's gonna check it out
He goes. Oh the fizzle puzzle doesn't I rather have that be more important and a little feedback from him
And maybe some of his peers look at it, too
I start spreading it out and they go yeah, it's pretty I think I could use it like this
And the fizzle boss could the food die to the flu die
So we get that happening and then actually get some pull in some real data
I know there's a lot of normalization they want to have down the road
But I want to make sure we get all the pieces in there
So it isn't until we've gone that far that actually I'm not looking for I don't care about insights yet
I care about usefulness. I think the insights will come once that becomes useful. I do one before you go too much further
I do one thing different. I do everything you just did but I do one thing first I
Ask what are you gonna do when you have this report? I do that's what I asked. I do two things I say
Who do you expect to use this report and what actions do you expect them to take upon?
Viewing the data. Yeah, I do those things too, but I got so excited about starting off
With the with the implementation being something stupid simple
That's you can do in five minutes figure out if you're on the right track or your understanding is correct
But yes, and there's the the Jim Moore question. Let's say you had this then what do you do with it?
That's a great. Let's say you have this this is the report. Yeah
Very question. I almost always ask I
Say almost sometimes I forget but rarely I always ask for something if any significance
So what are we gonna do when we have this so I get some idea of the user case
Anyway, I'm going to it's gonna be very simple until I don't need to start adding things that I think are clever and interesting
and and pretty stuff until I
Actually think it's going to be useful for a large part of the audience that was designed for and I can iterate through that and learn
Very very quickly. Yep. I'm undergoing that right now with a with a project that I just picked up
I just hate to go build it and they will come approaches cuz they happen so often
The the the initial approach so
One of my peers has fallen ill he's he's better again
but he had been designing this thing and
Basically what he had been doing is getting the requirements from from p.m. And when then I went I saw this
I'm like first question. I saw the design from RPM and I said who's the customer of this?
What decisions are they trying to make off of this data?
And what actions are you gonna take based off of those decisions? And then I came back a day later with a new design
optimized
for
That decision-making process I said hey look if this is what you're trying to do with the data
I can simplify that for you
It's frustrating to me on the on the report side
Because what we see is a lot of PM's still doing this this requirement driven model. Mmm
I have this awesome intuition and I'm awesome and I'm just gonna write up a document with the
Requirements and send it to you and then you implement it and I'm like look dude
I'm a data science team not a dev team you try that crap someplace else
Okay
In data science. I want to know what your decisions are and I'll happy to help you iterate towards them the
The problem is even the PM
Doesn't know what the decisions they're trying to do. They're not identifying the goal
This is why that key PI I was mentioning is really critical
Yeah, it can be shown up in in in this executive review and it essentially ends up being a bunch of vanity metrics
But if you want to drive real value, you want to drive real change you want to accelerate the business
you need to
Make sure people are
Acting on what you're doing and you need to make sure you're providing the right action ability into your design
This is a why I think actually agile and data science are critical that they go hand to hand
But the topic I wanted to talk about is the next thing
That's happening is as these teams are building all these reports and not measuring that no one's using them
They're they're beginning to understand the maintenance costs of keeping all these reports that no one uses online
Because what they did is they followed your model for for building a prototype
Except they call it the product and I see I see a lot of these folks that may not have a lot of expertise in
Data science yet, but they came from friggin dev and they suddenly just forgot oop
Like okay, you got the prototype now we need to harden this and we need to operationalize it
So why are you trying to?
Create a lot of the projects I have
Literally have thousands of input streams and instead of trying to manage this like in an async model
They pull all these input streams together and they wait for all of them to coalesce and all the data has to be there
And then they're gonna aggregate it up and such that if one fails
No report that week if if and of course because you have so many data streams
one fails every day and
Just befuddled that they're forgetting this the how to design
The second thing is I'm finding that
again the power in words
Data science being a buzzword. That's absolutely a buzzword and something
If it means nothing if the current Microsoft culture continues to persist it'll eventually mean something
That's entirely opposite of how the rest of the world uses it
Right am sorry world
Sorry in advance
It's our fault
We view it as innovation
but things like
normalizing your data
Doing data conformance
These are concepts that are key to data engineering to be able to light up data science and
And people are just skipping over these things
In I had a I had a long discussion yesterday
Where I had to sit down and explain to them
Normalization does not mean everybody uses the same schema now
Alan I don't know that you if you have my data engineering skills
But I do not in this case trust me it doesn't and if ever that word comes up in database you call
Unky Brent and I'll help you. Thank you, Brent. What's the database?
It is a it is any file that contains data
Sure is
All right
We're doing a bunch of ranting today. I was gonna say something very cynical about data science and about what you're talking about
But I'm feeling good. I want to move on and
Let's jump right into vanity metrics, but we're not gonna talk about vanity metrics, but Brent wanted
I sent Brent some mail this week. I
Finally for the first time ever went to look up the downloads for our podcasts and
Gave Brent the numbers, but am I wonderful provider lost all of my downloads stats for 2014 and 2013
So we only have 2015
Brent
Seem to think there was some insights there
I thought the numbers are kind of small they the variance isn't that big
They sort of taper off and in orders that make sense to me
But wait the order makes sense to you. I
Yes, it does the order of the counts the order well
Let's talk about what you think is an insight and I'll explain to you why I think it is
It is within the realm of normalcy
Okay, that's that's not like a good way to do this sure. All right. So what what was something that you thought was
What popped out as you as well? That's interesting there
There were two things that I found interesting and and I will say the first one I would I would agree with you
When we're talking about statistically interesting we're talking about
the degree to which
Random chance
Also explains the behavior
Yes, or that would I guess be?
Statistically non-interesting right right and there are methods to to sort of show
how much random chance could explain this relationship that's being observed versus a
relationship being there and you're right in terms of
The numbers are are relatively small
I think the highest number in the list you gave me was 400
No, if you look at partial streams plus full downloads the top one was probably closer to 600. Okay, I
Didn't even look at the partials. I just looked at the the full list. I actually interpreted as a subset
I didn't understand that it was
Yeah, it's weird. We're the way those are tracked. Yeah
So that data that that Alan had was it showed
how many people did a full download and then apparently in
Addition to those how many started listening and then stopped and then what he was saying is that some total was somewhere around 600
Now the first thing that I noticed we had just finished episode 21
Mm-hmm and episode 16 and 17 were in the were in the top, right?
Right, they've been out longer more chance for download
Sure completely great
the
And it could also have just been
statistical chance
but one of the things that I did wanted to do is see if there was a correlation between
Say links there could be other in additional information
It could be random chances as you describe, but it could also be additional relationships that we're not paying attention to
For example, how many people are linking to episode 16?
What did Alan write in this blurb is is is search engines?
Capturing that blurb and it's redirecting traffic there. Yeah, I have none of that data you do
I I don't have a I haven't looked at any of that data
the but the the one pattern that I found the most interesting and
And again that one because the numbers are so tight and they're small. There's a very good chance. It's just random chance
That's that's that's my gut
But what I have observed
Particularly with blogs
Although you did the aggregation for the last month
The sum total for the last this is no, this is the total since January 1st. Yeah
the one thing that I did notice though is
episodes one two three and four
were relatively high in the list and
episode five was the bottom one and
That shows me we have a lot of brand new listeners that haven't got all the way to episode five yet maybe
Or they listen to the first four and said I've had enough of this crap, right?
Or hey, let me skip the current events or whatever, but I do think that that is an interesting pattern
it's not what I would have expected looking at the data and
the the difference between number four and number five was
Five or six times higher
episode four and episode one. Mm-hmm. Right so
Something is going on there. The is there or is it just random? I don't think it's random
The other data that I have is is both you and I link to the podcast from our blog sites
Yeah, and I do look at my blog stats and I know
Introduce the the blog I wrote introducing a B testing is
Consistently one of the higher items in my list. So I actually think people are finding
Episode one via search engine off of our blog and going and starting
listening in episode one there's an
Then get to four or some of those folks sort of get to episode four and then they
Go off and do their regularly scheduled day and then they forget to circle back to a B testing maybe maybe so let me
Give you some quick data here on the fly and then we'll go on from here. So that's a hypothesis
So let me give you a little bit of this. So in January our top downloads were for episodes
16 14 15 pretty spread out one shows up somewhere down around number seven and nothing interesting there
But February gets a little more interesting if I remember maybe it was March
February is interesting in that our top episode 17 came out that month then three one two and four follow it in order
So there are this tells me we have maybe new listeners showing up. Yeah, I don't know that would be my hypothesis. Where's five?
Five five is five is far down there
I think maybe those I don't know why I'll check episode five over time
See what happened or what we talked about the made episode five so bad when I look at March
It's 18 19 and then two shows up and then 17 11 4 so that one not as much
One farther down the list and then real quick look at April and May and then we'll
Wrap up here. So in April it was 2019
three two and one and then in May
To cap it off here
It was 21 and one two and three show up wait on the line
That kind of tells me my my insight my hypothesis from that that again an athlete
March April we got some new listeners who started listening and that's and that's why those those earlier episodes started popping up on the downloads
March was our one-year anniversary. I don't remember I did
I did a blog post in January
All right, you know what I think we just contributed to a lot of partial downloads as people stop streaming our episode right now
Anyway, I
Want to see more of this data because I think I think
We can help to defend the the honor of data science against what will this will be that we won't return to this for a while
Don't worry those who are scared away, but we'll
We'll come back to this once we have some more
Data and see how we'll see what it means. You're gonna give me the data. I wish I could export it to Excel
The weasel. All right. All right. I'll give you your own special password that I will use with my keystroke logger
Okay
All right, I'm not Brent I am all right. See you later. Bye guys. Thank you