So I'm Alan. I'm Brent and together we do something called the A B testing podcast
We've done it for a couple years now pushing two years
almost two years and
Just for fun today. We're going to take a recording of this and make this episode 29 of our podcast and
Evan will send you a link. I'll edit out the parts that are that Brett will be probably inappropriate at some point
So we're gonna cover that
Honest, I'll be honest. Yeah, okay
So the way we do our podcast is the way we're going to do our presentation today
You don't see a big slide deck behind us
you see some things we're gonna talk about about surviving software in the
Being software engineer in the 21st century fancy fancy title to get you here
Although I know the pizza is what you got you here
We're gonna talk about we talked about a B testing and cross that off
We'll talk a little about what's changing in software engineering
then we're gonna talk a lot about how you survive and adapt and change and the process is people in tech and then most importantly
We'll take questions at the end, but even most er
No, yes
Good thing I can edit the podcast right even more and more importantly is that this is gonna be totally interactive if you
You don't have to wait for the end to have questions
Given that we don't have slides to go back and forth on and we just we have notes on things we want to talk on
but if you like I don't get that or tell me more about that or
In my group we have a situation close to that but it's different what we do here totally interrupt us and
After we're done yelling at you will answer the question to our full extent work for you, right?
Yeah, that works the you shouldn't you should feel welcome to interact, right?
We have a list of topics both Alan and I could probably do for every one of these bullet points
I think we could probably do a whole day talk mostly brand. He talks a lot. My job is to keep him in line. I
Do blow VA? I apologize
So
If we hit on a topic that seems particularly relevant like speak up, it's okay. If you want to go deeper, that's fine
Well, we'll go broad across this space as we go through it
But we encourage interactivity
Alright, so if you want to talk a little bit about do a plan here. What's going on? Yeah, it's right there
Red my also our podcast is very low budget and we refuse to prep and we're well known for
Ad we actually prepped very well
Brand has a nice list here again
My job is to fold three fold one give you some good information
To keep Brent in line three give Brent a bad time any chance I can
And he does all of those quite well. So shall we start by enumerating kind of what's what's different?
This like 20 years you've been so let's let's talk about ourselves a little bit. I don't like talking about myself
Okay, I'll talk about you. Okay. All right, so
Both Ellen and I have been in the software industry for 20 plus years. I'm not as old as I look
He's the way around he's older
the
Most sorry, I'm gonna interrupt you. Yes
I
When you should that one just for those that maybe didn't hear the question was what were punch cards like
There's a certain gesture I could use but
No, I've been doing this for 20 years
I'll jump in so
You all mostly look pretty young some of you probably weren't born in the early to mid 90s
90s kids raise your hands
Yeah, yeah, I'm old. So when your parents bought a computer in the early 90s it came with some music software
All right
No, actually you had to buy a sound card separately
So it came with some software from a company called MIDI soft and that crummy software. I tested it
That was my intro. So I was beyond punch cards. I got to use I was pre win 3.1
I got to use Windows 3.0 with multimedia extensions and that was my beginning
I joined Microsoft about two years after that and I've been there ever since all right brand blah blah about yourself. I'm done
Good question, by the way. Yeah, fantastic question. Let's have some more of that
In on the podcast like he he does use those hand gestures just interpreted it as your number one
That's that's what I do
So we've been in this
20-plus years the majority of the time we've been wearing the the title of
test
Alan's been test director
Up until about five years ago. I was middle management and test
and
Then Microsoft began to go through a transition. Okay
You want to talk I was gonna but I'll stop okay
Alan and I during that period of time even up until the transition we had been talking about this transition
I think what three years before it actually pulled the trigger because a lot of come it was happening in a lot of places
It's been sort of a slow wave across the industry. So it has
as part of that
Microsoft not only went towards unified engineering model, but they're shifting much more towards using agile practices
Yes, and in a lot more
Data stuff so five years ago I transitioned into a dev role into Bing
I was a dev manager and not that team
And then a couple years later
I've now transitioned into a data scientist role. I'm currently a data scientist manager
For the Azure compute team at Microsoft
Also in that same period of time
I've gone deep in in agile. I am a certified
agile trainer I
We don't like neither of us really care about certifications, but it does give me permissions to train other trainers
And Alan does stuff too I give a lot more detail. So no, but you know, the data scientist is
Anybody it's a statistician who lives in Silicon Valley
But all right. Yeah, so Brent talked about I'm gonna move on a Brent talked about some of the
Stuff he's doing some of stuff Microsoft is doing but
It's important to think about why
teams and companies and organizations are moving to using more agile stuff and and
maybe unifying engineering teams and blurring the lines being what Devin tests do and a lot of that is because
people see the value in shipping faster and
And I'm a big fan of a book called the lean startup you guys read the lean startup anybody
I know Evan hasn't cuz he doesn't do anything
but
There's I promise Evan. I give him actually five jabs today who in here was on Evans interview loop
Nobody. All right. Okay. Can we talk talk later? Yeah
I
There's a lion I thought horribly paraphrase from lean startup
But you just don't get value from your engineering effort until it's in the hands of customers
So if you can do that
Get get customers your software
Faster in a safe way where you can roll back if you screw things up and in a way
but you have the potential to learn from them there's all kinds of good things that come from that and
So I guess that drives a lot of the why on getting value to customers
They stick with your product longer because you're getting continued upgrades and value
All kinds of good things happen. What are some other reasons?
So it's not just speed
Also from from Reese's book
adaptability so it's
A lot of folks view agile as about oh, we got to go as fast as possible
It's that's a wrong way of looking at it
You have to be as adaptable as possible and when you are you end up going fast as possible
Okay, it's an important distinction
Adaptability right now is a huge business imperative in in any service environment your competitors are
Very likely, but let me put it this way. So you guys who's your number one competitor?
Someone speak it out who?
Zillow, okay. I've heard of them. Yes
How long how much time does it take to some are for one of your customers to come to Redfin and
Decide to go to Zillow
Even even that long
Right, right. So I hope this is going somewhere
switching what the switching costs in an internet enabled service world is
Like that so you have to constantly stay on track
You have to constantly adapt to what is the value that your customers are getting out of your product
The
World that we used to live in 15 years ago
Where you could win by being the first to market doesn't work anymore you could win by
Microsoft strategy used to be
We had a whole lot of money. So we would let our competitors go find the successful market and
Then we apply our resources and then go steal it from them, right? So we didn't have to invest in their indeed
Hey, didn't you work in Bing? How'd that work out for you?
It's still ongoing
But I was the last test manager for the the Zune
PC client how about workout for you not quite as well. Did you work on Ken also?
Actually, yeah, I did
No, so Ken the Ken product unit had been dead, but there was one deal we had with Verizon
I ended up being as a test manager at the time
I was actually the last person to do a test pass on kin because there was no way I was gonna have any of my
team do this
Kin I'll paraphrase and put up on the internet a
Can I call it a failure? Yeah, I a colossal failure
We actually ended up making money with
Microsoft's gonna make this phone for tweens
And they're very excited about how lots of cool features and it made it almost a week or two in the stores where they pulled them
All in it was essentially a smart dumb phone
So it was a dumb phone, but you could still do some things you could go up on the internet
You could do some email, but the big deal was at that time a tween could go buy it for 40 bucks
right
Completely failed. All right
Quite a history there. Are you gonna screw up Azure to know? Okay. No
The other thing so if adaptability is a business imperative
Then one of the problems is that the traditional methods the the waterfall methods the
the engineering methods
Invented say 20 years ago no longer scale if you are competing with your competitors on
Features on a day by day basis. You can't afford a month-long test pass
Okay, just simply you can't
When I went to being
That's where I took my job job
When you shift to a world
Where the the scale of the problems that you have go a couple of orders of magnitude bigger
Then you have to start inventing new techniques
right in Bing
We ingest thousands of data feeds every single day the size the number the shape the schema changes every day
In in addition to that we have all of our developers within 15 minutes any single developer
can check in and it goes to prop within 15 minutes and
Any developer can do that within the stack?
We have multiple layers in the stack and of course that can change at any moment and
In addition to that it's Bing. It's a search engine. We have a machine learning engine in the background
That's also trying to take customer input taking the new widgets that
Individuals developers have put together and combining them to create a UI experience that changes every refresh
How do you test that you don't you can't?
Bugs in Bing are completely worthless you file a bug in Bing a dev will come to you and say why are you doing this?
I can't act on it
What what then becomes more valuable is the patterns data analysis data analytics?
Understanding when is this when is the system making these changes?
That's fixable bugs
Again you could have a bug in one refresh you hit refresh it goes away
But the pattern that caused that initial bug is still in the system. That's what has to be rooted out
like
the
What are you looking at me for you're in the middle of a story? I'm babbling a lot
I'll go to the next thing then the other thing I would say that is a big shift
I'll go I'll just finish this off the other thing that I that this is how we roll
Another thing I would say is just there at my watch in a minute is quality
Quality the definition of quality changes in this world like in the world where bugs don't
matter
What matters?
right
There's a phrase that I use now. I don't I no longer refer to bugs and quality as synonymous
I talk about quality and code correctness
quality is a
Subjective point of view if you have a bug in a feature that no customer has ever used or does ever use
Then it has no impact on quality
okay, a
piece of software that everyone uses is of higher quality
Than a bug-free piece of software that no one's yeah, and that depends it
Given you know because there's like if I asked this room
I get probably a hundred definitions of what quality is but if I use Jerry Weinberg's which is quality is value to some person
Can I get done what I need to get done?
you can have
Pretty high quality products that if nobody uses them you're not nobody's getting value from them or all of the elegance
How many have iPhones do you love your iPhones? Do you love iTunes?
Really, you're like the only person ever
That's weird so but what else you gonna use right?
soon
Didn't they deprecate the software so even if you have a zoom you can't like doing with it because we still we haven't exceeded the
time limit on the devices
Let's go for bureaucracy. So
What were you talking about you were babbling about something quality? Yeah, it was me definitions. Yeah
So I'm reminded of I clicked in I am I am approaching 50. No, I'm beyond Weinberg. Okay, there's in Brian Merrick in
1998 somewhere in late 90s introduced what we called the agile quadrants which in these books called agile testing and more agile testing
Janet Gregory and Lisa Crispin talk about a lot which goes to your point which is when you think about quality you have
Engineering quality on one side and you have a customer facing quality over here
They're different and you also have technology facing and customer facing kind of going the other way without me drawing everything out
Your customers don't care what your code coverage is. They don't care how many tests you ran
They don't care how many failed and how many passed they care about
Do the experiences provide me value you think about all the different things that cover
what quality is and things we've done in testing and in in
Author testing out of not something just testers do but like unit testing very much in that technology facing
Engineering facing quality right good unit test. It could go coverage make sure they pass kind of that other quadrant way up here
You think about performance testing reliability even monitoring is up there
Those things are a lot closer to measuring what the customer perception of quality is but at the very end
What's the best way to get the customer perception to quality?
Measure from the customer right we can try as hard as we can as as engineering teams to go
okay, this is going to be the customer perception of quality and
Brent's a
Data scientist so we can probably predict
What the customer perception is going to be but that's certainly part of a big part of my my challenge
The so is there anyone here who's agile trained raise your hand if you are
Just just brand to one person know that all right
What are you all right now a couple of the people stepped in do you guys know about the pop and dikes?
I don't marry
Yeah, so her husband Tom in terms of his description of quality. I'm very very fond of it
Or it's not new description
But a quote he said everyone in software engineering needs to remember that no one ever
in the history of time
Has ever wanted software?
No one wants software. Okay, what they want is their problem solved
Okay, software is a means to the end bug correctness bugs
May or may not be a means to the ends if they get in the way of their problem getting solved, right?
the to continue on with less so what's changed there's
So we we talked about there's a lot of new engineering methods
Waterfall thankfully is slowly dying, but it's it's holding on with waterfall is awesome
We didn't need to hire testers till the end the docks always got done because we couldn't go on until they were done
So it's great. Yeah, I know what you're talking about
When you shift to this dry sarcasm it just bothers me
The you know what bothers me like an interrupt
It's like I think in some vague power play you scooted your chair farther forward than mine
I just noticed that I just wish the chair was a little bit lower
No, I'm using this as a desk me tired of holding it. Well stop looking at it the
So there's there's lean
Lean and fast agile methods
That is a new engineering model. There's there's safe Kanban scrum
There's about ten that are really popular. These are really coming in and helping businesses to be adaptable in addition to that. There's two key
New engineering roles that we now see in sort of my you know
Don't you think that and this is actually being a real question that I'm has to be brewing and somebody said
Don't you think these all these processes and names kind of almost get in the way sometimes
I think people get so stuck in trying to go
Oh, we're gonna do this process and they get married to the process and they forget that they're trying to make software to solve
Somebody's problem. There's the process is help. I mean if you want pick one there is a bit there is a
There is a bit of that of the the monkey's experiment. Do you guys are aware of the monkey's experiment?
You will be in a minute. What's that?
No, not that one
That's a Shakespeare or something or other
The monkey's experiment in a nutshell is essentially they did an experiment years ago
They got I'll just make up a number. Let's say five monkeys into a cage. They put a ladder and a bunch of bananas
Okay, I like this story. I'll let it all what they did what they did is
Monkeys of course like bananas and so they'll go after the bananas climb up the ladder and acquire the bananas
What they did though is any monkey that did that they would spray it with cold water
okay, and
Monkeys don't like cold water and started getting trained at going after the bananas was
an upsetting experience
Then they changed it then what they what they did because monkeys still try they really like bananas
Then what they did is when a monkey went after the bananas they would spray every monkey
But that one right the first one was the first
Stimulus was to train the monkeys to get them to realize hey, there's a punishment associated with going after the bananas
Now they shifted to oh and by the way
That punishment that you got used to avoiding
Now if someone else goes after it, you're gonna get the punishment. Okay monkeys
Didn't like that and they very quickly got trained
to
Beat up the monkey that went after the banana. They didn't want to get squirted
Then what they who wants to get squirted, right? All right
Then what they did once they had that is a stable behavior inside that cage
They swapped out the monkeys they would they would take one monkey out put a new one that's never experienced it
but they didn't change anything so they put the bananas in and
The old monkeys would if that new one went after the bananas, he'd get his butt kicked
They kept on doing that until eventually
none of the monkeys
Had ever been squirted with water
But the behavior persisted and that's kind of the same thing when we talk about processes
It's you it's it's an encouragement to
Sure, you're used to things
Think about why?
Does it still add value and in the environment that you're in today? What can you change in?
Terms of the names like again as an agile coach, I would say
The first thing you should do if you don't have an agile coach in-house if you don't have someone who understands this topic
very deep higher one
It is hard to just shift it is very easy
Agile is actually a much harder practice than waterfall waterfalls very structured do this then this then this then this
Adapting means you have to know when to change
When to change when to say that rule that we had last week is no longer applicable here
So how many have ever like to have tried to change something and work like let's let's change the way we do X
Anybody ever how many of you have heard?
The biggest resistance was but that's the way we've always done it
It's there it's it's a
Name for that but I don't know my name is I don't like it
But it's it's common and you that that organizational change part that convincing part is a big challenge
But people can get really stuck in that's the way we've always done it. I've heard it, you know at Microsoft a few
100,000 times there's there's a phrase right if it ain't broke don't fix it
if you think it ain't broke then my question would be
How are you measuring that?
Okay, you want to kick stuff I don't even know where you are on your little note list
I'm done talking about the I got my list over here. All right, do you want to talk about kind of what's how you survive this stuff?
Yeah, so I should talk a little bit about what I'm doing now and that may kick some of this off. So
We're changing Microsoft a lot of teams doing
unified engineering big fan of it. Oh, it's like it like so
You know if it's the name I use because I hate the term combined engineering that Microsoft uses
Just means we have a software engineering team not a separate dev and test team
A lot of teams are going that way in various different flavors like Windows has check this out
Or the operating systems group they have
engineering teams or software development teams, I guess and then
Because we got rid of testers. They have quality teams
who
Do
Not as much
They do mostly some data analysis some to let adding metrics measurements to the code
User experience testing etc. Perf reliability those things all happen there
Devdiv has this developer division has the same thing
Where they call it the E&I the experiences and insights team does sort of the same thing
So if you're a developer know if you break something you break you fix your own stuff
the intent of the quality team is that
they would focus mostly on
Customer focus purely on data science
analysis telemetry
It is the illities
And that the development team would own testing
You know most of the testing of their own code, but I won't say they've done that transition particularly well yet
Not windows. Yeah, so I was in windows for a little while by I like to say that my
Two and a half years in Xbox was the best five years of my life and that my two years in
Windows was the longest five years of my life. Oh, that's gonna go on the podcast. That's cool. All right, so I
Which makes you what 60 months ago?
Brandt you're number one. Yeah four months ago. I joined a team that was all engineers all developers all former developers
But they were smart about it. They wanted to adjust an engineering team for the devs own their testing
But they realized very early on hey, we don't know a lot about testing
We're not so good at this and I'm sure there's a lot of stuff
We're forgetting letting through the holes. So my job is to be the quality guy on this team. So I'm the combination
Test manager test architect release manager probably something else. I wear a lot a lot of hats the team
Small team Microsoft size probably huge everywhere else. It's about
65 engineers
Evan knows that small for Microsoft
And my job is to make sure the developers know how to test so they have the right coaching and training to do that
The developers own all their own testing all the way up through integration testing including some performance from reliability testing
And then I have a handful of
vendors we use for some extra customer focused experience testing and for some extra stuff, so
So my role has been to be part of an engineering team. I'm a peer with all the other engineering leads on the team
so we have a director of development and all the engineering managers who run the different feature teams and I report to him and
So it's been a good experience and working in an engineering team figure out how
What it means for a development team to own
Testing their own code and sort of some of the challenges they go through and doing that
I think one of the reasons it works for me is Brent and I have talked a lot about this idea of
Generalizing specialist or specializing generalist meaning you guys know this term. Have you heard it before?
I was gonna talk about it. Shut up
So it means I've described my role for a long time as someone who does you know is a little about a lot and a lot
About a little meaning I can cover I can I can really kind of help out a lot of different areas
There are some areas I go deep on and the areas I tend to go deep on may
It may change depending on context when I joined the link team
It's called Skype for business now, but they had a team a very
junior test team who were doing a lot of
Manual tests all day and didn't really know a lot about test techniques or they just needed a lot of extra work
So my job on that team, I just left engineering excellence where I was a sort of a trainer and a coach and a consultant
So I went into that team and I spent about a year and a half
Helping that team become sort of better rounded testers only had approach automation throwing out most of their manual suite because it was useless
and
Kind of turning them into was a I thought a pretty well oiled team
Then so but very high level kind of organizational change and training kind of stuff then I went to Xbox where it was
We need someone who knows see really well
We can write a lot of tools and test tools and things to get Xbox one out the door
So I did that for two years and it was a blast
And I'm doing sort of a and I did sort of a combination of that on the but that my transitional team in Windows
I'll help us call it the transitional team. That's better and then I'm and then I'm like I said
I'm doing sort of a release management quality architect sort of role in this team. So
the the line that runs through there is I think no matter how your
Engineering team or your development team or your team is put together
You need in addition to people that can just crank out good code because you always want some of those right?
I won't ask you to raise your hand if you're really good at cranking out good code
We always need those people but you also need people who can plug holes
once I changed my my LinkedIn profile at the hole filler and
Because that's kind of my job. I've told all my managers
I figure out what's not getting done and make sure it gets done
Whether I do it myself or work through others to make sure it gets done
So my role is to recognize what those holes are and then get them filled. Oh, and by the way, I have a tangent
We were famous for our tangents
Do you guys get like a lot of unsolicited LinkedIn recruiter mail? So I know how to fix that
Change I changed my LinkedIn title to generic employee. I don't get any more emails
That one's free. You can do that
So you're gonna add something. Yeah, I want to shift a bit deeper, right? Cuz um
Alan is in a unique situation his last team change right most of the teams that we go and talk to
Are in transition they already have
say
Dev test p.m. And they're trying to figure out how do they move into sort of a more of efficient
team model, right
Alan got lucky in my humble opinion is that you started off it was a lock
It actually wasn't he was looking for he was looking for the perfect job for him
Is serendipity
What's the quote about luck that says luck is I can't even paraphrase it
Yeah, something like that. Like I was ready for luck to strike me
so I
Think straight I don't know what you're talking about, but I'm gonna anyway. No, I was gonna go back to
So one of the experiences after I left Bing I
was
instrumental in helping the SQL server team
Go from sort of the similar point that you guys seemed like
That you guys are at now where you have these combined roles or not combined separated roles. How do you merge towards?
More efficient team for lack of a better word
There's a lot of struggles
Dev for example that will constantly ask well, what does QA do now?
Yeah, even when QA knows what they're gonna do now and explain it
they still ask this question because one of the biggest problems is
In essence a lot of deaths and I'm sure it's not here but a lot of devs for you testing as
Menial work, right? Why do I have to do that? It's below me. Okay
and
It's really not but you actually had a quote
Piggyback off of the the quality speech who owns quality the Twitter that you did a few months ago
I don't know what you're talking about fair enough
You said something if quality is
The customer subjective value something something something then who on the team owns quality
Producing that if quality is producing value to some customer then who on this team owns quality
Right. All right rhetorical question everyone owns creating value for the customer, right? I'm sure I said that I don't remember it was on
God you're old
The
So dev goes through a transition period if you guys choose to go with this sort of model tests will go through a transition period
I am a
huge proponent of
of the unified
Engineering model
I am too, but I don't know that it matters and I'm gonna interrupt cuz it doesn't matter as long as the roles are
Efficient and working together the second the roles become silos
Dev throwing stuff over the fence to test that's the exact work
I think the key is that engineering team is regardless of what you call yourselves
I was talking to Evan earlier and and
Everybody's just get to make up their own title because titles get in the way sometimes of engineering you think oh you had
You have this title whatever it is. And so I don't have to give you the time of day
But I remember in when I worked on Windows CE
That's an eye roll for people that missed it. I
helped this is probably 2004 I
Trained our dev team to write unit tests and
This is new to them. It's weird because
Developers about every other company in that time period were running right in their own unit test
But it's this brand new thing for these Windows CE developers. But the weird thing that happened was I
Developers come to me and say hey if we're writing unit tests, what are the testers gonna do?
I thought I can explain this and the reasonable question
What scared me more is when a tester came to me and said hey if the developers are writing unit tests, what do I do?
And oh, that's an interesting way to look at that
But when I think of my career I spent probably the first at least
Five years writing unit tests. We played this game of
Codependent ping pong I call it
where the developer gives me some code and
I quickly write a little test for it to prove that it's broken and I feel good because I found a bug
I'm validated. I give my code give the bug to the developer goes. Oh, thank you for finding a bug
Thank you for being my safety net. That's great. I love you and he fixes it and then he gives it to me again
I go I
Put a little more time on it and I find another bug I go that's great
He fixed it and I found another bug. I feel more validated here. Here you go again. He goes why thank you
This is great. I love you more and this goes back and forth and
It's really
Maybe the codependent metaphor is too far of it not too far off
But this ping pong when you think about efficient software, it's really inefficient to do that, right?
So a couple things come out of developers
Writing a lot of their own tests is one
I'm a big fan and I'll say everybody asked this a big fan of test driven development and especially
Even more behavior driven development. I'm talking about what those are in a minute for this
You guys know these I said I just talked about these in a minute for those you don't know what they are
But I said I wish I said I'm we're I'm there already know
Okay
That was Brent's attempt to giving me a bad time so
Keys here. It's very efficient for if I'm gonna write this code if I write some tests for it before or while I'm writing it
Make sure it works
Developers that write begin to write good unit test
End up writing more testable code
Because a lot of times I'm sure developers in the room have done this like I'm gonna write some code
You think I'm gonna write a test this. Oh shit. I can't test that
They go. I'm gonna refactor this which end up with this better code in the first place
Because you have to write testable code from the beginning and that code ends up being more usually more maintainable
Let's roll out the people yeah
Yeah, so
That's a good way and I take that one go ahead go ahead yeah, so better to have two minds yes
separate no, so
Huge proponent of pair programming where you have two people looking at at the same time
But the the trick with TDD
The the the brilliance of TDD is you test your code first?
So you writing up the test cases that need to pass before you write the code
Since you haven't written the code yet. You haven't yet been
Perverted by the assumptions that you're about to write so one of the things
That I did and then I want to piggyback on this and and that that's a great question because that ends up being
One of the challenges with the shift when I went to Bing I told you I went into dev
This was at the time where Bing was going with combined engineering
My team was 50% dev and
50% test is this a long story no okay the testers ended up being
the
Better developers in the world where we have to ship every 15 minutes
right the the because the
Turns out writing code in
in small chunks
Is not that hard if you have a rock star?
dev architect on the team and say you need a
You're using an n log n and union log or a O of n algorithm
You you need to have the ability to have that second person to go and ask you need to be able to do knowledge sharing
But other than that the 80% of the coding problems anyone can do
But the thing we're testing it up being a huge advantage is they already understood the value and how to test
it ended up
What happened is my team first came first were very polarized
Had a bunch of devs that say we're specialists. We are the ones that own this code up and down the stack
But we're not going to do our testing because we own enough complexity and I said
Honestly what I did is I ran my team if you guys are familiar with Kanban
I ran my team with a Kanban model as highly transparent. Yeah, and
You only ship in two week chunks. Okay, so anybody does something wrong?
it's only
Two weeks of one person's code that that could have an impact and it's very easy to react and and repair
But what ended up happening is is I I didn't force these guys to shift
I forced them to communicate be transparent walk through the board and as they went through that as everyone was transparent
These guys were realizing that the testers were getting their stuff out faster. They were getting more features done faster
And then they started shifting right once the team started sharing knowledge
The people with the super awesome very highly specialized algorithms started leveraging and learning from the test guys and once that
Tests are that knowledge learning goes
Then this team becomes a rock star. I when I left being I'll close with this when I left Bing
Alan really wants to interject something
When I left being I had one of my peer teams came to me a PM came to me
I had a team of seven at that time and he said Brent
I don't know what you're doing, but your team of seven is kicking my team of 30s ass and
I said we should meet because I know what we're doing. It's not magic. We just think about it in a different light
Go ahead. Let me give you also a sort of a pragmatic
Answer to that from my recent past we had a
Bad bug in our product. It's not released yet. So it's tough back gonna be right?
but our VP was pissed so it was that bad and
There's like how is this and I got the how did we miss this?
How did this get through and it turned out that?
Developers who are learning to write tests like our team was they're very they were really really good happy path tests
Our product as long as you use our product as expected
No, it's not even close to the edge stay in the middle of the room. It ran great
But it wasn't until then that hit me because I'm doing all these hats that I realized
Oh, yeah, there's a whole bunch of other testing. I've been doing my whole life that we're not doing yet
So what I did there easy thing I met with the engineering managers and people on their team little half-hour meetings
We did a brainstorm made a mind map of all the edge cases and things like that looking at quantity if you want
I mean you're thinking about
We'll look at places where concurrency that can happen places where large amounts of data can cause a problem
Things like that, you know look at you know non English characters or if it applied etc
and all those things that were
testers are traditionally really good at helping the deal don't me just think about those because
one of the things that a generalizing specialist does that maybe a pure specialist doesn't do is we go into the the
10-foot level and dive in and then go back out at 10,000 foot level look around and kind of see how stuff fits together
so
Yes, it is
You could say that you're biased to your own code
But you can there's plenty of ways to get help on that because I think I know plenty of developers who are really good at testing
Their own code. So I think it's certain. I know for a fact is certainly possible and for those where it's difficult
I think it's a learnable trait. It is absolutely learnable trait and then there's always the model of pair programming
Although it's much like
my experience with TDD and in helping
Say specialist devs learn it's much like
The speech you can lead a horse to water right it they have to be motivated to want to drink from and if they're not
It's it's it's going to be a hard-fought battle. The other thing I'll also share around TDD
No, I want to highlight the benefit
Evan has a question
Okay
the other thing about TDD or doing this test having the test and their developer owning it and
When not with a model where again within 15 minutes it goes to prod it creates a
Sense of ownership on the individual first and foremost if they're checking within 15 minutes can go to prod
Then they don't have to worry about the blame game of oh, no
My fix is fine is that you didn't integrate right?
Right. It's there's their control of their own destiny and as they learn
So I'm a big proponent of balancing the preventative and reactive measures and as you learned where your preventive measures weren't working
You add tests and as you add tests you realize oh my god
The way I've written my code makes it a real peony ass to add tests. I need these tests
I'm gonna refactor my code and what I've what I have noticed that every team that goes into this
That that code gets refactored into much more maintainable much more testable
patterns across the entire team and when you have
That type of code your ability to produce new features and change features starts to go like this
getting in a rhythm is is
Actually key. I think ever you don't know what the customers are going to do so
Oh, actually, that's a that's a really good comment
The comment was repeat what the question was the question was if customers aren't going to try those crazy things
Why bother testing for them and it goes back to the comment earlier?
But if a but nobody finds a bug does it affect quality?
I
Don't think is a real reason to go super crazy on the edge cases
But like there is a particular object we could pass to a message as long as we had one or two
Which was the normal usage case?
Everything was fine. But when someone added four of those or five of those everything broke
So that's not really on the edge. So a little bit beyond the center happy path
It gets to a point this is gonna lead into what I'm gonna force Brent to be the next section
Which is there's a comment. I heard probably seven years ago, maybe a little longer at a GTAC conference in
San Jose a Google test automation conference where says sufficient monitoring is
Equivalent to testing. So if you have the monitoring in your system to know when
Every failure has happened to get and get the right alerts on that and know what paths are being used and what's happening there
Sufficient monitoring to cover all those cases
Can replace testing? I want to be careful with that one though. I need say that I'm trying to tee up here
Go bright. Right. So you guys have heard I'm sure by now this concept of testing and production
Yes
Okay, it does not please dear God
It does not mean take your test suite and turn them into monitors that are on production
Okay, it means you do need those monitors
But it means you're looking at the the you're using your customers as your testers
It means that you have a much alone statement to write people freak out about that. No, okay. Go go go
Customers are fantastic testers. They are that and this is a point I always make for test reason go
I am the voice of the customer. I am the customer advocate. I am the customer and you're not
That wasn't very nice
But yeah, you if you can use the real customer as your proxy for the real customer
Yeah, it's always gonna be better off than using a proxy for a different proxy. Do you guys do flight control here?
Yeah, so imagine that you have a whole bunch of monitors that can tell you
What's your name?
Kevin, okay. So Kevin just did a check-in 15 minutes
It's now in prod. How does Kevin know that he just broke?
All redfin customers in Georgia. We have monitors that would allow you to know that in that type of world
Kevin kind of needs to know that right we need to have the ability to detect that something that the business values
Just is on the floor
now
So flight control also known as exposure rings is what you do is you?
Take Kevin's code you put it on
Call it exposure ring you put it on a segment of your customers say only a hundred people
Can see Kevin's code and then you have important signals if it passes those signals
Then you broaden it to an order of magnitude and you keep doing that until there's
Some some threshold where it's no longer value to keep just flip it all along
right
When we talk about tests in production really really at the end of the day what a test case is for is
to reduce business risk
That's the whole point you can do some of those things you need to do to do it preventively
It would not be a good idea for Kevin to do something
Where he checks in this fix and then anyone signs in and it deletes the customer database. This would probably be a bad idea
Right, but he has a unit test for that. That's all right, right
But he should have a unit test for that and and some mechanism as part of that 15 minutes to prod
Should be in place to check that no one can take out the entire business
Then things like okay, someone just signed in with some weird character
right that you can use your telemetry and you can use a
a reactionary process to
Get that going Google for example, one of the things Google does they used to be well known for shipping crap
All the time. They were always in beta. Okay, and I used to have arguments with people at Microsoft
He's like, oh, they're always in beta. They don't ship high quality
They're a fat
Okay, they're not a fad. I had actually these arguments and I'm like, you know what?
Their stock price and the number of users does not align with your statement
Right and the only way to make that for that to make sense and this is still in one of my test gigs
the only way to make sense is that bugs don't necessarily equate to quality or
Perhaps what's more important is?
As a business you're working to not prevent pain but minimize overall
Pain and what Google is masterful at they instrument everything
So they have a belief a set of hypotheses. It's like we think these are our
Catastrophic we're gonna pretest this code's not gonna go out but the amount of those test cases is not very large
Much much much smaller
They'll use exposure rings. So look at that instrumentation and they'll go. Hey looks like
We have more than we expect of people from Georgia
That's not are getting sign-in failures. Perhaps we should investigate that and see if we revert the code
so if you think of the purpose of tests is minimizing business risk and you think about
customer value as
Increasing it then you then you have the liberty
to start applying sort of an ROI through to
How you are doing everything you can use ROI to reevaluate your processes reevaluate your practices
the
The other thing Google is very good at is they can they can make a decision to revert the build right as I talked about
It would not go to the next exposure ring or yank it out. No, this is a bad build. We just destroyed
The experience for a hundred people in Georgia, but they can also go. Oh, it's not bad enough to stop it from moving forward
But it is bad enough
We're gonna get this
Fixed in in the next iteration and their iterations are either one or two weeks long
One of the things that I will say is that a huge time saver something. I'm very proud of
In the last five years. I haven't had a bug database
because I deal with it in real time I I
First got test clean. I first got bug clean then I started a cadence around shipping
Small chunks because if you ship large chunks, it's really hard to disentangle
But if I have someone on my team of seven and each one is going to ship something new on a daily basis
If I come in the next morning and it's on the floor
It's really hard are really sorry really easy to fix it because it's one person's one code
He might even be able to because the complexity is so small. He might even be able to fix it in line
very quick QFE
as
We go through that doing it. What QFE mean quick fix engineering release. What's the equivalent here? How fix?
the
I forgot where it's good. I can I can take a turn so
So I think we probably want to wrap up here and then take a bunch of questions
I think I think we want to get your questions and try and make sure we can adapt those so start thinking of those now
What works for us is I can go back to pragmatic our product hasn't shipped yet, but we're
I'm thinking hard about the plan to get there
And so we have you guys use continuous integration server you guys are shipping often
so we use a big fan of this this is where you catch all the
all the kind of devastating things that could happen you never want to get into a flight and
You're not really reliable tests there because we gate the build on these we gate deployment on these so it's like someone submits a change
It goes through this gate, which is a build unit test these all these other tests these their protractor tests running against the web page
If all those pass the bill gets deployed to our continuous integration environment, and that's updated all the time
So there's always a build out there with the latest check-ins in it. So that's going on all the time and then
What we're gonna do I know you guys are working on shipping much more frequently
But we're just my team is gonna start with one release a week
So and the good thing that happens from that is our team has been doing sort of for term on agile transition
I joined the team in the middle of their their love of what I'll call Scrummer fall
Which is we have a full week iteration?
Where there's some planning at the beginning and then the devs right and bunch of
Do a bunch of work and I make sure they're adding tests
But they still create a bunch of debt in there in there and then they try and cram in the rest of the debt at
The end at the end of that four weeks have a really crummy product that stabilizes the first week of the next iteration
Being transparent it's not perfect
But by moving to this by we're gonna shift to some internal customers coming up soon and by moving to that model
I got everyone bought off on shipping once a week
Which means whether they want to think of things as a four-week iteration or not
I can now in caps things kind of line up into a weekly rhythm and that's when Brent mentioned that earlier
I really clicked on that is having a shipping rhythm is really important
Teams can adapt to that like we know we have a one-week rhythm where you know, we're doing a bunch of validation on
Monday and the bill and we do some self hosting dogs
But on Tuesday and then we promote to production on Wednesday and then features are finished up for the next thing Thursday and Friday
And we start all over again. It's very nice so we can crank that up that
Speed up as needed but it gets
One of the things I'm looking forward to in that is like Brent said I don't
Well, first of all, we have a bug database and it's populated with more things and I'd like right now
But we're gonna I'm in the back of my head to put about
Organizational change my plan is
Little by little without the team realizing it because I'm not even gonna tell them they're doing one-week iterations
it's just gonna happen and a little by little we're gonna become a little bit more agile and and
eventually I
It's gonna be like the perfect team for me. I'm trying to mold them to be like what I want
I want to be clear though
Clear all day. I'm gonna try now
My teams I saw we don't have a bug database and I've haven't in five years, but that doesn't mean so
My teams still have developers in them and they still are human which means they write bugs
So my team still writes bugs, but the way we treat bugs is when we encounter a bug
That we have validated as customer impacting that we have a process. We call it the swarm process
Any bug that comes to my team the whole team jumps on it and that thing is gone within 48 hours
So bugs we viewed not only something that's harming our customer, but it's harming the overall
Process
And quality of not just the code but everything so I'm an efficiency geek and I mentioned earlier the the codependent ping-pong game
which is very inefficient and also it's very inefficient and
But by the way that that cost of a bug curve, it's mostly a myth don't draw don't draw that ever
Holding on there is a cost
accruing debt
So if you're gonna yep, that's a great bug. We'll get to that when we get to it. That's inefficient
It's so much more efficient to go. Oh, there's a bug. Let's fix it
Let's get it. Let's we don't want we don't want those when you can get to that zero and there's a transition step
To get there doesn't happen all at once. I've known teams that have gone through this and you kind of go for
Okay, let's have and what I'm doing right now is we have zero bugs at the end of our iteration
usually it's about two days into the next iteration and
Eventually, we're gonna be at zero bugs every Friday for the weekend
Our sappin and now eventually move into zero bugs all the time. I was planning my head all worked out
There'll be bumps along the way
But this is this is where I want to get to but you can't just go to the team and go
That's it. Everybody fix all your bugs. I'm not gonna have anymore
I think that's a typical I my team customer impact 100% my my team fixes a hundred percent customer
impacting but so what we will do though is
the bugs where
Hey, if a customer does this sequence of clicks at exactly midnight on February 29th it using a by dye character set
Yeah, I will make the call that that's
That might be a bug I can look at your code. It's absolutely bug
We're not going to fix it until we have proof. There's somebody impacted
I'm sure a lot of people in this room. I've worked on products have had multiple multiple releases and
I'm sure a lot of people in this room have bugs like we don't want to fix that
But we're gonna hold on to it because we may get to it next time then next time rolls around and you go. Yeah
We're gonna do that next time and you end up with this bug. It's like 40 years old
Okay, four years old but and it's like yeah, we're gonna get to that note. That's one thing
that I'm very adamant about and it's
My bug triage like this is customer impacting. Yes, we're gonna fix it and we're gonna fix it very soon
But we're not gonna fix it at all. So and that's the thing I want to I want to get a couple other things number one
We won't fix it if that bug comes in the February 29 scenario. We'll go. No, it's fixed
Okay, we track all of our bugs as tickets on our scrum board. Okay, I will take that ticket and it goes the trash
I'm going to completely from here on out ignore its existence if it comes up again
I'll say okay that we have customer impact now
Hey, and if the answer is still no it's gonna go back into the trash. Would you I have a
Would you
Could you would you could you dr. Seuss on a boat with a with a boat add?
I'm gonna go add a little bit of instrumentation here
So I know if this I'm gonna track how many people February 29th at midnight are are are entering but yeah, yeah, absolutely
it's so
Me that's what I most bugs where I would have with with one of my reports isn't gonna be so
Hyperbolic right it's going to be hey, but it could if this this and this and there's this other thing
And there's a reasonable expectations could but we don't have any proof that any customers encounter that I'll say you tell you what
Go refactor it go ahead and add instrumentation
We're gonna keep the code the way it is
But if if you're proven to be right I want to be able to switch on a dime
So make sure that the code can switch
And you can go the other way on that too. So imagine I'm gonna this is purely I'm gonna make up a bad example
That's what I'm best at like say you
Somebody comes says hey look I found this bug where if someone searches for a house that has an odd numbered address
In a state where the abbreviation has an a is the last letter and it's over a million dollars
This weird thing happens to the page or something bad happens again totally made up not a great example
But ideally you could go you could you guys fixing it's gonna be a real pain like okay. What's the impact?
Ideally you want to be able to go to your data that you've clicked it from your site and go how how often does this happen?
How likely is this to happen and use data to help you make a decision on on the customer impact of that as well
Yes, and if you have that data, then you should be able to align it very readily to what will be the business impact
Because you also have if you have that data
Then you have the data of all the other type of bugs and now you have the ability to sort of work through
Customer impact in what's on this parade order or the 8020 rule the other thing
I also want to bring out around this process that really makes things super sweet at the end of the day is
It's really it makes
Bug-free code or bug ish free code is much easier to add features to
Much much much easier
Yeah, and that's what the business is really valuing
I've been preaching that to my team as we knock our our bug debt down is that you guys we forget ship once a week
it's much easier to give value to customers if we're doing that on top of a stable code base and they all down their heads and
Slowly too slow for me whittle down that debt. Okay. I think we've covered pretty much. Oh, we've everything
We've covered more you don't get to bring your little note sheets anymore
I'm still bringing them. All right
We do some questions. Yeah, please. Yes
Yes, so I like to think of that sort of like a two-axis. Oh, sorry
Wow, they're watching me closely
So how do you how do you differentiate between the bugs that are minor but a lot of people hit and they're and the kind of the
Really bad ones and I like to think of bugs on that that to access
Scale of like how many people does it hit and you can get that from data and then how bad is it houses severity?
So is it is the the crash that only happens at midnight?
on the February 29th when you're entering bite-eye characters versus the
Cursor that disappears for five seconds for every single user using your page
One is not very severe, but you really want to fix it it
In my current team. One of the things that we're working through is something that we're calling a pain index
We have every team. I think I've been on at Microsoft has built a pain index
Yeah, I'm gonna build one. All right, cuz it's never been done before no
But I get to do it data science II way not a god old-school test way no spreadsheets this time
Gonna use our if you think of risk
You're number one too well if you use if you the biggest thing about risk
Right is how frequently does this thing occur and then what's the severity?
So all sort of impact statements it can be measured by frequency and severity now
you guys got to transform or translate what severity means in terms of
An impact to the business or the impact of the customer now
I'll also tell you the more you can make those things synonymous
The more you are measuring the business in terms of impact to the customer
then the more
this
really flows I
had the
Talking about the glory is again when I left Bing I had the ability
to in essence
When I was doing some of the the data science stuff that I was doing in Bing
I had the essence the ability to tell individual dev teams
the consequence of this bug yesterday by dollar signs
and once we had that and
And the ability to sort of argue through that no that wasn't just a random number generator
a
Dev started engaging because no one in this room wants to make unhappy customers
But a lot of what we do is based off of an intuition a base off of belief
Well, this would really impact me if I was that guy in
In that situation on February 29th. This is how I feel empathy is high
the data allows you to get much more accurate and get to the
Truth and the once you get closer to that you can really iterate faster
So I believe the answer to the question was yes next question. Yes
so what about the this is actually a
Tailor onto that question, which is we do with the gray area bugs that are like this is wrong
But you know the devs to the hopefully just the dev team doesn't have the only choice on what gets fixed
Here it should be for my team
We have a design team that would make that call and my design team is
Massively anal so that bug would get fixed all the time. So ideally, you know for me it's
It sort of depends on the team culture and what you're building but the way I think he was addressing it is great
I think we all know how to solve any decision making in any sort of command and control structure
So you had a design team? Well, they're the winners. Yep
How do you do to have the customer be the winner?
So, how do we make the political decision to fix all the bugs design team files luckily the design team fixes in themselves
They own are they not only design but they actually know the magic of CSS. So yes
So the question is do we have any experience in property based testing using some tool? I haven't heard of right
I'm not familiar with property based testing and I'm pretty sure that we understand what you're talking about but not in the way your phrase there
Oh, so test generation libraries not necessarily fuzzing but test generation like for for any sort of test data
Yeah, I use a tool a colleague of mine. I wrote when I worked in engineering excellence work with a guy named
The BJ Rellison who's one of the authors on the on the book I wrote on
One of the books you can buy no don't buy them
like
That was that was like Google AdSense just popping in and put that ad there
He wrote this tool called babble, which I believe you can still find on his website
But it generates strings in any language
So I use like that and it has an API as well and I use that today
I also use a tool believe it or not that James Bach wrote called pro clip and pro clip is an awesome tool
For it'll generate any length of string you want and with this idea called counter strings
It's actually a pretty nice tool for figuring out what the limits of entries are etc. I've
It's a pretty easy way to I showed dad like it's not that big of a deal
But you show somebody who hasn't done testing before and they go. Oh my god
If you put a long string in my field it breaks who would have thought of that
Yes
No
You definitely have to so the question was no sorry when you go 15 minutes to prod you probably can't build and test everything
So what do you do?
How are you guys doing it? I can explain go so I was asking you the question one of the things
So first off you you if you can leverage the system and it turns out in Bing
We are able to go massively parallel
And and a lot of the machines in Bing the the production machines have idle cycles
So we're able to capture those idle cycles and turn them into a parallel test bed
Okay
Certain but the the other thing too is if you're gonna be live in 15 minutes
Then you need to have the data that you can react to much sooner than that so that you can make a decision
It's going to go
So but you want to have an opportunity to make a decision to stop it
And it's not always going to go there are certain
Monitors in place that will stop any flow, but anything that's decision-making it's up to you
You have to think
differently around how your code works
The the the best example is any build
And you can do this whether it's a big service like Bing or it's even an on-prem product if you think about
the concept of an RTM build and
You you make a commitment you change the architecture in the process of your team and say we're gonna have a build that is always
RTMmable and one of the things that I actually tell people
Ship releaseable releasable. He's using weird words. Just ignore
It may not map to to this world, but hopefully you'll follow
So if you have a build that is it's up to the business team whoever owns the business team
Hey any build in this branch
You guys can decide the ship at any time. You don't even need to talk to engineering, okay
Then you have to then create a new incremental process such that you incrementally enhance that bill
Right now I encourage this process because you don't want if you can get to a point where engineering
Isn't part of the call of whether or not it ships
Then engineering then becomes a little extra diligent around making sure that they're safe because
This could be shipped by something that's outside of my control as you do that incremental then you do incremental testing
so you you compare your bits to
the RTM bits and
Then you can use co-coverage you can use standard tests to really pair down
What needs to be done and then if you then further enhance it with sort of an exposure rings with these monitors you really
Pair down the amount of proactive testing that you need to do to achieve the same degree of risk prevention
All right, let's do
That's a decision you can make so if you're making it
Yeah, so if you're making a claim that like what's different RTM and broad basically and you can you can make the same thing
RTM is for users like me who shipped a lot of products before the web existed
Yeah
RTM and
We had to we had to ship our code to some
Factory and who knows where so that they can burn our code on discs. Okay
That was the version of shipping to prod back in the day
All right, their eyes tell me their butts are tired anybody had one last question
Yeah back here I've heard from you
So the question is if this is actually a good one to close on if agile is about adapting and we talked about people being
resistant to change
Don't those work against each other and the truth is is you're absolutely right, but people still are resistant to change
it is
people get set in their ways and anytime there's a
Sort of you want to do something differently there are people probably like you and I am brand to like yeah
Let's go first. Try this out and see what works. I really believe in trying things out
Do a little bit of a time see what fails learn from that try something else
There's there are other people who are and we've worked with them
I'm not gonna point them out in the room
Evan told me who they were beforehand but some people who are like I'm fine the way I am
I don't need to change we don't need to do it differently
So you have those on both sides and then you have people in the middle who are kind of just kind of waiting to see
What happens? Yeah, whatever wherever you guys go. I'll go I'm going for the ride and
So you'll have 20% on one side 20% of the other and then everyone know what the numbers are
But yeah, it's you anytime you're making some sort of change even if it's about agile which is about being adaptive. There's
You still have a people problem is another Jerry Weinberg quote
I like says it's always a people problem and you always have to figure out how to
What the motivation gonna be to get people to change some people are very much driven by data
Some people are driven by you know more intrinsic things like simple just excited about
Big fan of the Dan pink work talk about change Dan pink says that people are give people are motivated by progress
So if you can show them with this change like oh, we're moving faster and cool things are happening
Then those naysayers are slowly slowly jump on board
You have to have a seed in which everyone agrees
Like if we are all deciding that hey, it is valuable to the business that we ship every hour and
And it's going to affect income growth something that the business values
then
Yeah, a lot of the adaptability can come into play but a lot of people
Honestly don't believe in adaptability, I don't know if that's going to be here
But they don't see it and they don't understand that value
in addition to that Alan has this
I'll let him decide if he introduces you to definition behind fragile teams, but you've all you've all
encountered those teams where hey
We're gonna be agile and then the person who's leading that agile transformation basically
They read the first chapter of the Schwab book and then decided oh they get the rest of it and then they deploy
Part of the concept that they picked up and and the rest of the stuff that they messed up or haven't
fully absorbed
And then and then discover Oh agile is a bunch of crap. It doesn't work
It was primarily because what you did
Wasn't agile. So when I probably go deep into fragile, but fragile is when you
Just pick a few parts of agile and then try and go with them and they don't work for you
But I one thing I want to make sure I mentioned before we close is
Elizabeth Elizabeth Hendrickson. Thank you. Yeah, sorry Elizabeth
She has this quote which I'll get all horribly paraphrase about agile the litmus test for agile is
frequently delivering
Delivering frequent customer value at a sustainable pace
If you're doing that you're probably agile doesn't matter if you're to the book on something or far on the book
But if you're too busy, it's really easy to get stuck in the process
Like we've probably looped all the way around where we started
But frequently delivering software at a sustainable pace and that has doing that
May cause you to change
some of the things we talked about today like how lines are blurred between what Devin test were forever and how
Engineering processes work and who owns what how to gain those efficiencies to get that frequency that you need I
I am also
Don't encourage any more of the usage of the turn agile even though I've used it a lot here
I definitely prefer adaptable agile means is highly overloaded
It means multiple different things
I
May or may not those of you who are agile experts
You may may not agree with me in terms of let's say a specific debate
But hopefully would all would agree that adaptability is really what's critical really what's important and there's different
Techniques and tools to get there. Yeah, one thing I learned from Brent was on the spectrum
There's you know waterfall was a predictive model and then there was spiral and some forms of agile
What you're kind of in that middle ground of their iterative models scrum is an example that so it go from
Predictive to iterative to adaptive. I think the the right way to make software especially web software in
Least for this decade might change ten years from now
But I doubt it is to make sure you're adaptable make sure you're always learning
From your customer always learning from your engineering practices, etc
Anything else? All right. No, I think we've closed out. Okay once again, I'm not Brent
I am. All right. Thanks everybody. All right. Bye guys