Hey everybody, I'm Alan and Brent's not here.
No, no, no, but even better, I'm here with three of the three.
Can you guys introduce yourselves?
Hey, my name is Michael Richards.
I am the director of Quality Assurance at a software company that does software for
the commercial real estate industry.
I'm Vernon Richards, no relation to Michael, and I am an independent tester from the UK.
You guys look like brothers.
And I'm Perzi Ababa.
I am a test manager for a very big healthcare company.
Smith and Smith?
Yes, something like that.
Perzi also a contributor to our Mail Bash, which we don't have today.
Hey, we are together because we're at Test Bash.
Guys having a good time at Test Bash?
Oh yeah, very good.
In Philadelphia, my very first time to Philadelphia.
How about you?
I came once when I was 15 with my mom.
I haven't been back since.
All right, anybody else been to Philadelphia before?
Never.
You live here.
I live like 70 miles from here, but this is actually technically where I was born because
I came here in this country via Philadelphia, I don't know, 20, no, 17 years ago.
Wow.
Yeah.
My first time here, I've been to like 40 plus of the states, but I've never been
to Philadelphia.
Most of my state traveling when I was a younger lad.
If there's not a Microsoft office, I probably haven't been there.
If there's a Microsoft office, a big one with engineering, I've probably been there.
That means I've been to great places like Fargo, tourist destination.
Never been to North Dakota.
I've been to 45 of the 50, and that's not one.
I've never been to Maine.
That's just like a few miles away, right?
Let's drive right up.
No?
I've never been to Delaware.
Yeah, it's like 11 hours.
That's really a few miles away.
I've only ever been to New York, so this is my second state now.
You're not from the US?
No, I'm not.
I thought it was a Southern accent.
No.
I'm not American.
You'll be surprised to hear.
Yeah.
Oh, I'm a little jealous right now.
Do I need to leave?
This is day one, the end of day one of Test Bash, a two day single track event full
of some really cool talks.
I've been five for one, have been impressed.
When I go to the star conferences and Lee Copeland's going to listen to this and be
mad that there's so many tracks.
The way I get value out of a conference like Star is I bounce around.
Because this one isn't very good or not a great speaker, not well prepared.
From that, from my willingness to bounce around, and Lee actually encourages that.
I actually get good value here.
Conference like this, I was a little worried, single track event, but all the talks are
really good.
At least in my opinion.
I thought we could just go around and talk about our favorite Test Bash event and just
see where that goes.
My favorite was the last talk from Elizabeth, whose last name I forgotten.
Zagroba.
And the reason I liked it is because I'm an introvert.
And let me, and I just got the WTF look from Vernon.
Because she gets what being an introvert is.
People who are extroverts, people who don't actually think about who introverts are,
think of them as these people that just kind of, they're, think of them as recluses.
People that don't like to talk to people.
I can be friendly, I can give talks, I can try and be entertaining.
But it requires great effort from me.
So if I have a day full of meetings, or if I have to teach a workshop or even give a talk
tomorrow, I will be exhausted afterwards.
So introversion is, it's an internal preference, but what a lot of people don't realize, it's
really the effort that it requires.
I can act extroverted, but it requires me 10X the effort that it requires a extroverted
person who's naturally extroverted.
I can do it, I can play that game.
And you have to be successful in a career for this long and deal with people and not just,
and have a lot of opportunities I've had.
I've had to play the part of being a loud person, not just loud.
That is a bad, that's a bad stereotype on extroverts.
Again, extroverts aren't just the loud frat boys.
They're the people who, it requires energy from them to not talk to people.
If you're an extrovert, but I want to talk to them, I want to find out this, this, this,
and this.
And for them, it requires more energy to not do that.
For me, it requires the energy to actually get out there and have conversations.
The last question from Maura really nailed it for me, because I'm, well, I'm pretty sure
I'm an extrovert with maybe introverted traits every once in a while.
But the thing is, in order to find out if someone is an introvert, I have to bother them
or I need to interact with them to the point where they're going to have to now use some
energy to let me know how, and I don't really want to do that.
I kind of just want to be able to just identify somehow their introverts without bothering
them.
Yeah, so it's a bit of a catch 22.
I'm always surprised when people turn with it, like I gave you the face because I'm like,
what? I just I just cannot detect who is it until you make it.
I can't do it. Every last one of my friends who told me that introverted, I'm like,
start or be under all belief.
I can't believe it. I'm like, what? You?
Like, yeah, I just need to I just need to just tap out and get the hell out of here
and just recharge because I'm drained.
I'm dead.
I'm always surprised by that because they always just seem to be always up.
Well, and with and with what Elizabeth said was really important that, you know,
it's it's not it's the preference.
It's exactly for her to do.
And, you know, I it's kind of interesting.
I don't know what I am. I don't know if I'm an extrovert or an introvert.
Under certain circumstances, I'm absolutely an introvert.
I feel the same alone.
Let me go do what I want to do.
And other times I'm very extroverted.
I was a radio DJ for eight years.
I just I learned how to be that way.
And I still kind of carry it to a certain extent.
But if I get into a situation where I have an extreme extrovert,
I'm all I shut down. I'm gone.
I will shut off and that meeting is done.
I'm pretty sure Susan Cain has a TED Talk.
And if you haven't watched it, you should absolutely go and watch it.
It's really, really good.
Very insightful.
Yeah, and I can I can identify with what Michael is saying,
that whether you're an introvert or an extrovert,
it's not like a binary function that gets returned a value that you are this or that.
There's definitely a spectrum by which certain aspects
or certain parameters where you can be an extrovert.
I mean, I come from
the Philippines and Southeast Asia and the power distance index, for example,
which is the sense of how you deal with people who you think are your leaders
or your elders out here in the West.
You're being dealt as if you're a peer.
Right. So you can talk freely.
You can disagree freely.
At the end of the day, there's no harm, no harm, no foul, technically, technically.
But from my culture, it's hard for me to kind of talk over
someone who I know is either much older than me, who is my boss.
And it took me.
Well, I'm still dealing with it until now.
I've been in this country for 17 years now, and I'm still dealing with that
on a daily basis.
It gets worse as you see these
titles that go up and I'm in the same room as them.
I just clamped up.
So one thing that would have been
a good answer to one of the questions Elizabeth was asked around how can you
recognize these things is there's a lot of good books and some bad books,
but some writing, at least on this idea of emotional quotient,
which is a lot of people look at that EQ is like making sure
you're not being a dick.
But there's a lot to it.
It's recognizing how you're coming across and how you're being interpreted
sort of in real time as you're having a conversation
and recognizing that people with different whether it's a cultural background
or introversion, extroversion, the way they're reacting, the way they're
taking part in that conversation and recognizing in real time how it's both
influenced by what you're saying and everybody else's participation
is a skill that anyone with any sort of leadership or management would really
it's it's like one of the hardest things to do, but it's really, really important.
Yeah. Yeah.
All right.
Let's that was my favorite event so far.
We have tomorrow to go.
But but Vernon, what what has been your favorite event so far at Test Bash,
Philadelphia, 2016?
So it was also Elizabeth's talk, but also the scavenger hunt was pure genius.
That was so, so good.
So you talk a little bit about frame that for the three
that haven't heard about, oh, wait a minute.
If the three are here.
Who's the hell is going to listen to this podcast?
You know, it's going to be some other.
I know it's going to be it's the person who's not in this room fondly is Mike Stan.
The testacular one.
Brent, well, Mark might listen.
You're right.
So, yeah, the there's a scavenger.
So how this works was
one of the organizers, Richard Bradshaw, who's a friendly tester on Twitter,
set us a mission to go and explore Philadelphia.
And we had to go and find interesting things and make notes on them and return
and give that information to our product owner.
And he said, he didn't say product owner initially.
Did he? Oh, OK.
What he said was, here's here's the scavenger hunt.
Here's the parameters.
As far as the boundaries are concerned.
Here are the points of interest.
Go.
Oh, OK. So it wasn't like a real interrupt.
It wasn't a real like a traditional scavenger hunt.
Because we didn't we were told where to go and not what to look for.
Exactly.
So there were some traps along the way that many of us blundered into.
And we had to come back and answer some questions
that we didn't know about in advance.
So we had to just go out, explore, like Alan said,
gather some information that we didn't know, whether it was the right information
to what degree of detail.
And then the questions came out an hour later and we had to
answer the questions and submit them by with a deadline.
And so it was very interesting how the different teams
captured all that, tackled that from really good, really, really good.
I think what's really interesting is is after the fact, when everyone came back
and you saw such a disparity in who really was able to think through
what this is really trying to teach us.
Yeah. And they went back to Richard and asked him, what's the goal here?
Because so often we go just running out to test or to do whatever it is we do.
And we don't know what the outcome is supposed to be.
We don't know what the final goal is.
We don't have really the definition of done, if you will.
Yeah, it was it was very so it sounds completely random
and inappropriate for a software test and conference to do that.
But the parallels between like Michael was saying, our work
and the scavenger hunt were quite quite, you know.
Yeah, I thought it was a great event just from the perspective of
taking advantage of the venue.
Yeah. You couldn't tell from where we're at, like that we're so close
that we're at the Fringe Arts Theater in Philadelphia.
You can't tell that we are like a quarter mile from Betsy Ross's house.
Yeah. You walk up the hill.
It's like history.
Flaming in your face.
Big time history.
It's absolutely fantastic.
It's brilliant. And I've got a couple of testers on my team.
My entire team is here.
And I've got a couple.
In fact, the majority of my testers aren't even from the United States.
They're there for I've got one from Ukraine.
I've got a number from India.
And for them, this was a great history tour of the United States.
And they absolutely loved going to Independence Hall and seeing,
you know, where the Liberty Bell is, et cetera.
And they didn't realize it was really Liberty Bell.
It's not that big.
But but wait a minute.
I didn't make it to Liberty Bell.
I thought it was like six feet tall.
No, it's the same.
Yeah, I thought it was going to be some gigantic man sized thing.
That was really not as big as you think.
And so I was going home.
But I think I'm going to piggyback on what we're saying.
This is my favorite as well, because of the fact that it took an object lesson.
And Richard did an excellent job.
And he's even now worried that it didn't turn out the way he expected.
I think it nailed it in spades.
He nailed it.
And and the way in which it was done and how he followed up at the end
with the questions he asked and the end of the.
Yeah, he had to lead occasionally.
But by the same token, it worked out to the point where I don't know
that anyone's going to go away from this, not having this as an object
lesson in their in their pocket.
And shout out to Martin Hinnier as well.
For doing a standing job is a terrible product owner.
And does anyone else find it interesting?
I mean, I guess you're from that country, too.
What's it called? The UK? UK. Yeah.
No, no, no. The country, the country is England.
I think you're correct.
It's sad that probably 20 percent of Americans can figure that out.
OK, where was I?
Oh, we have the foreigners, the foreigners coming to America.
As of two days ago, it's pronounced America.
Coming to America and giving us and then setting up a scavenger hunt
of historic American sites. Amazing.
Yeah, I'm going to piggyback on that, too, because that's really where
like one of the stuff that was pretty interesting.
It was I was in a group where mostly are like the people that are in my team.
So we're a very freshly set up team.
And our boss was even in that the disadvantage that I saw in that, though,
it was interesting that it was disadvantageous because my boss grew up in this area.
So he ended up being our tour guide.
So he had so much background history that he started talking about,
you know, what are the other stuff that kind of happened here?
Like, for example, the Christchurch burial site
where Benjamin Franklin was buried, there's actually four other
original signers of the declaration of dependence that were also buried there.
So he had all these like tidbits that he was, you know,
telling us while we were going through.
But the problem is we I would completely blame him.
He actually follows our podcast.
But our podcast, our podcast, our sorry.
This is what happens when Brent is not here.
He's been usurped.
Is that when when you're actually in a testing team
and you have someone who is sort of an expert, they kind of lead you towards
other avenues where he thinks it's important
instead of giving you the chance to be able to, you know, look around
and look at those opportunities where you can actually dig for stuff
that you find interesting.
And I think for me, that was the one thing that kind of
was front and center.
And then after towards the middle of that
exercise, we just started ignoring everything that
the Ministry of Testing were tweeting about.
Because we were just engaged and was just looking around
and just did not care about the product at all.
It's funny, because the after that, because I was in the same team as Alan,
but the sub team, because we split up into sub teams
that I was on, there were two Philadelphians on the team,
but they hadn't really engaged with the history of the city.
So it was it was it wasn't the same as the experience that you have.
There is a fantastic parallel there, though.
How many times have you been working like you, whether it's a tester,
developer, using an app that you've used before these for a long time
and they just get they're just so comfortable sort of working around it
and working within its its glitches and things that new set of eyes come in
and you go, well, why does it do that? Do what?
That? Oh, crap. That's a bug.
Yeah.
It's the same thing if the native going, and this is this is what is that?
I never looked at that before. Yeah. Oh, that's interesting.
Yeah, that's exactly what it was.
Hello, Georgia and Mike.
I don't know if you listen to this, but yeah, they they there were some bits
that they really knew, but there was a lot of it.
Oh, I didn't know that was here. No.
OK, I forgot about that.
And this even the the venue that we're in now
is has history that Mark was telling me about.
So I was sharing the history of this building with Georgia
and Mike and they were like, what?
I didn't even know I didn't even know that was that was the thing.
So so yeah, that was that was pretty cool.
I think ultimately the the takeaway from from that specific experience
comes down to looking at things in a different way and making sure
you know, from taking it back to a testing aspect where our jobs are
basically to provide quality no matter where it comes from, no matter what avenue.
And if it comes from a tweet, if it comes from which is how ministry of testing
chose to provide us with some of the details of how the product is supposed to be
and realizing that we don't always we have to talk to people.
We have to ask the right questions.
We have to talk to the product owners.
We have to provide that information back to our teams
and to the developers.
And however we go about doing that, that's our job.
And and that's what I think was really cool about it.
Hmm. Cool.
Any other highlights from the day you want to mention?
I think Nancy Kellins talk.
I wanted to talk about it, but I want to hear your take first.
It's it's pretty ironic for me in a sense that she was talking about context
driven testing, but then she realized that there's some times where we can be
very imperialistic about like we can we can be very imperious about how we
employ context driven testing.
I thought what she did was 100 percent pure unadulterated context driven testing.
Like it was it was like, what is going to what is my problem and what
what is the best solution right now?
And that's the thing that I'm going to do.
I I I found it interesting that
I interpret what she was saying as I ended up not doing context driven
testing because of the context, right?
Because of the context.
And I was like, you just did one.
You you couldn't have done any.
It couldn't have been any more context driven.
Right. That that realization really for me was was the big key.
Right. That she had to go through that experiment, realize that it didn't work
and then step back and said, no, this does not work for this particular situation.
Like it did work.
I went into a talk.
I mean, I looked at the title.
I thought, ah, crap.
Somebody else spouting off about CDT.
And my stance is testing.
If you're doing it right, it's context driven by definition.
You have if you're not otherwise, you're preaching to the choir
because anyone coming to a conference like this, not going, I love writing
test cases and actually, I'm going to go to a conference and learn more about that.
No, it's so I was pleasantly surprised.
I don't I'm I'm a little burned out on the where I'm a context driven tester.
And I think if you're doing as any sort of coach consultant,
and my line is all knowledge work, all good knowledge work is context driven.
So I went in there with like my bit flipped a little bit already.
But she gave a fantastic talk that talked about problem solving and organizations.
You call that talk problem solving and organizations to me.
I mean, I get why it was titled that and why it works.
I'm not nothing against it for that.
But it was a dang good talk talking about I go in, I recognize the problems.
I don't try and change everything at once.
It's boiled frogs. You change what you can.
Her story about now I got to remember, I remember like what it echoed in my head.
But there was some story about.
Oh, no, it was somebody else.
I'm going to change topics because I'm already this is the way A.B.
testing tangent.
You have a tangent.
I forget who someone was talking about.
Oh, it was the talk before Elizabeth Christina.
She mentioned that this team wanted to do BDD, but the director said,
no, you cannot do BDD.
She goes, I'm going to do BDD anyway.
I'm going to tell you.
They remind me of my very first day at Microsoft when I was handed
this list of test cases and printed out Excel spreadsheet
and managed my manager gave them to me and I said, OK, I got it.
When do you need these automated by?
He goes, oh, no, we don't have time to automate.
I just need you to run these every day.
So that was a Monday.
I had them automated by Thursday.
So it kind of like that is a great skill that, again, a knowledge worker
should have to know, OK, I know what you said and I know why you said it,
but it's not right.
So I'm going to do the right thing for you.
Great example. Give them what they need versus what they want.
That's what I was going to say.
Understanding what, what, what, what's driving this request
and then can I can I meet that need?
Can I scratch that itch?
That's another part of emotional quotient.
One of the talked about a minute ago, it's realizing when you say something
that I think is dumber than crap, there's a reason for that.
I think I know you're a smart guy.
There's a reason you said that. Exactly.
And then as much real time as I can figure out where you're coming from.
So I can interpret and ask you the right precision or probing question
and then actually give you what you need.
Is that a new word?
What's that? Interpret, interpret.
Is now.
New word.
I don't know. I don't know the sound effect for that.
I really liked Christina's talk.
I'm actually in charge of the change management for the engineering
and product teams at my company.
And so, you know, I'm a communicator by nature.
And so it's it's we're going through this period now.
Two years ago, we had to move buildings very, very quickly.
We had a very short time frame because a building that we were in,
the company sold it.
And so we had to move within 30 days to a new location.
It was complete chaos.
But the space that we found is some is a space that everyone loves.
It's open. It's, you know, all the stuff that people love about an old
building in the middle of downtown.
Anyway, now we're having to move again.
And this one is being done
for lack of a better term.
Really, really not well.
I'm going to try and frame this well, because
they've known since August and it's slowly they've not talked to people about it.
They haven't engaged anyone about it.
And suddenly out of the blue, oh, by the way, we're going to move.
This is where we're going to move.
This is when we're going to move.
And the lease still isn't signed today
and we're supposed to move at the end of December.
So everything you shouldn't do in change management is going on here.
And everything you should do is being left aside.
And so the her talk was really good in terms of framing
how it is that you really need to approach change management,
specifically the most important one being time.
You have to give people time to accept what it is.
And the thing that I took is is sometimes when we make changes,
the best thing not to do, the best thing to do is to not make the change
if it isn't going to work.
She didn't say that in the talk, but but there was a very much implied
state there that sometimes change for change is not the best course of action.
Right. One of the things that stood out were
Lynette's slides.
The pictures of the cats were outstanding.
Some of the best collection of cat photos I was.
Yeah, fantastic.
We cannot do justice at all to in a podcast.
No. So go and find that slide deck somewhere and just just revolve.
It's really hard to find the right cats, the right slide
and the right topic there.
Who knew cats were so expressive?
That's what that's what I'm going to say.
I just thought they were their cats.
I don't know.
They could be.
Could all be her.
They could be performance.
If they're all hers, she's got a lot of cats.
She's got a lot of cats. Yeah.
I should talk to Mark Tomlinson, also one of the three,
because we have if nothing else, we have made a great advertisement
for next year's Test Bash.
Totally. So far so good.
So tomorrow's my talk.
So it could be a little shaky as I make a hand motion.
No one can see.
But if it's anything, if the day is anything,
hopefully the talks tomorrow are as good as today's.
And no one will notice if I take it.
No, it'll be good.
Don't worry. You have at least three or four hecklers.
All right. We'll throw things.
That's awesome. That's awesome.
OK, so shall we wrap it up and get some dinner?
Yes. All right.
This is going to be I'm going to say it right here.
Thank you for listening to episode 48 of A.B.
Testing on the road in Philadelphia.
I'm Alan.
I'm not Brent.
I'm Vernon, but not related to Michael Richards.
And yeah, none of us are Brent.
Brent, we don't miss you.
I'll see you soon, Brent.
And the rest of you can hear from us on episode 49.