Hey everybody. Hello. Hey, I'm Alan. I'm Brent and we are here for episode 48. Wrong.
That was my Donald Trump.
47.5
episode
We're just gonna skip over 48. No, we're not because right now I was waiting till this moment to post it
But I recorded episode 48 without you
Okay, then so check it out lean over here for a second, okay
Here's the picture. I work with three of the three
The the four of us got together the three of the three and me. Oh, I like that three of the three and me we got
Vernon Richards has to from tester from from luster. We have Percy, you know Percy. Yep and
Michael Richards who was salty gunner. Yep. They were all at test bash. We recorded episode 48 together and I'm gonna post it right now
I was waiting for this moment
So episode 49 that's one way to make sure we get to 50 this year
And I'm not sure we're looking for
still looking for
Interesting suggestions on what we should or could do for episode 50. So keep those coming in
Hey, I just got notified from Twitter that we
48 and we're recording episode 49 right now and if all goes well, I'll have this out on Monday
I just got notified tips. What'd you do retweet it? I did
This is give me the worst podcast ever while we stare at our phones and retweet each other
So I just got back not just last week a week ago. I was in
Philadelphia you ever been to Philadelphia? I have not it was my first time to Philadelphia
great time
Impressive conference don't hear about it. I do
All right. I'll tell you I did a little quick little blog post about it. But in short
I read the quick little blog post about it's a single track conference. They do them all the time
the next one is in
His Brighton next I can't remember. Oh, no, maybe I don't know that they're all over
They did these little one to two day. This was the first two day test bash
normally test bash is a one-day thing, but it's a single track conference they
The one thing that was different from a lot of conferences is that I actually liked all the talks there were
but Alan
You don't attend conferences you only present I attend the conferences I present that
So this one I was so happy so Percy posted a picture of Alan sitting in the audience
I'm like
Yeah, you attend these things
Was good. I all the speakers top to bottom very impressed one here something weird all talks
Very good. There was one mention of contracts driven testing where I rolled my eyes for the obvious reasons. Yep, but I
Liked it. There was one event we came back from lunch on the first day and we talked and this is rehash of what's episode 48
But does it can I say we've talked about this before without drinking if you and I haven't talked about this before I
think so
So in short the just so you know
there was
This interesting scavenger hunt, but it wasn't like a real scavenger hunt. So we came back from lunch and
We were told all right form some groups of about 10 people and
This guy down here is your product owner and here's a link to a Google map with some sites marked go check them out
Take some pictures take some notes come back
So it was a scavenger hunt where we didn't know what we were scavenging for
So we visited these places took lots of pictures and we came back and there was a quiz
full of all sorts of random trivia and
Somehow the team I was on tied for first, okay
if
What in general was the point of the scavenger hunt just a building? No, it was interesting there were
I thought in history
I thought it was a
Weird reason to get us out in the fresh air which is great to get out in the fresh air in the middle of a
Commerce right after lunch when it's nap time
But there were some interesting parallels to testing
There were things that people and tell me if this is you haven't seen this before in like bringing a new person onto a team
Mm-hmm. There were Philadelphia natives there and there were people like me had never been there before
There were things that the natives didn't notice at all
But the new people coming in said oh, what's that? Oh, I've never noticed that before
Tell me you haven't seen that in software. I
Test your eyes is what I used to call it
So and I think it was more of a way to get us out and about but
Doing the sort of scavenger hunt and that what we didn't know what we were scavenging for has, you know dealing with ambiguity in there
Sure. Anyway fun time. I did have most of a Saturday to walk around and check things out
I saw the Liberty Bell. I was going to ask it's not nearly as big as I've been led to believe my whole life
How big is it?
Four feet tall. Okay and with the bell about the same
I was the pictures I saw in my history books. I thought I was this massive like 12 foot tall Bell. It's not maybe it was just me I
want to
Times times tick enough like I have an 18 year old now. I've always wanted to sort of cats in the cradle
Little boy, yeah
Weeds
I always wanted to sort of take them on sort of a history tour of the of the Northeast
Yeah, I love but right now if I can ever actually get him to
Apply to college which he has to do by the end of this month
We're thinking of our big
Brew ha ha for summer is a
Crew someplace. All right. All right. I'd like to go to Washington DC sometime me too
So I am inviting myself to speak at any conference or group in Washington DC
Place I have a band I really like to go to
all I require is
Flight and like three nights hotel and I'll speak whatever you want me to throw it out there for the three
When do you want to go? Oh anytime?
Anytime maybe before January you want to go like
I'm just worried that the city may just implode or explode maybe implode on after January. Oh
We could spin the rest of the podcast if we want
better not
We better not
Okay, so you talked to test bash I did I gave a talk it was
testing without testers, which is a flavor of talk I'd give them before but this one was
much much different from the versions I gave previously at QA SIG in Seattle and
When did I give it before then? Oh, I gave another variation of it at
What's that called in Waterloo?
Test
Group SIG up there. So I was following
What was it Twitter or something?
People were posting comments. I had a good Twitter explosion during my talk. I was very happy
I was like coming back from my talk and bringing out my Twitter phone and seeing like a whole bunch of tweets one of the guys
That I read in the way he commented him. I I interpreted it as
He walked away from your talk sort of feeling that
testing without
testers blows and
And that kind of surprised me. No, no, I don't think that's I don't think I was his takeaway
That was a Twitter is a moment in time, right?
So at the risk of getting hammered at 830 in the morning, we've talked about
Way me I'm too tired to hammer wait ways to do
Combined engineering or engineering teams incorrectly
So I did talk about the fact that if you just say okay, no more testers everyone's a developer
You're probably gonna fail and that does blow
It does and you will yeah, sure that that moment and that that's the moment in time. He was capturing
Okay, if you do this wrong, it's going to suck if even if you do without a plan whatsoever
It's going to be wrong and therefore it's going to suck
So I talked and again, it could be a rehash of a a B testing episode
But I talked a lot about how you can do it wrong
What the benefits of it are because a lot of inefficiencies in having the siloed teams
I got to imagine it's not coincidental, but I got a spike on the
The unified engineering blog post right interesting right when you were
Good Wi-Fi there people were looking stuff up trying to understand what the connection would be
I don't know. I mentioned unified engineering so they searched your I don't know
Like a precog I don't think you talk about it. Yeah, I don't I don't think you ever did a blog post on my blog post
No, so I'm not certain how they would I don't know
But there are search engines where if you search for terms it may show up things that show up in your blog
Did you call it unified engineering? I did I just said that okay. Jeez. That's how they did it then
So anyway, it can be very inefficient to have siloed engineering teams. I talked about how my previous team
Definitely didn't need any testers, but we didn't have any UI
Didn't have anything that needs have any visual verification very easy to do though. Those are those are no-brainers
You shouldn't have a test team test that crap
But a little bit different on my current product where lots of UI
built very quickly
There are some dragons under the covers
We require our and expect our developers to write lots and lots of tests
But we do even though we're technically an engineering team
We have my team that does some quality infrastructure work around diagnostic tools
Making sure test infrastructure is working etc
And then we have a small team of vendors who do manual test manual visual verification sort of testing
So we're not completely testerless
No, you're not by the way last time I was in your building for podcast. Yeah
Ran into one of my former employees who's on your dev team. Who is that?
Ron Hatton. Yes, that's right
Called out here along the world
I'm sure he's one of your favorites. Ron's good. Yeah, Ron's good
He's working a lot on the mobile platforms now and doing very very well my experience is
people who
Spent a lot of time as Estes and then moved to the dev role
Get this new world much faster and better than oh, is he an estet before? Yeah, okay
Yeah, that's probably gets it and it's weird. I know
Given who's making a change how much I have a gut feeling of how good I feel about it
Most of those people are former testers
Here so there are some of who aren't former testers who are very good as well
But they just see the forest for the trees a lot better
He was one of my ICs when I started down this agile journey in Bing
Very interesting. Yeah
So you've heard the whole story
Dr. Rehash the whole talk was about how it can work
For the problem solving how you get developers to do testing
there was a little bit of organizational change a little bit of
Preparing people who are maybe heading down this path and what it means and how to coach their management on how to
make this change successfully and
Also just how to coach developers on how to become testers how important that is for
How important of a skill that is for people who are testers today one interesting thing I asked at the beginning
I said how many of you are on a team with?
No testers and this one woman raises her hand. I goes so I was going for she goes I cry a lot
It's really easy to head down it's really I think easy to get in that stage where you're just if it's done wrong
you're the only tester and you're and all the crap is flowing downhill to you it can be a
Very lonely and dark and sad place what I'm imagining
Remember back in the days when?
Q-tech still existed. Yes the quality and test engineering community. Yep that that Alan was the chair of within Microsoft
Do remember dead you remember the talk? I did it one of the Q-techs on this journey
I'm kind of imagining what you did a test bash is
an equivalent to the talk I did at that one Q-tech meeting where I was
Essentially trying to communicate to the to other test teams at Microsoft the same sort of thing
You remember that are you saying I copy you no because I don't
No, I'm just kidding you know
I do even if you did I'm sure your talk is way better than I do vaguely remember it
Yeah, and it really is how do I take all these skills? I have as a tester and
Maybe it's a survival guy like what if this happens to me? What if my org gets rid of testers?
How do I survive here are some ideas and it turns out there was a consultant there that gave a talk about
Balancing from company to company doing organizational change, and it's actually what she does and what I do are very similar
Going to go into the org
It starts bottom holes and filling them
So are you there a lot of power you now announcing on the podcast to your up-and-coming?
Career as a test consultant. I would except I
Don't want to be a test consultant
Really no desire I
honestly don't
understand the psyche around those who do
look
There is an entire industry, and I'm pretty certain that several of our three are
Look, you know look again, and look look once look twice and then look three times
There is and maybe will always be this
Business if you want to there's so much turnover in test and one thing about test bash is the audience is very sophisticated
too a lot of not
Or even called novice but a lot of experienced testers in the audience so they it's easier to get the point across
I don't think I could have given this talk at to a bunch of newbie testers at one of the big conferences
They would have wouldn't have got it at all
But because I'm talking to people who kind of been around the block a lot and they kind of it was a lot better
Received the maturity of the audience helped
Me deliver the message of my talk
But to finish my other thought because we do on on a B testing is we just bounce all over the place is
that there is a whole
Business that I could work as long as I wanted as much as I wanted
Teaching brand new testers how to test software that will always exist and there that's what that's why test consultants exist
Because there are always brand new people that want to learn testing software. Just like we did it in 1992
Forever I that's boring to me to me. That's
Sad I don't think I could do it would be like
being a nurse at
Children's Hospital in the fatal cancer wing. I don't think I could do that job
Yeah, I'm I'm helping you to kill your career wait wait
I just bring a dark downer to everything so so let's let's go back to something more up in in your blog post
You mentioned something that in some regards surprised me
Knowing how tight you are with Lee Copeland
You mentioned that test bash
Might in fact be your official favorite test conference. I think it is
Yes, and what you describe it you describe it as a sense of maturity
But one of the things that that I keep
Harping on it on the podcast is I don't think I don't know if it's a set of maturity or a modernization
Right because what it what you described to me feels like hey, this is a test conference about
testing in
2016 not
1992 in many ways yes
But it may be in all ways a couple other things that make it better and nothing and Lee I like you
I like your conferences. They're good for a
people who want to know a
broad
Number of ideas about testing there is four or five tracks going on at once the keynotes are always very good at star conferences
The track sessions I at star and Lee actually suggests this you can bounce around from session to session
And I usually do that as a way to get the most value
There wasn't one session. I saw at test bash. I would have left to go see anything else
They're all very good even the ones where I you know
Maybe had a few eye-rolling moments. I enjoyed I thought everybody had a good story to tell some were fantastic
there was
tangent there was one talk by Abby bangs or and
Someone she works with whose name I forgotten and they did what I thought was a fantastic talk that could be done at
Not probably even better suited for like an agile conference in a dev conference, but it was they did like a a
play
Where it was really cool. They would act out like the talk was about how to treat infrastructure like a real product
But was really about how to they were there
Did a synopsis like a little reenactment of a real-life work interaction?
then
They had a way of like stepping out of it and talking about what was going on
Fourth wall break. Yeah
It was like it was like yeah, it was exactly it was breaking the fourth wall third wall fourth wall
And then they go back into it and then pop out and it was it was done really well
They obviously worked on it a lot, but executed super well
Really really cool. I thought it was a great talk Lee actually pinged me afterwards. I gave him a few suggestions for
People to invite the star I think there's I think that conference
I think all conferences have their place in an audience are looking for what frustrates me about star is not the speakers and the talks
I get value out of when I go and I go to a lot of talks when I'm there is
how much of star is a
How much star is a platform for vendors to try and drum up business for test consultants to try and drum up business and
even though there were people who are officially consultants speaking at test bash
I didn't feel like at any time they were trying to sell me anything or try and get business
Where I really feel almost overwhelmed with that at star
Yeah, I get what you're talking about like
The last conference I went to a strata
Right and they had different
they they had the tracks that were sort of the sharing is carrying tracks and
the sharing to sell tracks and
the sharing I even think those the sort of
Sharing to sell tracks the best way to drum up business would be the soft sell and that is
just show
That you are awesome because of of your knowledge and your tooling and show the
Awesomeness in a way that resonates with the people right you do that enough time is playing the odds. You'll get your sales
the
the test bash talks were
Almost entirely not entirely almost entirely experiential people were telling their experiences on the job wasn't
Very little like theoretical like here's the definition of the word metric and here's how you know
It's like oh god. None of that crap that I ate all very much. Here's an experience
I had at work and what I learned from it and
Here's some things that maybe that I've discovered. Maybe you should know too, which was what kept me engaged in the talks
So kind of a TED model in some ways
Yeah without the strict like Ted you must talk for 22 minutes
Then you're pulled off the stage by a hook and you must but very good everybody's well prepared
I give a lot of credit to Rosie and Richard and whoever else on the staff put together test bash and
Helped prep and choose speakers. I think it I was very impressed
There's an elephant in the room. We haven't talked about
Brent doesn't understand the word metaphor
Or metaphor means I had a great by the way before we get to the elephant in the room
Great metaphor this morning from a mutual friend of ours
there is a
engineering manager a peer of mine on our team who's
Struggling to get the right data for his performance metrics
always frustrated not never can figure out what he wants or the best way to put it and there's and and
then the data team is trying to figure out what data he wants and then he says I can't refresh the cube and
What what he's doing but not Jim what what this engineering manager is doing is the equivalent of so the metaphor was
He's shopping while hungry
So he's taking he just want he's going into the store and wants everything just give me it all
I'll figure out what I want to make later
Which is good for the soul but bad for your diet and checkbook
My advice to Jim was says take him to the grocery store teach him at a shop for a sensible meal plan
All right away from metaphors elephant in the room means something we haven't talked about
One week two weeks ago and one week previous to my test bash talk
My product was officially announced this thing. We've been talking about as my product is now known around the world as
Microsoft teams whoo-hoo congratulations on the ship
Shipping is a weird word in the new world, right?
Congratulations on your release
announced and I'm still training the congratulations on general availability. No, no GAs later. Oh
Okay, but it's weird a lot of people on my team are used to and I've mostly work on
Traditional shrink wrap products as well, but the transition has not been difficult for me because I actually pay attention to the real world
But there's this I still hear words like okay. What are we working on for v2?
So what's a v2? I don't get it. We ship every week. We ship all the time. Yeah
V2 is that like next Thursday? Yeah
so and
Couple interesting things it'll tie into
We took a little about teams teams is a collaboration platform a lot like slack
Which you can use one of the three dot slack comm to talk about our podcast
But our product is targeted for yes, you can go to the teams
You can sign up to the teams competitor to learn more about teams
exactly
Brent gets it. You can't get the elephant in the room
Selective intelligence. Yeah
anyway
targeted at office 365 users
So if you're a company that has a oh 365 tenant you can flip this thing on you have a great collaboration tool
it works really well, there's a lot of spit and polish and and
Feel little bells and whistles to put on top, but it's
Coming along so so we're not going to abandon the slack channel anytime soon to go to teams then not soon
But at some point
There's a there's a plan to
Not have the oh 365 requirement. I cannot talk about how we're going to work around that but at some point it'll be a viable
Alternative to the slack channel. Okay. All right, let's go there a couple interesting things
I have several questions afterwards, but I'll wait for your interesting things because you
Talk about shipping because one interesting thing I've noticed is we ship all the time
We have seven services and a front end
That ship and all those ship one of the services ships twice a week. Everything else ships once a week
So that makes nine times a week
seven eight nine times a week we ship
but what's interesting and I'm sure this is not uncommon for
Teams that ship something. There's a front end lots of back end stuff is
from our our team
Most of our team especially like program management and designers and up. They really only care about when the front end ships
Yep, they asked did we ship yet this week? I said we ship on when we actually first thing I say is
We ship all the time. What are you looking for? But do we ship?
So I still do we I we have some new we have new rounded corners in the buttons
Oh did the front end ship the front end ships on Wednesdays?
it's
So yeah, it's not visual. It didn't happen
the question that I
Here's a question that I think you should practice
when they come to you I
What?
Features are you looking to understand when they released?
Because it's not a product ship anymore. It's a feature release now. Yeah. Oh and also this is it's getting more confusing
There is you ever seen this you know, you know the move my cheese metaphor
Yep
Well, I have these confused mice who can't find their cheese because not only do we ship we ship to the world on Wednesday
but we ship to
The Microsoft ring on Monday and then to our team for dog food the previous Thursday. Okay, and
Is it the same mice that are confused the mice just can't follow?
It's like rings of deployment are confusing. Let's not do that. I said
I'm too scared. I see my head shaking here. Like yeah, I'm too scared to not have rings of deployment
Yeah, I wouldn't do it. I wouldn't do it that way of Mike. Okay
Let's sit down and figure out how I can help you
Get be less confused. Do you think I have time to sit down with these people?
You don't have time to deal with them pushing back every day
I'm being slightly facetious here. All right, you have some questions you fire away. Yeah, so
long strings and
The average. Oh
That's right. Not jeopardy. Good. Go ahead and start over in terms of your designers and your PM's I guess that's that's
not too surprising when when
When I went to power bi and help them walk through it though, we
We were very
Planful and proactive so I didn't experience
When we finally started doing our regular continuous deployment
I did not experience this same phenomenon that you are with your PM's
because
We told them upfront. This is how it's gonna work now over and over again
the biggest impact though was on the dev side and so I'm curious as to
how live site handling might be working now or
Have you seen any behavioral change?
Within the dev team, I'll give you I'll give you a rough number here like
My dev team
Lately they're they're essentially expressing that live site activities DRI
Which stands for designated responsible individual the person who answers the phone right?
that
overall live site activities is
taking up about 50% of
Devs time now. Yeah ours one thing that helped us with that is
We even when we're only shipping we weren't really shipping. We had only our team was using it
We had the DRI process in place
So we had weeks and weeks and weeks and months and months of practice
Going through the DRI path before we even had any real customers and then as we slowly added customers
They were very used to it. We definitely have more issue. We're cleaning up a lot of
Monitors and when you're the DRI right now, it's pretty much full-time. You're figuring out what's wrong and tweaking stuff
we also have a small team dedicated to
site reliability engineering or SRE and those people
Very much following the Google SRE model were 50% of the time they're they're coding and running diagnostic tools, etc
And then 50% of the time it's sort of helping and coaching the bailing out sometimes the DRIs
but our
One thing we're doing pretty well. We have I was incident manager this week
And I still am until this afternoon
And I didn't get any calls this week. Everything that was picked up by the DRI which was good
Are you tracking uptake?
Like what's the usage? We're up to well over a hundred thousand active users
So on our way up, okay. I am looked at the numbers that they probably higher than that we've had
thousands and thousands of tenants turn on and a lot of people just turning on small parts of their tenant or or
Like the IT admins generally will have like a test tenant. They'll play with they'll turn on for their company
But it's a more uptake than I planned
We've had a couple set of ones
A few set of two is a lot of threes and fours which are actually mostly monitoring glitches
But some we're learning to filter the noise from the real issues as we finally have
Something close to real traffic. You're on top of Azure. Yeah, we are
Okay, we're entirely on top of an Azure. We depend on you very much
Send me your subscription
The the other thing that would that would be good if you have your own monitoring
And if you don't it's a top of MDM
No, no, no, no Microsoft stuff. Yeah, but one thing that would be extremely valuable to us here is
If you had your own monitoring, we're on your own not relying on our data, but on your own
Determine outages that you would blame Azure on okay interesting as Brett and I bring up work stuff in the podcast. Yeah
Last weekend before last
Tell me that brings a bell we had all kinds of failover in East US
There was a big outage in East. Yeah. Okay. All right correlation. So but which is actually really good
For us because we had manually tested failover
But it was good that automatically those things were rerouted to West US and and in particular
My team is really looking for is an internal team that
Monitors the availability and reliability of their own service independently from Azure data and
attributes out their own outages to Azure
Independently. Okay. So if you have that or something like that, yeah, I want to talk. All right. I will connect. Yeah
Well, oh shit. We're doing a pocket better together
I
Mean yeah, we're talking business on the podcast, but
This is all about how how to use data to even improve quality even better, right? If I can take your data
Connect it with the Azure data and change certain behaviors here because you're independently measuring this
I can improve my platform which then improves yours
Sounds good. Yeah, follow up
Back to what we're talking about teams and deployment and teams and you said SRE live site
So you're saying you haven't seen much of a behavior change yet with dev because you've already
Yeah, not much not trained them beforehand. I think
Yeah, we train them beforehand. They're acting pretty well. They know where they're
We're yelling at about the same things and they're slowly getting better
Our we had a lot of noise in our monitors, but we knew we had noise that's getting better now
Could we have traffic we can believe it?
I like having more users because the numbers start making sense around, you know, but we look at perf latency and errors happening
We can start to actually know what's going on in the world. Have you started?
Trying to fake out a B testing
That is definitely on that is our about experimentation not Alan Brent testing, right?
Experimentation slash B
That's definitely the goal. We're not quite there yet. We're not quite to the stage where you're my
One of my goals is everything's an experiment. Let me ask you this. We're not quite there yet. Let me ask you this
There is I'm gonna assert this
That there is at least one feature
That you and a PM argued about that you lost
It shipped and now you have the data to determine who was right. Mm-hmm. Absolutely. Have you done that yet? Not yet
Do it then you need help. Let me know
I've been busy with the other part of my job, which is getting getting crap out the door not crap getting
quality bits out there the second you can get the
It's a huge opportunity to get your PM's now
understanding
What this data can be used for and to start?
Start the the journey we actually talked about in
Episodes 45 through yeah 40 whatever no and I've definitely applied a lot of that and we are getting there
But we are just getting
Our flooding system hit the ground hot
So we're still ironing out some things there. It's getting better and better but
absolutely experimentation is on the short-term radar and
looking at data to
Looking at the data to see what's being used and how it's being used or not
And I'm saying you don't need experimentation to begin your drawing the intuitionists. I
like that the intuitionists
Which both of us are very much driven off of intuition
And there's I did a tweet well, I'll paraphrase my own is it paraphrase and paraphrase myself
I can't remember exactly what I said, but the tweet is much more profound than I'm about to speak right now where I will say
The the root of your killer features is I thought it would be cool if it's probably not
Right, and I've seen just a lot of a lot of dead ends there
Yep, because we are intuitions. Oh, you know what our customers really need. You know what they need
They need a pink theme. Oh
For sure. They gotta have the pink theme. It's really important. I talked to my daughter and teams team should automatically integrate with lift and uber
That would be so cool if that could happen
We have a lot of third-party integration we and I could just see that yeah
We need a tab for lift we have imagine like slack channel
We have tabs or you have different functionality like a VSTS tab, etc
Right visual studio team system and then we give them for a lift like you go to the tab to order your lift ride
If you mention that to someone on my team like a PM they might do it and then I punch you in the face
So which PM
How do you know I mean it's
Interesting to do an experiment actually the way you do an experiment is you do an experiment is you say?
All right, let's give them a lift tab very low. See if they use it. Oh, they don't use it
Must be because it wasn't pink enough. We'll make it pinker any other questions about teams and deployment and things
I should be doing better
No, I think the I think the next part of your data culture
Journey is is is going to be
Introducing PM's to a better way. Yeah, if you're if your ops are there
Right the the other thing I would recommend
So if you're doing a traditional
DRI approach with TSG's and you have an SRE team whose entire job is to
Identify and put out fires, but not necessarily put out the fire starters. Mm-hmm, right?
then
You should start paying attention to what TSG's are being actively used
You should ask that you should ask your SRE to keep track of the TSG usage stats
Because those are things
That you should get your dev team to automate now. Yeah, that's actually a really good idea
I will do that one thing
I don't know if this is common or not, but it made a lot of sense to me
I want to talk about briefly is talk about deployment
So my team owns everything for the moment code is checked in till it goes to the customer
So a lot of quality and testing is in there as well as you know, check in tools gates, etc. Build, etc
One thing I've done recently
Before we ship but maybe a last month about month or so is we get everything deployed to the Deadpools
No Deadpool is good movie. So
Everything's ready. The bits are live or ready to start routing traffic to new whether it's back-end server stuff or a new front-end
I let our SR. I don't let I
I
Passed at that point. I'm done with it
I give it to the SRE and the SRE actually routes traffic and does that move because they can
They know how to watch the monitors and see what's going on and when to roll back or make those choices, right?
So that's been very helpful because then I feel a little felt like I'm passing the buck to them
I've said this is
Like this is ready to go but you know better if it's not or if it's something's gonna go weird
And we have for better for worse one thing we've learned over the last two weeks is how to roll back
Good. Yeah, I'm like a roll back very effectively
quickly that is some
One mistake I see a lot of teams do is that when they start going into the service world
They don't have a plan
for
Rollback and when you're in this world, right?
Which which then reinforces this this preventative?
Test model which directly harms your ability to do continuous deployment
Mm-hmm, which is the which is another one of the places I want to get to you
We're not we're we're rapid deployment, but certainly not continuous deployment. Maybe not even rapid. What should I call it frequent?
semi-frequent often deployment
So that's that's really good news the my team right now is
Working one of our key missions is to apply data science towards
the NRT
DRI life site type problems
Azure is growing very rapidly
I'm not going to mention numbers here. It's highly competitive space but
What our predictions show for what's going to happen in the next five years is
unlike
Anything we've experienced thus far and so I'm helping to lead on helping
to get our assets
scaling to that
Should be a fun adventure the more the more and more I think about it. We've talked a lot on on here around
Shifting to out agile is important because of calendar time, right?
That's something that the Azure team fully is bought into
But what's happening next the next target is engineer time
Right, we can't have
50% of our engineers
You know
Just focused on putting out fires
Absolutely, correct. So I'm very excited about this stuff
It also it is also exciting that I can say hey
Alan start thinking about this that'd be good to do. Yeah, we rely a lot on Azure everything's yeah
Okay, as you can imagine
Okay, this has been episode
Apparently so
Sorry, brant man. I blacked out of all 48
So we'll be back next time for the big 5-0, right? I guess
All right, it's been a hell of a time. We'll see you next time