It's up everybody. Hello, I'm Alan. I'm Brent. And guess what? We're back again.
Episode... How many are we, Brent? Episode number 36.
All right, we're not recording. We're not. I'm kidding, we are. Yeah.
So again, the astute three will know you record usually in the morning at 8am.
Yep. And it's a good time to catch Brent a little off guard. And Alan takes far too much pleasure
in that. You know, I do. I do laugh at the misfortune of others. Did you see the Taylor Swift?
Whoa! I kicked the button on my chair and I just dropped about a foot. It was like a little
elevator drop. I'm good now. Did you happen to see the Taylor Swift versus a treadmill?
No. Oh, it's good. So not a big Tay Tay fan. Not a big fan of treadmills. In fact, if I were to
choose one or the other, I would choose the treadmill. But there's this video of Taylor
Swift. It's an app. It's an ad for Apple Music. We're at Microsoft. I just talked about Apple.
It's great. And she's running and rapping and showing like she can pick whatever song she wants,
you know, and she goes doing her thing and then she falls flat on her face. It's hilarious.
The misfortune of others always... Was it Chaucer who said that? One of the three tell me
there's a line, a famous line about laughing at the misfortune of others. And I laughed at
Taylor because it was really done well. Honestly, if we take away all of our social
filters and really think about it, I think we'll all agree that there is nothing funnier
than watching somebody actually or accidentally hitting the coffee table with their shin.
As long as you don't die. As long as you don't die.
So how many? 36? 36 episodes. And we have hit our two year mark.
We've been doing this for two years, 36 times saying the exact same shit.
Over and over and over. And yet we have now multiple people claiming that
they've binge listened to us. There's only three listeners, Brent.
Yes, they rotate through. After one person finishes Ben listening, you're like,
Oh, I've pretty much figured out everything these guys have to say.
Yeah. I don't understand. Honestly, thank you, Danny Fott. I know there's others, but
he's one of the three now and he said he binge listened. And honestly, I can't stand listening
to myself talk for more than about 15 minutes. I don't know how it happens. I don't know how
you survive. I'm betting alcohol or massive amounts of coffee.
It might be a distraction from like a commute home. I don't know.
While we're wallowing in our two years of... Whatever this is.
I think success is too strong of a word. In fact, I'm sure it is. Two years of therapy.
In one of the topics that was rejected from today's list, as the three know our process,
as we get in the room and set about five minutes writing some things on the whiteboard, we say,
Yep, yep, yep, nope, nope, we order them. And then we go. And one of the things we cut was
just some stuff often listeners may have figured this out.
Are you uncutting it?
No, I'm cutting it. I'm just saying that they were there because I just need some therapy on
this and working through with Brent in front of the front of three people we can't see
often helps me. So if we have not helped the three and the community,
maybe in a way we've helped each other.
No.
So speaking of hugs, I got the nicest LinkedIn comment that I share with Brent.
And now I'm going to share.
Hey, wait a minute.
Wait, wait, not yet.
Did I ever tell you that I kind of invented a drink?
Okay, no, but there's a story here. Please tell me.
I call it the group hug.
Oh, please go on.
And it's it is just n shots of Patron.
I love it.
So that's so interesting. When you thought of drink, I thought I really don't. I love wine,
beer, it's IPA or nothing for me. I'm a Northwesterner.
I love the bite of the IPA. But if I drink a hot hot alcohol,
it's almost always tequila occasionally have a gin and tonic, but I'm a big tequila fan or mezcal.
So I don't know what a mezcal is.
Mezcal is like this. It's still from Agave, but it's a smoky. It's really good. If you can find
a good one or really awful. If you find a bad one, the swing on mezcal I found is a bit large,
but someone at work yesterday. And once again, I'm proud of ourselves because we cannot quite get to
that first topic without a tangent. But there's a tradition at Microsoft. I don't know who started
or even if it's really a tradition, but people bring in on their anniversary of n number of years,
that many pounds of M&Ms.
Yeah, I don't know when that actually began.
Because I didn't even hear of it.
20 years.
I didn't even hear of it till I've been here at least 10.
Yeah. And I actually started getting harassed for not doing it like the last three years.
And people do variations once in a while, and I've never, ever, ever done it. And someone
yesterday been here 11 years and brought in 11 pounds of M&Ms. And maybe I'll be a team player
and I'll bring in some on my 21st anniversary coming up this year. And I thought because
my 21 year anniversary at Microsoft is in June.
Is it?
Yeah, I hit my 20 year last year. So I'll be 21 years in June.
I must be 21 now.
Yeah, maybe.
Because I'm like, wait a minute.
So because I have been working long.
I am.
Brent. The sight of Brent actually thinking is like freaky.
You know, as it's like, first days and anniversaries as I get older, I was like,
I don't even want to know him anymore. So yes, I'm old.
Anyway, go ahead.
My story.
You're listening time. I'm glad we didn't hug.
I will this June I will have been at Microsoft 21 years and 21 is the legal drinking age.
So instead of M&Ms, I am going to bring in a nice bottle of tequila and doing shots.
Then you want to come by my desk.
Oh, but not that we drink at work.
It'll be all the time.
Little teeny shots.
If you go to you have a bev mode just down the street.
We do here.
Yeah, just up the street.
Oh, I know where it is.
Yeah.
I don't know if you've seen these things. They're called twisted shots with a Z.
I really leery of pre mixed drinks.
They're not. No, they're there.
They're these small little shot glasses, kind of like K cups.
And in the middle of it is is there's a divider and they put in one beverage on one side and
another beverage on the other side.
And then when you shoot them, the mix and so it's mostly not pre mixed,
but they're fun as hell.
Some of them are really good.
Next time I go to a frat party, I'll bring one.
No, go get a six pack.
You can test them out at home with your wife and then you go, hey,
I'm thinking about getting I don't know what are you going to get 21.
Anyway, I like getting good like Patron.
It's a sipping tequila.
That is shouting to get its group hug.
It's a group hug.
Yeah. All right.
Oh, so anyway, back to the podcast.
We're still recording.
Looks like it.
Yes.
Oh, indeed we are.
So I got a nice we got I got it.
It came to my LinkedIn inbox, but I shared it with Brent.
A very nice comment from a LinkedIn, a linker.
What's it called?
A linked someone I'm connected to.
Yeah.
That sounds very new agey.
A connection, a connection.
Chris George.
He says, Hey, I never thought I'd write a letter like this.
Sorry, wrong one.
Hi, I recently found yours and Brent's A B testing podcast and as such have found a new
use of the two hour commute time in my car.
Wow.
One two hour commutes a long time.
And I feel sorry for that.
Luckily, there's an hour we can do something else because our podcasts are usually.
You think it's two hours one way.
I don't know.
Anyway, he says, and I say, I've been a tester for 20 years,
mix of automation, exploration, management, et cetera.
Sounds like a lot of the three and rent and I, and I guess in the last couple of
years have been struggling with working out how testers fit into continuous delivery teams.
I've experienced the dev tester dependency cycle, which we've talked about.
I love that.
Thanks for picking that up many times and have been in denial that the tester role is the
problem.
Listening to your podcast and the explanation of the dependency cycle and the unified engineering
teams.
I love that he uses unified, not the stupid Microsoft combined thing.
Yes.
So I'm digging.
He gets our lingo.
He does like he's really like, this is why I'm all tingly and happy.
One of the three.
Welcome.
It's consolidated and validated many thoughts that I've been having recently and helped me
adopt a more consultancy role in my current team to help the devs do more and better testing.
So in a word, thanks.
Keep up the good work.
So thank you, Chris.
Yeah.
Thanks, Chris.
I we love hearing that we actually do something.
I'd say right again.
I'm not really.
Yeah.
Help totally wrong.
My my goal in life is one of the one of my principles, I guess, wouldn't say goal.
A principle is just to help people.
And if I can help you, it's good for my who I am.
Well, we talked about it last time.
People want purpose, mastery and autonomy.
Yeah.
And furthermore, they do want those.
We're still working on mastery.
We're still and we're still huge fans of Dan pink.
Yeah.
If you get bored of our podcast, just pick up like one of the Dan pink audio books and go
from there.
So I run the hidden brain quite often, which is good.
NPR podcast.
I have to add that one.
I have too many podcasts in the delete some.
Anyway, I wrote back and I said, as I worry, I said, I see to say, I said, I worry that
we're kind of beating a dead horse because as Brett and I already mentioned today,
we've been talking about the same thing pretty much for 36 going on 36 hours now
over two years.
But I say, I worry sometimes you're beating a dead horse and he wrote back.
Nice guy said, I don't think it's a dead horse.
So we're beating a live horse, apparently.
Many teams are at various various stages in this journey.
He's been in a position where being able to react and ship tools quicker
is important for a number of years.
It's quite easy.
But however, howings, however, seeing how you guys change track from my perspective
are knocking it out of the park regarding frequent high quality and reactive
releases.
Is it just inspirational for a massive organization?
So when he said change track, I'm like, wait a bit.
Is he about to give us a compliment on ADHD?
That's the, you know how I don't know if you're like me, but all the podcast on the
car and then I'll think about something and I'll space out and I realized I
haven't heard the last 10 seconds or 30 seconds or whatever.
So yeah, of course.
So the, the bonus in our podcast is when it happens, you wonder,
am I still listening to the same podcast because we changed our.
And it, and it's a positive thing with our podcast, a feature of our podcast.
If you do zone out for that 10 minutes, you don't have to rewind.
Absolutely correct.
This is like the inception podcast.
Really.
It's a podcast within a podcast.
Cause our tangents have tangents,
but they don't have tangents within tangents within tangents because we're
too old and we will just lose track.
No, I think we've done that despite our age.
The, um, one thing I was thinking about when, when I saw this comment for the
first time, you know, a couple of podcasts ago, we were talking about how
back in the day Microsoft used to lead the way on testing.
But, um, and then you and I sort of started this conversation, uh,
earlier than the podcast, but like four years ago now where, uh,
we realized that Microsoft wasn't doing what the rest of the world is doing.
But now we've kind of, it kind of occurred to me is, is, is Microsoft again leading
the way in how, in some regards of how tests should be done.
Cause I see the, uh, perzy, um, uh, the comment that we got today, uh, other comments I've received
Chris, yes.
Other comments I've received from other folks.
Right.
They're really seeing us kind of showing the way.
Yeah.
But just like, uh, in the preface to this, there's this big book I wrote that called
how we test software at Microsoft.
And even in that book, which is horribly at a date, uh, as the three know, uh, in the
preface, like there's no way for me to capture, you know, with at the time you believe it
nearly 10,000 testers, Microsoft, you know, what they did as a whole.
I tried to gather some of the things that were common.
Um, but even there to say that Microsoft is leading the way, I think in some places,
some parts of Microsoft, there is some, uh, leadership and how software engineering
is done quickly and at scale, but there are also as you and I know, without calling
out any names, some really poor examples of how to do that as well.
Yeah.
No, even as the words escape my mouth, I was like leading the way to bring
Brent down from cloud nine skip right past eight, seven, six, five, four, maybe
cloud two, we'll start there.
So I'll say, you know, I'm, I'm extremely grateful in some regards that, that the
the stuff we babble about, uh, approximately every two weeks is, is adding value to
somebody's life.
Going back to the therapy, just talking through these things, uh, that we're
going through in our daily work helps me refocus on a lot of them.
So it does it, I get benefit out of it as well.
There's a reason I get up early twice a month, although we had a little break.
Brent Brent skipped out on our last podcast.
I just moved it one week.
A digit.
All right.
Yeah.
Nevermind.
It was last.
Yeah.
We're going to try and be back on a regular schedule now.
Yes.
I thank you outlook.
Not a not very often do people say thank you outlook.
Uh, no, no.
Before we go on, we have another topic around this, but I want to give a quick
plug.
I always like the plug.
I haven't given a talk at a conference or anywhere.
I guess in the fall I did Euro, Eurostar, the mobile deep dive after Eurostar.
Nothing since then and nothing for a while before them, but I am doing a flurry of appearances.
Are you?
I am.
A flurry.
A McFlurry.
Is that four or five?
Three.
Is a three a flurry?
What's three?
I don't know.
I thought that was few.
Okay.
But they're all close.
A flurry sounds cooler.
But they're close together.
Does that count?
Sure.
What is that called?
A storm?
Maybe we shouldn't worry about it.
So on May 11th for our local three, I will be at QA SIG, which is at Cordez offices in Seattle.
And I, this is, I was worried they wouldn't want to do this talk,
but Jamie Campbell, a former Microsoft, he gave a talk there about combined engineering
in maybe a year ago, but it was in a way, it was a different version than
the unified engineering of my team.
We did talk about it about a year ago when after that talk.
So given my experience, it's always easier for me to give a talk if I can just,
I can tell how easy, how much fun and really how good my talk is going to be
by how quickly I can run an abstract for it.
Okay.
So I quickly wrote an abstract and I said, Hey, I know Jamie gave a similar talk.
If this, if this is too much overlap, let me know.
I'll do something else.
But this is kind of what's top of mind for me.
And what is the audience here?
This is, it's mostly tester people.
It's the three people like the three.
Is it sort of an open space?
It's an open meeting.
Anyone can go.
Yeah.
Open space meeting.
Anyone can go.
And what did I call the talk?
I called it testing without testers.
And I won't read the abstract here.
You can go to qasig.org and check it out yourself because I didn't bring it up
ahead of time.
I don't want to search around on my computer while we're talking,
but that's on Wednesday, May 11th in the evening.
I'll talk and lobby about what's how I've done things here on my team.
And a lot of Q and a interactive as my talks usually are.
Is it re it's going to be recorded?
It'll be, I think they stream not only record,
they stream live.
So check that out.
Yo.
And then a few weeks later, I can't remember the exact dates.
I am giving a talk to a, where the audience is a special interest group in Waterloo, Canada.
I'm brushing up on my Canadian.
I'm going to see how well I can do.
I'm going to give the talk entirely in English Canadian.
And that one, I think it's going to be a similar topic,
but I'm going to do it.
It'll be a little bit more broad.
It'd be a combination between the talk I'm giving QA SIG and the keynote.
I gave it star Canada last year about how Microsoft now tests software,
making fun of my book and talking about some of the more sweeping
general changes of Microsoft versus just my experiences.
And then I come home for a few weeks.
And then I'm off to Las Vegas, Nevada.
You heard of it?
I guess they have like restaurants and these gambling places there.
And they also have a conference called Better Software,
where I'm giving a, you know, this a three and a half hour workshop on.
Do you know what it's on?
Testing.
What kind of testing?
Exploratory.
Oh, no, Brent.
The three will be automation.
How about AB testing?
Is it?
It's on experimentation.
And then I'm home for the summer after that with nothing else planned.
But really, it's a large expansion of talk I gave there last year,
sort of at the last minute.
So it should be a lot of fun.
I'm so glad you played right into that.
That was it.
It's so much amuses me on so many fronts.
Whenever you bring up, you're doing talks on the AB testing.
I'm sure you do it just fine.
It just I'm like, okay, why not?
Go, Alan.
You did a great job last time.
Yeah, thanks, Brent.
All right.
So shall we start the show?
Longest.
No, not the longest.
Not the longest.
This is how we roll.
Actually, we've gone through four of the items on the board.
Yeah.
One says one is episode 36.
One is two years.
I think we covered those at about the first 30 seconds.
So my product, which is hard and fun and interesting and for all sorts of different reasons,
we ship to our production server once a week.
You do that now.
We do that now.
We ship once a week.
Okay.
So you deploy once a week.
We deploy once a week, yeah.
But because I still think you're extremely locked down.
Can anyone go to it?
Can I go go to it now?
Different.
We deploy to our production server and there are about 200 users at Microsoft outside of our team
who can use our product for what our product is designed for.
You're not one of them.
No, I am not.
I offered for you to be one.
You said, I don't know.
I don't want to see it first.
So I'll show it to you after the podcast.
Okay.
And then I'll get fired.
But I'll show it to you.
Okay.
Anyway, we can get you on board.
If only you knew someone who was sort of in control of access.
I don't know what your product does yet.
Oh, it slices.
It dices.
It makes your, it's a floor wax and the dessert pudding.
Every product coming out of Microsoft today does slicing and dicing, it seems.
But ours seamlessly integrates into the enterprise world with more buzzwords that
I can't flip out of my face at 8 30 in the morning.
Right.
They all seamlessly integrate as well.
So I didn't I say that?
You did.
So we have for customer and business satisfaction.
Anyway, our product.
You forgot the line.
God, we can't, we cannot get to the point.
Like Brett and I are kidnapped.
They have guns to our head and they're saying, tell us, tell us where the diamonds are.
So, oh, did you know that diamonds are from carbon and.
And carbon.
Oh, oh, this is about a baseball diamond, but I was at, you know, it's like, oh my God.
So anyway, so one week you say every week, every week.
Uh, uh, and it's, it's going, it's going well.
But you know what, Brent, it's not enough.
We're going to ship more often.
So what I want to talk about the subject I want to go back and forth is, uh,
pros cons, pitfalls and benefits of, and I have a live list of these myself because
I've been preaching them to the team of going from shipping once a week to once a day, once
every weekday, let's say, and then maybe even more often after that.
So what are the things in, this could be a way too open ended of a question for a,
for a Brent question.
But as you've seen teams and your experiences as you've gone from shipping once a week to
once a day or any sort of acceleration like that, what are the big, uh, benefits
and the big challenges to doing that?
And I have a big list myself, but I'm going to let you start.
The biggest benefit, uh, bar none is the more often you ship,
the less risky shipping is.
So, so shipping more frequently dramatically boosts quality and reduces risk.
Well, there's with a whole slew of caveats, but yeah,
devils in the details there, right?
And that's exactly it.
There's a, there's almost a little yin yang thing of because we're shipping every day,
um, there's a chance that, I mean, there's, you don't get that bake time.
You get shipping once a week and maybe some little things begin to slip through.
But because you're shipping every day, those things are mitigated or fixed, uh, much quicker.
I think over, over, uh, I do believe that the benefits outweigh the scary parts that
come with that.
I think there's a cultural and people thing of getting over the fact that, uh,
there may be some minor and I'm going to call them bugs because they might not even impact
the user.
There may be some minor things that aren't caught because that's that big time.
And for example, maybe there's a, um, uh, in one build, you introduce, uh, something that
causes this API to fail.
Um, but it's not noticeable and you're blind.
You don't have the right monitoring in place.
So you miss it until you start getting reports from a large, the larger deployment.
And then you go back and fix it the next day.
So it was a dip.
Yeah.
But, but what that forces you to do, uh, to me, shipping more frequently is all about what
we call the outer loop.
You know, the inner loop is like unit tests and deployment and, and, and, uh, test the,
the testing you do, the internal dogs, a little bit of bake time you get moving in
a one in whatever your release is.
But the outer loop is monitoring.
How quickly can you detect an error with monitoring and react to it and maybe even
deploy a hot fix?
How does that, so I'm breaking.
I was about to go on there and then Brent gave me a look.
So you're, you started this question primed with, I gotta be careful because it's a
Brink question and it occurs to me now that you're doing a great job pretending to be me.
I'm answering the question.
So this is again, this is the therapy part because this is what I've been telling
our team and, um, by Brent nodding his head, having gone through this more often than me,
the fact that that's now I want to hug you again, but not really.
It's so I'm, um, talk to me some more.
So let me put my Agilist hat on, right?
The, do you ever take it off?
Not very often.
How about in the shower?
No.
Okay.
All right, go on.
It's, it's water resistant.
There is a great book.
I may be forgetting his name, but Donald Reiner.
Is the author's name.
It's the title, I think is product development flow.
Oh, flow.
Yeah.
Hop in my bookshelf.
He, if you, if you want to understand Agil and there's only one book you're going to pick,
that's the book.
Uh, because he goes through, uh, lots and lots of white papers, lots and lots of science
and evaluates which model is better.
Okay.
And now what you're talking about going from one week to one day is sort of the discussion
of small batch versus large batch.
From a, from an Agil point of view that that's, that's how we refer to it in the vernacular.
Small batches, meaning you're constantly shipping small things is significantly better than
constantly shipping large things.
Um, those of us in testing can, can recall, uh, so for example, the periods when there's
a massive stabilization period and there's a co-complete date, right?
Well, and I'll interject there.
There are teams.
I know that Microsoft who even within the last five years have had a coding milestone
where three to five months, I don't know how long, three months were spent where you
write code.
Uh, you don't stop, you don't get this is flow also.
Cause you don't want to get out of your flow and fix bugs
because you can use the six months stabilization period to fix your bugs.
You're right now.
And it's just a stupid process.
So the, um, so they spend two years writing up all of the bugs that they're going to
fix in the final six months without any sort of customer feedback as to which ones
are important, which ones aren't.
Um, so I, I think I've told the story on the podcast.
So when I went to Bing before I was a, um, I went to Bing primarily because I wanted
to learn service software.
I had not at any point in time shipped the service, uh, in my career.
So I wanted to add that little bullet to my resume.
And, uh, at that time, Bing was known as the, the most agile team.
Okay.
Um, so I went there.
Uh, I studied up on agile.
I was not yet a, uh, uh, a coach by any means, certainly not certified in any way.
Um, and read several books, uh, before joining and I hit the ground running and
we started a scrum model.
Now they had already been doing scrum.
Um, and we made a, we decided to do a scrum model and there was a pre-existing
asset, which I didn't like the design.
And we decided as a team to completely refactor the design.
We changed a major piece of every component and we did it in two weeks.
We were proud, but just like every team ever, um, we did a bunch of features and
then we were like, ah, integration will be easy.
And we ended up trying to integrate at that, the 11th hour before the sprint was done.
And that two week sprint cost us two months of unwinding because we had changed
everything.
And of course, none of it integrated.
Um, it was funny cause when, when I had, when I had taught my team the scrum
model, I said, we're going to start with this, but then we're going to shift to
the Kanban model.
You knew right off the bat, you're going to go on bond.
Yeah.
Uh, the, the, I can't tell you why I knew off the bat.
I just had forgotten, but if he had asked me back then, I would have told you.
Put a pin.
I want to come back to that in a minute, but go ahead and go out.
So the team after hearing, after going through this experience, like our,
it was our second sprint that we had ever done.
It took us four sprints to fix it.
And, uh, after that, my team essentially revolted.
They said, Hey, we want to go with the Kanban model now.
The, um, and the Kanban model is one of the things is, is you don't do these massive
integrations.
You integrate one small work item at a time and then everyone spread out.
So when the, I had a team, a set, there's a subtlety there.
That's important though, because it's goes back to batch size a little bit or
a work item size.
I'm having technical difficulties.
I'll help you in a second while you're dropping.
I'll fix it for you in a second.
Stop playing.
Stop playing with the brand.
I figured out.
Stop playing revenue.
Oh, great.
Physics come to AB testing.
So the, uh, the size of the ticket on the Kanban cord on the Kanban board.
What's a Kanban cord?
That's interesting concept.
We'll come back to that.
One could be integrate into a ticket could be integrate.
No, I could wouldn't be a good one.
Or do you mean a column?
No, a ticket.
So it could be, you could, the point is you could have an item on there.
It's way too large and it would run in the same problem.
So part of the part of the board, part of what works is you need to have,
uh, items that are, uh, smaller.
Yes.
It took a long time to make that point.
I'm very sorry.
Uh, we even today, um, the, the policy that I, I did back when I started in Bing is what I've
kept doing.
I haven't changed that one.
Um, one of the things that most teams are aware of when they go into this and they're focused
on waste is how much time is wasting wasted rather on planning.
So the Kanban method, um, I kind of do and planning, I now kind of do a hybrid of multiple
models.
I think we talked about this a couple, three, four episodes ago, but the Kanban model
is essentially saying waste is or planning is a complete waste of time.
Um, I don't know if Kanban says that directly.
The Kanban method does the one by Dave Anderson.
So he, the, the framework called the Kanban method invented by David Anderson at
Microsoft.
Surprisingly, when I read that I was surprised.
I'm like, what?
This awesome thing was invented here.
Um, yeah, he invented it here and then left.
And then he actually deployed it, um, and, and made his success in an entirely
different company.
Anyway, um, basically says as long as the work, everyone agrees there's an 80% chance
that it takes two weeks or less.
Good planning done.
And that sort of lightweight model, uh, works.
It works very well.
The, what, um, because it'll get caught, uh, in, in the next phase, which is sort
of an analyze phase where you have to deconstruct it into the work and, um, we
don't let the ticket move on.
If that person or the, the, the people who review, if any of them believes, dude,
there's no way you're getting this done in two weeks or less, then it, then it
gets broken down into different tickets.
So what are your columns?
I actually want to dive into Kanban.
You're used to Kanban here a little bit.
What columns do you use?
Um, the columns I use are the first one is analyze.
Then it goes into engineer.
Then it goes into release, then customer validation, then done.
Okay.
Um, so they come from the backlog into analyze these things.
Oh, and yeah, there's backlog then ready.
Sorry.
Ready is the very first one.
So these things could be analyzed.
They, they, they're loosely analyzed.
Okay.
So, but ready moves to analyze.
So let me go again.
Backlog ready, analyze, engineer, release, customer validation.
Done.
So I follow the backlog.
Basically the backlog to ready is, is like a traditional product owner, a
scrum type process.
So my team can pick whatever they work.
They want to do in the ready column.
Okay.
Any, any ticket in the ready column is open to them.
Anyone can take whatever they want.
That is not pre-assigned.
But only I can put tickets into the ready column.
And the promise that, that I make, and when I put tickets into the ready
column is that these are the next set of things that from the best available
information I have, we'll add the most business factor.
Okay.
Do you use a physical board or?
I do.
So good, because I've been playing with digital boards for our team and I ended
up making a physical board first for some part of our work, not all of it yet,
just on the window behind my desk, because there's something about a
physical board and I want to move it later, but so this is just temporary.
But I can explain it because I've had this question because I actually, um,
okay, I want you to explain it because reason is I think physical boards,
the action of move physically moving a ticket for one column to the other.
And me and having, when you go to is one thing.
So one, the physical action, I think is, uh, it going back to damp pink.
I think it shows you get progress from that.
Yep.
More than digital board.
But even moreover, I think the digital boards, because they,
they can be open or not on your computer and everybody has a different view of them.
One of the principles of Kanban is visualize your work.
And I think having that board in a place that your team can all see multiple times a day and know what
people are working on. And just, I think that physical board for me is, uh, a better way of
doing that than the digital board. But I'm curious to hear your answers as well.
I will tell you that I have figured out what is the ideal board.
Um, but I haven't yet figured out a way to build it.
That's cheap.
The ideal board would be a digital board, but on one of these gigantic touch,
touchscreen monitors in a place of a physical board where, where people
have the tactile experience where they move their tickets to done.
The reason why a physical board is more powerful is because of the social influence.
The fact that you have a physical board requires you to have a regular standup where everyone gets
together. Um, forces transparency, forces, knowledge sharing.
Yeah. It to me, the transparency is key there for it.
It encourages, obviously forces, but it encourages accountability.
I know in people are built, it not only is accountability, but it also
allows people to have recognition. So there's the negative thing like,
Hey, Alan, I see you have five tickets. All of them are over SLA, which in my vernacular means,
um, you've gone beyond the two week limit. Right. So that's, there would be two crimes
in there. You're multitasking and, um, everything's over SLA.
So, um, I'll interrupt for a second. So when I think of Kanban, I think of two main principles.
Uh, one we've talked about before, visualize your work. Other one is limit your work in progress.
As a manager, how come you let me have five open tickets at once?
Uh, what's your deal?
That's actually the thing that's also cool about Kanban is it does support autonomy.
So if, if you have five tickets in flight, um, you made that call.
Boy, I was stupid, huh?
I will as if I'm the, if I'm the, the, what we call the Agile coach, which kind of takes on the role
of like a scrum master, but it's Kanban not scrum. Um, if I'm in the scrum master role and I see you
doing that, whether or not you're my employee, I will give you crap about it.
Alan, you, all of these tickets are now over. It's because you're multitasking.
I want you to pick three of these tickets and hand them off right now. It will like right during
standup. But, but Brett, they're, they're almost done. They're, they've, they've been 90% done for
a couple of weeks each. Great. Yeah. Then that handoff should be easy. The God, where was I going?
I don't know. Oh, so the, the, the ready column. So you said visualize your work,
um, limit whip, limit work in progress. Right. And the other one that, that is just super critical
is pull. Don't push. Um, you're looking at me puzzle. No, no, no, I get it. Um, the,
so the, the ready column itself will have a whip. Um, cause some, some teams, when they
first roll this out, they just make their backlog and the ready column the same thing.
And I go like, no, no, no, no, no. I'm going to put, I'm going to force a limit on me as to
how many most important things there can be. Right. Right. So putting a whip on the ready column forces
people to say, I don't know if you've ever heard of this speech, but I back in the old days,
the first decade we were here, I heard it all the fricking time, the tyranny of, or yeah. Yeah.
Which is essentially in an, in an enablement argument to say, Hey, multitask and don't incur any cost.
And it's kind of like saying gravity work the other way. Like multitasking, uh, the, the mythical man
month, um, there's all kinds of proof on this that multitasking slows you down. It, it isn't,
free. You can humans cannot context switch freely. Anyway, where do you want to go next with this? I've,
Oh, oh, we have now officially gone from tangent to tangent to tangent. And now I'm lost.
It's AV inception. So we were talking once upon a time about shipping more often. And,
Oh yes, I'm a big fan. I'll just kind of steer us back here. Um,
I like this conversation, but I'm a fan of Kanban as well. And I also limit our,
on our digital version, uh, my small little teams, um, ready calm. What do I call it? Um,
I call it something else. I can't remember, but it's ready.
And then what I would do, actually, when you go from one week to one day, the one thing that,
after to in, in a feeble attempt to try to add some value to the 15 minutes of babble,
I just did. Um, it does occur to me that when you go from one week to one day,
what you, you want to decouple each developer's cadence from the ship vehicle. In other words,
Hey, whatever is checked into this branch goes live daily. If you, if, if your stuff is not ready,
do not push the master. Okay. And so our, our, uh, branching structure is a little different from
that, but we, um, uh, we will still pull from our development branch to a, uh, pre-production
branch daily. And then later in that day, um, that branch, once we've done just a little bit of,
of validation, uh, user experience, evaluation, et cetera, that will go to, uh, production.
So there's a couple of things that we talked about the outer loop and getting monitoring in place.
Um, uh, that is often the best way to make you do something is to force it to need to happen.
We, I'll be open. We don't have the outer loop. We need to be able to do this. So there's going
to be a pain point as we do this. It goes, Oh, wait, we're blind here. We need to make
sure we have the monitoring here. So I'm willing, I'm willing to take that risk to force what I
think that important monitoring, which good monitors are to me equivalent to good tests,
um, to force those to happen. So one of the things, um, God, how many years are you going to tangent?
Cause I had more to do here. No. Okay. So my variant of, of Kanban, right? I listed off the
columns that I used in, in that variant. This is a re tangent. No. Okay. Okay. I'll be quiet.
If you remember, I, my columns, we released, then it went to customer validation, then it went
to done. Um, what that customer validation does to a team is you can't call your ticket done until
you've proven by whatever means you have available that the customer is now getting the value
intended out of the, out of your ticket. Right. So in this particular case, if you go to daily,
so let's say I work on, on your team, um, we're shipping daily. I just finished what I believe
is my feature. I released it. It is now in the wild. I can't move that ticket to done. I can't
work on the next feature or bug or whatever, and tell I have proven to you, um, the guy taking the
role of the product owner that is doing what we believed it's doing, which means I have to have
telemetry or I have to have a customer to go interview, which is the two most common ways of
doing customer validation. Um, there is a team at Microsoft, the SQL server reporting services team,
which I used to work on. So I, I taught them this stuff. Um, they're about to ship and I am,
my team is one of their customers now and I'm finding, uh, bugs or, or feature requests. And now
they're, they're giving me what we call a CV customer validation, a CV request all the time.
Hey, Brent, can you CV this? Here's our bill, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
So it's fantastic. It gives me the opportunity as a customer to say, no, that is not what I want.
Right. And, uh, leads into experimentation a little bit. Cause one of the things we do when
someone has a new feature, we have a very simple mechanism, what we call feature flag, put the
feature behind a flag, meaning has to be turned on explicitly. Um, and we can do that for a
subset of users and, or, or for all users, when, when it gives us a way to, uh, not like here's
a brand new feature that may be disruptive, turning it on for everyone at once may not be the best
idea. A B testing and exposure rings and flight control and all of that is really critical when,
when you are really live and you have more than 200 users. Great. Because it,
you can't interview them all. Right. You need telemetry and data and those assets in order
to scale. Right. I think that's the big shift. Like right now we can get away with a team like
mine shipping once a week can get away with bug reports and, um, you know, uh, little mini
stabilization. I called it bake time. It's really just stabilization. We can get away with that
shipping once a week, shipping daily or more often, or even twice a week, uh, that outer loop,
that monitoring, that, uh, being able to react to monitoring and alerts are just, it's critical.
Waiting for test results is, uh, not the way to do this. The one culture shift that you
might encounter when you, when you go into this one is, um, what we call swarms. Okay. So
once you're shifting to prod daily, you have to sort of create an entrenched
life site first mentality. Absolutely. Like life site cannot be down. This is a service.
It can't be down. And any bug discovered in production has to be resolved within the,
my team is within the next 48 hours. Oh yeah. I would say less than that,
but depending on the severity of it, if you have the, it's a reasonable SLA
is directly related to how quickly you can react. If you have the automation, the tooling in place
to do it. Um, you also need to have the ability to, if you look at the bug and you go, Oh crap,
this is on the floor. I can't get this fixed in 20 and 48 hours or whatever your SLA is.
Then you must have the ability to do a 15 minute revert. It just, it's, you can't have life site
down. Right. And then once you have something like that in place, the magic really starts
to happen in terms of getting your devs aboard on the culture because devs don't like being interrupted.
And if you have the principle of life site first, then them, they deploying crap to production
creates this loop where they created the, the, this, what we called swarm tickets.
Swarms are essentially bug tickets, but on my board swarms are the only thing that actually
cause interrupts because life site first and Hey, Alan, if you don't want to be interrupted,
quit shipping shit. And they learned that on their own very quickly that they're in control
of their own destiny on that one. I agree. Yeah. That's a good plan. Do you want to do the last one?
Sure. Okay. So I gave, um, we're in, uh, lovely Lincoln square Bell view and I gave, uh, Brent,
uh, not even a tour. I showed him where I sit, but, uh, I have a kind of, uh, cool little space
where there's, uh, four of us work together, uh, on the areas I work on and we have a nice little
open space. Um, open space is a big topic at Microsoft and in the industry, as far as,
you know, how teams are organized and sit, uh, there are excellent ways to do it. There are good
ways to do it. And there are horrible ways to do it. And Microsoft who because it was such a big
company had done all of them. It's great. Yes. Mostly we found all kinds of different ways to do
it really bad mostly because often people see open space. Oh, open space is better. Okay.
And then you end up with a, I'm not going to name any teams. I know one building, which is basically,
I call it a barn. Yep. It's huge. Like, it's like Rose, it was like study hall.
It's not really, it's a barn. It's not open. It's not open space is meant for collaboration
and working together and being able to have those quick conversations. So it's interesting, um,
back. So the first team to do this at Microsoft was the Xbox org. And I happen to think so.
I happened to be in Xbox when it happened. Right. This was just before the commons were built.
And yeah, I know. I think there were teams doing it before then. The prevailing,
maybe the prevailing pattern that I noticed or noticed before then were, uh, uh, the shoe box
office, right? The, the office where you, you basically get a four by six office, um, with
a big heavy wooden door. Yes. So like the, the offices in my building in Bing were, were like this.
Oh yeah. You get this small little thing versus the old school, like, yeah, you got glass doors
there a little bit, a little more open, right? Call those the open office, but not open office.
Yeah. Um, what, when Xbox, uh, did this move, whether or not they were the first fair point,
when Xbox did the move, the spaces were labeled as collaborative spaces. Okay. And over the last
10 years, it has been shifted to open space. Well, it's, it's been misinterpreted a bunch
of different ways. So, um, let me put it in perspective. When I have like an example here
and, uh, even when I was an E E we had a really nice team room. Uh, the idea is that we're all
working on the same thing. Uh, we have an area where we can work by ourselves and there were,
where we can work together. Uh, and those things I think are important, uh, where it's been screwed
up in translation. Uh, and I don't know about other kinds of, but I can talk about Microsoft is
one, the barn, but two I have, there's been a few buildings remodeled for open spaces recently.
And I have a, uh, colleague for example, works on a team in one of these buildings and it's,
it's a big, they have rooms that hold, and to me, the ideal team room size is, you know, less than,
less than 10. I like, like four to eight. It should be, uh, it should be able to fit
one whole team plus whoever the manager is that sort of scope. It should be a functional working
team. All right. So, and maybe it could be a little bigger. Um, but there's a lot of
these open space rooms built to fit 18 to 20, which I think is a little large. I think it's
too large for a team. Maybe if it's all the same team, it's all right. But the problem is,
is they don't have teams this size. So he's working on the, the six people that he works
with are all together plus some random PMs and if, and a few other people, they just kind of
shove people in and go, here's an open space, but they're not working on the same thing.
They're working on, they're just, they're two different or two, three, sometimes four
different projects going on in one open space, which is, I think not cool.
It creates, um, it creates an environment that does the exact opposite.
And to me, it's critical because it's not just, I lost in translation. It's happened with,
you know, you know, agile has been bastardized in the same way, a million ways.
But if you look at the open space, I think it's a very powerful thing that really, really,
really works unless you totally screw it up by not paying attention to the parts that actually
work about it. They were actually, so when this first started, right, there was a study that came
out and I no longer remember who it came out around 2003 that showed like a back then valve
and how they delivered software was, was, um, and you can still on today,
go to the internet and find a copy of their employee.
Oh, the, the, the employee handbook. I love it.
That, Hey, you come in, you check out a desk, you move your desk to whoever you're working with
and you get stuff done. And that study showed essentially that these open spaces
improve productivity because they improve collaboration. Okay. And that, in my belief,
I don't know if it's true or not, but in my belief, that's what kick started this,
this Microsoft. I don't know if it's that, that that's not it either. It's, it's more of, oh,
open spaces are good. The college kids like open space. Let's see if we can not do any more.
That's what it is now, but it wasn't what it was then.
Yeah. I'm, I'm blown away by it.
In 2008, there was a study done by MIT that said, no, actually open spaces is not what creates
collaboration and productivity, but fungible spaces. The ability for me to go to a particular
neighborhood, change the wall structure. Such that. So imagine this, this one neighborhood
you're talking about with 30 people in it in five different teams. If I can change the wall
structure such that now it's just me and my team in here until we're done with this project,
and then we'll take the walls and we'll put them wherever these walls go. Yeah. Right. And MIT has
this famous two or three story building where they can reconfigure just about everything.
And it's the ability to have the environment shift actually boost collaboration and productivity.
The other thing I'll say, Agile helps a lot as well. The, the joke I would, I would tell people,
and it's not much of a joke because I've had it validated multiple times.
Most of these open spaces, what ends up happening is people go to it and they rebuild
their office world in the form of a $75 pair of headphones. They're like, I will
filter all of you people out. See noise canceling beauties. The, what I discovered in
my last move to open space and, and apparently my building, the one I'm in right now is slated
for conversion, the beginning of the conversion in the next couple of months. So I'll be in a
new building sometime soon. My team, when we moved in our, in our last adventure, we, we moved
from office world into open space, but I had been working with the same set of people for
a couple of years before we did. And I warned them all. I'm like, no, this is open space.
It's not collaborative space. It becomes collaborative space based on how we, we use
it. I preformed that. When we moved in, actually one of my employees who, who, who is no longer one
of my employees, but still one of your mentees came to me and he said, Brent, have you walked
around all of the other neighborhoods, which is what we call these open space environments?
And I said, yes, I have. What's your take? And he's like, in comparison to ours, they're like
graveyards. So you got a whole bunch of people and there's a practice where they actually create
rules around silence and turn it into like a library in the middle of a funeral.
Whereas my team, we had, we had been practicing agile. We had learned very quickly
the benefits of collaboration and knowledge sharing. So when my team moved into this
environment, we were still kept together and it was a freeing experience, not a trapping one.
So, and, and that's the key. I wanted, I'm looking at the clock, we have to wrap up here, but,
but moving to an open space doesn't make you agile, but an agile team.
Or collaborative. Or collaborative.
Matter of fact, doing it wrong will do the opposite.
But an agile or collaborative team can take advantage of that open space.
Right.
And that's, so yeah, stop doing it wrong. Do it right. That's my advice.
That's essentially.
It's like a pile of a sell high.
That's, that's kind of the advice of our podcast every week.
Quit being stupid, do smart things instead.
Yeah. Yeah. That's a good, that's good advice. Thanks, Brent.
That one's free.
You know what? They're all free.
Good, good point.
Except to take an hour of our time and an hour of our listeners times
that they can never ever get back.
That's why we have a continuous flow of threes.
We'll see how we do. Hey, I am still Alan.
And I am Brent.
And this was episode 36 and we'll see you soon for 37, right?
Yes.
All right.
As long as math still works the same way.
All right. Happy springtime, everybody.
Bye.