Hey, it's episode 33 of A.V. Testing. I'm Alan. I'm Brent and
For better or for worse. We're back. What year is it Alan? 2016. Good job. What's what's the wrong answer?
Anything other than 2016? You know what? This isn't on the board, but you know, it's wrong
We've covered this. Yeah. Okay. I think we covered it like exactly a year ago because we didn't call it
1910 we called it 1910. I don't get it. No, it's 2016
I get that it was awkward to say 2001 or 2002. Yeah
onboard, but once we passed the 10 mark, it's 2010 and
We just found a dead animal in the palatial podcast studios
But actually it was just the sound on
Brent's phone so I got a new phone and there are
Still random noises they come out of like what the hell was that sound me? I will I don't know if the podcast picked that up
But that gave me a little chill
It kind of sound like a speaking of a chill, you know, I've been
Took a little time over the holidays
Yeah, I saw I saw on Twitter that you picked up
Snowboarding. No, I want no I snowboarded once my daughter wants to switch from skiing to snowboarding
So we thought it'd be a fun little family thing a lot of families go to movies and we went to Star Wars
Yeah, as it are or bowling we say we take the whole family. We're all gonna give snowboarding a shot just for one night and
We my daughter kicked butt she's gonna be totally great I
Did
Better than I thought I would but one thing about learning to snowboard is you fall a lot and when you're older and bigger like me
Those falls man. I I'm still recovering from a couple of them. I have never snowboard. I
Haven't downhill skied the last time we skied was like 10 years ago and it was cross-country
So as you know, as I'm sure I've mentioned on the podcast. I'm on a
Now don't take this the wrong way
I'm on a ski racing team
But it's really an excuse to go down the hill and then drink beer when you're done. It's it's it's competitive
But not it's like a think bowling is it like last one down the hill buys no think bowling on a ski slope
It's head-to-head. I'm gonna erase twice a night on you go up on Thursday nights, but
it is
I'm not wearing any specialized gear or anything
I'm just trying to beat the guy next to me
And then once I'd finished my second race
I go straight to the little ski hut at the bottom and get some beer that
Except for the whole exercise bit that almost seems like a perfect day
I like skiing is how I get through look out the window Brent you guys in podcast
I can't see the window, but you see the typical Seattle dark gray cold fog here
Fog is all the way up to the floor 20. That's impressive. Yeah, it's gross. Hey one aside. So
Your family went to see Star Wars. We did my family went to see Star Wars
Spoiler alert. No spoilers. Let's not make
On those spoilers that makes no we shouldn't spoil
So far no spoilers here's the challenge Alan what's the top
positive and the top negative thing
About the new Star Wars movie from your point of view positive thing is the movie rocked
The top negative thing is the next one doesn't come out for 18 months
Now that was well done on the no spoiler, but that was boom boring and safe
I'll show you boring and safe. I do that every podcast. Oh
Oh
You set them up I'll knock them down are we going anywhere with this no, all right. I guess not
All right, you scared me with the whole spoiler thing. I don't like yeah
It was a good movie. We'll talk about it later and the and if you want to I mean the internet is full of
Theories already. It's great. I
I'll put it this way. My favorite part was like really like the ending
Even though you could kind of see that the ending was gonna happen throughout the whole movie
Yeah, but there was something about the way they did it. Yeah, I agree but
the biggest thing that bugged me is
Except for I don't think hey Han and Leia are in this movie. I don't think that's a spoiler
Except for Han and Leia. I thought it interesting the ages of the entire leadership in the entire movie
All of the generals were like 20 something's
alright, and I'm like
That just sat with me as like
Really? Maybe they dude, maybe they they're like these in humans that they're actually like 150 years old
I looked at hopefully he explains it. Otherwise, I just like this is weird
General Tarkin
He was intimidating because he looked old and grizzled and he knew he's killed billions before
All right. Anyway, so can we move on or did you need to do anything else in your holidays that is worth
discussing for our three listeners
So obviously the holiday thing
It was a break for me from from school and from work
So the first time in like two years I got reacquainted with my Xbox
Oh, I was gonna mention that because I saw that you and I have been playing the same game lately
You I've only been playing one. So how do you feel about fallout?
I'm liking it because you know, I was
Horribly addicted to Skyrim when it came out different series same publisher
You see a lot of the game mechanics if you didn't Skyrim and oh look it's a video game review show, but
it is
Inappropriate to play with my children are around not like Grand Theft Auto inappropriate
But a little bit too much blood and broken bones sticking out of bodies for 11 year olds me and my 14 year old are
I figure I'm a couple couple years away from that blood being actually cool and not like disturbing
So yeah and some again that no judgment are sure some 11 year olds that handle it just fine and
Understanding wives who let their kids get away with that
So
But yeah, I'm enjoying it. I think it's the story like like Bethesda does and again, sorry for the video game review
It's a story lines fun
There's enough variation in gameplay that it keeps me interested. I play my goal is like I don't play every night
But if I but like three or four or five days a week, I play a little bit off the kids go to bed
I try and like gain a level every time
Which it which means I have to but as you know
It's the the leveling like most games is get sort of exponential as you go up
So as you each level took a little harder longer to get to so have you played any from the fallout series before?
No, so but I just I may go out back and do fallout 3 on 360 actually it'll play on
It now plays on Xbox what Xbox one now comes with fully backwards compatibility to my Xbox 360
But anyway
But the point is that full except for all the freaking statement. Go ahead
I was gonna say because I bought fallout 4 I got a free fallout 3. Yep. Yeah, so I'm gonna give it a shot and
Yeah, we'll see I'm enjoying fallout. I'm level 15 now. I think you're up like 20 or something. I'm 25
Yeah, you're gaining on me. You've been doing you've been doing a little bit more than the level of night then and then though
I was I know cuz I looked online a while back and you're like 19
You can you can stalk and see my levels. Yeah, you're in my for my Xbox friends list
No, I know but you tell us what you do and what level you are. Okay, right with Brit
It's playing playing Fallout 4 and Xbox one level 9
So I have only leveled up I think twice since we've come back to work. I've only played one day
Yeah, I was like 22 on Sunday. All right, cool. All right, but it's a great game
But that stuck could get me to at this point in time they could release
Hey, I knew game crap on a stick. Ooh, okay
Well, they do
They have a good game engine a good they put some good thought into their games. Yeah
I like the non-linearity and they they have done a great job
Doing story development even given a non-linear linear world. Yeah
So now that we're down to two listeners
No, no, cuz maybe our three listeners are complete geeks
Yeah, they probably all have nice floors or we use right
Do you want to to let's go to two? All right
so I did a tweet about this want to get your thoughts on this and actually
When I thought of straw man arguments in the past
I always thought it's like, you know, you take something out of context and you throw that up there
But I was looking at the straw man argument Wikipedia page
I realized there's this thing that bugs me in a lot of writing about software
That's exactly one of the bullet points in a straw man argument where the straw man you throw up is and it makes total sense
I think about it now this throw up is not the right word. But the straw man argument uses you say something that's
sort of absurd or
at least
Incorrect and then you base your article on on on the other end of that and it's all over the place
I see things like most of you think that unit testing is useless. Here's why here's three ways how it can help your team
wait, most of who or I see things like
Driving towards driving towards a most of you agree that code coverage is
Useless for most software activities. Let me show you how it can be helpful
So is this a straw man argument where you make a sweeping?
Generalization without any no you set yourself up
There is I forget the name of the fallacy for a sweeping generalization
Like we talked about this one before and I used to remember it
But you talked to one manager at Microsoft and he said something goes management at Microsoft says blah
Like it's a little bit different. I think the straw man is when you you
Set up the statement you want to say by making an argument that is either out of context or incorrect
Okay
Because the the challenge I had with your examples is like most of you if the first thing I went to is okay
What where the hell did you get your data? Yes, and that's what happened. Maybe you're combining often. It's anecdotal
I mean you see this all the time with I see several people who tweet about you know managers aren't enableable to do blah
This is a little bit out of on the edge of a stretch
Managers aren't being nice to their employees
So well which managers will I talk to two managers and they weren't being nice so managers aren't it's like yeah
But I want to start calling these I want to like make a collection of these for a blog post or something and maybe
It's just me that I noticed them
But and I find the sites that I don't want to pick on people that'll get mad
But the sites that sort of crank out articles
Like their whole idea is just to get crank out these
Half written articles and I say half written because literally they do like two paragraphs and I say more to come next time
It's all about getting ad
Getting views for the ads
Yeah
Still they write about 400 words at a time and as the and most of those are set up with some sort of straw man argument
and just and again, I could vote with my feet and stop reading those things, but I do have a lot of blogs and and
News sites in
Feedly and I go through most of them every day and kind of glance through them and just looking for
nuggets of information nuggets of inspiration just to see what's going on and
So I could just stop reading those and and fix it for myself
But I just wanted to bring it up because I learned I I guess the main thing was I didn't realize that that was
A form of straw man, but now I think about it. Of course it is so that was my big revelation to share today
The is that's not quite an Alan Page soapbox rant
We'll just throw it out there in the new and improved new year
years ago started blogging and
It's interesting. It's slowly
Transforming but a lot of the the reason why I started it is
Just to get practice at it gave me a reason to practice
Writing and communication. Yeah, it's funny if you go back and look at my very
first or very second or third one of my first three blog posts from
When did I start a long time ago 2006?
No
2004 I was still on the Windows CE team the 2004
Was for that I said for that exact same reason just want to practice writing
Yeah, and it's it's been helpful for that. But now I play
different games with my blog like the
How do I change what I write about or my writing style to inspire
different
Behaviors, for example you go to Alan will will write a blog. Hey, I read this book and he'll get like 15
Comments on there to me. I treat comments like gold I
I
essentially write a book and
I know people are looking because I look at the stats and and
There is a rating page and I get people to
vote on a rate
But comments don't show up and I'm I found you have to piss people off a little bit to get them to comment or really
Yeah, I found I found
So here's my current acting theory. All right is I need to
Not cover all bases. I need to create holes
So that other people can add value
Yeah, but don't add lines that say more about this next time or I'll talk about that in a future blog post
Those things drive me crazy. I
Will do when I bring up a topic. I will do things like
Yeah, that's a future blog post
But what I've done once the the the series model
This is part one to be clear. I've done series before as well. But as I I will never do it again one of the things
That if you read any book about writing
They'll tell you many great ideas and I can recommend books on writing, but I'm not going to today
But books on writing will tell you one of the best ways to get to be a better writer is to read a lot
And that's true for I think a lot of creative fields when in college when we had our jazz band auditions
We had a great jazz instructor and a lot of times
he would listen to you play for a little bit, but he asked who do you listen to and
and make sure you had a good repertoire of artists that were sort of you know relevant and
you know inspirational at the tip of your tongue to prove that you actually listen to that stuff because
That's one of the ways of getting better at improvising and getting ideas for jazz
Just to listen more and anybody who's any good, you know
Yeah, I mean they will tell you everybody to listen to all the time
And so same thing with reading and one of the things
looping this back a
Lot of what I've learned about or what has influenced my own writing style
Is things that I've read and the fact that I get annoyed when I see these half written articles that say more to come
Next time I go you only wrote like a hundred words like I'm exaggerating now, but I realized I never want to do that
I never want to do that more to come next time and the serious things the same thing because it's
Although I've done it in the past, you know guilty as I read
More and more of these, you know sound bites of information that we get on the internet these days. I realized that I
Don't want to read a serious thing
I want to get the information I want and then if the if the blog if the author is good enough
I will come back even if it is a series, you know call it a series
Maybe that's better. But you know, I find things I like and don't like in that writing
I try and reflect some of those things in my own. But as you know, most of my writing is
Sort of a flurry of conscious like I'm thinking like I want to tweet this I go
There's no way I can tweet this and like one or two or three tweets. I'll write a couple paragraphs
I was that your decision?
What no, so so one big difference between you and I is you're always up on the the Twitter sphere
I'm up on the Twitter sphere
Primarily in response to something somebody I'll go up. I will look at Twitter
Three four or five times today just like in between meetings or during lunch or something and I'll catch up and I never like look
Through like I don't know if anybody does this who follows any number of people I never like go catch up on my tweets
I'll look at the last dozen or so tweets and if anything I want to reply to I will I may throw something out there
I may throw something out there. It's a general
comment to
many of the tweets that have gone by
Your I wouldn't say always but I think it's frequent
well, what I was commented on is that you're
You're an opener
far far more often than I am you'll go in and
Often see rants or often see
Status updates or things like that. Yeah
So I completely agree around the more to come it's it's it's not a good device
So I've tried this
But it it depends it is a good device if the entire goal is to get viewers to your site to get ad money
Sure, that's not a problem. I'm interested in
Solving in Mike. No me neither
But for me the that when I use the device it is often when I'm writing something I've realized
Hey the rationale for the thing. I just wrote could actually be an entire other blog post
I'm just gonna say hey this could be a similar lines if this could be another blog maybe one day
I'll write up on it. I leave it to the reader to go do their own research. Otherwise
Trust me. This is the reason why I said this
Moving on because as we all well know I am riddled with ADHD
And if I were to follow that thread that's going to be a hotter page block
so
You hear that sound? That's the sound of a
Beating of a dead horse Wow, so
But on the same subject
You wrote a blog post recently about combined engineering
Yes, the that the Jive chosen to call unified engineering
But for various reasons to cover before but if you haven't read it go to
Testastic dot WordPress dot com and
Nice lengthy tough for the ADHD crowd to get through that. I took me two sittings. Why why was it long? Oh
Yeah, that's lots of paragraphs
Words and words and words
Yeah, I have been told
that one of my communication problems is
Is I often choose to say in ten words what can be said in three wasn't is it Mark Twain that said I was going
To write you a short letter, but I didn't have time. So I wrote you a long one instead
Yeah, no, and you know what that sounds funny, but I completely totally understand that
Anybody who's done any writing totally would
Speaking of long words total rant when did people start using the word utilize instead of use?
I'm going to it's like little five-year-olds good. I'm going to utilize a blue crayon to draw this. I think that's when
When synthesis kind of got out of favor in terms of management buzzwords
excellent
So
Good blog post one thing. I don't think you meant to imply this but one thing that you know when you read
There are techniques on reading and I and if there's like something that bothers you it ends up distracting you from comprehension
One of the reasons I read this twice because in the very first or second paragraph
I don't think you intended it but you sort of made you sound like that unified engineering was invented in Bing and
And to be clear that there are teams doing an engineering team without separation of development and test no
It's you know as you it which I'm sure you'll agree with many many other companies
I think one of the first places that Microsoft if not the first place at Microsoft that to happen was over in the Bing team
So I will say
and
They spent some time trying to because the way I worded that first
Definitely implied it and I didn't want to do that
However, here's here's what I'll say the foundations of the model
Were not invented in Bing or in Microsoft. Absolutely not it was
Much like other companies do and they watch
Microsoft to see what they're doing like we know for example
Amazon is like 10 years is following the model we did 10 years ago and it's
You know, that's to be clear I wouldn't say that wholeheartedly there's some bits of the model
Following is probably too hard
But what happens is Amazon has gotten a lot of X Microsoft ease and they've taken what they've used
For better or for worse, right? I think
It depends on your point of view. I
Think for Amazon for worse if you're a competitor of Amazon for better one thing
I'm gonna interrupt because that's what we do on this podcast
But one thing it's I like about what I hear about Amazon culture is they have these company values that come up daily in
Meetings like they actually live their company values. I'm gonna ask you name one of Microsoft's company values
Point point made. All right, go on. Yeah
We used to do that actually
Then the first decade of my career. I mean remember having lots of discussions around
Our competencies in a line
Yeah, we'd have brainstorming meetings and the line discussions to our competencies, which was
that's the most recent version of
Values that I've actually paid attention to that's old but to your thing. No, it wasn't invented but
There was a very I mean it
How to do this model other companies have done before right the specific variant
And the specific set of documentation
That got deployed at Microsoft did initiate. Yeah, but I'm being honestly and this could be a huge rat hole
I don't think the initial and it rarely is it but I don't think the initial implementation for people I've talked to of
unifying engineering
Was particularly successful in being
And let me give you some anecdotal stories and again
It was a large part of the group that a lot of people I've talked to
I feel like I'm like to have looped Brent into this like I'm ready Charlie Rose sort of interrogation
so
Anecdotally, I've known a lot of people in that org
I've heard following statements
Managers were surprised that by making everybody a developer that
Throughput didn't increase reflectively. I heard that multiple people
I also heard that you know a lot of the but probably more believable was that in that move
This is one of the things talked about and things that fail is a lot of
People were valued on
feature
Feature output in production and then a lot of the testing activities although necessary were valued less or not done
so
That so the first one I never heard
Okay in terms of a throughput a
Theoretical throughput tests that failed I had I I've talked again. I was in Bing. I talked to a lot of folks
Yeah, you never heard your knowledge is a little better than mine mine's a second hand, but I
Think you learn there the second one. I mean that by far
the
the biggest
double-quote surprise
was that quality fell and that I did hear a lot and
The the focus on features now that is one of the things I
experienced two different models the the model
That they deployed in Bing. Okay. Now was their first attempt and not only that so they started off with one specific team
And that one specific team worked very well, and then they very rapidly broadened it
the
Thing that I believe that they did an error is they had the right thing, but they had the wrong
principles and goals that they were trying to accomplish things like
throughput or
Efficiency, okay
Several of these things and it occurred to me. I actually had a mentee the other day
Come to me and he started talking about combined engineering and I'm like I
Had just written my blog three days ago at that time and I'm like, did you read my blog?
Is that why you're here? He's like you blog
And I'm like and that happens quite a read this and come back that that happens quite a lot
I don't I don't I
Don't understand that phenomenon
but
There was that experience in Bing and the and the learnings and the mistakes and then after after about a year and a half
I went to a different team and
They wanted to go with this model and they had learned that I was there. So I helped to instruct it
The biggest thing that I realized that I left out of my blog was
very specific common things people do
That they should not
As an example, you should although this is one I called out
one of the mistakes that they did is they wanted to do the combined engineering and
They said that they valued the test expertise as much as the feature expertise, but their actions and their words
were not
With strong integrity of each other. I believe it
right
but
the teams
Where their actions in the words lined up?
Succeeded with the unified engineering model
They recognized
But it comes down to there's this prevailing subversive belief that that the prior test team
Didn't add value and never did the only value that they had is now
Those guys would do my testing for me
right and actually we
we served a
stronger purpose than that and those teams that that
Realized that became stronger
In in actuality. Well, I think we talked about this loss
last time
What I am finding is
The teams that go whole hog into unified engineering
with with a respect both points of view and have the
leadership run by
the test
they're actually shaping up to be stronger than the prior and I think it's because
tests had a strength with respect to
Balancing quality and features. All right, we always were for the the one month test pass at the end
We were always only given two weeks. So we had to be able to do a good ROI
to prevent someone coming in yelling at us and blaming us for the quality at the end and
Also, I think test is inherently
Better at doing the generalist
To in between shift. I agree. I agree. Hey real quick. Yeah one thing you didn't touch on your blog
I'm curious to know your answers on is what are a couple things that you definitely don't want to do when you have a unified engineering team
Well, I think I just touched on one. Yeah, right. Well, let's give it some more
It's easy to mess up, right? So just give you a couple quick if that have ever happened to you
But well a couple examples
Ideas you notions you don't want to have the incentive principles
Be of the old world. You mean like features or what was right? You don't you don't
It's a new team. It's a new concept
you don't want to try to figure out how to
Take these new guys from that discipline and
Now rank them through the world that you're used to you have you have to change
The worldview so one of the things I do think I I glanced over
The incentive structure has to change
So how do you incentivize people?
What what what is the right? What is a right?
What is something what do you do to incentivize people in the right way in a unified engineer?
I'm gonna hand wave on on this one, but it's
You need to
value
throughput and quality and you don't stack rank those two it's
No, it's the you've heard the phrase the tyranny of or it's not an or
Yeah, you can't provide me ten features
With a quality level one and call a win. No, right, but and you can't just in the unified engineering team
You can't just the other thing you can't have
Is a caste system you cannot
Create
This new
Unified engineering team that that in my view is what makes a difference between a combined engineering team and unified engineering team
Ah, good point and I love the analogy in the blog about salad dressing
Yeah, so and I've seen this before well has seen well my feature team is unified engineering team. That is scrum team
On my feature team, you know so and so and I are the testers. We do the testing for everyone else
That's our role on the scrum team
Brad just oh, you know what? I saw this in big bang three last night. You could actually hear someone's eyes roll. Yeah
Especially when I watched that last night as well
the
the one of the problems that my mentee has
is
Was that it was was that issue?
So his expertise his strengths
were in
infrastructure test automation
in the in
Testing okay. Yeah, that was a value proposition and I said that's fantastic, right?
Until it's unified we need to operate on the assumption. It's only combined
unless you have a
An insightful a smart manager who realized no, I'm gonna start with the beginning or the with the end this I'm gonna
I'm gonna act like my team is already the team I want. Okay
But they were overly focused on their strengths and I'm like if you do that and
I'm not gonna mention the team
But I did mentioned. So here's the thing. I actually think that you're on a team that
Probably isn't going to exist for a long time
Right. It's one of these teams where we're experimenting with things and I don't think the experiment has succeeded
so
The rest of Microsoft is moving towards this model and if you don't start to transition
Yourself if you focus on only your strengths if my prediction comes true
You're not gonna find a job
Because you're gonna be two years behind everybody else in terms of their learning of how to be able to do both successfully
Yeah, and one thing to be clear on I was afraid of making this point
I agree, but I was afraid of making this point earlier why I hemmed and hawed a little bit but
When I look at a team, of course, it's quality focus. It's collaboration. I are some things I care about
output and
Maybe technical ability I might throw in there
But I'm looking at how I'm going to and that was a little iffy but the first three for sure
So collaboration thing is really important. I want to reward the
People who work together and enable others much better, especially at higher levels of Microsoft. I also want
output and
but clearly by output
One trap to fall into is that output includes customer facing features only so I want to
So output is are you getting work done and maybe maybe another one is business impact
So I'm gonna look at if I'm looking at my team. I want to figure out and again, it's not stack
I can figure out who wants to get the most rewards. It's not tyranny of war, but I'm looking at
You know who has a great combination of working with others
Gets
Relevant work done. So they get a lot of work done to that work
We've seen people get a lot of work done but none of that work is actually applicable to anything we care about
People go off on these science projects forever, but I can't you know, those people are people I cannot reward
but if you're doing a lot of work and it may not be feature work, but if you're like enabling the team like I
want to look at someone if I'm
Cranking out I'm making sure that this infrastructure works to make it very easy for devs to check into a CI system and get data
Out and and make decisions very very quickly, etc. Etc. Even if I never write a customer facing feature
They're doing a ton of output on relevant work and they're helping other people
So although they haven't done a customer facing feature, they may be one of my most valued employees
Sesinctly like I have the same bar
Sesinctly the way I and then I order it for me. What's important first and foremost
Validated ROI that you delivered something that was validated as ROI. It drives me bonkers
That there's a lot of folks highly successful at
Hand-waving and saying oh look at all the awesomeness that we did
When all they did was ship well ship in two weeks later you you you got two people using it
I'm like no you didn't deliver ROI
Okay, ROI business ROI delivering business ROI is absolutely my first one. The second one is absolutely team collaboration
Hero is a four-letter word. I
Cannot any longer stand siloism there. We've talked about a blog
Before or we did a podcast before
There is a place for heroes, but in general
They're not used in that fashion that we've discussed before and in general they drive me bonkers
And often the hero is ends up being a bottleneck
It almost always does we'll be fine as soon as the hero comes in and saves us saves the day
and then
So it was ROI
Collaboration and then lastly is throughput if I can get these first two principles
throughput is easy to turn the crank up on when when they try to do throughput first and
They abandoned the others two principles then things go into the weeds. That's my experience
It was great to have a mail-in mailbag item from you Alan
Yeah, we forget to do the mailbag when it's a question from each of us. Yeah, I don't think it really counts
so
One thing one last thing. Yeah is I should probably talk about is
Came back from the break after the holiday on Monday. We're having a meeting. We had a little bit of a
Architectural reset on my team
We're gonna change our back end and we're talking about how to get that going and we're having this discussion and and this is totally
Out of context, but one of the and I tweeted this and maybe I should just read read the tweet
This is words removed and paraphrased to fit in 140 characters
But basically what happened is I I said this
Peer manager said today that his current plan was to quote not worry about tests and quality
Well, his team got their features done, you know
I wrote hashtag last words and just a little bit of event for me and kind of you know, it's
Kind of funny, but it's like 20 some odd retweets and then 12 likes of that
Well that struck a nerve or people thought it was pathetic or something
but and then
There are some follow-ups on that or so there's some context where I think he meant the right thing and and we had a long
We had a talk afterwards and a couple talks afterwards
One where I told him he should be fired but
He took it well
So the point is is when in the world and again he didn't use those exact words, but
Why do smart people this is our I think our smartest dev manager. Why do smart people?
Say dumb things
To me that's a very easy answer you think it's an easy answer I think it's complicated
What's your easy answer? No, so it's it's it's broad enough
that I could easily see your typical answer for these type of things of
It depends would apply
So but I actually think I can answer it with an equivalently broad answer
Oh, I can't wait go the answer is I'm letting it even say always
the wrong combination of fear and hope that is
Always the answer. So let me go a little bit more specific smart people do dumb things because they're not using their smartness
They're not analyzing. They're using an emotion. Yeah, motion is always there influenced by context and largely emotion and
One of the things I learned a few years ago. I spent some time
I don't have time for the long story
I will tell it anyway in the brief form used to be a thing we did at Microsoft called an MS 360 where
If you get up to hire their own leadership ish levels
They one of the things you can do is this thing called the 360 where they take people from all over the company
You've worked with people that work for you. You work for you work with you work outside of your org and they fill out
This extensively long survey about you and just to kind of get feedback on kind of how you're perceived around people and I grew
up in the Microsoft of you know
Steamroll take names and you know, if you leave bodies in your wake, it's cool
so those are my mentors my first like 10 years at Microsoft and
That's where the good attrition comes from and we know people that still try and act like that and where I made a big turning
This 360 and I met with HR and you know because they
Still people as part in that I know and they're idiots as part of this
It was kind of eye-opening because I felt like I was doing good
I was emulating my mentors and and I was having a great time and being a dick and
Part of this is the ad like a one-on-one with some HR person talking to you about stuff and and they go holy cow
Alan everyone you work with loves you. They think you're fantastic. They also think you're an asshole
Yeah
So it was like oh
Is that good or bad?
So I ended up because what I do is what I want to improve it something I study the crap out of it
So I read like a half a dozen books on interpersonal awareness, which a lot of people hand wave as oh
I need to be nice to people and that is the most shallow
It's like it's like to loop this background at the beginning
It's like learning just enough of the force where you go off on the dark side and become an income a jerk
I would say if you wanted to do a broad generalization, it's not be nice to people. It's no it's understand. No, it's understanding
How you're coming across as well as what other people are saying it's a different you need to concentrate on perception and learning about things
Yeah, so when I see someone anytime like that's really stupid
But and a lot of times like I used to like flip the bozo bit like you said something stupid. You're an idiot
I'm never taking anything you say at face value again because you're an idiot
But I look at and I assume for the most part if someone especially someone's fairly senior
They're a smart person and with this guy. He's a smart person thinking why would he say that and it's about context and the context
Is is he had some fear?
About you know getting things up and running
We have a lot of dependencies like in order to get the site up and running on the new back end like it
We need to get you know level stage D or E running before we could actually dog food on it
It's depending on ABC and D and he's thinking well if I am blocking these five other things down the road
The important thing is get them unblocked first and then if I have to make some shortcuts, I will
But once he said that I said oh, I'm actually okay with that
I'm actually I'm all for do not skimp on adding unit tests. Do not skimp on code review not skip any of this stuff
If when push comes to shove you want to take a little shortcut
I'm not saying right crap throw away code
But if all you're saying is sometimes gonna take shortcuts in order to unblock someone then you go back and do that work by all
Means that's okay cuz unblocking I think is very important
But I want to be exception rather than the rule but even then once you unblock
Then you immediately have absolutely and and and he was okay with that but though he was looking at it from the I
You know, I look at things that
We wanted the goal is quality. We're not we're never going to ship if we don't think of quality first, but
sometimes
There's no rule that I can think of that's written in stone
This is you have to follow every single time you can bend these things for a reason when I was in college
It was great. I took this and I mean I'm on my talent chair had music theory for two straight years of music theory every morning
exciting, huh and
We spent the first four or five four and a half quarters of that like learning rules the rule of fifths
That's like day one. So it learned rules and rules and rules and rules is Kate now, you know the rules now
You can break them not allowed to break the rules till you understand the rules. Yes
So that works a lot. So anyway, that's important
That's like the first lesson that I teach and is broken in a true with agile as well, huh?
Learn the rules that there's probably a blog post in there. Yeah more next time. So there's two two
For lack of a better word I'll say wisms that I pass on that's real
Relevant to this when mentees come to me first and foremost
Everybody is awesome. It's their behavior set piss us all very very well put just because I like that nugget
Just because you think they're a dumbass
More than likely it just means their worldview is different than yours. Now there could be behaviors
that are
The oil and vinegar with your behaviors, but it doesn't mean that their worldview is
Necessarily invalid. Okay, this is one of the things that were why I love strength finders as a framework because it gives me insight into
Okay, this behavior is really pissing me off
how do they look at the world that would explain this behavior and
which enables me to
Then go have a conversation say, okay, how do I suggest a behavioral change because these people are awesome
I want them in this party. I want them part of the team
But I can't live with how they're doing this behavior wait the second wisdom
This is something that I've learned
It's not always true, but it is true. So friggin awesome or not awesome
Often that it is awesome
and that is
in general
though the worst things people do
The behaviors that they do to screw up their own lives is because they are operating out of a fear and they don't
Often even realize it the best thing people who are observing this like you go you go Wow this guy
Normally really smart. He does does does these things really well, but this thing this thing he's doing
Which is completely wrong is also
Uncharacteristically
Part of his behavior said this is a new pattern
This is something I've never seen this guy do before and I will tell you 80% of the time
It's because they're afraid of something even if they are claiming they aren't so two quick things before we close today is
Two things come to mind both from books. I read a lot huge number of books
Jerry Weinberg said on multiple occasions. I don't know what book or whether
It was somewhere else, but it's actually I do know a book is from but I can't remember the name
Doesn't matter
It's always a people problem
Which is true, but what is even better and I really think it's important if you have to work with people
You need to actually work at it the same as you work at your code
If you're a consultant, especially or a sort of leader as much as you work on your technical skills
You need to work on how you deal with people just as much and maybe more if you're behind the curve
Michael Lop wrote a book called
Managing humans, which is very very good
There's a whole chapter on FUD fear uncertainty and doubt and how to deal with that in your organization
Which is you know right along these same lines and you need to be able to handle that you need to understand that
You know people have weird behaviors. They're gonna act differently
You need to learn if you really want to manage someone or lead someone you need to take time and effort effort
Especially to kind of figure out where they're coming from what drives them
There's a motivation that makes people say silly things or do dumb things
there's a motivation that made this dev manager say we're gonna make shortcuts and I real demand like this to make the shortcuts for the
exception rather than the rule and and
Working with people is a lot about compromises not about setting hard rules and making people
You know strictly adhere to them and you and I have both known test managers throughout our career that say this is the way
It's gonna be and you know, I'm in my own quality and these are the rules
But you you could have rules. We also have to understand that sometimes in
Making progress I was once I I was that test manager once
I'm glad you grew up Brent it and it did not go well
It was the single most important learning lesson in my career
Very cool. We could go on and on on this thing is a good subject to explore more next time just kidding
But our three listeners are tired and probably want to get off to bed. Yes. All right, so happy new year
Happy new year. Everybody will be back with episode 34 next time I am
possibly Alan as am I
Later bye guys