Hey everybody. I'm Alan. I'm Brent. And it's episode 51. 51. 51 of A B testing. Thanks everyone
for downloading yet another podcast. It's our end of the year episode. It is. It is. You know what?
Now at this point, maybe hasn't passed. I was going to say at this point, we've done more episodes
than the oldest of A B testing. I turned 51 a few weeks ago. It's a tie. And now we're in episode
51. If we survive the holidays, we'll do 52. And then, uh, yeah, what are you doing for the
holidays, Brent? You staying in town? You going to Las Vegas? No, staying in town. And, and, um,
I'm doing what is an accidental tradition, which is at the start of December, I go, Hey, I take,
I'm going to take the last two weeks off. That's enough to do my shopping. And then when the last
two weeks come, I go, Oh crap. The last two weeks only gives me one week till Christmas.
Why don't I learn this year over year? So I will be fighting traffic. Oh, wait, it's Christmas.
It is. Shoot. I have to do some shopping too. I'm in trouble. That's what Amazon's for. Thank you,
Amazon. Yeah. The only problem with Amazon is it doesn't tell you what to buy. You still have
to look for it. Yeah. We're down a rabbit hole. I don't want to be down because this is a,
it's hard. It is hard. I was going to say something funny and clever and interesting
and relevant. And now I've completely forgotten it. I will say that the big value adds to society
for those data scientist guys would be to solve that problem. Pretty soon. Can't we do that? Can't
we just plug in a name to a search engine? It tells us what they need or what they'd like,
even better, not what they think they want, but based on their analysis of social media,
research, postings, whatever their internet presence, it tells you what they want that
they don't know they want. Right. And prune out the risks of things like, Hey,
my wife says she wants a vacuum cleaner, but does she really know, dude, save the vacuum cleaner
for Valentine's day. Is that better? Is that really better? Yeah. Do the vacuum cleaner. Here's a
romantic vacuum cleaner, honey. Get her a red one. Oh yeah. Sure. Come on. There you go. Perfume it up.
Yeah. Yeah. Present it in candlelight. Yeah. Yeah. I got you a vacuum cleaner. Yeah, baby.
I'm, I'm driving to Bozeman, Montana. I'm sorry. Yeah. I, do you think of a better month to drive
over the Rocky mountains in December? No. Yeah. Yeah. You got to go through 90. So like you're just.
It's 90 all the way. You got two sets of chains in case one breaks.
Just, just one set of overpriced Tesla chains. You're driving your Tesla through the snow.
Heck yeah. All right. Way to go. The thing, the thing I, I remember is, uh,
I 90 is a huge trucker route. It's driven on all the time. So even if there's snow,
it gets kind of beaten down pretty quickly. You should double check. Cause I did hear in
the news that they were going to shut down 90 sometime around now ish.
It can't shut it down. It's a major thoroughfare. Yeah. But they were doing some avalanche. Yeah.
They close it like, yeah. So they don't shut it down. I'm not leaving now.
They're moving a mile an hour. Just look, just saying, or don't, you know,
it'd be a great story for next year's podcast. Yeah. Yeah. If I live, jeez. Hey,
it's the last podcast of 2016. Yep. And we should talk about some of our favorite things.
Here's where I'll cue the, we really need.
Yeah. So our favorite things from 2016 and maybe some things we'll predict from 2017
and we can reflect on our predictions from 2016 and whatever else comes to mind as we
babble through the next 40 minutes or so. Right. Hey, so the first thing, uh,
it is episode 51. We, uh,
I always worry when Brent starts reading his phone during the podcast.
Yeah. I can write it down here. So last time we did this last year was somewhere around episode 30 ish.
30. Oh, I mailed it to you. It's like 36.
36, 30, 30. Yeah. You can go. I'll, I always say I'll link to things in the show notes,
but I probably won't, but I will try and remember to add a link to last year's prediction episode,
because I'm going to quote from it. I'm going to paraphrase from it loosely later.
Yes. So what's your prediction for the episode number for this episode next year?
Oh, that's a good one. So our prediction show for next year will be,
oh, there's some factors in here. I have to talk to you about after the show.
Let's say 72. 72. I'm going to say 70. So it'll be real close.
All right. This is like the prices, right? Where you, as close as we can go over, right?
So if it's 71, we tie and we hug. Otherwise, yeah, if we want to,
want to do it that way, it's the closest without going over.
And if it's going to be episode 70, I will break one podcast into like three.
I have the power to control my own. You forget I can be clever occasionally.
Yeah. Hawthorne's effect in effect.
This is not even the Hawthorne effect. This is just me being a dick.
Yeah. It's people's behavior changed in accordance to how it's being measured.
You want to win. So you're going to change the behavior.
And you're like, ha ha ha. I have power. Brent doesn't.
It's because I'm a winner. Winning that meme is like five years old.
So done. Yeah.
So old. Okay. What have been some of your favorite moments for 2016 that you recall?
And keep in mind that both Brent and I are old and we can't remember what we did last week.
So remembering podcast moments may be difficult.
The positive thing is I took notes. Oh my god.
The one episode a year, I know upfront I will have the Hawthorne.
I however am completely unprepared.
I have three I wrote down. So first and foremost, my absolute favorite moment of 2016
was our first promo code.
You mean our sponsor from Star?
Yeah.
Hey, I would like to take this point to let Brent know and our listeners know that
they enjoyed our little plug so much. Star would like us to be like a regular,
like once a quarter sponsor for 2017. We have made it.
We have made it. We have like,
we haven't totally made it. Like aren't we supposed to get paid for this?
Working that out. But at the very least we may get a very huge
free Star logo to put on the hood of your car.
Nice. Swag.
Yeah. AB Podcasting where the sponsorship is super friction free. I don't know. I have to work on the
Yeah. You keep thinking about that.
So anyway, yes, we had our first sponsor.
So they circled back. So the people actually use the promo code?
I don't know. That's interesting. I didn't ask.
But they did. I don't know if anybody did or not.
Because we only have three listeners. I don't know that any of them went to Star.
However, they think we're mildly interesting and we don't rag on Star too much.
So they're going to have us back. So congratulations, Brent.
That's awesome.
You're like a professional podcaster.
Almost like one.
At a very loose definition of professional.
And podcaster.
Yeah.
True, true, true, true.
Hey, hear that, Vernon?
Test Bash.
Vernon. Test Bash.
Promo code.
Yeah. Oh, yeah, we can we can sponsor Test Bash, but they're pretty low.
They're such a different beast than Star.
Yeah.
I'm star is like this corporate enterprise marketing machine.
So you get it's a great place to get as we mentioned before.
This one, not even any sponsorship.
I think stars where you go and you want a bunch. I'm new to this.
I need a bunch of knowledge and ideas, etc, etc.
And then just bash where you go. It's like more in the masterclass.
Sure. Really, at the end of the day, I just want more promo codes.
All right, man. We'll get that done.
Low, low hanging bar there.
My boss is texting me, so I just got to you talk for a minute.
I'm just going to let him know.
Oh, OK.
My second favorite podcast moment was the spontaneous
invention of the one of the three slack channel from one of the three.
That's right. That's a good moment worth remembering.
It was better at this than me, Brent.
It helps to remember when you've already thought about it and wrote it down.
Yeah, whatever.
You have a slack team and it's kind of fun.
I really am enjoying the conversations there.
Yeah.
It's like hanging out backstage with Alan and Brent.
If Alan and Brent, it really is.
If Alan and Brent don't actually participate as much, but Brent does.
There's a lot of great conversation among the three without us.
Alan's, I would classify you sort of as a slack channel stalker.
You get involved if someone's mocking you or usually me.
Or someone says something that you just can't stand anymore.
I imagine that's how you handle Twitter.
That's usually you also.
But yeah, the slack channel, if you're not on it,
you should get on it.
It's really formed up an informal community.
Yeah, it's one of the three.slack.com.
If you need an invitation, you can email me, Alan at angryweasel.com.
Oh, we're gonna...
Okay.
You can do that.
How else are you gonna do it?
I just like Hawk and Percy like crazy on that one.
Percy has done a lot for us.
Maybe in the spirit of the holidays,
you shouldn't chuck more crap on top of him.
Is he your lackey?
I think he likes it.
Did you hear episode 49, how happy he was saying, and I'm not Brent.
That was 48, right?
49?
48, yes.
Anyway, that was my high point of the year,
recording that episode with the guys at Test Bash.
That was a lot of fun.
Yeah, I wish I had been there.
I've not been to Philadelphia, so it would have been fun doing the historical tour.
And then from...
I really enjoyed the series we did on transforming the data cultures,
starting in episode 44.
I have...
Bringing in Steve Rose.
I have myself stolen so much information from those discussions on my team.
Oh, good.
So that was a good learning experience for me.
Have you tried like, hey, here's this awesome podcast.
UPM should listen to it.
These guys, they know their stuff.
Have you tried that angle yet?
No, I haven't tried that.
Wow.
You think you get away with that?
Well, Microsoft has this huge value and huge push around the growth mindset.
Yep.
Which is from the book.
It's called Mindset, yeah.
You can look it up.
I don't need to talk about it.
Most of our PMs don't have that.
I hope they don't listen to the podcast now.
Yeah, so I'm guessing you're not going to use this as a reference to them.
No, no.
But I think the point is, I think I can safely say that and not edit it out.
That's the fun part.
Oh my gosh.
Alan's getting the love from the management.
Yeah, and my boss is in India right now, where it is only about nine,
a little after nine o'clock at night.
Yeah, most bosses I'm aware of still aren't in.
I was feeling bad for you.
Like 24 seven, he's got his eyes on you.
That was, was 48 your highlight?
It was episode 44 is where it began.
I think we did three or four episodes.
I'm sorry, 48 was, I meant it was 48 the highlight of having AB testing without Brent.
No, that made me sad.
Like really between the two of us, you've done 51 episodes and I've done 50.
And I'm not entirely certain since you have all the equipment, how I catch up.
Maybe I record a conversation on the phone.
Tell you what, you can just talk into a tape recorder
and then figure out how to upload that to the internet.
Yeah.
Again, not catching up.
All right.
You have any of your own moments?
49 was my favorite.
Sorry, 48 was my favorite.
You screwed me up by calling it 49.
Try bring games or something, pick up your memory agility.
I'm sorry, what were we talking about?
Yeah.
So you liked going to Philly and recording with the one of the three?
That was a lot of fun.
Anything else comes to mind?
Uh, was it this year with the episode where I asked you the ISTQB questions?
No, that was last year.
Damn it.
That was our favorite moment from, that was one of our favorite moments.
I can't remember.
Yeah.
I really, this will be the year 2017.
Yeah, right.
As I get older will be the year where I really break things down.
We need, you know, um, the Stack Overflow podcast,
they have people that translate, that translate the text,
not only into English, but into different languages.
We need one of those.
I didn't like someone Stack Overflow had a podcast.
See, that's what you know.
So, uh, let's flip those two speaking of podcasts.
Um, I was thinking about my favorite pot, the podcast I listened to the most
ones I listened to the most in the last year and they haven't really changed.
So I, so for me, freaking omics, although, um, because of your suggestions last year,
I listened to a great deal of the ones that you suggested last year.
For example, uh, I don't remember what I was forgetting.
Then actually I have my phone.
So I'll tell you why you look it up.
So my, the staples that I listened to regularly, I'm sort of a trivia nerd.
I just saw a good job brain.
Yep.
So good job brain is something I listened to.
I listened to both.
Wait, wait, don't tell me.
And, uh, what's the other trivia?
A little bit lamer trivia show on NPR.
I don't know.
Uh, I don't have it.
It is a shoot has a fear of Eisenberg crap.
It'll come back to me.
So I still actively listened to this American life.
I, I like the story model.
It's a great way to learn.
I mean, the way to learn anything is to immerse yourself in the technique.
For example, when I was in college and played in a jazz bands, we'd have this grueling
audition process.
And a lot of times he'd ask like, who do you listen to?
It's what there's so much more of what you get as like a jazz musician on what you
listen to.
And there's so much you learn by listening to players play the good, the great players
that will eventually transition into your playing.
All the great writers say the way you get better at writing is to practice writing a
lot and to read a lot.
Stephen King has a great book called on writing.
He talks about just if you want to be a good writer, you need to read a lot.
If you want to be a good storyteller, listen to a lot of good stories and read a lot
of good stories.
Yeah.
And, and learn the art of a, sounds like a James Whitaker talk, learn the art of
storytelling.
Years ago, there was a class here at Microsoft advanced presentation design.
And that was a key aspect of the whole thing is if in present in presenting your goal
is primarily entertainment.
It's not the delivery of the content.
Absolutely.
And that's like the step in between there.
And I've been trying some different, I learned a technique.
I haven't pulled it off really well yet, but someday I'll give a talk where I can
pull it off.
It's this five by five technique where you start with a story, you don't finish
it.
And you go into another story and then you kind of build this inner loop and
kind of get the fourth or fifth story.
You tell the ending to that story.
And then in weaving your talk, the ending to the, after the fifth story, the fourth
story, then the ending to the third story.
And then people are waiting for, they're waiting all for the, they know at the end
they get the answer in the punch line to the story you started at the beginning.
It's a really difficult technique, but in the examples I've seen, it's really
cool to watch.
So I want to pull that one off sometimes, but I think if you want to be a
presenter, I think storytelling, as you mentioned, very important.
How many talks have you seen about data presentation?
Again, to give test bash a plug, one of the things I liked about it is it wasn't
that, although some people bordered a little bit on it for the most part, it
was experiential and there was a story there.
And I think that's really important.
I hate this.
So what you want to do with metrics is you want to measure things, measure them
again, but first let's look at the definition of metric and see what that
means.
It's like, Oh my God, I want to gouge my brain out with an icicle.
Um, happy.
Every, so you mentioned, you know, the data presentations, even then you can
do it with a brilliant story.
For example, every Ted talk I've seen where they're presenting data, right?
Those guys are good.
I have not seen a sucky one of those.
No abs because they can tell a story with right.
So, so important.
So anyway, this American life getting back on track here.
Uh, absolutely.
If you listen to those stories, you will, if you don't regurgitate those
stories, uh, you will, uh, you will be become a better storyteller.
One of the things that we tied us back to jazz again.
One of the things we always do in lessons when I was, uh, playing a lot is
in lessons.
We, one of the things I always have to do is learn a solo from John
Coltrane from, uh, Sonny Stitt from Dexter Gordon, um, you know, off, off
of the recording and learn how to play it just like they do.
And that's gotta be hard.
We would, um, you get better at it.
Cause the ear is so important.
So we would do like, I would do like one a week, learn a solo a week, whether it's.
So what happened is occasionally then when you're playing your own solos, a little
bit of those things you go, Oh, I can play that riff.
I learned from that Dexter Gordon's whole earth.
It fits really well right here.
And those little bits of they call them quotes and those little, those quotes
come out in your own playing the same thing.
If you listen to a lot of stories like this American life, like a lot of the
NPR shows or Ted talks or, uh, one of the podcasts I'll mention is Dan
Carlin has a couple really good podcasts.
Who's named that completely forgotten one on history, which is like their
three hour podcast, but he doesn't know what sort of on politics and current
events.
He's just a good storyteller.
It's all by himself telling, talking about how these things work.
It's very, he's very, uh, engrossing.
And although I won't tell his stories, there may be an anecdote I'll pick up
and maybe from this American life, if you listen to it enough, you'll find, Hey,
you know what?
That's that relates a little bit to work.
I can weave in this story in a presentation about something I'm doing
at work and those, so the exact same patterns happen.
So if you, that's something that you want to be good at listening to those
things will definitely help you.
It's very aligned.
Like you mentioned mentioned the Ted talk, uh, they have a podcast.
And so the two things, the two podcasts that I am regular listeners to
that I added this year are the Ted radio hour.
Cause the other thing I think I really like about the, um, the two that I've
added, they're both very much around stories, but they're grab bags.
You don't know what you're going to get on any podcasts.
So I find that that opens up the realm of possibilities.
Have we as we've talked about here, new ideas come from old ideas
coming together.
So whenever I hear my Steven Johnson bone, who's the guy that wait, where
ideas come from?
Yeah.
Steven Johnson.
Does he have a podcast?
He just started one.
Okay.
I'm going to, it's called wonderland.
All right.
So my third that I haven't even listened to yet will be wonderland.
Okay.
But the one thing that I found that I think is a gem is called 99% invisible.
I have heard about that have not listened to it.
99% invisible is a podcast around design and how design has positively and negatively impacted
the humans that interact with that design.
So the latest episode as an example talks one second.
Is it called wonderland?
Is that it?
Yeah.
Fantastic.
Subscribe.
Oh, Steven Johnson.
I just clicked through.
Oh, Brent.
That actually is that's, that's honestly, that is better than a, than a Christmas present.
Good.
Cause that's all I got.
Yeah.
I mean, I just liked the, the, the latest podcast is called the, the plat of Zaya.
And it's about salt lake city and how bring them young designed the city.
And they have these 660 acre blocks, which is, I believe nine times larger than a normal
New York block.
And the streets are like, um, I want to say 120 yards across.
So a traditional stoplight signal.
They have problems with it.
Because if pedestrian starting to walk the traditional timing for pedestrians,
they're in the middle of the street when it gets to don't walk.
So there's the, um, they're going through how that initial design benefited and then
how it changed, uh, society later and what they're trying to do about it.
Like it, it's a brilliantly named, uh, podcast, 99% invisible.
I've added it to my list.
Yeah.
Okay.
So, so mine are like, I'm looking at my list now.
So I remember that the Ophira Eisenberg hosted chill on NPR is called ask me another.
And it is, uh, while wait, wait, don't tell me is, uh, news related trivia from the week.
It's a great way to catch up.
The fun way to catch up on news, uh, ask me another is just rant like stupid word
games to play this game called this, that, or the other, which I find kind of hilarious.
And one of it's one of the games they play.
And what they do is they'll give you a name and like they'll pick three categories.
Like what was the one yesterday?
A national park, Japanese movie monster, or I forget the other one, something else.
And they give you a name like to try geeky.
And so it's just, it's not like any, any information you would use
ever elsewhere, but it's fun to hear people.
It's just, it's just, it's a good commute.
Listen for me for those.
So do you listen to Freakonomics?
I don't.
Okay.
Occasionally if I'm out of other podcasts,
Stephen Dubner has a new one that it's, uh, tell us something we don't know where he,
he invites participants to come in and just tell a story of that.
They expect people to not know already.
It's really random.
Um, but you learn something from every participant.
Okay.
So back to my turn.
So the podcast, I listened to the most again, most of the same as last year.
Uh, I'm what I haven't mentioned so far.
The Dan Carlin shows are common sense with Dan Carlin.
I like his history show is called Dan Carlin's hardcore history.
I don't think he even does that show anymore.
But, uh, if you can go back to the back episodes, uh, he does these like seriously,
like three hour long podcast talking about, you know, the Cuban missile crisis or,
or the, the plague or any chunk of history.
He will actually make it interesting for three hours,
which I get is great for the long road trip.
Right.
A lot of fun.
Uh, only other thing interesting on here is I do listen to total soccer show.
Of course you do catch up on things.
Congratulations.
Sounders.
Stephen Dubner also does a soccer show with his son.
Oh, there are too many soccer shows made listen to them all.
I used to listen to the one from, uh, MLS major league soccer sponsors,
one called extra time, which is awful.
I listened to it for a while.
I just couldn't stand it.
I'm sorry.
So, but you need a hug.
No.
So anyway, that's kind of my podcast list.
I was on the testing show this year and we'll check out that podcast from time to time.
Uh, and I did, I don't think it's a really regular podcast.
Now I recorded a little short with Mark Tomlinson, who was one of the three
for a little test bash pre-show.
He's on the East coast.
I think we did it like five in the morning.
My time.
Jinkies.
Right.
Jink.
Yeah.
You're so weird, Brent.
So anyway, those are my favorites.
Those are the ones that get regular play in my car on my commutes to work.
And I will be listening to a lot of these on that drive to Bozeman, Montana.
I need to.
Okay.
All right.
What's up next?
What blogs are you plugging for 2016?
So as I was prepping through this, I realized that not except for prepping for this show,
this is the year where I didn't proactively go out and follow up on, on, um, testing podcasts
or not podcasts, uh, blogs.
Like the, the closest thing I would say to that is, uh, anytime you post something
because I have the notification on, I read it, but I don't, you're so lame.
I don't even, I don't even think I would classify yours as a, uh, testing blog as much as I would
have say a couple of years ago.
For sure.
And interesting.
I was going to bring up the same point.
I still read a lot of blogs.
I go through my blog list usually daily and flip through it and it's half software engineering
blogs, half other things I'm interested in software engineering, including testing.
There's a few, I won't pull out any names, but you readers could imagine.
There's a few blogs I read just to see if someone's going to say something
extra exceptionally stupid or thought provoking or interesting.
Everyone want to look at it.
Well, the, the, the, the test related blogs that I have read read rather are when listeners
or you, um, have sent it our way as sort of podcast fodder.
Uh, the I am reminded of the, the episode we talked about, uh, in this last year, um,
on the box, uh, controversial slide.
Oh yeah.
Well, there was the right.
There was the whole thing on agile is coming to get you, you, you,
agile hate your doors.
Agile hates testers.
What does it?
Hates testers.
Agile hates testers.
Yeah, so for me, two blogs that I am going to totally screw up,
but I spent a lot of time on nowadays,
is number one, it's cleverly named AndrewJellman.com
and Data Mining Blog.com.
Both of these are applied data science blogs.
They both are around, they simplify,
they give you techniques to observe,
and they open up things to a lot more people.
They're not data science blogs for data scientists.
Oh, I need that one.
I need data science for non-data scientists
and people that aren't very good at math.
This is something that I'm thinking about
changing my blog towards.
So I've been doing a lot of ML in my day-to-day life.
Machine learning.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
And I have one of my employees who is just a brilliant guy.
Hey, it's Talon.
And about this point in the audio,
things start going badly and they only get worse.
So we'll finish up this topic.
And Brett now, kick off 2017 at episode 52
with a rehash of our 2017 predictions.
But he can be, he can tend on the impatient side.
So this data science thing, he immediately sort of goes,
this is hard and it's math-y
and I don't want to get involved in it.
But he's a smart kid.
And he started doing Azure ML.
And he realized that by observing what I've been doing,
that he was able to apply some of those basics
that he's picked up and immediately start rolling
on Azure ML.
So I'm thinking through this idea of also helping
to simplify things as well as get better myself on Azure ML.
Send me a link to that blog.
Yeah.
And I will put it in the show notes
and add it to my own feed as well.
I'll send you the positive thing about me having notes
is I can send you the whole bloody thing.
Oh, great.
Blog pose.
There were two that were really interesting to me this year.
One was from knowledgetester.org.
And it was on the generalist versus specialist discussion.
And I recently wrote a blog on this sort of topic
where I go through the history of where specialists come from.
And we kind of, I'd say, accidentally collaborated.
But he invented this thing called a pie-shaped tester.
Pie as in the Greek letter.
OK.
Which is like, there's a thing called a tree-shaped,
or a T-shaped tester.
Right.
T-shaped persona.
It's a T, but with one more depth skill set.
Great.
And then the last one, which I will,
I think this is something that everyone should listen to based
off of our data.
Or not listen to.
It's a blog post.
I'll just click correct you later.
You can have Cortana read it to you.
On the Data Mining blog, one of the posts that they did
was the five most common data relationships
shown through visualization.
So I think one of the first places people need to get into,
and we talked about this in the past,
is how valuable just staring at histograms are.
And they wrote a blog post around different, most
five common relationships where you can look at it and go,
ooh, I see something there that's
worthwhile to dig in further.
Cool.
Interesting.
That's it for me on the blog post.
How about you?
I gave this one last year, but I'll give it again.
I'm going to try and print out.
I probably screwed up her name last year, too.
But I got to meet Merit at Test Bash.
But Merit, oh my gosh.
I looked this up last year.
Merit, who has at visible-quality.blogspot.com,
has her season testers crystal ball.
And her role is so much like mine.
She knows testing, and she's on an Agile team.
My team's not really Agile, so maybe it's not that close.
They like to think they are.
But that's a whole other topic.
But it's not as much fragile your team.
She blogs almost every day.
And everything is, I have to read them all.
Because she does a good job.
And oh, yeah.
I've done that.
That's cool.
Oh, new perspective.
Cool.
Really impressed by her blog post.
I'm jealous of both that capability.
And even yours.
When I sit down to do a blog post,
I know the next four hours of my life are dedicated to this.
So you can just, and it's a brilliant blog post.
Depending on your definition of brilliant.
OK, happy 2016.
We'll see you in 2017.
I'm Alan.
I'm Britt.
And we're done.
Happy holidays all the time.