Hey everybody. Howdy. I'm Alan. I'm Brent. And we're back for AAB testing episode 46.
Hey Brent. Yes, I don't think we're alone now. We are not. Today we have a special guest.
Is he special or just a guest? He's a special guest. A special guest. Steve Rowe is a data
scientist manager in the Windows team. His journey has been much like myself. Why don't
you say a few words, Steve, about how you got here?
Sure. So I'm Steve Rowe. I came through the same similar channel to Brent and perhaps Alan.
I was a test developer for a long time in the Windows team. I did multimedia for a long
time and then I did some developer service stuff and then made a changeover to data science
as I saw things moving and changing and I thought that there was a lot more power in
figuring out whether we were doing the right thing or not and bringing quality through
data rather than quality through repeating testing over and over and over and over again.
What's wrong with that? People are now worried for their jobs. Don't freak them out.
There is, yes, there's some of that. There's going to be, what was it called, creative
destruction. I think would be Schumpeter's turn that is going on in some of this. So
I don't think you'll get rid of testers but I think that there's definitely a reduction
in the need for raw testers as they were replaced by data. Just the same way that there was kind
of a reduction in the need for manual testers as test development picked up.
You'll see if you follow Steve Rowe's blogs, you'll definitely see that he's cut from
the same cloth as most of the three. Actually, it occurs to me. We have two of the three
in the room today.
Wait.
Yeah.
I think I'm one.
Yeah, but Alan doesn't listen to the podcast.
I do.
I have multiple personalities.
Those guys are smart.
Oh, God.
Brent, Brent, Brent. So I have a question. I've been waiting to have a guest to do this because
like testing, if you ask two testers what they do, there's a lot of overlap Venn diagram
but there's differences. I think I bet my hunch is it's the same thing in the data
science world. So you've listened, you know Brent really well, you know what he does.
What are some things that maybe differ in what your approach and what you do and then
what Brent does?
I don't quite know what Brent does well enough to tell you exactly what.
Yeah, Brent doesn't do anything well.
Well, then I do things well. So there's the difference.
I do perception management really well, apparently.
So my team is kind of a split team. Half my team is what I would call a data engineering
team and the other half is a data science team. And so we spend some of our time
figuring out how to move data and process data at volume and then some of our time
trying to actually analyze data and figure out what the insights are.
I think the big difference is organizationally we're probably at different
spots in an organization. Windows is still trying to figure out how to use data.
And so as you guys have been talking the last few times about the process through
data, we're clearly past the data oblivious phase. We know no data exists but we're
still in this phase that I don't think you quite mentioned but kind of a
confirmatory data stage where half the time we want to use data but only if it
confirms our intuition. And we don't really want to be challenged by the data.
I've heard some people around me say, you know, I only want this result if it's
going to show me what I want because if it's not what I think is true, then I
know that the data is wrong, which is clearly an interesting stage to be in.
So a lot of our job is spent trying to get the organization to pay attention
to data, to become more data literate and more understanding of what data
should be used for. So we have less opinions and more data-driven decisions.
That's actually very interesting. There's something we talked about that data aware
stage, which was interesting and maybe it's somewhere in there. I think you're
much farther along than my org, for example. But there's a data trustworthy.
Remember we used to deal with, used to, like last week with test trustworthiness.
Can I trust that this test failure is a product failure? Or can I trust that
this test passing means the product's working correctly? We kind of, not kind
of, there's a huge parallel with data. Can I, is this data telling me, do I
believe this data? Do I not believe this data? Right. And I think that's, that's
accurately a question people ask because the one thing I keep telling my team
is when you're writing programs and you get them wrong, oftentimes they crash
or they go clearly incorrect. If you're using math, it doesn't generally crash.
You can divide by zero. You can get some imaginary numbers, but not in
numbers, but otherwise it doesn't crash. It will happily tell you that the
average house price is $2 billion. And if you believe it, you know, that's the
case, right? It won't tell you, sorry, you gave me the wrong input. It'll just
tell you the average house price and value is $2 billion, which is off by at
least one zero. At least yeah. So I just had this happen yesterday. I, I got the
phone call, the IM, summoning me to the boss's rooms, the VP's room. And yeah,
we looked at the bug data and some just going back a decade looking at bug data
and incoming rate was dropping way down. We're at the part of our product, right?
Where it should and he looked, I don't believe it's dropped down that far. I said,
well, that's what the data says. I'm gonna go take a look at it. I, that it
is a little bit too good to be true, but I think we're over that corner. And
sure enough, I go back to the data. Someone had mucked with a query
underneath me and got the, and screwed it up and they're off by about half. So
the numbers were not good, but it's like, I think anytime what my lesson learned
there was trust, but verify just, I think with, yeah, I think that was the
wise wisdom from way back. I've definitely seen it happen both ways. It's still
true here. People find data that they want to believe and they, they believe it
to be true. I remember years and years ago, somebody did some analysis, not like
data analysis, but some analysis of a, we had this big system called WTT windows
test technology or whatever. And there's all these jobs that ran tests, like
thousands and thousands of jobs that ran tests. And somebody came in one day to
a develop directors meeting and they said, half of these jobs don't work. I
ran my tool and I found out that half of them don't work. They just can't run
it all. And they were beating us up because we were all idiots for not
having working jobs. And we go back and we're like, well, they actually do
work. So what was going on? Well, their tool had forgotten how to parse or
they hadn't built it, how to parse variables. And so there might be a
directory like, you know, SQL and back just windows. And then we would say
winder in as a variable and it wouldn't parse the directory and go, well,
there's no directory called winder. So therefore this can't possibly be
accessing anything on the system. They were happily trusting their data
instead of verifying it. And they were, you know, and that happens both
what happens that way, or it happens on the dev side or the PM side
sometimes where they don't want the data to tell them something wrong.
Like I don't trust it no matter what, because it's not matching my
intuition. You do have a lot of those problems in, in the data science
space. I'll give you an example. Just yesterday, we have a new data
scientist that ramped up he's come from office, where they have a much
more well documented curated list of data sets. And he's like, Hey, I
want to do is essentially, hey, I want to do data science. Can you
point me to the documentation for our data sources? And I'm like, okay,
dude, you and I need to meet. Because there are literally hundreds of
them, none documented. Right, we have, we have this one system that
does kind of automate away all the data movement for us. And they
able to use reflection to get essentially a reflection to get the
schema and publish the schema. But you have you have things like a
widget, goo it in a widget ID. Are these things the same thing? Or
are they not, right? We you have a lot of exceptions in the data
because the data doesn't come to us clean. You have a lot of
people who go to the raw data directly directly operate under the
belief that they do actually understand everything about the
data that they need to, which is I think similar to what Steve was
talking about, but they don't. So part of the things I do now is, hey,
I'll point you to the data. If you present any analyses you do
without vetting it through me to make sure you've got the tribal
knowledge, right, dude, you're on your own. And when someone
comes to me and says, hey, your numbers don't line up with
Brent's. I'm telling you upfront, you're the one that's
going to do the the the digging to figure out why. So what do
you think is the right level of documentation to do on data
sources? Like I've seen people that want a white pages of data,
right? I want to be able to like point you at every single data
source. I want to have them all fully documented. And then I've
seen teams that operate more like what you're talking about
where it's there's a bunch of data and you can kind of tell
the names, but you can't tell anything else. Where's the
right balance? Because you can get it right. You can easily
over index. So I'll tell you the approach that my team's
taking now. We are building what we call the CDW, which is a
common data warehouse. And it's initially we had planned it to
be something more directive where we would build it up and
then democratize it. Now what we are doing because I so I
flatted that as a proposal. And what it turns out is my own
team, Dev and PM, they're at the phase of Yeah, that could be
really useful as long as we don't have to build it. And so I
think the ROI of us doing that upfront is rather low, because
it's uncertain who who are going to be my customers if I
build it. But I need the data curated for I need a subset of
it for my purposes. So what my team is going to do is every
time we ingest a new data set, we'll curate it and then
we'll document it and we'll do it one at a time. I'd say right
now, most of 80% of what I'm working with is against 20
different data sets. That's easy enough to document. There's
there's a lot of asks for a lot more. But it's not high in my
backlog today. So when it becomes when it becomes it and I
then I pull the data in, I'll document it. In the meantime, what
I will do is document and police standards of practice. So
those those others who want a different data set, I'll say,
Hey, you're welcome to add to the CDW turn it into sort of a
shared source type project. And but you need to you will follow
these rules. Because if you don't, and I discover it, I
will remove your data from the CDW. Right? So I turned it
into much more of a shared source, but moderated to
prevent broken window theory.
So you have a few sources, a limited number of sources that
are commonly used, they're all documented, and then everything
else is kind of still the wild west.
Absolutely.
What are some examples of data sources you use for data sets?
You can you can generify for the external audience.
Until right now, I'm spending a large portion of my time
focused on availability concerns and reliability
concerns. So we have a transaction feed for the
heartbeat of VMs is the VM up or down. We have a ton of
metadata feeds, we have another transaction feed that that we use
quite often, which is our we call it our control plane. It's
essentially, hey, how many times the customer says create a VM?
Do we actually create a VM? Because now those two together,
we can then come up with new insights like hey, if a if a VM
goes down, can we determine if it was because the customer
asked for it to be down, which the heartbeat feed won't
necessarily tell you, but the control plane feed will. And
then we have a just a crap ton of dimension feeds, which is
essentially metadata about the nouns that we see in the
transaction feeds. So we'll have a VM dimension, it tells us
everything about where that VM lived and who it belongs to, we
have customer dimensions that say, hey, this customer is
Walmart, for example, and their headquarters are over and
wherever.
Isn't that personally identifiable information?
It is not. That is tenant, what's known as tenant identifiable
information. And that is fine.
I said that because we've had the same discussion often in my
team. So what about you, Steve, what data sets is your team
primarily working?
So we have quite a I work in the developer space. So I work
with a lot of application development and application
lifecycle kind of data. So we have a lot of streams that
show us like what applications this is for people that send us
data or in the beta program, not the general machines out
there. But we have data that tells us like what applications
were installed or attempted to install and which ones
succeeded or didn't succeed what the application lifecycles
were, was it launched? Did it go into suspend? When was it
killed? Or was it closed down? That kind of stuff. And so we
can see whether or not applications are successful or
not. We also have interesting data, we can watch what API's
various apps call. And so we can use that data to do cool
things like figure out whether or not the build of the
operating system regressed an app. So let's say that maybe
the Facebook app calls this networking API 40 times in the
first minute or whatever. If I can actually watch that over
time and say, Oh, on this day, it dropped down to 20, we
probably just broke that application. What we do wrong,
I don't know yet, we'll go figure it out. But we can
actually see in the data that that application broke on a
given build of Windows because that it behaves very
differently than it used to behave.
That's cool.
Wasn't Windows recently in the news on this data thing?
Isn't it wasn't at Windows, the where we announced or
where it was announced that we are following all of you?
I don't think so. No, there was some news. I don't
actually follow the news. We don't follow everybody. We
certainly don't. We have very strict restrictions on
pride, personally identifiable information and all
kinds of stuff that we do to make sure that we can't
track people. You can also turn it off. And, you know,
that kind of stuff. So if you're in the beta program, we
tend to watch more because it'll check boxes that tend to
be on by default. But a typical person using Windows has
a lot more control over it. And we don't do anything
that we would identify you as anything. So
so you do not have the ability to see what websites
Alan is looking at.
We go out of our way not to be.
Just mostly I shop on Amazon. Just total tangent
because that's part of the show. I was talking to
neighbor my works at Amazon and I said, man, if I
got a discount there, oh, it says we get a discount.
And but it's like, it's not really much they get
like 10 percent up to a thousand dollars.
Yeah. So they get one hundred dollars a year.
Yeah. So basically they get a hundred. It's not much.
And you worked there for two years. So really you
got about two hundred dollars as you.
It's more than that. But it's like a really when
you do the math, he's really excited about it.
The math. I go, wait a minute.
Yeah, it is something like that. I've heard friends
talk about it.
So that's their equivalent of the company store
program.
I guess because yeah, I'm I don't like shopping in
stores. So I'll buy clothes in stores. And
obviously I don't buy clothes very often, but
everything else I buy. Eventually they wear out.
Well, you don't have to stop wearing them when
they wear out. That is a common misconception.
You can just keep on wearing them. This T-shirt I
bought in 1998. Still little colors falling off.
Windows 95 on it or something.
No, I was wearing this when I was working on
Windows 95.
And that's the nice thing, right? With with if
he just waits long enough, he'll have his team
feed him new clothes.
Although no one commonly gives out T-shirts or
common, but no one's doing pants.
No, I haven't. I don't know that I've ever
gotten pants.
I have me neither. No, I'm I'm kind of upset.
I think I saw a pair of shorts once.
That's an oversight. I don't nothing shirt.
Lots of T-shirts.
Jackets. I just got to meet yet another jacket.
I've got two jackets on this team, a sweatshirt
and a jacket.
So maybe you should propose when your when your
product finally ships, you get a pair of sweat
pants with the product name right on the butt.
Like those pink ones.
Right. Yeah. Juicy.
That's the name of our product.
They just take things for a leak in our product
game. Microsoft Juicy for business.
Actually, I saw PR for your product recently.
So you guys are announced now.
No, we're not.
I didn't see anything.
Nothing. Nothing.
Nothing. I saw something.
There's nothing nothing condoned by our
organization has been released on the interwebs.
Gotcha.
And that's where we're going to keep that one.
So I've done enough things to piss off management.
I'm not going to go there.
So Steve's here.
Yeah. Hey.
So back to Steve.
What are we going to say?
How about now?
Sabre.
Go ahead.
So Steve.
Yes, Brad.
Um, I anxiously await your question.
I anxiously wait his question too.
So I've, I've gone through and sort of walk
through how I got to the position I'm in right now.
Uh, a lot of our listeners are, I'll say data
curious, right?
Um, and it's very, very clear that they are
operating in worlds that are behind us in some
degree, very similar to us, uh, 10, 15 years ago.
Or three years ago.
How would you, how would you guide from, from your
experience, how would you guide people, uh, making
this transition?
I think it depends on what course you're going
to take.
So there's two courses to try to get your team
to be more data driven.
Uh, one is a top down approach and the other one
is kind of a bottoms up approach.
Um, so you can either try to find or convince
management that this is a good thing.
And then management can create the edict that we
will go do this and, uh, then started building up
the organizational skills from there.
Or you can try to make your little section of
the world more data driven and do that in a way
that also gets your other jobs done and try to
become a center of excellence.
And people might mock, might follow you, uh, over
time and emulate you.
And those are both possible routes.
Um, I suspect most of our readers, listeners,
whatever, uh, we'll have to be in the second
bucket because probably most of them are not
directors or, you know, CEOs or whatever, and
they don't get to come down with the, with
the edict, they can try to convince management,
but it's not always easy to convince management
to do anything new and different because it's
scary and dangerous.
Um, and so I think that the pattern is to try
to start at the bottom.
Uh, a lot of times as unfortunate as that is,
I think it's a harder road to go, but it's
also the only road available a lot of times.
Um, and I think the right way to do that is
to figure out where, where you can replace
current functionality with this data or
supplement it with data.
I don't think that you can just say, we're
not going to test anymore.
We're going to use data.
Cause I don't think anybody's going to believe
that that is effective enough in order to
let you spend the time doing that.
They're going to still expect their test passes,
but you can start running data analysis on
the test passes.
You can start running data.
You can try to get some instrumentation into
the builds.
A lot of people have at least logs or
something along those lines, convince the
devs or go at it yourself, depending on
where you are organizationally and
what's allowed, and then use that to
try to understand, uh, whether, um, your,
the quality is high or not.
I think there's two major uses of
data, um, in an organization.
One use is to understand the health of
the product and the other one is to
understand what I call the success of
the product.
So the first one is to figure out whether
or not what you built is doing what you
expected it to do.
And the other one is figuring out, figure
out whether or not the users are
appreciating what you built.
Um, and I think it's much easier to bootstrap
the first one, the health metrics than
it is the other ones, because it's
more of a drop in replacement for, or
a supplement for traditional testing.
And, uh, I have a couple of blog posts
from way back talking about data
driven quality and kind of moving in
that direction, which focused mostly on
those health metrics.
And so I think one thing you can do is
you can start monitoring the percentage
of time that your test passes fit, pass
or fail.
You can start monitoring data about
the machines or the builds or the, the
environments that they're in and try
to tease out data from there.
Um, and then you can over time, maybe
start getting data from real instances
of the application, either through logs
or through some kind of, uh, you
know, data API that you have.
If you're in a server, you can do
it much more easily than if you're,
you're running distributed software.
Um, and then figure out whether or not
I can give you some sense for the
quality of your product, uh, for the,
the health of your product.
And then maybe you can turn down
the dial on testing and turn up the
dial on data.
What about your journey personally?
So how long ago were you in a, a,
let's just say a pure traditional
test manager role?
About three years ago.
It was the fall, about three years
ago, right?
When we started the work on, on
windows 10 that I moved from a
traditional test developer job to,
uh, a data science job.
When, when, uh, so windows was
essentially the first of your two
ways to get there.
If I, if I recall correctly, you, in
other words, it wasn't a bunch of
small satellite teams trying to
convince upper management upper
men, as this is my perception from
outside of windows, it was upper
management said, no, we're doing.
It was definitely a, a, a student
body left movement.
Like everybody, uh, has to go this
direction.
We took what was a standard test
developer role and said that role
no longer exists.
We now have a quality role, which is
not the same as a data science role,
but this thing we call the quality
role, which is just a label we put
on it, um, was all about using data
to understand the quality of our
product.
So we had in that group, we have
people that are more traditional
developers whose job it is to
instrument the builds and then do
basic analysis on those builds and,
and understand the area very well.
And then we have data scientists
whose job it is to help bring actual
math to the, to the problems, um,
in, in non-basic ways.
Um, I'd like to think of, there's
a Venn diagram that's pretty
popular out there that says data
science is kind of a combination
of area knowledge, programming
knowledge, and statistics or
math.
And I tend to think that no one
person really has all of those.
And so we've almost ended up in
a world where the area knowledge
and the programming knowledge are
owned by one group of people.
That's the quality teams.
And then the, the data science
knowledge or the, the statistics
knowledge, and then maybe some of
the programming knowledge as well is
owned by the data science teams.
And so the combination ends up with
a sweet spot in the middle.
So when, when they pulled this
trigger, were you anxious or
excited about it?
I was personally excited about it.
I'd thought about it for a while.
I'd actually been looking for ways
to try to go do this in my, my old job.
The difficulty that I had as I was
on the team that was developing
what was called Windows runtime,
which is the API model for all
of the, the Windows apps, uh, the
app store apps, the hard part
about that is trying to use
data in something that has a very
long pipeline is super difficult.
You can't exactly A B test an API.
You can't send it out, you know,
one version of the API to it, to
developer a and one version of
developer B and see which one
works better.
You know, you can't really watch
for applications to be submitted to
a store somewhere six months after
you introduce the API and then
start gathering data.
So it was the, one of the more
difficult places to go use data.
And so I hadn't figured out yet
the right way to go use it in
that space until the edict came
down. Um, and then we moved, but
even there we ended up in a world
where although upper management
said, go do this upper management
didn't really know exactly what
they wanted to do with it.
Either they knew they wanted to
get there, but they didn't know
they'd never done it before.
And so they didn't know what
parts to appreciate or not
appreciate. And there was a lot
of, of trying and failing and
learning that happened along the
way. And so we had a lot of
we're getting much better, but
we had a lot of, uh, early
pressure from the top to go do
this. And then various teams
tried different things. And so
you ended up with kind of
this hybrid model where there
was a lot of local, uh, idea
development and talent
development and, and ways to
use stuff that was developed and
then kind of pushed out to
other people as centers of
excellence.
So it was a couple of things on
you, uh, touch on that you
talked about one was, uh, going
way back the, um, this is why I
edit. You were talking about,
uh, you can either have an edict
from top or sort of, you know,
grassroots and, you know, try
stuff and do it gradually. Uh,
generally that latter approach
in my experience sticks more. If
it's harder to do driving from
the bottom up, but it, in my
experience in any sort of
organizational changes sort of
sticks more, um, edicts are
interesting and they can often
work. They're often difficult to
get, you know, all the time I
see people, they go to a VP or
somebody high up and go, you
should demand that the whole
org does this. And they rarely
ever do that because they,
it's not always a good thing to
make an edict. Uh, but one
thing was interesting, glad you
touched on it with the
windows one is, is they said
we're making this change and
the, how does it happen and
what does it mean was all left
in the air. So was why, no, no,
why was there? Why was not
partially there. I'll go more
than what or how. So there was
this and either it was, and
Steve and I may be on two sides
of this, but it may be either
genius or idiocy of this. Just
let a thousand flowers bloom.
And the end of worked out.
All right. Regardless of the
how it got there, let a
thousand flowers bloom and the
strong flowers will guide the
way for the slash and burn all
the white ones, keep the red
ones. Is that you describe it
like we were sitting on a hill
and we, they showed us this
picture across the valley of
another city on another hill.
And he said, we want to get
there. And you have this
valley laid out in front of
you covered with clouds, you
know, and fog. And they said,
go over to that other hill.
And you're like, well, what
do I need? Do I need like a
camel? Do I need a parka? Do
I need a boat? Like, how am
I getting there? Like, we
don't know, just go, you
know. And so we all tried. And
those of us that chose
camels, you know, ended up
poor in the, in the, you
know, middle of the Arctic or
and you get halfway there. And
some people say, let's turn
back. This isn't working.
We're not all the way to the
city yet. Let's turn back. And
so we had those people that
said, let's go back to the
traditional ways of doing
things. I miss this part
that I had before. And then
some of us pushed on and
we're still in the process.
We haven't gotten all the
way to the city. Maybe a
few. I think that's true
across a lot of Microsoft.
I think a lot of people
have made it to the city.
There are a ton of people
who just want to go back
to their old comfortable
city that that comfortable
city that's it's now been
raised to the ground.
No, it's full. It's full
of great 90s grunge music
and other things from the
90s, many other things from
the 90s.
Yes. The problem is that
people don't realize that
the old way was just not
fast enough. You're
guaranteed to be beaten by
your competition. That's
what I was saying. All the
old ways. That's what I
was saying when when this
first rolled out, like, I
think we were still doing
a we we were doing the
podcast then one of the
biggest things that both
Alan and I discovered during
those phases, explaining to
people why from a business
context, because the
number one question we got,
at least I got from from
individuals in the
Windows org was no one's
explaining why the old
system is broken today.
Right. It's kind of a
precursor towards these
folks who if if they're
forced to journey are
likely to want to go
back.
Right. I think that
they're there. We could
have been better about
that. If you go back,
there's some blog posts I
have on kind of the
development of tests or the
evolution of testing and
we kind of walk through. I
think the important thing
to recognize is that the
people who have made it
to data science, you know,
Island or Hill or
whatever, sometimes look
back and go, we were all
idiots. That was a terrible
way to do things. It was
never a good way. You
know, and I think that's
wrong. I think there was
certainly a point in
time and certain
requirements in the in
the environment and around
the ecosystem that made
that the right way to go
do things and still to
this day makes it the
right way way to do
certain kinds of work. I
think you can't say
that data science and
data driven quality is the
only possible way to
handle quality and it's
probably not the end way
that will handle quality.
There are probably other
ways that will be
invented later that will
replace those a lot of it.
But to say that manual
testing was always a bad
idea or that S-net work
was always a bad idea is
to ignore what was
actually happening in the
industry at the time. And
I think those were
actually very good
things to happen at
points in time when you
had certain requirements
from the ecosystem. If
you don't have the
ability to quickly push
new software out, if you
have to get it into a box
and get it onto somebody's
desk, you can't use the
data driven world that
we have. If you're not
connected, you can't use a
data driven system. And
so there was a point in
time when that was exactly
the right solution. We've
just moved past that
time. Right. I think I
totally agree. And one bit
of advice for pretty much
anything you're doing is
look for efficiency and
don't fall into that.
That's the way we've
always done it. Trap. And
don't fall into that.
That's the new way to
do a trap either.
Sometimes it's the new
shiny way. And so
everything has to be
rewritten or redone to be
the new shiny way. And
it doesn't always apply to
every part of every
industry, right? If
you're working on
healthcare equipment, I'm
not sure that data driven
stuff is the best way to
go. Like, oh, we killed
three people. We should
probably change that. It
depends on the area of
health, right? If it's
in some areas, yeah, but
there may be some, uh,
I'm trying to think while
I talk here, but, uh,
some more preventative
things. Maybe there's a
better way to measure your
blood pressure. I always
see every time I go to
the doctor, they have
like some better device
measure my blood pressure
and, and they have like
scales that are networked.
And there's a lot of, there
is room for, I think even
in healthcare to have more
data science and to learn
how doctors are using
things and to make tweaks
in the equipment. Yeah,
you got to figure out
where the places are. I
think it's always a
question of, of how long
the damage is going to be
sustained and how big the
damage is. Right. And
that's how you figure
out whether you need,
whether you need to
scale things. And so if I,
if I, the advantage of
using data is that I can
release something into
the wild for a little
while, and I can quickly
fix it, which means that
the data is the damage
that is doing, if it's
wrong, isn't sustained
very long in the old
world, it had to be
sustained for months or
years because of the
release cycles. Now you
can have it out there for
a day or half a day and
fix it, which is all
awesome until you have
an infinite cost, right?
If, if one second of
damage or one split
second of damage, it
causes a death or causes
major harm and you
can't afford to let that
go. And you have to
fix it before you
possibly, or even
worse breaks the
Facebook app. Yes. Yeah.
That's, that's
unconscionable. We are
definitely, we are
definitely in a world
where we have a lot more
options than we did
back in the day. I do,
to your point, like there
is a lot of revisionism
in a lot of the people
that I talked to, right?
It's easy to predict the
future in hindsight.
Yeah. Especially to
create it. Right. The
lot of the world and
back in those days, a
lot of the world and in
a lot of our listeners, I
think I still are still in
what we refer to as the
old days. Yeah, I think
they are. They're, they're
missing knowledge. They're
missing assets that we've
built up over, over the
years. Um, the, the
positive thing though,
is in today's world,
there's a lot of other
examples to learn from.
You don't have to treat
it as theoretical. I know
back in the windows 95
days, if I had brought up
anything along the lines
of what I do today, they
would look at me like I
had three heads. Right. And
it's just because the
ideas of this type of
work that we do and the
benefits of it were sort
of academic theoretical at
that point in time.
Well, at that point,
that would have been
impossible to carry out.
But even if assuming it
was possible, you're
right. They would have
looked at you like, this
doesn't make any sense
because they were just
moving to a large test
organization at that
point in time. Like that
was kind of when a lot of
the independent test
organizations are starting
to spin up. Um, I think
around that time, maybe
today, just been up not
too long before that.
Now back to your personal
journey. So you've been,
you've been doing this
for three years.
Correct.
What did you do to
prepare yourself to be
the head of a, of a
data science that
engineering team, did you
have that skillset
beforehand?
No, I didn't at all. I,
in fact, I've never even
taken a statistics course
when I was in college. So
I was uniquely on
skilled in this particular,
in this particular thing.
So what I did is what I
always do. And I started
reading, I started
reading blogs, I started
reading books, I started
reading papers. Um, and
then around that time,
all the, the MOOCs, the
Massly online open
courses, like Coursera and
edX, et cetera, uh,
started existing. And so
I took a lot of the
courses. There's a whole
series of, of almost
collegiate level courses
that you can take for,
for free or almost for
free. Um, and so I went
through a lot of those,
um, over time, I had to
learn a lot of the
techniques that I had to
go learn. So you have to
kind of become rigorous
and go back to
fundamentals and learn
the basics so you can
figure out what to apply.
Um, and then you have to
read, you have to figure
out where it applies and
where it doesn't apply.
But a lot of it, you
have to understand enough
techniques in order to
go back and be able to
figure out which ones to
apply and not apply.
Is there one thing if
you were to say, if you
only do one to start
from your experience,
what is the one concrete
thing you would suggest?
If you're trying to,
is there a data scientist?
Right. Yeah. So there's
there's a series of
MOOCs, about nine, eight
or nine of them, depending
on the take the caps in
from, uh, Johns Hopkins
University, um, which is
called, I think like data
science or whatever. Um,
it's on Coursera and
there's a series of,
of they're offered every
month or one per month.
And I would suggest going
through that set of
courses. It's a very good
set of courses. Most of
them aren't too hard.
There's a few of them
that are quite rigorous.
Um, but when you get
to the end of it, you'll
have a very good sense
for things. You won't
be a PhD by any stretch
of the imagination, but
you will have a very
strong sense of things.
And how often have you
been finding yourself
using what you've
learned in your job?
Daily, probably. Right.
So my job today is as
a manager. So I don't do
a lot of the direct, uh,
data analysis, but I
overview a lot of with
the data analysis. And
so I will oftentimes meet
with my teams and
they'll say, we're going
to go report this. And
I'm like, well, what
about that? You've
missed this corner over
here. Maybe you should
use this technique. And
so those all become
useful to ask questions
to make suggestions, um,
and to understand what
is possible and what's
not a lot of data science
can feel like magic and
but it can't do
everything. And so you
have to understand where
the constraints are in
order to be able to
figure out what to tell
your teams to go do or
to try to go do. Um,
one of the things I
think is important is
to realize that you
also need to be
willing to make mistakes
and willing to fail. And
so there's definitely
times when I have sent
my team off to go do
something and it turned
out it wasn't possible
to do like we went and
tried really hard and
then realized, you
know, PhDs in the
corners of universities
haven't yet figured
out how to go do this
thing. So it's
probably not possible.
And then it's your
reaction to that.
That's important. You
have to go like, okay,
cool. Now we know and
we'll go down a different
path. No way they
can't figure out you
fire them all. Get some
smarter people in the
room. That is sometimes
the management strategy.
That's not the one
that I recommend. Um,
just just throwing
spitballs. I think
we're very much in a
world. Uh, one thing
that I've noticed is
the world of, of test
development and to some
extent, the world of
development is a much
more constrained world,
meaning you generally
don't send people to go
do something that you
don't know is possible
to go do. It does
happen. Um, and you
can go read like show
stopper about the
building of NT and there
were people that were
sent off to go build a
graphic system that they
didn't even know was
possible. And they went
off and I think lived on
a boat for like three
months and came back
with a, with, with GDI
or whatever, uh, out of
the system. But, um,
that's rare. Most of
the time you're sent
to go do something
that everybody knows
is doable. It's just a
question of how long it
takes. When you're in
the world of data
science, you don't know
if there's enough
signal among all the
noise in order to be
able to generate what
you need. You
sometimes will go,
we'll get something and
realize all I can tell
you is there's no
conclusive answer and
that has to be okay.
There's another
tangent. This is my job
to make tangents today
cause I don't know
nothing about no data
science. I know a little
just enough to freak
Brent out, but for the
younger of the three
listeners, there's only
one left of two are
here. Um, one thing I
wanted to call out, it
wasn't just that the
guys went off and
built GDI, but it, you
know, in seclusion, but
imagine if you will
building complex
software without the
internet. Yeah. Without
stack overflow, without
Google or Bing, you can't
just ask somebody how to
go do it. Uh, what an
archaic world. My job
today, trees that will
give you a hint. Yeah.
My job today would,
would have been so much
harder to get to. And,
um, I'll double quote
master without the
internet for sure. One
thing. And yeah,
everything is faster. Uh,
the reason that we're
data science as a role
is cause we're moving so
much faster, both for
necessity and for, and
because, uh, possibility.
One of the great moves
about moving to a lot more
open source at Microsoft
using things like Git
for source control is
all of a sudden, uh, we
used to have like
horrible internal
documentation for our
internal tools, if
they were documented at
all. But now that we're
using a lot more stuff,
open source answers are
on stack overflow answers
are documented in blog
posts. It's, it's, it's
been, it's accelerated.
At least one fantastic
thing our team does, I
pick on our lack of
data science, but, uh,
we have a very good
modern engineering
system. It's all builds
in Azure. I find them
red. Woo hoo. Use a
lot of VSTS get first
source control, uh, the
whole crap ton of open
source and enables us
to move pretty fast
despite ourselves.
Yeah. It's, it's
interesting to leverage
the new world, but
it's also changed the
way that people learn.
It used to be, you went
and you got a book and
you read and you got,
and that kind of
forced you to get an
overview of the whole
area and kind of get
deep and realize how
the pieces are
connected. And now you
almost have, um, a
paging system where you
don't even have the data
until you need it. And
then you go to stack
overflow or you go to a
search engine and you
find it. And so you
kind of piecemeal build
this thing up in your
head, but you don't
understand the big
picture sometimes
almost ever. You just
learn the pieces you
absolutely need to
learn. And then you
move on and that's
good and bad.
Yeah, I agree too. I
call it just in time
learning the, actually
to that point. So you've
been here at least 15
years, right?
About 19. Okay. So
almost catching up with
you guys.
The, the, the situation
you went through three
years ago, where you
were, um, told to go
into this space, which
was fine. Cause that's
where you wanted to go
anyway. If that had
happened 15 years ago,
what do you think would
have happened to you?
It would have been
different, right? It
would have been, you
know, go find books and
read a lot of books
and then, and then
figure out how to go
do it from there. Um,
which is a lot harder.
The hardest part
actually would 15 years
ago is there's no
tooling. So 15 years
ago, everything was
proprietary tooling.
Everything costs money
or the company had to
go build it. And so
today I can just go and
I can get our, or I can
get Python and I can
have basically every
data tool I want at my
fingertips and a bunch
of documentation on how
to go use it.
And examples everywhere.
Back then you
probably would have to
go get a book that told
you here's how
logistic regression is
implemented in math and
you would have had to
turn that into an
algorithm and write your
own logistic regression
routine.
I, as, as our listeners
know, I've gone back
to school on this. Um, I
don't, if, if this had
happened to me 15 years
ago, I don't think I'd
be in this role. Right.
Cause it, it's, um, it
would have been a lot
harder to, to quickly,
first and foremost, online
academia didn't exist.
Right. Um, so I would
have had to gone to U-Dub
or some other, um, travel
situation, which would
made my life a lot harder.
Uh, so much so I may not
have done it.
Yeah. I mean, you kind
of had to, I actually
had to some extent that
I was strangely enough,
I was, uh, in law school
when I started at
Microsoft. Um, and it
didn't have much in the
programming background.
So I went to U-Dub's
website that existed, but
didn't have much
resources on it. And I,
I figured out what books
you read for a, uh, CS
degree. And I read those
books. Um, I went to, you
know, the local borders
and I bought them and
then I read those books.
So I have like half of
a CS degree cause I
didn't do any of the
homework. C plus plus
programming in 21 days.
Probably not.
Not so much that. Yeah.
This was Hennessy and
Patterson and a bunch of
those books. So I was
talking with one of my
children the other day.
Um, actually they were
listening to a podcast
and they were talking
about you are so cruel
to your kids. And I'm
leaving that statement in
the podcast.
They think it's cool.
They think Allen's cool.
Yeah.
So that you drug them
too. That's awesome,
Brent. Nice fathering.
And they were surprised
cause there was
something you brought up.
I think it was your
music major. And they
were like, Allen's a
music major. I'm like,
oh yeah. I mean, there
are, um, I don't know
what the stats are, but
there are just a ton of
people here that didn't
grow up through the
prescribed and defined
academic route.
Yeah, there's a good
fraction of us that are
that way. It's still a
much harder route to go
through than going
through a computer
science degree, kind of
traditional route to
get here. Um, both
organizationally, like
it's hard to get
through the gauntlets. If
you don't have the right
degrees, um, and it's
hard to get the right
level of knowledge. Self
taught people tend to
have big gaps in their
knowledge a lot of
times. And so it's much
easier to have a better
sense of how everything
works together. Um, if
you, if you're forced to
learn all the pieces in
between, um, that usually
means you don't know the,
the details of any given
piece as much, but you
know how they work
together.
The self taught people
today, um, the way I've
seen, I don't see a whole
lot of self taught people
today in the resumes
that I look at, but the
ones that I do see have
been, have a, a large
number of examples of
things that they've
shipped and applied.
This goes back to what
Steve was talking about
earlier. I think the way
Steve and I self taught
ourselves gave us those
overviews that are missing
with the way people are
self taught today, which
is the just in time
learning of just a little
chunk here and there. So
I think it's more
difficult if you're
learning that way,
cause you really do need
that overview cause
systems thinking, whether
it's data science or
testing is so important.
I think Joel Spolsky
used to talk about, uh,
he's created stack overflow.
One of the guys who
created stack overflow.
Um, and he's talked
about abstractions and
how abstraction layers are
useful, but they
always leak and you have
to understand the level
below that abstraction
layer. And I think the
problem with a lot of
today's learning models
is you only learn the
top level of the
abstraction and you
don't learn anything
down below, you know,
and that, that shows,
I've seen people in
interviews that will
do things like they need
to concatenate two
numbers together. So
they will turn them into
strings, add the strings
together and then turn
them back into numbers.
I'm like, yeah, that
works. But what, how much
work just happened in
the system in order to
make that simple thing
happen, you could
have multiplied by 10
and you know, added. And
instead you, you know,
did a whole bunch of
parsing and conversion
and then re parsing.
Yeah. But you told me to
concatenate so I
concatenated. So
technically it got the
job done, but not in a
way that was, I'll
save the long
explanation so they can
get onto the bag. But
I'll just say this for
the first time in my
career, I'm working on
a team full of
JavaScript programmers.
They're a different
breed. Yeah, they are.
It's a trip that
they're at an
abstraction level way
higher than I've ever
worked with. Hey, it is
time. And I've never
done this in front of
anyone but Brent before.
Mail bag.
I always wondered if
you did that live or if
that was just in post.
Apparently it's live.
Live and a little
reverb later.
It'd be good.
Yeah. It's really hard
for him to get the
the reverb across.
He's he's been
working on this for a
long time. Yeah.
All right. So we
have two mail bag
questions. We'll see if
we can get both of
them. I'll go in order.
And Brent wrote down
the names for me
because I always get
them wrong. So Abraham
Lincoln said,
no,
or score.
And I memorized that
in seventh grade,
I think, and still have
like the first two or
three lines memorized,
but I won't do them
today.
Percy asks, where or how
do we start with this
data democratization thing?
That's the word Brent
made up last time.
That's apparently
people had heard of.
My company has BI
data and analytics group,
but it seems that only
senior management are
the ones getting insight
from what information
they provide. So how
do you start?
I'll just bring it to
your word. How do you
start with this data
democratization?
Well, you sweet.
I am retroactively
be going down as record
as the guy who
invented data democratization.
That's fantastic.
It's one of those time
travel movies where you
invented it in the
future and then brought
it to the past.
Right.
Just second, my mind
settle after that.
Okay, go on.
So Percy has a
situation where they
have a data science BI
team that essentially
services the executives
and he wants to know how
does he get into data
democratization?
Well, so the
data democratization
means you publish your
data, you make your
data available.
I think he wants to
be a consumer of it.
So what he needs to
do is start off with
what actions does he
want to improve the
productivity or efficiency?
He is a manager.
What actions does he
want to take to improve
the productivity efficiency
of either his team or
his product?
So you start off with
what are the, where do
you think you can make
better decisions and
take stronger, faster
actions.
Then what you do is you
go and you just talk
with that team, say,
hey, I have this
concrete situation that
I think you have the
data for.
Do you?
If they don't, then
that's also going to be
a good team to get
advice from on the
data engineering front.
In order for you to
democratize data, you
have to have the data.
If your BI team has it,
then work with them
to figure out how to
share it.
Now, I'll tell you, a
lot of these guys will
view themselves as, oh,
we were the guys that
build the scorecard for
the execs.
So you may need to be
willing to pony up
resources in order to
share that data.
The thing is that most
of the data doesn't
exist. It's not created
by the BI team.
It's collected by the
BI team.
Yep.
So one possibility is to
go to the team that
they're collecting it
from and say, hey, you
have this database with
this information in it,
or you have this Hadoop
server with this
information in it, or
you have this, you
know, spreadsheet with
this information in it,
whatever your form of
information is, could
you please share that
out company wide or to
a much larger group of
people, you know, not
just me, because that
doesn't really, that's
not data democratization.
If you say you have
this data, can you
share it with my team?
That's not really
democratizing things.
That's making yourself
part of the special,
you know, part of the
elite. The better model
is to say, Hey, I need
access to this data.
There's others that
probably do too. Could
you make it more
broadly available? Could
you lower the access
rights on that server
and start having that
conversation plus any
data that you control
demonstrate how it
works, make it openly
available. A lot of
times people are
scared to open their
data because what might
happen if somebody gets
ahold of this. And I
think too often we
are, there's no
advantage to opening and
there might be some
risks somewhere, some
existential corner case
risk where we're like,
okay, I don't want to
share it because it might
cause, it might leak and
this might happen. And
oftentimes it's
overblown. And so I
think it should take a
little bit of risk, but
not much. And just,
the situation that I
encounter is, is I do
encounter that the teams
that I know that lock
their data, I would say
the primary reason is
because they know
there's a lot of
tribal knowledge baked in
and how to use it
correctly. And they
don't want to be
randomized by people
doing it wrong. Right.
Which is why I
basically say what I
told earlier in this,
in this episode. I will
say that if you're
getting the data in
this, in this space,
you, you do want to,
so Steve is right. The
data is being gathered by
the BI team from some
place, but the BI team
most likely has already
done the work to clean
and check that data. And
to encode the tribe,
the correct tribal
knowledge, start there
first, see if they will
share it out. If they
don't, then yeah, you
may have to go back and
reinvent the wheel, but
you should figure out how
to make sure you can
bootstrap that domain
knowledge and not
reproduce it. Right. It
is always difficult. Data
democratization solves
the access to the data,
but doesn't solve the
ability to use it
correctly. Right. And so
it still really
requires a domain expert
in order to be able to
use it correctly. Agreed.
Hey, we have two
male bait questions. We
do, but I only sing the
song once. Henry
Golding, who says, so
chaps, how long do you
think it will be before
data science becomes just
another tool in the
specializing generalist
box rather than a
separate thing you need
to spin up a big team of
specialists for, which I
think is a really
interesting question. I
will say, uh, my answer
for that is actually
pretty short. Um, it
ran. You have never had
a short answer for
anything in 46 episodes
of AB testing. I can't
wait. It will be a very
long time. The reason
why is, uh, data
scientists, uh, in the
tooling is advancing, but
the rate at which we're
acquiring tooling and
the rate at which we are
acquiring data science
is not keeping pace
with the rate at which
new data sources are
coming in and not keeping
pace with, with our need
to go deeper on data
science problems. So we
are currently just
scratching the surface and
we have a lot of
tooling. Um, but as more
and more data comes in,
we will have the need to
improve data engineering.
There's this sense that,
uh, at least in my world,
that there's a sense that
we're always six inches
just underneath the top
of the water. Yeah. I
think that you'll, it will
not go away and just
become a tool, but I
think it will become, I
think you'll always need
data scientists be pushing
the edge and to do the
more complicated things.
Um, for the primary
reason that the thought
processes of programming
and doing data science
are so different and the
knowledge bases are so
big that you can't keep
both of them. You cannot
be an expert in both at
the same time. That
said, I think that the
pieces of data science
will move more and more
easily into the basic
toolkit of your
generalizing specialists
and your specializing
generalists. Um, and so
they will be able to do
more and more parts of it,
but they won't be able to
do some of the more
advanced parts. And I
think what it defines an
advanced part and a
basic part will over
time, that boundary will
continue to move
forward. You know, it
used to be five years
ago, if you were data
science, you had to be a
PhD because you had to
go invent all your own
algorithms. If you
wanted to go, um, do, uh,
some deep learning, you
had to go invent your own
neural net and you had
to go know how a back
propagation worked and
all that kind of stuff.
Today, you just go and
use the package in
Python or a package in
R or you go to Azure
machine learning and
you just say like, please
train a neural net for me
with, you know, 18
levels go and it will
just do it for you. Now,
understanding what that
is doing and how to
tweak it is difficult,
but it's easier to go
do. And if I just want
to go figure out the
median for some values
or I want to go and
create like a simple
regression, it is very
easy to go do. And it
doesn't take a lot of
knowledge to be able to
go do the basic versions
of that. And that will
move over time up the
stack. Yes. And so what
we'll find is a lot of
that there'll be a
broadening that a lot of
the simple problems will
be readily automated
away. But to Henry's
question, there probably
will be, I don't know,
I'll just make up a
number five years from
now that the tooling
will exist that the
generalizing specialists
or specializing
generalists will be
able to solve 80% of
the problems. And there
will be environments
where solving 80% of
the problems is
sufficient. I think all
the years of today's
problems. But I think,
yeah, as always, you'll
get to more and more
complex problems as you
can solve the easy
problems. It will depend
on on the competitive
advantage like it. The
as right now we're all
competing on the basis
of speed in the world.
And I think once
everyone is kind of
going at the same pace,
then there's going to
be other things that
that are the
differentiator in the
market. And I think
that's where the deep
data scientists will
come into play. I think
you're both wrong. Not
totally wrong. I think
I think there's another
spin on it that I'll get
to before I run out of
time. I think both
happen. You guys are
talking right. I sit
back and listen. It's
like you're talking
like Microsoft data
scientists. But
remember, if I'm on a
team of 20 people
making some cool app,
absolutely. There's a
twist on Henry's
question. I need you're
not going to have a
data scientist on the
team probably in 20
people, maybe not even
40 people. But you
absolutely as part of
a team of specializing
judge generalizing
specialists, you need
someone with some data
science chops, someone
who's gone through a
couple of course, not a
man, an expert, not a
PhD for sure, but gone
through the course or
classes, you know, read
lean analytics. For
example, they have some
idea of what to do. This
is the role I play a
lot on my team. So I
can advocate a little
bit there is I am not a
data scientist. I know
enough about it that I
can tell them we're
doing stupid things or
where there's things
that were obviously
needed to be doing. We
are now ramping up with
some data science people
in the org to help cover
some of the things that I
can't get to. But I think
you need both. At some
point, you may need a
team of data scientists
we as you get bigger,
and you're making more
impact, you have more
data coming in. But
absolutely, I wouldn't
say I wouldn't say
there'll be a time when
I think the time when
data science needs to be
a tool in your toolbox
is now.
Right. I think the
time when it's only
tool in your toolbox,
and you don't have
specialists is a long
ways away.
But I think it's
becoming more and more
democratized.
There's a subtle
every year.
I think it becomes a
tool now. It'll be. And
so I want to make that
point. But I think
definitely it's probably
never just that,
especially, it'll
always be with scale,
but it'll always be
moving on. So I'll
invent another new term
today.
This is Brent's
continuing short answer.
Expert systems. So an
expert system is a new
newish asset in which
you apply data science,
automation, machine
learning, and you apply
in a rigorous fashion
domain knowledge from
particular teams.
And I will say, for
example, 60% of what I
do is analyzing
histograms. And there's
a very succinct period
or a rigor around how
I do that, what I
discover. And that's, I
would say, readily
automatable. Right.
So once an expert
system or something
similar comes into play
that can generate these
things, do the
if conditions determine
what further analysis
needs to be done and
then output, go do
this. This is what appears
to be the problem.
I think that's
certainly doable in the
next five years.
And there's tools that
are making it easier and
easier all the time. Like
the new version of
Excel has histograms built
in in a reasonable way,
which it never has had
before. Power BI is now
fairly democratized.
You know, there's other
platforms out there that
you can use to analyze
your data and get a lot
of sense for it just
from the beginning with
it with very easy tools
to use.
Very cool. Hey guys,
we're out of time.
Hey, thanks Steve, which
means shut up. Thanks
Steve for coming.
Yeah. I guess you just
showed up anyway.
It does. If I didn't
show up, you would
have been what?
As testing? What's that
ass testing?
You need me. All right,
then. All right, I'm
Alan. I'm Brent.
And I am neither.
Awesome. See you next
time. Bye guys.