Hey everybody! Howdy! I'm Allan. I'm Brent. And we're back for episode 30. Ocho. The Ocho.
30-Ocho, Tronte-Ocho. Did I just mix two languages? I was close enough.
Okay. Tronte-Ocho version 38. AB testing podcast. Did you say 20-Ocho? Tronte-Ocho?
Tronte-Ocho? I don't know. Tranta. Alright, take 2, just kidding. Yeah. We don't have
time for alternate takes. No. So how you been, Brent? You know, I am under
caffeinated today. How about you? I just took the lid off my coffee, which Brent
prepared for me by hand by hand. He pushed the buttons on the coffee machine,
let the brown liquid pour into the cup and then brought the cup to me with
loving care. Oh, it's awkward. Awkward. So, uh,
hey, should we do a podcast? Sure. But you know what? We kind of,
we almost don't need to do a podcast because you know what our good friend
Percy did for us. I do know what our good friend, we, we, we last just, uh,
two weeks ago on our last podcast, we, um, Percy had asked, Hey,
what about a one of the three slack channel and live on AB test? We said,
sure. And then there were three, then we had the, um,
we have one, one of the three dot slack.com. Yep. And although somebody
pointed out there are more than three people there, there are never more than
three there at once. I have very important to note. Yes. The, the,
the reality is we have three listeners and is it entirely irrelevant?
Any facts that you may have to the contrary. Whatever. All right.
You know what we're going to do because for our, for two of our listeners,
hold on. No, I don't know where you're going. I know you don't.
I'm not done with number two. All right. Okay,
Brett finish your number two and then we'll go on. Thank you.
So Percy, thanks for hooking that up. It's fantastic. Uh, we had,
we're having some great discussions on that off offline. Uh,
if for some sick twisted reason, you can't get enough of the podcast,
that's a good way to a good place to go to get additional content.
It's actually a good place to go and say,
what the hell did you guys mean when you said blah?
That does seem to be a common thing. Good for clarifying.
Uh, Percy, uh, his Twitter tag is at P E R
Z E that's P E R Z E for our listener north of the border.
Yes. Uh, he is sort of our self appointed administrator of this,
uh, Slack channel. If you want to join, you're welcome to just self-appointed.
I second his nomination and approved.
Absolutely second his nomination as well. Uh,
laziness will win almost always with me. If you want to join,
just direct message him in, in Twitter,
your email account and he'll hook you up. All right. Yeah.
Are we done with our PSA for one of the three dot slack.com?
We are this episode brought to you by Percy. Yeah.
We don't really have a sponsor. So now you know what we're going to do now.
What it's been a long time since we did this. What?
You know what a two baggers. Yes. In baseball to double, right? Right. Right.
Right. Today it is time for not one well timed.
Can you turn off your phone? Cheese. Not one, but two.
I think it's just one mail bag.
Oh, but two mail bag questions. Right. Two, two mail letter things.
Whatever. All right. So, uh, uh, the first one,
I guess you want to read it. Do you want me to read it to you so I can fix the
words you don't like yet? No, I got it. All right. It's from, uh,
this is the one from, uh, Nathan, right?
Known on the, uh, the slack channel as knit dog X.
Yeah. That's actually one thing I really am digging about the slack channel is
listeners are, are now putting their questions in one place.
So it's easy to find long gone are the five minutes we spent on the podcast
looking on LinkedIn or Twitter to find the question.
We'll still get some there. Yep. It's just,
it's just the loyal three that show up in the slack channel.
So Nitin says in a previous episode,
you mentioned how larger teams break up projects into seasons,
including the planning season or something. Uh,
just so that you know, we break them up into what we call semester.
So it's more of a, uh, university style, uh,
paradigm. Um, but continue on.
The VSTS team also mentioned this at build. To me,
it sounds pretty much the same as what Microsoft used to do with large waterfall
projects when seasons,
some S semester's were just called milestones.
How are seasons semesters and whatever other ways projects are split up time
boxed different than milestones.
That's a great question and I want to hear a great answer, Brent.
What do you got? Um, nothing, right? The,
the reality is I'm putting on my best Microsoft manager hat.
I'm getting out my best puke bucket. Right. The, the,
the reality is the difference between a semester and a milestone at the end of
a semester, we expect full features to be shipped.
So the biggest difference, um, is just simply time compression.
So what used to happen in three years now happens in six months.
Uh, on how it is rolled out,
it really does depend on the team.
So some teams basically turn it into a mini waterfall model where the starting
in completes in six months. Others, other teams, um,
uh, take a different approach and a much more agile approach,
which essentially you start with a planning milestone.
The planning milestone is a planning milestone or planning semester.
It's not a planning summit. There is no planning semester.
He explicitly asked for that. There is no planning semester.
So when I worked on windows seven, for example,
we did six months pure planning before,
um, we started working on the code.
Thank you Steven Sanofsky for really emphasizing the power of waterfall.
Yeah. Yeah.
Didn't you follow that was six months of coding followed by 12 months of
stabilization. Uh, I think,
I think windows seven was a three year might've been whatever,
whatever, but yeah. And then, uh,
six months of DCR and I'm going to interrupt because I'm not hearing a lot of
differentiation between a milestone and a semester.
I think these are like some teams treated like a milestone teams that are more
agile, treat it more like a,
that the difference is is that in milestones,
you just be a check mark on the way to make sure some stuff was kind of mostly
done and kind of working so you could maybe deliver it to some partners or
beta customers, et cetera. And you're saying in semesters,
what the good teams do is make sure that instead of having a bunch of
the half done features, you have fewer fuller done features.
But is that it otherwise it's just two, two labels for, to me,
it's two labels to the same thing. It's how you approach the end.
The yes and no. So when I think of milestones, um,
the milestone model and a waterfall thing,
I think of things like test complete and co-complete and UI freeze
and all these sort of, uh,
alpha date, beta date,
all of these sort of intermittent dates that we would put in the old waterfall
process that were sort of checkpoints as you're talking about. Um,
the way, for example, my team does, does planning and,
and just want to be super clear, there is no planning semester anymore.
There the planning is expected to,
to be sort of the, the two to three weeks before the start of the milestone.
Is it, wait, you keep on saying milestone, but is it a milestone or semester?
Semester. So you are nailing down the fact that these are kind of the same.
One way to look at it is that it's just a,
a name replacement and I agree that you can look at it.
Milestone implies, um,
kind of like when you're driving, like here's,
here's a check that we've made on a way to something. Okay.
This is not that this, the,
what a semester is you start off a semester doing some lightweight planning that
says, this is our North star. This is our vision for the end of semester.
So planning's purpose in life is guidance.
Okay. So I get it. And, and to be clear to the listeners,
I am not playing devil's advocate here entirely because I have never,
I for one have never been on a project at Microsoft that used semesters.
Yes. That term.
So you're saying that I think the difference is like,
I kind of go way back to windows 95 and like,
I want to think the oldest waterfall project I've been on,
but it had milestones and like every even numbered milestone was a beta release,
but there were really just sort of checkpoints and planning things like by M seven,
we expect these features to be in M eight will be beta two M nine is when we
finish up this, there was sort of a theme, uh, for maybe for each milestone.
But with semesters, it's like, here's what we're going to do for the next,
is it six months? Is it drew six months?
So here are the guiding principles for the next six months.
And that's a semester. And then you,
then you do some lightweight planning and do your work. Yep. So,
so the really, so you're agreeing. So I'm saying they're,
they're not the same, but highly similar.
They kind of accomplish similar goals, right? The,
the biggest difference in the,
and say the waterfall model is here in the waterfall model, these milestones were,
were really about showing progress towards the,
the, the ultimate shipping division. Whereas semesters,
it's not about showing project or progress. It's about shipping stuff.
Right. Um, the six months,
its whole purpose in life is to,
to have a cadence with upper management to see if we need to do things like,
uh, minor reorgs or minor shuffling to,
to reallocate towards what we know at that time is a better business
direction.
So the one key difference between say the semester model and the waterfall
milestone based model, the mile, the waterfall model,
what I from my experience,
the key vision for the goal rarely changed dramatically.
Yeah. And to be clear, it does. Yeah.
It's a lot of semantics here because milestones don't imply waterfall.
We associate them with our past as a waterfallish thing.
I believe in that's correct. Right. Um,
I'm kind of mapping it because I view this because he, his Nitten asked, Hey,
Microsoft used to blah, blah, blah.
So I'm kind of viewing it from my perspective in terms of how milestones were
managed back in the day.
Yes. And that's kind of what I'm doing too.
But I think you could treat milestones very much like you're treating
semesters today.
And I could also see a way that a engineering team could treat semesters very
much as we used to use milestones back in the day.
What I see, well, so, and then in, in that context,
so I can snap to your definition, what loosely are you calling a milestone?
What, what is a milestone in your mind? Um,
a milestone is a point in time,
which could be six months.
It could be another amount of time where we expect to have,
where we align towards a goal.
We align towards a goal that we think will occur on or around a certain date.
For example, a product may say, we may have a milestone.
We may have a public beta milestone and you know, in, in month,
you know, in January, we're going to have a public beta in, uh,
or a small, we'll call a small public beta in January.
That's our January milestone. Then in March,
we're going to have a expanded public beta. Um,
and then that can, we'll call that a milestone and we have things we need to
do around that. So there's some,
there's some rallying cries need to happen around that.
So if you're, if you're like, I'm just, this is not my product, but say I'm making
a, um, uh, app for iPhone and I'm doing my public beta,
there's things I have to do. Okay. Working back from that milestone,
I got to have the,
an account set up in the app store to make sure I can get that uploaded. Um,
I have to look at all the requirements for that and make sure I have work on
it, make sure that all those are done beforehand,
make sure I have ways to get feedback from my customers that I trust.
There's, there's a bunch of stuff we need to rally around for that milestone.
So those are the features that have to be done. And then as we go wider,
there's, there's other things that come into place.
I'm not going to list them all out, but if I have a goal,
a target for date and date, you know,
date M and date L or whatever, uh,
I can rally my work around that to make sure I'm prepared for that milestone.
So with that definition in mind, um, then there's,
there is a, I'll do an attempt at an important distinction because the way you
described it was in essence,
we have this sort of tactical goal and the purpose of milestones is to
synchronize the entire organization towards that goal.
I, I, I figured that out a little bit as I went along. So it doesn't,
it's not waterfall. It doesn't need to be,
we need to rally around some dates,
but the semester is not this is like at the end of the six months,
we're going to ship blah to N number of customers. It is the vision and our
strategy, our principles for the next six months are this is how we're going to
work. And then at the end of six months, we're going to stop reflect.
It's kind of like a, it's kind of like a macro retrospective. Yes.
You're going to stop and look back, see what you learn, what did we go?
What has changed in the marketplace since then?
Cause the six months changes a lot. Let's re-strategize,
let's adjust and then set a goal for the next six months. Yes.
So a semester. So I'm learning,
I'm this is actually me learning as we go through this. So now.
I'm sure it's so it will, much like in the definition you can talk about,
it will have goals enumerated,
but those goals will be in terms of customer outcomes delivered the versus the
milestone model, right?
Ultimately there's this customer outcome we want for the RTM and in a
waterfall model or a milestone model.
And these many milestones in between is about creating synchronization to get
the whole organization at the same place at the same time.
So we can move forward. That is not what happens in a semester. No, I get it.
Now what happens in a semester? Now I'm responding to Nitten.
What happens in a semester. Who cares about him? I get it. Fine.
What happens at the semester is so one important distinction between a
waterfall and semester model is that you do not expect nor do you generally
see all of the features delivered in the last month of a semester.
Yeah.
So you see them continuously delivered throughout the semester.
But the, the goals are customer outcomes desired.
Okay. I, you lost me a little,
I think you're a lot of times in the conversation is kind of set your in your
head. I think you see milestones, waterfall, semesters, agile.
And I don't know if you actually think that it's coming,
it's coming out in the way you explain it where I think it's sure,
where I don't think it's, it doesn't have to be the case.
It doesn't have to be the case. So,
so all of my present experience in a semester model,
it has been on service teams and a service team doing,
so I may be associating semesters service and agile all kind of lumped in
together, right?
But the whole point of a semester is to,
to generate new North stars every six months and to create a
synchronization point with management so that we can redirect towards the most.
In a way, when you compare even some people say six months, that's forever.
But if you look at some of the traditional three year shipping cycles,
a lot of Microsoft products,
one of those office had years ago and both of those ship more often now.
But if you look at how often they used to ship, you know,
actually stopping and changing direction every six months,
that would have been disastrous. Right? They couldn't,
the Sanofsky version of windows couldn't have even executed that.
Yeah. Let's decide what customers want three years from now and we'll give,
and we'll make that for them. And you know,
stupid customers that keep deciding the wrong things. I know.
Can you believe that they decide, oh, we don't, they say,
we don't like this. And I say, well, you're wrong. Right. Okay.
Nevermind. So I get it.
So if I got it didn't smarter than me. So I hope he got it too.
All right. We'll find out shortly. All right. All right.
Do you want to go on another mail bag? The next mail bag? Can I,
can I read this one? You please. Cause I read better than you. You do.
That was in, I know it was in the Slack channel somewhere.
What don't you do better than me, Alan? Seriously. Yeah. All right.
So, um, our, our good friend of the show,
Mr. Steve row, got that rhyme there. Yes. Yeah. Way to go.
Steve row from Microsoft. Way to go. He said, here's a question for your,
and he put it in capital letters, mail bag.
You have a lot, like lots of A's there, but he didn't do that. All right.
He said in a recent episode, and this is a whole new topic.
We should have had a commercial break there,
but we don't have any sponsors other than perzy and slack. All right.
In a recent episode, you mentioned that you were against V teams. However,
you also stated that you thought people should be coached and managed by people
who weren't necessarily the owner of the features they were working on.
And I'll elaborate on both of these in a second. That was me saying that, uh,
this sounds a little like a V team hypocrite for some uses of that word.
Can you explain the difference between what you do and what you do not want?
Um, lots of things. I mean,
let me do a even more annotated version of this. Um, yes, I,
in for the most part,
I don't like the way Microsoft has traditionally done V teams,
uh, which is let's get a team together that meets perpetually.
And yeah,
forever and with no stated outcomes,
they just get together and they, they, some stuff happens.
Some of those napkin.
Some people are in the V team because they want to be informed something like
a 10th or less stuff like wicked, like, uh, uh,
contribute to Wikipedia. It's like 1% actually do the work. Uh,
so that's the kind of V team I'm against. Um, and I,
is it however you stated that people should be coached and managed by people who
weren't necessarily the owners of the features they were working on.
Meaning I think, uh, even my team today,
uh, for the most part,
we have one manager as kind of risen above this traditional Microsoft
bucketing where a manager owns a feature area. We own this.
And I kind of liked the idea of a manager owns managing and coaching about
10 to 16 people. And, uh,
they work on what's important and there's a lot of fluidity. And of course,
there's expertise on the team and some,
some managers may take on particular types of work more than others,
but I really think that, uh,
you don't necessarily need to own a feature area on a single group of people,
uh, where that's really backfires.
That you see in some orgs that rhyme with Lindos, uh,
you see teams of a manager with three people and each of those has two people
reporting to them because it's they,
they've structured the exact like almost down to the detailed UI of the
product down to teams.
And, and structured the organization that way,
which I think adds so much overhead, uh, that it can hinder progress.
And again, windows is a big org. I'm sorry,
Lindos rhymes with Lindos could be windows. I don't know. Um,
doesn't work that way across the org.
Not making fun of Steve who works in windows.
I think his org is actually much flatter than other parts,
but it's just dry. See the, uh, the, the biggest offenders of that.
So anyway, um, I prefer larger teams.
That can be fluid and take on a different work. So those are different to me.
Those are different things. Let me address.
Brent is being very, very patient with me.
Uh, let me talk about the kind of V team I like,
cause I've already elaborated on what I mean by sort of the,
the team that's coached the manager is the coach and the, and the,
and the grower and the, and the manager of these teams.
I don't think you've defended yourself against
the accusation of hypocrisy.
So I think these are two different things. Okay. So, uh,
I will go back to the, the manager one if you want,
I think I've covered it,
but let me talk about the V teams that I do like.
And I know I've mentioned it on the podcast before,
but I'll bring it up again, which was,
which is what I like to call the world of Warcraft guide to project
management, which is in world of Warcraft, you,
and in many other, uh, sort of multiplayer role-playing games,
you, a group gets together to take on a common cause to do a
quest. You share the rewards,
which can be treasure or recognition.
And then you either take on another quest or disband.
That is how I think V teams should work.
A group of people should get together that have complimentary skills.
They may be project management, maybe technical, whatever.
They solve a particular problem. They,
the first thing a V team does is what problem are we solving?
They work till that problem solved. And then they either say,
do we have another problem we can solve together? And if so,
take that on, or they disband and go back to their jobs.
They don't meet forever and ever and have the 90% of the group be
informed. It's a group that gets together. They have,
they all work together towards a common goal.
And then they move on and take on other work or, or,
or another project together. That's the sort of V team I like.
As do I.
Not the traditional at Microsoft. Uh,
let's just get a team of way,
of way too many people together and you know, quote,
share information and talk and not really get anything done.
So one of the things that I think Steve is, is saying,
like in his mind, from implication, from his question,
in his mind, um,
people being coached by someone that is not their manager,
seems in his mind is the functional equivalent of a V team.
He's like, what's the diff? Oh,
and honestly I think the difference is like in your world,
a Warcraft model,
whoever spontaneously gets appointed the,
the leader of the quest,
isn't necessarily a people coach, right? Right.
Their job is to, to project manage for lack of a better word
towards the goal. Right. Um,
that's what I think is the primary difference.
Right. So there are, um,
I think he's reflecting upon different leadership models.
So you got the V team model where,
where you do kind of need leadership.
Otherwise you have a bunch of people running around, right?
You have to have something that pulls them into it.
Even the bad V teams I've seen have a leader,
but it's important that the leader, uh,
actually leads the group and doesn't just schedule their meetings.
Yeah. I've seen,
I've seen like the most horrible V teams I've seen is where the leader schedules
the meetings and because he's a leader, he's accountable.
Everyone else says, Hey, I'm, I am on this other thing.
I have a higher priority and so therefore only the leader does the work.
And so now he's scheduling a bunch of meetings and doing the
work himself. Um,
again, I think a good V team has to have everyone invested in the outcome.
So the first thing you do a good V team is what are we going to solve?
And often I've seen V teams meet and talk about the problem and realize,
in fact, I was on one last week where, um, I won't go into details, but
last week where watching Brent, uh,
answer his phone during the podcast. Hello.
So I met with the V team last week.
So here's what we got to do. And I, and I joined the V team late, uh, a week late.
And, uh, there was, they had a goal. Here's what we need to do.
And I said, can you just do this? And they looked at it and said,
yes. And I guess we don't need to meet anymore. So the, the,
if you find the solution that quick or sometimes even in discussion,
it would have been that the first week would have lasted even less long.
But sometimes if you, if getting that goal is key,
sometimes in discussion of the goal, you just,
you realize that you don't need to do anything. There's already an answer.
Yes. So, and that's, uh, many V teams would go, well, what else?
Immediately like, like, well now what do we do?
We should keep meeting and talk about this. But anyway, yeah, no, that's all
right. I think I've made my point about V teams. I like in V teams. I don't
like, uh, you were going somewhere with the parallels and,
and with leadership. Well, so what's your,
what's your view in terms of what you expect? So his last question, what do you,
what do you expect or what's the difference between what you do and
do not want as it relates to both the
topics of V teams and people being coached.
Okay. With V teams, what I do want is just to summarize,
what I do want is a team that works together towards a common goal and
then either disbands or takes on another goal.
What I do not want is a team that just gets together and, and meets and does
nothing. Yes. As far as managing a team, uh,
sort of the way I prefer, although I don't live in that world entirely,
I think people managers, what I, what I want to see,
I love the way you phrase that so I can focus my answer. Uh,
what I do want to see is people managers who aren't in love with owning a
particular feature set and structuring their team around that.
And instead have a group of people that want to leverage their strengths to get
whatever work done.
They can that comes their way that makes sense in the context of their product.
Meaning cause I saw, I saw confusion in Brent's eyes. Right. Uh,
I have horse.
So what I do want is say I'm a manager of a team of 10 people.
And we, we have some expertise in shimmery blue menus. Uh,
but we also have other things we can do.
And then my job as a manager is to know all the strengths and also growth areas
for my team. So rather than have us take on all the work and feature X,
I very much like the model of it's Kanban like my team will take on like it
isn't just our Kanban there's there could, there's maybe we're not,
there's I have five peer managers.
So there's 50 of us together and with our teams of 10 and we can go to the team
Kanban and take on work and we may take on likely we'll take on most of the
shimmery blue menu work because that's where our expertise is.
But it doesn't mean we can't dive in elsewhere as that work becomes more
important. And in fact, uh,
we may be so far ahead on shimmery blue menus that there may not be any
more shimmery blue menu work to do.
So traditionally what a team could do would be to invest in enhancing shimmery
blue menus even more,
but that's not the most important thing to work on the products.
I want my team build to take on, uh, whatever is fits our expertise.
That's in that stuff that needs to be done to the high priority stuff.
So I'd rather look at that sort of team backlog and take on what's most
important and have my team be able to take that on versus a sticking and
uh, working on a particular area, even when that area may be done.
Um, that takes care of a couple of things. As you know, uh, see my team sucks.
Your team sucks.
Well, yeah, they do. So we're awful.
I have a bunch of junior people and I took some hand me downs and they're not
performing very well. Uh, what it could happen if I just own my feature area,
it's probably going to suck and, and we can work on that.
But as I'm working on my team, getting them better, making them suck less,
uh, we're going to work slower through items rather than have my whole area be
behind. If we're working from a team, Conbon or a team, you know,
some sort of poll system from a team level, we're going to be taking items.
I think, okay, this is,
these are some good items for our team and we're going to work on those.
And we're going to be a little bit slower, but they're going to get done.
And your team rocks. Your team is like superstars. They're just like, Oh,
I eat code for breakfast, lunch, and dinner. And they take some,
they're with quality of course. And you're taking items from the,
from the backlog and cranking them out and,
and moving them across the board.
And what happens is your solid teams take on the high priority items and the high
risk items, um, and work through them quickly.
And the teams that are learning, uh, can take other items still need to be done,
still important. Uh, and those get done.
And what happens is the whole product actually gets done in this model and is
of high quality, uh, much more often than in the traditional model where you have
some features that are overdeveloped and have too many shimmers in their blue
menus and versus, uh, and then you have like the team that was slow or some
people quit or whatever. And, and that whole feature is behind and sucks.
So that's why I like the fluidity of a model like this is cause it allows you
to work in a system like that.
Do you think Steve's question was no,
but I just was on a soapbox.
Fair enough.
So I, I come, this is, this is the AB testing.
We're not about answering the question directly. It's inspiration.
We haven't, Steve, you're my muse. Right. There you go. Um,
I take your question and go ahead and answer whichever one I feel like you
should have asked instead.
That sounds like a politician. Yeah.
Oh my God. Speaking of which,
I should, I should have phrased the answer is Steve,
let me tell you about my good friend, Henrietta Higgins one time.
All right. Um, I want to make AB testing great again.
Speaking of which, aren't you doing that sometime soon? What?
You're winter, uh, talk on AB testing. Um,
I actually finished my slides and everything. Yeah. Um, uh,
it's going to be in June. I also have a talk, um, next week,
the slides are, believe it or not started, but not done. Uh,
next week I'll be in Seattle at a Cordov in, uh, uh,
where is Cordov near the U district ish, revenge. Now I have to,
now I have to remember, maybe they moved. I should look before I go.
At a secret location somewhere in Seattle. Right. Oh my.
Um, so, okay, back to the,
really.
So there's two things I,
so I completely agree with the project model that the only thing I would state
differently is, um, for me,
it's not about importance, uh, going back to semantics.
Um, it's a, because words have meanings. Yes.
All right. Do I just want to say that. Um, it's about ROI.
So in, in the world where, uh, let's say there is a master
Kanban board and teams go and select from the master Kanban board
and that world, then what I want to do is sort of
pick the,
the highest ROI that I think that my team
can close on within the,
in a reasonable window of opportunity. Obviously,
if my team can't execute it and there's a tight window of opportunity,
my team shouldn't take this one. Um,
but I also want to look at the ROI for the team itself. So, uh,
in some teams and right now my team is,
is kind of in this place where we're really good at
executing and adapting and even picking up things that we don't
understand. So I just like, Hey,
whatever the highest ROI is, that's all I want.
And that's fine. That's cause that's about learning.
It's not about just like picking like the easy,
like I don't feel like my team's very good. I want to pick the easy work as a
manager. It's your job to give your team, yeah, the highest,
the most difficult work they can actually accomplish. And that's,
but that's true for growth, right?
Always put yourself on the steepest learning curve is the way you get better
as a steepest learning curve you can handle. Yes.
Right. Yeah. And if you're a little bit underwater, like,
I love being on the project where I'm not quite sure what I'm doing.
Cause eventually I know I can figure it out and you want to challenge your team
to do that. So it becomes, this is the,
a big difference is it requires a good manager to do this or a good people
manager. Uh,
Microsoft has a lot of managers who are good at the project management.
I own graphics. So my team does graphic stuff versus,
uh, and, and that's very much a sort of a project manager kind of role. Um,
where I want to see more managers who are the people,
managers and coaches who look across their team can figure out, okay,
I know the skills of everyone on our team and how they compliment and where
our holes are. So here's the, this knowing that's some work we can take on,
where I don't think a lot of managers, I'll say at Microsoft,
but also a lot of managers period necessarily know how to do that.
I think a lot of software managers are pure project managers and turn the crank,
what I call the traditional, uh,
turn the crank manager versus someone who actually knows how to
coach a team. And I would prefer,
organization of managers who knew how to coach their teams and grow their teams
versus just project manage.
I even would take it one step further. Cause in my view, you gotta,
if you're going to be,
if you're going to be an environment where you as a manager owns your project and
your team, right? Not sort of the models we talked about earlier,
where perhaps, uh, the,
the person you report to is solely responsible for people growth.
And maybe they're sort of these virtual scrum teams that are formed up that,
that drive through the project. Right. Um,
if you're going to be a manager that owns both,
then the way I view it is my responsibility is to grow my business. Okay.
So that means the value outputted by my team and my team's ability to scale,
to, to accomplish and pick up new,
the next set of value, the, um,
where was I going with this story? Who knows?
The in,
by taking this sort of point of view,
what that means is I'm,
I'm going after what is the most valuable thing.
And I'm also trying to reduce the cost to deliver,
right? So it's not just it's,
it's how do I deliver great projects and grow my team,
not one or the other. I, but,
I think, but there's another thing I want,
I want you to think about because this is something I've started,
I started writing a blog on this. Um,
probably we'll post it this weekend. Um, but one thing,
let's, let's take an aside for a moment. Cause there's also this product. Um,
sorry, you talked about the managers versus the leaders,
which in my mind is the project managers versus the people managers.
Maybe. So let's talk about goals.
Like one of the things I see a lot from these project manager types is this focus
on efficiency. And I'm curious,
do you see a difference between productivity and efficiency? Yes.
Okay. What is it?
Which one's more important if you can't have both?
I think you're preaching to the choir here.
I think productivity is more important. Okay. What is it?
Productivity is, uh,
how easy it is for me to get my work done. Okay.
Um, so it's simplification in some cases. Um,
whereas efficiency is, uh, how do I describe efficiency?
How would you describe efficiency?
So the way I described the two productivity is,
uh, how long, how,
essentially per a unit of time,
how many units of value can you ship? So product,
so if you think of productivity, like an assembly line,
if we are all working on cars, productivity, it last week,
we, we, we built two cars a day. This week, we built five cars a day.
We are more productive this week.
Efficiency is how,
what percent of your individual time is allocated?
Are you, um,
a hundred percent of your time working on something versus sitting around
waiting. The,
a lot of the times what I see is these project managers. Um,
this, this kind of goes into again, the assembly line. So on a,
on an assembly line model,
if I had a team of people who only know how to do one thing,
then I need to funnel work to,
to that person so that they're a hundred percent utilized.
But now if you, what'd you call it? The shimmery blue,
shimmery blue menus, my shimmery blue menus,
my standard answer for a standard example for anything.
So if you have one guy in your team that, um,
is the master of shimmery blue, right click menus,
and another guy on the team is master of shimmery blue buttons.
Um,
how do you rearrange the work so you can take advantage of these guys's
expertise? That's the other thing that I see these,
these project manager guys do because they, because they're like, Hey,
I can only take off of the backlog because I'm focused on efficiency of my guys.
I can only actually take the,
the item stacked 2050 that's that that's the only thing my guys can do because
it's inefficient for them to learn something new.
Yeah. Well, that's just stupid. Right. So I, you,
you were on a long diatribe rant, something there. Uh,
I want to go back to a point you made about, um, an hour and a half ago where,
uh, you, you're talking about, you have what you could have, uh,
now I can't remember. You said you want, um,
you want to grow your team or like, was it make a good grow your team or have a
good product or something? If you have a manage, so reflect,
refresh me on that. So I tell you you're wrong.
So if you are in an environment where you as a manager,
simultaneously are responsible for a team and a project or a set of features,
right? The, it's two separate things.
So that that's far enough because I am a firm believer, um,
both in concept and in practice that by building a strong team,
you will build a good product completely agree.
So I think you can over index on one.
You can't just lose sight of the other.
You got to make sure you give them the right work.
But I think if you have a great team, um, and not just that you've,
you've hired superstars, you've, uh,
a good manager can take a bunch of misfits and, uh,
get them to work together and enjoy their work and find their strengths and get
them and, and make a good product as well.
The great products come from great teams. You, I,
I think a great product built by a bunch of shit heads is, uh,
oops, PG ready. Just went up, um,
is not completely impossible, but nearly impossible.
Uh, it happens, right? The,
the law of probability say is if,
as long as it's non-zero given infinite time, it's going to occur.
Anyway, the point, the point I wanted to make there is please,
as manager, start by building that great team, the,
okay, there was stuff I wanted to get to, but we have like,
we have like three minutes left. So
I completely agree in terms of starting by building a great team, right? The,
the, if you can pick only one thing to
do and that's business value or establish
get earn the trust of your employees
and inspire the intertrust
between them. Um, working on that,
that trust I would say is more important than working on the business
file.
I completely agree. And there's, um,
I'm going to use some of the time and talk about that because, uh,
with trust, um, trust is the, is the basis.
It's like the base of the pyramid because with that, then with that,
can you can have,
if I don't trust you and I have a conflict with you or heated discussion with
you, uh, it's very easy for me to take that personally and,
or, and, and do you have an effect to my work?
Cause like, I don't want to argue with Brent again,
but with trust we can talk about whether we can have a
argument about the best way to implement shimmery blue menus.
And at the end of it,
we don't dislike each other any less cause we have trust in our
relationship. And at the end,
what we probably have is a better design than we would have had if we were
just passive, kind of like, okay, whatever you want to do is fine.
Trust in, in, in this trust is the basis for, for a conflict and conflict.
I don't think it's necessarily bad when you have trust behind it.
It's actually very good when you have trust behind it.
Cause that's where good, the good things come out of those conflicted
discussions.
So negotiations, arguments, debates, whatever you want to call them. It doesn't,
it doesn't matter to me,
but trust makes an important distinction
between are you arguing about who's
right or what's right?
Yes. That's a good way to put that. Yeah. Congratulations. Thank you.
That's a very good point. I think we should close on that one.
Fair enough. All right. Uh, I'm still Allen.
And I'm not. We'll see you next time. Thank you. Bye.