Hey, howdy
From do a podcast sure. All right. Hey everybody gets Alan is Brent and we're here for episode
45 45 of a be testing
I was just thinking I thought 45 and just at this moment thought of like the kids listening today won't remember these but 45 records. Oh
Man the records like a CD but it's made of vinyl and they had a big hole in the middle and they played at 45
revolutions per minute and if you didn't have the freaking adapter
You couldn't play your 45. Yeah, I have it. I still have adapters. I'm sure you do
You're much more of an audiophile than I am. Yeah, I still have 45s
I'm sitting around I have about 700 CDs
Sitting underneath my bed wondering
What I should do with those so I have this I have like this pile of 45s a lot of them are collectibles
He's to get like these collectible import 45s
But I also have buried in there like a Van Halen dance the night away
45 that's pretty cool. I
Have all of the Van Halen stuff. That's great up until they
Changed to Van Hagar, which I was anti Van Hagar. I don't care Brett. Okay, then. All right then so
Shall we begin on?
our last episode
There's we don't have a recap because we don't have I don't know about you
I don't have retention beyond about 15 minutes. So I don't know we talked about last time but it was something around
How to become data-driven and I feel like we got a great start
But that maybe there's more we could talk about so I like to continue that topic if you don't mind
I've written on the whiteboard
pew
Ww. L. Oh, what's your thing means pick up where we left off
You want to start with the second one? No
Really?
Okay, cuz I can't it's too early in the morning for me to do the song
Later, that's a teaser
Later
alright, so
last time last time on episode 44
shots
we covered as Alan just called out how to
begin this journey and we
We addressed it by talking about
essentially
Leveraging the strengths of your team right now
beginning the journey and
We spent a good amount of time
talking around how to kind of clear the way by
connecting with your executive
Um
here I
started I am
Looked over our show notes. I actually relistened to the episode
We have lots of great questions and comments up on the slack channel one of the three dot slack calm. Yes
Actually it occurred to me as well we have a
listener who up on Twitter is very actively
Stating what episode he's up to and he's like up to 24 and
He was asking a whole bunch of questions and I'm like, why don't you just go to the slack channel?
And I realized oh if he's up on 24, he doesn't know the slack channel exists
Maybe we should add that on the eB testing. It's it's kind of a time paradox
Thing right it is. Are you giving me web administration tips?
Requests all right, maybe I can do that
I'm taking volunteer webmasters as well
Maybe Percy will sure
alright, so I was thinking about it and
one of the least useful things that I did over the weekend is
Lots of
Catching up on Xbox and those connections hit and it it
It occurred to me that really what we're sort of talking about is not
Unlike a tech tree from any game you've ever played ever
where what you're trying to do is
Master a particular skill and then when you have enough
Experience points enough mastery or experience points right then the next
Element of the tree opens up in general
Some questions I
Thought about is as you're pursuing
What exactly are you building? So what I don't mean the product here, but I mean the
the assets that you're putting together to be able to
Do data analysis
That of course leads into what are you're measuring
Another thought you need to think about is where does your team grow?
its competency next
Right. So let me just recap here. So you have I remember the steps are data oblivious, right? Then date was a data aware
That's the one I added in between there's data oblivious then what happens next data oblivious data aware
We'll go ahead and go with that
Then there's data driven then data centric. Okay, so
One of the techniques I like to help map out my tech tree
I like that is I
describe my
Current state how my team works today my desired state and then I know there's like 150 different paths to get there
Which is your tech tree? I like that analogy
So could you take a few minutes and describe what is the desired state if you are a data centric team?
Firing on all cylinders. Tell me what that looks like because I think a lot of people have a hard time imagining that
data centric team
first and foremost
Has a dependency on on the data. So the the one high order bit is
People feel like if they don't have the data
They can't move forward
Right. So there is that dependency that you can
You can use to detect
number two
In a data centric team
Most organizations have lots and lots of data you have
billing data you have customer data you have operations data you have a
Factory data and what I mean by that is how well you're able to ship a new product
You'll have all of this data and I'm barely touching on okay, so I have a bunch of data and I'm dependent on it
You'll have all of this data
Integrated in some fashion such that
There's a term called SSBI which stands for self-service bi and what that means is a
person who
doesn't have statistics or data science skills is able to consume the data and
Confidently and competently make 80% of the decisions with that data on their own
Okay, so the data has been integrated has been cure curated and simplified
Such that you can light that up so to paraphrase so far again because you use more words than I would
I'm dependent on the data. I have a lot of it and it's
Available in a format that could be consumed by anyone on the team consumed and acted upon. Yeah
What else is that it?
Confidently as well that because one of the problems with the data is
formulas
and and to tangentialize that a word to
Tangent we've made up words here before why not really we have tons
Now I forgot what I was gonna say
It's Tuesday morning after a long weekend ah and the kids are back in school rough life first world problem. Um
So
The tangent was that's important because I've seen so many over the last 20
Some odd years of being in software people
Using what he called confirmation bias look at the data and make it and make it say what they want
What they want it to say versus being able to use the data to make actual competent decisions that actually are true. It's like
years ago, I
Went to a leadership class and they gave me a definition of empowerment that I'm rather fond of which is
When you empower people
You are expressing a confidence in those people to make the same decisions
You would in your absence
Awesome if they had the same
Information okay, so you can think of it here is sort of data empowerment
So you in that world you're setting people up to be able to make the same
analyses as a data science team would in the data science teams absence
So let me modify my paraphrase. So we have a lot of data and I depend on it and
the data is
consumable in such a way that anyone on the team can make
Make similar decisions based on that data. Yes
Anything else to it the the last one that's
The next
Three things that I would say are that are critical number one
Generally when you start this journey, you're gonna be working against what's known as cold path data and cold path data means
It takes a while before the data itself
Yep, I get that you kind of back into the how you get there
But I want to I want to make sure I understand what the desired state is. Are we done with the desired state is
near real time
real near real time hot path hot path a lot of
Action ability and decision makings is
Automated so you have things like machine learning algorithms or you have that's more the how
We can get there
I want to make sure I have a good decision that I can out because I really for me being able to describe this
Desired state of where you want to go and sort of an elevator pitch
I think I think any leadership over any change requires being able to articulate exactly where you're going and it's an adaptive problem
Meaning we don't know exactly
How we're going to get there or if or if the actual desired state is going to change
slightly or more that or
more dramatically over time
But we want to have being able to articulate that goal being able to tell people whether it's an executive for
bought enough for
Didn't want a drink for
Whether it's anybody on the team just to explain kind of where you're going so
We could talk about I love the idea of warm path hot path cold path
I want to talk about those I used one time a Microsoft history called fast path and slow path
But I like the terms warm hot and cold much better. He explained what those are in a minute. Yep
But if I can I have a bunch of data that I depend on or to do our job and everybody on the team has
a way to consume that data in order makes the same decisions no matter who they are and
Those decisions are and then that data that we get is as close to real time as possible
That's a great state to be in yes
I rely on this data coming in in real time like I know right away when something's going on and I can make the decision
You can make the decision just down the hall can make the decision
Cindy upstairs to make the same decision because that data is easily consumable and interpretable
The last constraint or the last just when I thought I'd get it nailed you add more crap
There's one more. I said three start when well, you can't count
the last one is
event driven responses
So a lot of analytics will be when you first start off it will be everything's get pumped to a data store
and
It relies on a human to go in and do queries and say hey
Oh look something happened two weeks ago
Here in this world not only do you have?
NRT or hot path, but you're going to have
Event driven
situations where
Customer just did this and that kicked off on its own a whole new analytics
Path I'm gonna put that in the close to real-time umbrella fair enough
So I have to modify and once again try and restate my desired stuff and you did a very good job
Okay
No, I get and and what the things we're doing here and what I do in branch starts talking about either
One he's talking about stuff. I don't fully understand or two. He just doesn't make any sense regardless
I try and paraphrase parrot it back to him. So I'm going to make sure I understand things good technique to use
I'm sure all the all the three know how to do this
But you kind of make sure I'm in the right ballpark and it's it's useful for the three as well since
They're at least two days delayed on their ability to ask me questions
Are you making fun of my ability to get the podcast edited and out?
No, maybe sometimes do sometimes a whole week
All right, it depends how much it depends on how much of your idiot stuff and coughing I
Have to edit out. So what Alan just walked through?
Seems like 10 minutes ago is
How do you know if when you've got there we've already established Brent can't tell time the oh
That was before knowing the North Star knowing the North Star can be
helpful
I don't like the term North Star. I'm gonna stick with desired state. I like current state desired state path
I'm just gonna pick on everything you say for while till I feel better about myself
That shouldn't take long
Might take a long long time
So you're trying to understand what do we desired state, okay
And that frames it up nicely
One of the things from my experience though that if you do
in I would say 70% of the time
expressing the full richness of the desired state
When you are in a data oblivious team is a bozo bit flip flipping moment
That is
So far out there
People can't can't really visualize how to get there from where they are at
So I recommend a strategy
Around hey those who are the leaders who are pulling together this this strategy
don't go so far out of the box that you lose the attention of
What you hope to be your future customers
Instead do around the box thinking which is
Kind of what we've been talking about. It's
Establish where you are today and what is the next useful step?
That moves towards this this long-term
Direction and that's that's how my exercise of current state desired state works is you don't it's always a
multi-step
Path to get from current to desired and desired changes as you go along the way which isn't to say if people ask you
What's what's your desired state and I am totally okay if I give them an answer and they look at me like I have two heads
Right because I can move them gradually in that direction. I've done this before and they get there and they go, holy
Heck the other thing to to assure them is
that
They are not going to get their value only once you've achieved that dire desired state
You're sure you have to get value along the way. Otherwise, you can't they won't continue the journey with you, right?
Alright, so you brought up cold path warm path hot path. Do you want to go into that now?
Sure, do you so yes for our look for the three should we just tell each each of them get one cold path warm path hot?
No, so what do you mean by cold path rent?
cold path data
is the easiest way to qualify it is it is a a
ton of data
And because it is a ton of data
It gets transmitted from your system into
this final or this
Final destination where people can use it
So we have a big
Data store that we've made in Microsoft for years
But you can think of a lot of people will use
Hadoop or elastic log search solutions or Azure data lake or Azure data lake
I get yeah, I guess there's an opportunity for us to
Hock our own wares
So basically some sort of massive storage where stuff sits for a while. Yeah a large data warehouse say based off of
SQL or an oracle type solution. Okay, so when when the data gets from your product into those
Storage locations and it's a large amount of data
That's typically called path and it's called cold path because by the time you can use it
The the data is multiple days old
Okay, a bunch again to paraphrase a bunch of data shoved into some big storage solution
Yep, where it sits for a while and becomes cold hot path is
The the opposite of cold path in its so the data comes from the big storage thing and gets no
No, not quite that opposite hot path is a small amount of data
that is
That lands in its store very quickly usually within
Five minutes or less and I would hope even faster some of those things are like site availability
Yes
The
It isn't very rich
But it can tell you things like for example in Azure
We one of our big hot path
Signals is VM up or down
It's basically a list of its metrics in our team that we need to act on immediately. Yes
That's not everything you can measure it's it's for us. It's mainly things around site performance and site availability
now on warm path
there is
Of these names warm path is where there's sort of the semantic religious war
Now I also I'm blown away
There is something in software that has become a semantic religious war. Yeah, I know well just a minute
Okay, go on. Yeah
Well, I cannot represent
the other point of view because I
Because it's wrong and I semantically and religiously disagree with it, right? I I don't I don't even pay attention to it
So warm path is essentially when you mix cold and hot just like in my tub with my rubber ducky, right?
So in the data path there's these there's there's generally two types of data ones known as
Dimensional data and another one known as fact data fact data
is essentially
Transaction information this event occurred on this time
This VM was up this VM went down that sort of thing. Okay
Dimensional data is the metadata
So for example, which customer owns this VM? Okay
So a a
Strategy with with warm path data is essentially you reuse your hot path store and
You have cold path updates of the metadata such that you can then join these things together
And have a fairly good confidence
Of
Building new insights, for example, if you wanted to in my situation if I wanted to know which customers were down in near real time as
Long as the the customer didn't sign up in the last two days. I can do that
And a lot of times that's a that's a valuable and a reasonable miss
Okay. Okay
All right, so and and that's probably fair is cold path definite definition we can all agree with
Hot path we grew it as well
Warm path is something in the middle. It depends on right? Hey one. So that's fine
Well, that's true with water as well. If I might digress cuz like what maybe warm to me may feel cool or hot to you
Yes, the the
You know what one of the things I say we can solve this
When we're done here, let's take a shower together
We'll see we'll see what how as long as the check clears first Alan. I'm okay with that
There's no check. There's no check
Our relationship is based on nothing but trust
Brent is frantically trying to look at his notes and get back on track
It's my job to not let it be that easy for him. Yeah
so another way of thinking of
I don't know how to incorporate data awareness, but when we talked about data oblivious
Data driven and then data centric
There's another terminology they think is a good synonyms for this one. So that oblivious
It's you're driving the business off of intelligent or off the intuition
that adriven you're dividing or driving it off of intelligence and
data centric off of
Smartness now define smartness. I was about to say
Several folks will say hey isn't intelligence and smart
Synonyms no in in the data in the in the data analytics world. They are not synonyms. They might be in a dictionary
They are not here. So
Intelligence is you can think of it's you can think about the difference this sort of book smart versus Street
That's exactly what I was thinking is the difference there
So when you have an intelligent system, you're basically book smart you you are
You now have the data where where you are able to confidently
Express what is happening and to some degree express why it's happening
When you're in when you're in the world of
smart
You have able you have been able to filter out which of those
Intelligence aspects you generated
You can automate and
drive action with
so
intuition
You don't they don't even have the data in an intelligence phase. You've got gain a mastery of
Curating the data
but you don't really know which of these data feeds really helps to drive the business or
any
customer set sense within the business and then when you're in a world of
Smartness you not only know which ones drive the business
But you've you've begun to leverage that data and automate that data
So let me moving the people aspect of there's an interesting
I'll paraphrase but this time in with an interesting maybe insight maybe stupid comment sometimes hard to tell the difference but in
The first step is intuition only and then you're sort of you swing the pendulum all the way and it's all just like data only and
Smartness this street smartness comes from being able to combine intuition with that data
Yes
with and
Connect it to validated outcomes
Like you've but to me that's that's connection of intuition and hard data
No, you so you can connect intuition with hard data. Yes, that's intelligence, but then connecting it
to
proof
That responding to intelligence
Actually moves things forward one of the biggest challenges
there are there are
The two biggest challenges that I've encountered from data science teams themselves
Number one, I have produced
World-class brilliant insights and no one is using it
Okay, and this is this is a common phenomenon
People will leave their data science team because of this and the second one is all I do is reports
Right. So the the value proposition
To get to smartness is you got to get people to use it if they're not using it
Then you're in the wrong path. I agree and that usage criteria
If people are asking you for a lot of reports and they are
And you're generating a lot of insights
You're in the intelligence phase and you're working through how to get to smart a lot of data scientists will come out of school
For example, and they've been told by their professors. Oh when you join a data science team, it's all about ML
and it can be
That because we're in a phase in the worldwide where
Where there's sort of a shortage of data science teams and a lot of organizations are trying to build this up
Most teams aren't at most companies aren't fully at the smart phase. There are a whole bunch of them but most are so I see
and perhaps I
Think you'll agree with me
Although he may be offside of this and the data data science fairly new profession people come out of school with
degrees that didn't even exist a while back there used to be called just statisticians or and
But being able to apply what they do to provide value to an organization is critical, but I've interviewed
I was gonna say hundreds maybe thousands
But definitely hundreds and hundreds of people at Microsoft from very good universities with very impressive degrees
And these people were all intelligent in your definition
But not but not I shouldn't say all of them many of them were in very very intelligent, but not very smart
this is a good parallel for you to me with data science software developers who
Wrote papers on algorithms, but actually couldn't figure out how to apply them
I'm not talking about making the right code at the whiteboard just talking through like
How do you think through solving a problem with code was something?
Just they couldn't make the connection and the same thing with I see software testers
Who can't eat maybe they have certifications or whatever they've they'd know a lot of facts
They know to bring up things like boundaries and performance and but they don't
Know how to apply those things to actually test something. Well, there's a connection that has to happen to be successful between
This background these tools you have and being able to actually apply them in a meaningful way
And that's true with any knowledge work
but there's that connection and then data science is sort of on the edge of the same place and other professions have been where you
People have this background like you should be able to do this, but you're just not being successful at it
You're not crossing that bridge, but I've studied machine learning and I know how to use our but there's a leap from there to actually
Doing the work that provides value to your org
Moving something by by using that knowledge
right now the
The other thing that's just as an aside
most of the people that I interview for a data science position are PhDs and
Professional students. Yeah, there's there is a challenge with with those folks
I
Don't know if you were aware. I learned this just in the last year
that most
PhDs are encouraged by
say their prior sponsors to stay in academia and
heavily encouraged it's almost viewed as a
Desertion if you go into industry, so there's a big discussion between academia and industry
am
Academia is has a lot of value. I'm on the I talked about this a lot. I'm on the board for
the Alumni Board for my university's School of Arts and Humanities, which is a
Different side it's not in the computer science software world computer science side of the world
but one of the things we discuss a lot is
the ability to
Basically just talk about before the ability to apply
critical thinking to knowledge work versus just the thing on the theoretical side
Versus the practical side and we need people to bridge that yes, we do the academia is
Really good at pushing the edge
They have a whole engine around not only masters but
PhD students
Looking at the current body of research and creating new
Original work in the general way that you create a new original work is you look to see
Where there's unanswered unanswered open questions this this leads them to to push forward on the theory
And so some of these folks come in and they've spent the better part of the last eight years
With that is their personal culture and so when they come into industry
I
Spend a lot of time looking through
great like
Here's one here's
50% of my
interview
In one single question great. How can I use that? That's fantastic. How can I use that? Okay, and
They struggle with that. Yeah, at least I want to get back on track here, but at least once a year
there's a PhD paper on
someone who solved the problem of making bug-free software and they haven't
some method whether it's an analysis tool or a new programming language that
eliminates the
functional bugs from their software, but
They're just oblivious to the fact that the software
They're describing in their paper is nothing anyone would want to use and we've talked about where quality comes from
People wanting to use the software
Either it has bugs not quality is value and you can make a bug-free program that has no value
therefore no quality
The other thing too though
Because when you say they want to use there's an element of proactivity the nice thing with
with the data space is
As you build up the assets and as you are working towards
making
your analyses more truthful
and
simpler
Then whether or not they want to use it if you socialize it correctly
It becomes more actionable and you can essentially force their hand on using it
most people when you have when they have a belief like
By shipping this feature. We will grow customer engagement by
Blah blah blah if you can show them the data
That says that does not appear to be true
Data
Well-articulated
defeats intuition
Almost all of the time correct
So let me let me do a couple things
First and foremost we talked about how do you know when you get to data centric?
when you get to data the way, you know you get to data driven is
You are doing a lot of what's known in the statistical world as
Hypothesis testing and what a hypothesis test is is you you've trained people to
Date their beliefs in the form of a sentence
So much like what I just said
this feature will increase customer engagement by
50%
then
So the PM or whoever is working on it will continue on building their features
But then they're gonna work with you to figure out. Okay, what's the data that needs to be done or
Generated in order to prove or disprove
that hypothesis, okay, this is different than say the
Gqm model that test was informed as
As the brilliant way of going years ago
Go question metric by the correct silly what I want to do
I guess in the remaining minutes is I want to walk through
Sort of the phases since we're talking about how do you know when you got there? I want to walk through there is jog through
jog through
Gallop through
the phases of a data analytics maturity
Now here I'm gonna talk about abstract stuff again the principles we talked about last time around
starting with what you have and
Building from that solidifying that then build again is the right approach here
Don't swing all the way over to any sort of these North stars
So the first phase is what's known as measure am
in
when you're in the measurement phase
Really what you are able to do is answer what questions?
What what feature is the most popular exactly what customer?
pays us the most
what
useful feature is
And come back combinations of those
One of the things a tool
That I've used in when we're in this phase. I call it real and it's an acronym
What it stands for is reliability engagement availability latency
So if you can pull together an asset that measures those four things
it generally isn't a challenge to
Get dev bought in and it also isn't a challenge to
Provide useful value
so
You're using existing data. You're being reactive. You're not being proactive
You're basically saying hey dev that feature you shipped yesterday
Here's what the the real report shows
our reliability
reliability
Engagement engagement availability and latency. What's the difference between reliability and availability?
Let me go through them all. Okay reliability is a measure of the frequency in which
failures occur. Okay, okay
Engagement how often it's being used is
Yeah, it's like how many people so engagement is a measure of the priority of this path. Okay. Okay
so if whether it's used or not
Availability so if reliability is a measure of the frequency in which things are occurring
Availability is a measure of the consequence of failures. Got it
So the way you measure is it just an API failure or the site become completely unresponsive?
The typically the way you measure availability will be by downtime
Okay, this failure occurred
These these machines were damn down for two hours or two days. Okay, and then latency is essentially
A measure of the success path. Hey when everything's working. Is it zippy or is it painfully slow?
Yeah, so these four things together
really useful
then the biggest thing you can do in the measure phase is
automate this the visualization of this data end to end such that
whoever using it typically developers don't have to come to you and
As for this report you just you've strung it together you've worked through it you've you've
Talked with devs and found out that this is fact the truth. They began to leverage it. Okay
The next phase now great you can answer what questions
The next thing is that people will start ask want wanting to diagnose
How to fix that?
So you have you have all of these
Services, they're all failing dev wants to know what's the pattern? So you being able to drill down your aggregates and diagnose
It is the next one
Here you want to be able to automate drilled in an exploration in that context and
But your goal is to enable human beings
to do the root cause analysis
You do want to automate what's known as the Pareto order?
So as you work through debt with dev to figure out how to automate
This process and how they investigate it
You're gonna learn new knowledge and you'll learn that they have common patterns and then you can automate the Pareto order of the impact
You now have the data so you can create a new
report that that says
These are the things that should be worked on next and that's extremely valuable
The next phase is known as predict and optimize. So now you have all of this data
You you now want to be able to not react
But how do you know when you're about to encounter a reliability problem?
Generally, there's other signals perf counters
Traffic
Changes that you can use to sort of predict these outcomes
This enables you to answer
Not only why questions very confidently, but also what if questions so you begin to be able to
Predict the future
Okay
Predicting things is hard, especially about the future and with the what if questions you now are able to
address
Hey given two choices of the next steps, which choice should I take? Okay good and the next step which is there
How many more are there three more?
operationalize and integrate
But this means is data is easily integrated across all teams
and
here we're
decisions can be made on
Multiple different fronts as you go through this though
I started off talking about with quality of service the type of data that that
Us as testers are accustomed to why do things fail bugs, right?
Here between then and now you're gonna want to incorporate customer and business data. I
Will tell you nothing drives an
Action with a developer
Better than the ability to file a bug and say this bug cost the business this amount of money and be able to state it
with confidence
Then after that once the data is operationalized and integrated then you'll start getting into
What's known as automated decision-making?
This is the NRT stuff that we're talking about event driven decisions
Plugging the ml instead of the ml being something that drives decisions with humans
You plug the ml into a product right for example just to interject even though we're real short on time is that right now?
Our product gets released through rings of deployment pretty common and that is always a human decision at this point
It combined with data. Yep, but that could very well and I want it to be purely automated based on data and then the very last
step is
A lot of people you will hear them talking about data democratization
No, I don't hear a lot of people talking about that. Okay, a lot of people in my neck of the woods
Okay, we're data democratize
Whatevs and this is
Essentially meaning the data that comes from the service. It's democratized anyone can easily use it. It's a key part to the
operationalizing integration step
Like I want to I'm gonna add a survey to the slack channel and ask how many of you use the term or hear the term
data democratization in your daily work
the last phase
Which is known as transform is around knowledge democratization
So we talked about the difference between intelligence and smart you need to have data democratization
in order to reach the intelligence
When you're smart is you now have
Curated assets that allows you to democratize the knowledge gained
Does that make sense? It does make sense is democratization too big of a word for you. Not too big for me. Okay, and then
Hey, we just got just a minute left, but I want to make sure we cover one item as teased earlier from the mailbag
We
Got a question from Michael Rocha. He asks what?
resources articles white papers
exist on data driven testing
Unfortunately simple question and unfortunately I have a simple answer
I'm sure they exist. There's none of them that I'm aware of
But if I were to begin looking at this I would look into the concept of testing in production
Just search this just do I would say being in some good. I would do some Bing in on
effective means of
for testing in production
that we've
We've talked in the past the testing and production does not mean you move your test cases to the cloud
It's the testing and production done right is heavily driven off of data emitted from the product
That's where I would start the stuff we talked about in episode 44 is a bit different
It's sort of testing in production when you don't have production
Got it. Okay. There's our episode. There it is. Hey everybody. Don't forget to re-swizzle your thing about
Or whatever Jim Moore had us say. Oh, right. It's a little bit different
Oh right in in is a
Is star is the the star promo code still active should we do a reminder of this sure you can go?
Do if you go to the star to register you can use the code a be testing and get two to two hundred dollars off
All right, then. All right. Hey everybody. I'm still Alan barely and I am confidently Brent