Hey Alan, how are you doing?
Super hey everybody listening. We're happy to have you here. Thanks for listening. Tell your friends so we can have even more listeners. Oh
This is the a B testing podcast. There will only be three
So we are at
Episode number 65. I like to let Brent say that because I can't count very high and he's a he's like a math guy
Right. Yeah, so we are here once again early in the morning recording a podcast Brent. How was your last week?
It's interesting
Big deal happening in the Jensen household
Emptiness syndrome officially starts Wednesday
Is your last child start school? Don't you have a young you have a young daughter?
I said it starts doesn't start. Yeah first one left first one leaves Wednesday
But I like to count down the other way, which is the year until they're all gone
So how old is your youngest seven? Yeah, so I I will be done earlier because my youngest is
starting seventh grade in three weeks and
I'm just counting down the days until they're out of the house and we sell the house and don't tell the kids where we move
Everybody laughs when I say that like it's a joke. No, I'm I think I'm not 100% serious
I think it's fascinating that you have this position already in your kids aren't teenagers. Yeah, I had it before they were born
The older ones a teenager. I had it before they were born. I
Took my daughter clothes shopping yesterday
She is such she's such a shopper
She
It was I I did the thing where I sat on a bench in the mall for about an hour and a half
Well, she looked at and tried on clothes. I figured out what I hate malls
It was physically draining on my soul. My daughter isn't old enough for that yet, but I do remember
Gosh, I think she was like four
where she and mom went out shopping and
She
Came home. She's like dad. I made mom buy me two pairs of these shoes just in case one gets dirty and
I'm like, oh my god
She's like already in the shoes and she's already four and my wife is not like one of those
Shoe people I'm like I and I have three pairs of shoes. I'm like, I don't know where you're getting this from
My son was with us he's massively patient he's the opposite
he
Didn't want to buy any clothes. I
finally made him buy a pair of sweats he's where he wears sweats or shorts and a t-shirt every day and he has a
infinite well, not quite infinite a
Continuous I'll put it a continuous supply of brand-new t-shirts coming in through loot crate. You know what loot crate is
No, loot crates this thing for like 20 bucks a month subscription service. You get a box of
Stuff every month which always includes a t-shirt some sort of little statue
It's a little knick-knacks he did just a general loot crate, which is just kind of cool nerdy geek stuff for a while
But now we just loot crate gaming so he gets a little little game trinkets sometimes stickers
figurines
But some really cool t-shirts as well. My daughter does loot crate anime
They're on a tangent she got some she gets some cool stuff loot crate is on our sponsor today
No, how would your son 13 13?
And the stuff he's getting the loot crate gaming you think of age appropriate. Yeah, there's no it's with a 15 year old
Find it age appropriate. You can go to loot crate comm and check out and again, man. They should be sponsoring this show
Loot crate comm check out the crates. See what they have. I do one thing with my daughter
Have you heard a kidster? No, it's a essentially a
recipe of the month type of
Loot crate thing. So every month there's a theme every month
We have three recipes and every month she gets some specific tools like it was it sandwiches this month
And what I do is my daughter and I it's a it's a father-daughter thing my daughter and I we will pick a recipe
one every weekend and then
As I mentioned, there are only three recipes. So the fourth one
Every week kids sir will send you another recipe and email
But this month it sandwiches and one of the one of the tools that it came with is a little sandwich cutter
So it's a it's about the same size as a regular two piece of bread sandwich
But when you squish it down, it's kind of like a cookie cutter when you squish it down on top of your sandwich
it automatically cuts off the crusts and
It cuts it into a little like
puzzle pieces
The little four pieces of puzzle stuff and we've used that tool gosh
She
Got it. I think that's kind of awesome like three days after August started and we've used it probably ten times already
That things cool. That's pretty cool
Alright, so as I mentioned neither Loot Crate or kids stir nor kids stir are our
Sponsors, but you know who is yes, I do who?
Coba time Coba time our friends at Cobra time once again sponsoring a be testing
If you don't know what cobit on is let me tell you a little bit about it not in my own words
If you're looking for an easier more affordable way to test your mobile app on real devices
Welcome to cobit on the complete mobile device cloud platform that gives you access to test on the latest iOS and Android devices when you need them
For manual to automated testing cobit on is a simpler cost effective way to test your mobile app the way you want with no
Commitment for only ten cents a minute
You can get 100 minutes of testing time for just ten dollars and the best part is that your minutes never expire
Buy the minutes you need use them whenever you want add more when you're ready. It's that easy
So I like this model. I also like that you can do a free trial without a credit card to tell you about that
in a minute
But just buy a chunk of minutes. You can test manually on those devices. You can run automated tests on those devices
Almost any device you can imagine and if you're building well who's not building a mobile app today
Something like this is I think
Absolutely necessary a little more from automatically generated activity logs to one source for your testing history
Cobut on gives you tools you need to find and fix issues faster true
Empowering developers and businesses to get their products to market sooner
Test your mobile web and hybrid apps on all the latest devices and configurations from anywhere anytime
Sign up for a no commitment free trial at cobut on comm forward slash AB testing to start testing in
minutes and as usual I will post that in the
The blog post that contains this mp3 you're listening to now. I'm I
Remain a big fan of cobut on and tools like this and again if you are
Testing mobile apps and you're trying to build your own mobile
Lab, please stop. I I can't imagine how it could be cost-effective
Using tools like this and and again by the minute on the paying by the minute scheme
Spreading those minutes out across your team running automation being strategic about it all kinds of capital win there
the other thing I was thinking about here is
The
Individual angle is one of the things that I'm seeing a lot when I'm called in to interview developers
I'm seeing a lot of people who are just app developers and they're the only person
I don't know. I don't know what if it's cost-effective, but if you're an individual
Right it you certainly not gonna find a better way to scale
It's gonna be more cost-effective if whatever you're building
You need to cross platform thing. This is gonna be way more cost-effective than going out and buying the devices yourself. Absolutely
Although I suppose there's the model of
Getting friends who have different devices to try your app out you could just try it out but
mechanical Turk it up
There are other companies are yet sponsors
So I won't mention them by name for crowdsourcing a bunch of those
Crowdsourcing is really grown in the last
A few years especially seems like I see if a new
crowdsourcing company every few months
It almost feels like
crowdsourcing's
Kind of gotten over the plateau and there's no longer the I wonder if it'll get to the tipping point where it's just
Everything is tested by everybody which is a lot of what we do in testing and production
They just do it willingly versus unwillingly
Yeah, it's it's crowdsourcing. It's just a technique now. I think it's not
Like a lot of the big crowdsourcing companies. I haven't I haven't heard mention of them in
years
Like like when you test came out you test is still very big applause
Test I owe off the top of my head
again naming companies that are not sponsoring this episode, but
Well, we talked about a lot of things here on a be testing. Hey, I
Had a vacation last week, which was great or let me rephrase that as great as a vacation can be
When you spend it with your extended family
Which is actually pretty good my mother-in-law actually listens to the show sometimes
As I've as I shared on our slack channel one of the three dot slack comm
She says I'm a little harsh on Brent sometimes and I say Brent deserves it
So I'm back and while I was driving hanging out I had really had a nice time
But did some kayaking saw some harbor seals did some mountain biking down a mountain Constitution highest point on on Orca silent about
2400 feet
But a good five miles down. I had a lot of fun one thing I pondered is I
Just recently passed my six-month mark at unity
where I've been the director of quality for services and
For some reason reflecting back on my time at Microsoft and I spent a chunk of my career at Microsoft
advocating
For the as I say advocating successfully unsuccessfully. I'm not sure but I'll just say advocating for
The role the role in career advancement of the individual contributor tester for better or for worse
I think at the time it was the right thing to do so no regrets for that
But but that wasn't what I was pondering. I was pondering. I
Wonder I was trying to think how much
Time of my career I spent as a manager versus individual contributor despite that big chunk of my career dedicated to the let's
Look, I'm an IC role model and look and look what we can do. I see being individual contributor. So
But I have a question for you before I start. Yeah, how did you become a manager?
What was your path at Microsoft? You obviously weren't hired as a manager. How did it happen?
Of course, you didn't even know you're an intern when you're
It was a it was a different Microsoft so
I've held before I came at Microsoft. My very first job was
At Carl's Jr. In California, which for those who aren't in California, it's a fast food joint
And say what you will about that
Like there's still several of the burger recipes that I have memorized I love to cook and
And what's a burger recipe you take hamburger and you fry it?
No, that's how you cook a hamburger. It's a hamburger. The rest of the rest. Oh put lettuce on the bun. Sure
All right. Great. Great. All right. Glad you're proud of this. Go on but it actually also solidified
my Spanish skills
Because the no one spoke English in the kitchen
That's very cool. Then when I went to college
Was a dishwasher
Then it went up going into a
Grocery store
Now the reason why I'm bring all these I was gonna ask. Yeah, I have no idea you're like what what question are you answering?
How did I get into management?
just checking
so
There's something when I when I came up to Microsoft. I mean we I already told the story that that
Around how I came here
But I was an intern for six months and then I was a contractor at Microsoft for eight months
And then I shifted the full time and I spent I think a total of six months as an IC and I have been
a manager ever since
Now the
What led me to this
When I became a when I became a contractor I worked for
what I still view today as the best manager I've ever had and
Even before it was a full-timer. He told me
Brent you're gonna get converted to full-time in the next couple of months and I see you're gonna be a manager within a year and
That actually freaked me out
he I
Had had in all of other jobs I had had
There's something about my work ethic my style
I've noticed that I always get promoted into management pretty quickly
In terms of like the Peter principle they they
they state a
common phenomenon is people get promoted in management are often the best workers and I've always had a strong work ethic I
Always wanted to get stuff done
So I I knew when he told me that that he was right that I would get promoted into management and it actually freaked me out
Because every other job I had had I had been promoted into management because I was good at doing that individual job
But once I got promoted into management
Getting others to do as I asked was a challenge and I ended up
in my early
Jobs I ended up going no
If I can't get my staff to do it, then I'm gonna do it because it I
My name is on this thing and it's gonna be of high quality
That actually freaked me out
Because every other job I didn't really care if people didn't really listen because there wasn't a consequence
Here I was no longer at a job. I was at my career. So I had to pay active attention to what
What it meant to be a manager how I got into it is I kicked ass as an IC
Should I should I've been promoted into management because of that? No, and there's actually
I've I've I've logged on this. There was a study done that says people do actually get promoted
for the wrong reasons and
In this particular case promoted because
There's a subconscious belief in humans that they I guess they don't really recognize where it's a fundamentally different
skill
To be awesome at something than it is to get others to be awesome at that thing that you're awesome at
Yes, however in this case, I recognize that I worked for a great manager
Someone that I could learn from and mentor with and then I had a very
When he told me that he gave me sort of a of a timeline and I had a very active
Paying attention to who's succeeding and how are they motivating others and things of that sort? So very early on
I knew I would be going into management but knew that it would be leadership
skill set that
enabled me to survive it
Interesting a lot of things to comment on one just I'll pull out from the middle and then I want to share my story
Cuz it's a little bit different and and I think there's some points
I want to talk about the thing I wanted to bring out is you mentioned something
Very quickly that may have slipped by some people but the job and the career
Yeah, and I've had lots of jobs and quickly my path is
Graduated college taught music in the public school system for four years went back to grad school
After grad school masters in music composition. There's a thought as good as an English degree or maybe slightly worse. I
Worked as a bicycle messenger for about six months
Fell into a job doing tech support at a music software company where I eventually learned
Actually on my first day became a software tester as well and eventually learned to program there
from there fell into a contract job at Microsoft that fell into a full-time job at Microsoft and it wasn't until I
Didn't even realize it was a career. It was still just a job to me for the first probably two years
I never thought and today people change jobs every five years as a matter of course
It's almost weird that they don't but at the time I never thought I would be at Microsoft as long as I was
so I
Early on in my
career at Microsoft I thought maybe I want to be a lead but really I
I didn't know I didn't care if someone would ask me to be a lead
I would have been a lead and those times in those days. That's kind of the way it worked
I'll say that since I've known you
Until recently until the last few years the majority of time that I've known you you've you've sort of been
anti
Management well, let me tell you that and specifically what I mean is
You felt the the burden of managing people
Let me go out weighed the benefits
Let me go on the subtlety of that because I don't believe there's a burden in managing people in general
But I want to talk about the subtlety of what you observe because there is something there so
Point I was gonna make is my first manager at Microsoft was
We were both like oh my first manager Microsoft was awful
And actually to back up another thing you said I don't think I've ever had a great manager
I've had some good managers some really crummy managers
But I've learned something whether it's something to do something to emulate or something not to do
Or something not to emulate from all of them. So my yep who I've become has been
Formed from my managers, but I've never had a great
Management mentor and I want to go in how I've learned about management in a minute as well
About five years into my Microsoft career. I became a lead and the way I became a lead was
Doing well as an IC. I was writing a lot of code a lot a lot of code
product code debugger code some test code
At the time I was writing the I own maintenance and writing of the debugger for Windows
Also was doing some kernel bug fixes and stuff
I had no right to be doing given my background, but they let me because I somehow managed to make it work
Anyway, I went to my boss said I you got to take some stuff off my plate
I I love working. I was I was single I was working
5060 hours a week and loving it. It wasn't a work-life balance thing. I enjoyed it
It was exhilarating, but I said I can't it's just too much. I'm getting overwhelmed. He goes
Oh, we actually have a new hire starting on the team on Monday. How about he works for eating help you?
I said great. So wait a minute you tricked me
And
Then some other things like oh this person is working on the stress tools. They use the debugger. He should work for you, too
and and over that team morphed into another team and
So I would end up being a manager for about those I drew some lines on the whiteboard wall print was talking
But they're wrong. I think I ended up being a manager for about four years
total
growing up to a team of about 35 40 people
And I was four years total at Microsoft
Well four years total in that stint. Oh, okay. Okay in that stance gotcha
At the end of it towards the end Microsoft created this test architect role
And my manager said you actually would be really good in this role and I said, I don't know anything about testing
So yeah, you do and that's when I started to really study testing
So if I'm gonna get this test architect role, I'm gonna figure that I don't know what this means
And part of that role was to trance was it took about six months because it said I want you to move in this test
Architect role that could be great at it
But you have to help figure out who's gonna lead your team and grow someone into that role took about six months to find
The right I think I knew who the right person was but to get them ready for that role. I had never studied
Management at that point. I knew nothing other than just my what was in my soul and my guts and what you'd seen from
And what I'd seen from examples, so I was very hands-off which worked
Well, which is kind of how I am now, but it works better in the culture here than at Microsoft
one of the reasons I didn't like management is
Was really one of the reasons I didn't like school teaching. I loved teaching kids to play music
That part of my day was fantastic
Dealing with all of the BS bureaucracy and red tape was one of the reasons I never went back to teaching
and
At Microsoft especially at that time and it got better in later years, but at that time and for a long period there
management required a lot of bureaucracy and red tape and
Fitting into fitting everything into very good boxes and the training they offered
Generally management training I see is not about how to be a good manager for your team and how to
And how to be a good leader for them how to set good examples. It's about how to not get yourself in legal trouble
Yeah, so I became a test architect for about four or five years
The last few of that I was in engineering excellence when that group
I think actually made a difference of Microsoft I took over as the director of test excellence for almost two years
Could you take over from?
Nimrod I I only say Nimrod because that's what his name resolved to an autocorrect
Is alias Jim James Rodriguez Jim Rodriguez who Jim rod not Nimrod
Yeah, but I typed up Jim rod in a word doc it autocorrected to Nimrod
So I that's how I that's my that's my trigger to remember his name Jim Rodriguez. He was only there for about six months
He replaced Ken Johnston who was actually one of my better managers at Microsoft. I didn't realize Ken was
Was in that role. Yeah, Ken hired me into that team. I took over for Jim EE started really going downhill
I left took an IC role. That was always my plan
I was even though I was a lead of a team of five people there
My plan was to always leave to an IC rule
I went I continued on my I see career path stuff for a while through link and then through Xbox one and
then through the science project and then
became a lead again
in the Microsoft Teams team
but at this point now the difference between this stint in management and
Even in my EE and especially in my first stint is at this point. I had actually
read
10 20 books on
Management so I had and the story I tell about software testing. It's a first read a book about testing
I thought I knew everything about testing
I read another book started to get different ideas
When I read a third and fourth and fifth and sixth and seventh book is when I began to form my own opinions
And the same thing happens reading books on management and leadership
Mm-hmm, and it's just as hard to learn to be a good manager as it is to become a good programmer and I
Don't think enough people in management positions put that
Realize that and I didn't realize that the first time I did it either and I think
Not many managers the first time to become a manager do but I think by the time you've done it for a while
by the time you've made your
Second or third stint at it fifth or sixth year at it you better have started to study some things not just directly about management
But reading books like drive to understand how what motivates people looking at
Other books on my favorite so drive is a good book on just what motivates people
Some of my favorites are Michael ops book on managing humans
He he didn't read that one. He talks about the skill and the will matrix, which I use a lot
Okay, high skill high will low skill low will high skill low will I will skill
People generally follow one of those but unlike a bucket model of stack ranking
Genuinely want to try and manage your team towards high skill high will positions where they're in the and I know we've talked about this
before coffee shop
You have people of low skill you can get them training get them coaching mentoring people with low will may be on the wrong job
But you want to get people the right work that makes them the most productive and most beneficial to your team
there's a
Actually a really good book. I read
Fairly recently. It's called the manager's path and I forget the author
But it talks all the way through like first becoming a lead to becoming a lead of leads to being a director and kind of the different
Things you take on it's a pretty quick read pretty well written
I'm about three-quarters the way through a book written by a Google exec whose name I have forgotten former Google exec
Called radical candor. Have you read this book? Nope?
I think it's a very good as well. The reason it's very good is the reason I say it's very good
Is I tend to fall in love with books that echo my own values
Because and there's things I've built up now that I've read a bunch of these books
I like oh, yeah, this is either it solidifies or Marty thinking gives me a new way to think about some things
I've been thinking
Everybody wants validation. They do they do and just be careful though because
Every time you get validation validation balance it with
Okay, great
There's a 5% chance that both me and this book are wrong, which is why I keep reading so I can everything
Everything is a minor course correction at this time. It's like, okay
Yeah, and it's not like I wrote the book. It's gonna have some things like oh, I haven't thought of this before
It's a great idea. Yeah, but I've had a good time learning that so anyway, that was my path where I was going
I forgot where I was going. So I've been in and out of management
I can't count the time but I've probably been an IC more than a manager, but I have been really more than any time at Microsoft
For a lot of reasons. I don't want to go in the hole unity is awesome Microsoft sucks thing
But they're just different companies at different stages of maturity
I have really enjoyed my time as a manager at unity to haven't exactly put my finger on why yet. I think
One thing is though a lot of it is just there's just so much freedom in how I do it
Let me offer a suggestion. Yes, then I'll go back to my subject. Okay
first and foremost like over the years I have read just a ton of
books as well and part of
Just like what you mentioned
Every manager that I've ever had
Some of their style their philosophy got incorporated into my own
It's now at a point where it's really challenging to go. Okay, what's the difference between these guys?
I'll say the first manager I ever had was absolutely worse and I absolutely know what
What I will never do as a result of the things
He did when I reported to him
But and the other thing I would say the thing that that I find kind of quirky
Like it seems like every management book if you don't have your own variant of a truth square
You're not building a proper management book
Every single one of them has their own variant of the truth square. Yeah, but you mentioned the skill vish as well
I actually like I can't pronounce the guy's name
So and I'm not even gonna try out of respect, but it's a it's concept of flow. Yeah
But there was another one and I don't remember the guy's name
I'd like to give him credit, but he came over this concept that I've actually used
With all of my employees ever since I learned it that really what you're trying to do is a as a human being is
You're trying to align
your
value system your
strengths
With a business that shares those values and actually that's what I think you've done with going to unity
You you are highly adaptable you like strategic thinking
You like the freedom and not to be bogged down by
bureaucracy and the big thing is is I like to be trusted yeah, I think
maybe
I'll put this nicely. I think
My experience at Microsoft as a manager was there was and again for very good reasons and not a big knock
But almost too many guardrails put in place
Yeah, and then
When you're gonna get to a particular size, there's there's there's a lot of philosophies
This is a company thing. There's a lot of philosophies that
Move
forward unquestioned
right am and that that ends up being part of the ecosystem now and it didn't and there's a
Steven blank
is
probably my favorite author on
Rise and fall of companies going from sort of the startup mentality to
Taking over the world and he's studied it very well
But this other guy
Here's what I tell people and this is again not mine
But what everyone's looking for is a job
That is the center of the following three
You can think of it as a Venn diagram
number one everyone
Has a set of things that they do well
Everyone also has a set of things that they like to do
lastly
There's a set of things that you can be paid to do
Yep, and really you want to find something? That's all three and honestly Alan
I think that's that's what it feels like you've done. So
Yes, perhaps perhaps so I have a question
I want to get I want to ask you but I need to address some things and
Evolve some things and not get lose my train of thought in that process
So what I just want to be clear that skill on the well matrix was an example
It's not the center of my management philosophy and I think
One thing I've used more often is the ACB thing which I'm working on renaming to I forget what I've
renamed it to the most recently but another model and as
Managers, we should build these models as much as we have I don't want to compare them to design patterns
but just have some models for how you
Can maybe find the center of that Venn diagram and one I use this ACB thing
New name I'll blog about it sometime, but you have some stretch work some above work
Stuff that makes you learn if you're not doing any work that's making you learn new stuff
Or if you're not giving your employees work that makes them learn new stuff. They're not growing and they're not they're just stagnant
Yep, then you have a chunk of stuff that you're just good at
It's it's it's worked. It needs to be done. Of course. It's that current that concrete stuff
The stuff in the milk duck is in your wheelhouse stuff
You're great at and then every once in a while we have to do some kind of grunt work
Yeah, I have to go, you know shovel out the horse banner in software
I need to go I need to be the guy that goes make sure all these VMs are up and running
Because I don't have an automated tool for it. Whatever it is some sort of it's not it's not stretch work
It's not something I'm it needs to be done. So I'm gonna jump in and do it for me
It was I'm gonna go fix a bunch of these static analysis bugs
I don't really want to do it, but it's a good place for me to jump in
So it's an example of a model and we have multiple of these models and that that
This in the Venn diagram and the skill of the will there's a lot of overlap
There's another Venn overlap between what those target but the point is
Through observing through your own experiences through your own values
Through what you read and discover in books what you read and discover on the internet
Both in blogs and I think hbr.org is a great
Source for a lot of great ideas and management leadership. That's where I first saw the hint of what I later
Developed more into the world of Warcraft guide to project management, which I've mentioned before so I won't do now
I can elaborate later if if someone gets in the mailbag and chooses
So if you want to get good at it, you have to
Absorb from a whole bunch of different sources and from that form your own management philosophy
So my question even that's not good enough. You have to act you have to try things out
Yeah, and I tell my team this is part of my management philosophies. I tell my team is
Everything I do is sort of in the agile way. So I'm gonna try shit all the time and
Before it's perfected before it's complete
I'm gonna try and see if it works and if it is we'll do more of it or elaborate and if not
I'll throw it away and we'll do it again
All the time always try and crap always trying to see what works
so I want to lead that that's part of what I do and
But let me ask you do you have and if so, can you share the Brent Jensen?
Management philosophy. How do you what are your what are the core things you try and do as a manager?
You have you thought about this before I thought
At a abstract. Yes
It's it's actually very easy
So, what are my guardrails?
Okay, first and foremost
I will communicate myself as my my
Teams manager just because that's the easiest way to explain the concept. Okay
First and foremost, I don't view myself as my teams manager. I view myself as their MSP. Oh
God, it's an acronym. It is I view myself as their management service provider
Okay, and every time I share it that's what I get I get giggles
Because it sounds very manage managerial
I can see the pointy here growing out the side of your head now
But there's an important distinction and why I view MSP as a better way of describing it than manager
Because if I'm so let's say Alan I was your management service provider
Okay
versus your manager
the difference is
Who fires who ah?
Okay, if I'm your MSP, you're my customer
not my
slave or
work doer
so by by
reinforcing myself as an MSP it
It helps me to stay balanced at what my job is actually to do
It's to help
grow
Not only the project but you Alan if you leave my team
You fired me. Okay, and
Now if it's mutual for example, there are many times
Actually just this last year that I had a report and I could tell
That what he could be
He was out of balance the stuff he liked to do
He could be paid to do the stuff
He did well on my team, but it wasn't the stuff he liked to do and I'm like
Let's let's find you a different place
The second
The MSP is a is a big one
The second thing that really is the other guardrail and it's probably aligned with
the first and some great degree
10 years from now the code that you're working on today is irrelevant and
In pretty much anyone listening to this podcast. This is going to be for the most part true
I'm happy to like one of the things that I'm happy with
I've mentioned this before I have a test harness that I patented back in 1998
That thing is still in use
This surprises me
I'm well, I'm a little I kind of know why because the way we designed it we designed it to be
adaptable and flexible
But that's a rarity
What persists though 10 years from now are those people?
Who you interacted with?
So as a management, I'm like we're here to to get things done grow the career grow the business
But I do view myself as more beholden to the the people I work with and
Work underneath me than anything else. Okay, so though that's the primary guardrails for me. Okay, so
You could work on concise in that up a little bit, but I get it
so mine simples I have two big points in mine and
These have come from again my own values and finding things that I've liked and latched onto from some of the things I've studied
So I'm gonna talk about I think two books. I haven't talked about
which
again, they yeah, that's how I would like to do with that that fits how I function and
Very similar to the MSP. You've probably never read
Reed Hoffman's book called the Alliance
Yeah, Reed Hoffman is one of the founders of LinkedIn. I wrote a book called the Alliance. It says in today's workforce
It's not the job like my dad got a job out of high school and worked there till pretty much till he retired
Consulting for the last five years of his career, but he worked at this company for like 30 years
That world does not exist for most people anymore
although I've worked at Microsoft for 22, but
Things happen the differences is like say say you work for me
Okay, so similar to the MSP
But you didn't talk about what's in it for you and we're gonna make an alliance for different kinds of alliances
Can be they're like a tour of duty is what Reed Hoffman calls him
Let's take a given time period a year six months 18 months. Here's what we're gonna accomplish together
I am going to help you be successful in your job by doing a B and C and
in that that's going to help me and the company be successful by doing DE and F and
We have a packed an alliance together because I think that goes two ways
I think I get the MSP thing because I my job is to help you be successful
But I also recognize that in helping you to be successful
I need we need to both agree to understand how that helps the company and
In me in some cases be successful as well. We need to grow together in this journey in this alliance
Yeah, then at the end of that alliance, we can either re-up we can
Go our separate ways
I may help you move to another team or a different company if it's a better fit like you talked about
Or we can do a different kind of a maybe we're doing a transformational alliance like you want to move to a
Data science architect role and for example a different rule like with my manage helped me move to a
From a manager just architect role. We're gonna take like here's what I'm gonna get at the end
Here's what you're gonna get at the end. Let's work on this together. We're in it together. Mm-hmm
So it's a slight variation on your MSP
But it says in practicality, it's it's very much the same
Yeah, like in order in order in order to in order for me to be a solid MSP
I have to guide those people
Towards the center of the Venn diagram with the with the business constraints, right? I I
Cannot put them in a position
Well, I mean I can but it's foolish
I can put them in a position where they only do the things that they do well and they like to do
But they can't get paid for and my paid for I've mapped that to sort of the review model like great
You can do these two things
but
This is what's gonna happen at the review model
That's let's continue searching for the thing that's that's gonna be right in the center in terms of the partnership and the alliance
Stuff like what you described very aptly is is a hundred percent
number one the best relationships the best
managers I've ever had
is where
they've
Didn't view me as a report, but viewed me as their peer
They're part of the team. I think they're ally great. And one of the things anecdotally I've heard from
Multiple people on my team without me even like trying to do this was they just appreciated that I was there to bounce ideas off
Oh, and I thought well geez, what else would I do as a manager?
That's like one of the best services as you put it I can provide right? I'm happy. I have some experience
I have some ideas
by all means bounce your ideas off of me and then cross team like this alliance model if you're
The other the other thing it's not really related to management, but one of my driving philosophies is
NIH kicks ass
and for those who are not familiar with the the acronym NIH is not invented here and
You really need to create and grow
Negotiation skills and practice
creating win-win scenarios
To make these Alliance
models work across team. Yeah, and
Plenty and plenty of nuance there before I run out of time the other half of my the second of my 12
No, pretty much two
things that drive me as a manager or
Frameworks, I rely on one is the Alliance model. Other one is taken. Have you ever read Steve Dening's book?
You know Steve Dening is yes business author writes for Forbes magazine all the time. He is a
not a software guy a business guy who discovered agile and says and just
kind of embraced it in the business sense and wrote a book called the leaders guide to radical management and
You can it barely mentions agile but you can see some of the agile principles seeping through his ideas and how to lead a team and
One of the things from his book is basically give your team a framework they can work in and then get out of their way
Amen, and that's I've always had that philosophy. One of the reasons my last team
really
Graded on me. I mentioned my blood pressures going down
It was a team driven by micromanagement and that is just not who I am. I want to give I don't want to
I don't ignore my team at all
But I do want to give them I want to give them their own guardrails
Make sure they know what our alliance is where we're going what they need to do and then
Give them room to learn and to grow and ask questions and I have some people doing really well. I have to
challenge them to
Learn more to one of the guardrails I put up is you must learn to be successful on this team
So what did you learn this week?
but
Building a framework around I the things I value the things I think that will make the individual and the company successful and
Talk about those to the team make sure they know
What those things are and then get out of their way they need to they need some room to grow and learn I do this with the
Obviously the more junior people do a little bit more hand-holding but at some stage
I expect this is probably especially true on a team that's geographically dispersed, but I expect independence and autonomy
Yeah, as you were talking it reminded me of
The safe planning event and
Try to do it in in a in a succinct nutshell so I can I can drive my point home
Right what first and foremost what they are saying when safe does this planning?
Right, there's the fail-fast principle. There is
accountability and there is a power empowerment and
Probably a topic for another day
But we could philosophize on can you have empowerment without a catability?
The my short answer is no in a safe planning meeting. You have a bunch of scrum teams
Let's say five okay, and they are treated
Independently so they are they are
Proactively assigned items that they're gonna own for the sprint
at the very beginning and
The neat thing about a safe planning event is essentially in two days you plan out the entire three months I
Did this a couple years ago at Microsoft?
and it's the first time in my entire career at Microsoft where a
Plan that was built in us in essentially a day for a team of 40
Was nailed on time to the day it was
Really freaking cool anyway. I think I think it's a fluke but go on
They so I left shortly after that and they continued to be able to do that
No, it's it's it's the model. It's because knowledge is
shared up front
We can go into bigger detail
At so the planning event so you you get assigned these tasks and then the teams can horse trade amongst other teams
And so if they got assigned a task it makes more sense for another on another scrum team than on theirs
They're allowed to trade these things across. Okay?
they have to go through the process of building a
Sprint plan breaking these things down into stories and at the end of it they say okay based off of our resourcing
These are the objectives we're gonna accomplish and before a single line of code and every sprint team has to do this
They say these are our objectives. We're gonna accomplish sprint by sprint and these are our stretch objectives
now the thing that I think is fascinating is
At the end of this there is a team that serves as the business team and they go sprint team by sprint team
They look at the objectives and then they score what's known as business value points
now that business value points
the value of that is is
Now so planning has gone through then we now have an execution plan
We now have a solid vision for the sprint now the business team is going through
They're realizing that what they were hoping for
Versus the reality of what's going to get delivered is now with they know that within a couple of days
in
Addition to because they have to go and put these business value points. They now communicate feedback back to
That's that
Scrum team each of your objective. This is what we think is the worth of these objectives
So even before a line of code you have a complete three month end-to-end plan
Including a fail fast opportunity. Was that too much? You didn't understand that no
I understood I not quite understand the segue from give people a framework that can work and then get out of their way
Yes, so it's it's it's it's not just good get out of their way
You still are accountable to be the representative for the business
Right and what this does is it gives it is a framework that
Allows management and the execution team to work copacetically together. Gotcha
The one thing I'd the other book I'll throw in there that you sprinkle in with the denning thing is the one-minute manager
Which is knowing yeah
When rather than manage all the time micromanage just know that even if you're out of their way
You have to pay enough attention to know when to dive in make course corrections before it's too late fail fast
Whatever you need to do jump in take care of the whatever correction you make and then step back out of the way
And that's frankly how I scale across a team of a large number of vector ports
How and it's not that I guess the thing the way you said it because a lot of the ways managers
Implement that and I've seen a lot of people do that. They do it in a reactive style. They're like, okay
I'm gonna give them the freedom freedom until they screwed up
This model tells it tells people up front
This is what we see
That's the value and what you're planning to produce
Yeah, I think and my love that pro activity and the ad that to build yeah, and I think that support
You do need to be proactive about not wait for recognize
Don't wait for it to fail completely but recognize that old things are a little off course. Let me as I've been here
Give a little coaching a lot of I do more coaching and then I do managing
Yeah, definitely
Anyway, I think we're about out of time, but this was a fun little digression into management. Thank you, right?
One last thing
Sure, thank you and you're welcome. Me neither as a manager
If you want to fake it till you make it and you don't know what you're doing
Then if there's only if there's one technique you could do that get you most of the way there
It's just study the Socratic method just ask questions
Okay, maybe more on that next time. Maybe all right. See I'm still Alan and
I-am-not
We'll see you next time. Bye