Hey everybody, howdy.
I'm Alan.
I'm Brent.
And we're here for another episode of A.B. testing.
What number are we, Brent?
I believe we're 73.
I believe you are correct.
Yeah.
We made it to 73, it's been a long time coming
and this is our last show of 2017, right?
It is.
Next time we talk to you, it'll be a whole new year.
Happy holidays everyone, happy new year.
All of those things, yeah.
How you been?
I'm tired.
I just, tired, I just got back from not just,
I was in Moscow last week.
Yeah, you know what, some of the questions
that you were sending me, made me a little concerned.
I'm like, huh, Alan needs to make it home.
We got the end of the year episode to do.
I had a lot of time in between talks
and at nights and things.
I was doing a bunch of work and I had some questions like,
hey, how can I do this thing?
What would you, mainly just kind of Brent
as a sounding board?
Oh, those weren't the ones that bothered me.
What were the questions that I asked you?
The ones that gave me an idea that you may choose
to be extra dramatic on your presentation.
You know, one of the things though,
so I saw your deck.
I'm always dramatic in my presentations.
I saw your deck.
A little bit of controversy never hurt anybody.
Sure, depending on where you are I think.
Yes, you saw my deck.
I thought the deck was, as usual, fantastically done.
The slide with introducing the modern tester.
I drew that guy.
No, and actually, the thing is is that that guy.
So Alan in this deck, if you haven't seen it,
we'll probably post a link to it.
Maybe.
Drew a stick figure.
And I will say it is one of the better stick figures
I've seen.
I think I could draw stick figures that good.
There was in high school, as an aside.
Tangent inception, thank you.
So in high school and in college,
you're required to take some sort of arts classes.
Theoretically, to round yourself out,
I'm sure you didn't have a problem with that.
Being a music major, I'm pretty certain that that counted.
So I always tended towards photography
because the way you do art with photography
is a little bit more scientific.
Exactly, it's a little bit more science-y.
How much light do I let in?
That's a science question.
Right.
And then it's about how you frame the shot.
And I always like doing sort of the different
sort of camera trick shots.
Like one of my favorite techniques was
taking the same picture three times,
but with a different lens.
So if you put a different color filter lens,
red, green, blue, and you take the same shot three times,
so you can set your camera typically,
well, this is old school cameras with film,
you can set it to not advance the film
until you want it to, you reduce the light
by obviously down to one third
because you're gonna take three shots.
But then what you do is you take it with a red filter,
then you move some stuff around,
then you take it with a green filter,
move stuff around again,
and then you take it with the blue filter,
and then you move stuff around.
And then what ends up happening is
the stuff you didn't move looks like a normal shot.
But the stuff you moved show up in your image
with the color of the filter that they were there.
That's cool, that's cool.
Very scientific formulaic approach to art, right?
Yeah, and then, I mean, there was another.
It's like following a recipe.
It is, it is.
It's by no means art, but it was fun,
and I guess that's part of art.
So this story came all out of the stick figure.
It did.
So I was talking to someone in Russia,
and luckily in English,
because my Russian is two words.
Da and what?
Spasiba.
It means thank you.
Oh, okay.
He says, I like your podcast.
Normally, I don't like when people do some banter
at the beginning of their podcast,
but with you guys, it's sometimes funny.
So I said, thank you.
Yeah, I mean, that's a higher bar
than we've been seeking, sometimes funny.
Indeed, indeed, indeed.
So there was something else I was gonna tell you.
Oh, I sent you some questions,
doing a lot of thinking and working over there,
both on my local team and on the presentation.
You can see that that's the presentation evolved
out of my technical testing presentation.
You can see it's, there's some remnants there,
but it's moved a lot forward.
And I will let you know, and the three know, asterisk,
that the stick figure and that slide will be returning
for my Test Bash Brighton talk
on the adventures of the modern day.
Oh, so yeah, you're not gonna pre-upload the deck.
This is, well, no, I can, I can, that's fine.
But definitely, as I started figuring out
what I was doing here at the, there at the conference
and like the message I wanted to send,
and basically, I originally went in with something closer
to my technical testing talk,
but the audience there was very technical.
There weren't a lot of this typical, at some conferences
and some circles of testers who were trying
to justify their job of refusing to be technical
or refusing to write code.
I mean, there's guys that, one of the presenters there
is one of the contributors to, I mean, actually,
contributors to Selenium, contributors to Jenkins.
There's some fairly technical people there.
So I had, I wanted to go a little bit different direction
and talk about the modern tester a little bit more.
So that's what I did.
That's why it evolved that direction.
And I was really happy with where it ended up.
But how was the feedback of the presentation?
I haven't got the verbatim feedback.
I got tons of questions afterwards, lots of,
of the, you know, 10 people I talked to,
they all really liked it.
But I don't know if the other 200 hated it or,
we'll find out.
Oh, the other thing I've been doing,
I haven't written, except for running through some tutorials,
pretty much zero code since I started at Unity.
And one of my team members pointed me to this thing
called Advent of Code.
And this thing in December where there's a new
problem solving thing every day.
And I've been running through those.
It's, there's a kind of a stupid story,
I think stupid's fair, that goes along with it.
The days are supposed to get progressively harder.
But for me, it's more of a jagged, unpredictable thing.
Like two days ago, I struggled.
I understood, took me a while to understand the directions.
Then I kind of understood the problem,
just like, I just couldn't get my head around it.
And I thought, okay, it's just, given that,
this is probably the last day I do.
Then last nights came out, it's like,
oh shit, that's easy.
I did it like in half hour.
So I will keep on doing it.
I'm already 15 days in, I only have 10 days to go.
I saw your tweet when you did the first day.
And I went and looked at it and I'm like,
oh that looks fun.
You don't have time, but you're in a break
between classes, you can do it now.
Yeah, but now I would have to, I mean,
can I go back and do the old days?
Yeah, for sure.
So I did actually the first puzzle of the first day.
So when you sent out the tweet, that was day one,
and I did the first puzzle.
I don't know how often it happens,
but there's, at least on day one,
because I haven't gone to day two.
Here's the question.
What language did you do it in?
In this instance, like that first one,
I actually did it in Excel.
I did day three in Excel.
That's an Excel problem, I'll just do it there.
This is the weird thing working at Microsoft for so long.
I never really learned C-sharp.
I mean, I used it, but I wrote very procedural C-sharp,
didn't use much of the language.
I learned C-sharp and as listeners,
a long time listeners will recall,
I spent time as a dev lead.
But the last time someone commented on my C-sharp skills,
their phrasing was literally,
Brent, you have mad .NET 2.0 skills.
And this was at a time when 5.0 had already been chipped.
I've been learning a lot.
My C-sharp kind of sucks, but I'm getting better.
I learned link.
I wanted to never learn how it works
and it's some places where I thought it would work
and I kind of learned it.
I'm learning a lot, I'm not very good at it.
I have full admission.
Last night when I saw problem 15, day 15,
I looked at it and said.
I'm linking that up.
No, no, I thought, I know how to do this in C.
I wonder how long it'll take me to learn it in C-sharp.
And then I thought for about literally,
it felt like a long time, it was like half a second.
I said, screw it, I'm doing it in C.
So I did day 15 in C.
C++ actually.
C++ is something that I never really mastered.
I could code all day long in C,
but no one does that anymore,
except for maybe at school, at colleges.
I'm waiting, because C is unfortunately,
at this point, still my strongest language.
So I'm hoping that someday there'll be a shortage
of C programmers and I can step up and make bank.
Sure.
Okay.
Yeah, the thing is, what was it?
I was talking to a mentee the other day
and they had gone through a interview
and I don't want this to go into a rant
because this is our big end of year show.
Way to foreshadow there.
Yeah.
This guy got rejected because he stated in a dev interview,
what I think, what I definitely agreed to be true.
And that is, once you understand how coding works,
the language is irrelevant.
That's absolutely true.
Yeah, so.
Did someone slam him on that?
Yeah, because he didn't know whatever language,
Java or JavaScript or whatever the language
that that guy wanted him to know, but he knew coding.
He knew how to do it in Python.
He knew how to do it in C sharp.
That statement you made is absolutely correct.
I would question the abilities
of anyone who disagreed with him.
I, yeah.
I told him, I'm like, hey, how long,
I asked him, he didn't know,
but how long do you think that guy has been in his position?
Because it's a behavior I see from people who,
you know, have just recently been promoted to management.
Right?
This is a, there's a belief that all I have to do
is keep doing what I did.
Because that's why they promoted me.
No.
And it takes a while for a new manager to realize,
no, what got me here isn't going to get me there.
All right, I could rant as well,
but I think instead.
I told this guy that, hey, don't worry about it,
because if that's how the,
like literally that guy did you a favor.
You don't want to work on that team.
No kidding.
Yeah.
And I'm going to curb my rant over this
and the causes that may happen.
And perhaps suggest that we start the show.
All right, let's do that.
Okay, it is our every year,
like we've been doing it for a long time.
This is our third, I don't think we did it the first year.
Maybe we did.
I don't remember.
But anyway, we are, end of year recap.
No, we did.
Okay.
We for sure did it our first year
because we started in March.
Coming up April, coming up on our,
now I forgot what I was doing
because Bright interrupted me.
But that's okay, that's what we do on this show.
End of the year show.
End of the year show, we're going to
have a little intro to, a re-intro to A-B testing.
If this is your first episode, raise your hand.
Put your hand back on the car wheel.
A little re-intro to A-B testing for any new listeners.
We're going to take a look back at the predictions
we slash Brent made for 2017
because I've forgotten mine.
Well, a little bit of a year in review,
kind of what happened with A-B testing over the years,
over the last year.
And then finally our predictions for 2018.
Sound good?
Yep, let's do it.
Okay, so the first thing is, there's a couple little
perhaps inside jokes, not jokes, inside statements,
things that maybe a new listener wouldn't understand.
So Brent, explain the title, A-B testing.
Is it about experimentation?
Sure.
Actually, no.
It is.
You are a crappy cohort.
No, so for those who haven't listened
and actually, we have seen on Twitter
that actually there's at least one person
that both Alan and I are aware of
that has started on recent episodes and going backwards.
They'll discover the inside language very quickly.
So A-B testing is essentially,
it's a, in my view, it's a double entendre.
It is number one, it stands for Alan and Brent testing.
There's no slash in the A-B testing.
But when we first started the show,
for those who haven't listened,
both Alan and I, I think we still were both in test.
No, I wasn't at that point in time.
But we both saw that data was becoming more prevalent.
So I thought the name A-B testing
would not only allow us to sort of cover
the testing sort of themes,
but it would be a great name that would allow us
to carry on and go into data science-y themes.
And I think it's proven out correct.
Very happy with the name.
So A-B testing, Alan and Brent,
sometimes about A-B experimentation.
Sometimes, yes.
All right.
I think we had two episodes where you were talking about,
you talking about actual.
Yeah, since we've been giving this podcast,
I gave, at one point,
I was asked to come in at the last minute
fill in for someone who canceled giving a talk
on A-B testing at a dev conference in Las Vegas.
And the talk went well enough that they asked me
to come back and give a regular workshop on A-B testing,
which I did a couple, maybe two years ago.
Nice.
So yeah, and that's where I,
I like doing that because I could talk about it
and I threw out like math terms that Brent said,
oh my God, Alan may actually know what he's doing.
Even if he doesn't, he used the correct math term.
Like, you know, hey, fake it till you make it.
Story of my career.
You're there to teach.
So there's another.
It's irrelevant whether or not
you know what you're teaching.
There's another term we throw out.
We reference the three or one of the three all the time.
Yep.
Brent, what does that mean?
What is all that about?
Oh, that's in reference to the fact
that we are just a low production crappy podcast
and have only three listeners.
Look, we are a high production crappy podcast.
When we first started, we joked a lot
about our three listeners.
In fact, we knew them
because they were mostly Microsoft people.
And so we joked about our three listeners
and when someone asked a question,
we sure it was one of the three.
And while we know there are many more
than three listeners now,
we still like to refer to our listeners
and thank you very much for listening, by the way.
If you're listening still,
if you haven't given up on this podcast,
for being one of the three,
even though three has turned into a metaphor for many.
So we refer to the three a lot.
It will always be part of our nomenclature,
but the three refers to all of our listeners.
Yes.
And probably worth mentioning is
because we don't have,
and this is probably a prediction
or a goal or a work item for 2018,
we should probably have some small bios
on the A-B testing site.
But then again, most people just subscribe to the podcast
and don't actually go to the website.
But we both worked at Microsoft for a long time.
Brent still works at Microsoft.
And I work at Unity Technologies.
Focusing on quality, but from a data perspective
on something we call the modern tester,
which we've talked about many times on the show.
I'm not gonna give a recap of that,
but I think it's something that will probably come up
in just about every show for a while.
Yeah.
And Brent is a principal data science manager
at Data Science Manager at Microsoft still.
And we get together every few weeks
and record this podcast.
If you're a new listener,
that's kind of the gist of who we are.
Let's get on to the meat of the show,
which is, was it predictions from last year?
You're not gonna do number one?
Number one is part of the predictions from last year.
Oh, you wanna do predictions from last year?
Okay. Yeah.
Gotcha.
Okay, so I'm gonna read them here
cause I have them in front of me.
2017 predictions from Brent.
And again, I don't remember mine.
And last year's prediction show had horrible audio
and I had to cut them off.
Something weird happened.
I'm blaming it on Microsoft.
Number one, Brent, we will finally have
A-B testing branded gear on Cafe Press.
Did that happen?
It did.
Actually, it did.
I think I've only told Brent
and those on our Slack team,
one of the three.slack.com,
DM me, Alan Page, A-L-A-N-P-A-G-E on Twitter
with your email address and I'll get you signed up.
But we have a Cafe Press store, minimal right now.
Happy to take feedback any way you can get a hold of me
if you want to see different items.
I don't have much or really any influence on the price.
I think I've already knocked everything down
so we're making zero off of those
cause if you want A-B testing stuff,
you should be able to buy it.
And Brent is here by the way
with an A-B testing coffee cup and polo shirt today.
Yes.
So I'm fairly certain we have made two sales so far.
That is excellent.
But just in time, you can, I think,
if you order today,
today meaning whenever I get this episode out,
maybe you'll get it in time for Christmas.
I don't know.
But before I forget,
and I'll guarantee I'll put this in the show notes,
it's just cafepress.com,
WAC, A-B testing.
Yeah, and again, Alan and I have talked about it.
We're not making any money on that.
As Alan was saying,
we kind of do this because we find it fun
and we like to help influence change
in these particular industries.
We're not here to turn a buck.
If for some reason you're interested in it,
it's now available, knock yourself out.
We went through,
no, that's probably pretty early,
but I'll give a pre-step.
Like one of the things I think was the coolest thing,
one of the coolest things we did this last year
is all the logo rebranding stuff.
Yeah, let's just jump topics completely
into the year in review.
Sure.
We'll bounce back and forth.
That's what I just did.
Yeah, thanks.
Right, but yeah,
so there's been some discussion on the Slack channel
that maybe someday we'll put together an A-B conference.
And if we do that,
then we'll probably have to go someplace
other than cafepress
because to print out and produce swag.
I'm not thinking that far ahead,
but as far as the main point Brent was making,
yeah, we occasionally, as you know,
we will have advertisers on the show
and who give us a little bit of coin our way,
which mainly goes towards recording equipment,
hosting stickers that we sent out
to many of the listeners that asked for them,
things like that.
It goes back to essentially you guys.
Absolutely.
Let's get on with your predictions.
Okay, so one of the things,
and I think it's aligned with what you just said,
one of the most common things that happened
in the last few years is people are pinging us now,
hey, Brent, what episode did you talk about this
or that thing?
And I go, oh dear God, I don't know.
Someone should frickin' title these damn things.
I predict that I will actually get off my lazy ass
and actually title the episodes.
In addition to that, I'm gonna get them transcribed.
We have a whole topic on the whiteboard
on predictions, on last year's predictions,
and then the year in review,
and then our predictions for 2018,
but you don't seem to care about any sort of order.
Oh, you're talking about our last year's predictions.
You said predictions.
All right, fine.
Yeah, you're right.
I don't care about order.
Let me get back into the order carrying mode.
Let's just retitle, screw A B testing.
We'll just call this podcast My Co-host is a Moron.
Welcome to the My Co-host is a Moron podcast.
I'm Alan.
So back on 2019.
All right, so our year in review,
our last year's predictions.
Let's go back.
I'm gonna read them to you
so you don't get so damn confused, all right?
All right.
Number one, we did it, yes.
Yeah, we have a cafe press store,
cafepress.com, like A B testing.
Brent says he will finally graduate.
Have you graduated?
No.
Are you about to graduate?
I have, I...
One more quarter, right?
Two more?
I await the results as to whether or not
I have passed this current class,
and if I have, then I have one class left.
I'm sure you passed.
Congratulations, Brent.
Yep.
Dev learning knowledge, machine learning,
is required at most schools for comp sci.
I don't know if that's...
I haven't researched that.
I don't know if that's true or not.
I definitely think that will happen at some point.
I do think it's growing up.
And it could just be because I sit right next
to our machine learning team at Unity,
but it seems there's a lot more emphasis.
And it could be, there's a bias
where I may just notice machine learning
and AI more in the news and articles.
We'll talk more about that,
but it is not just a bias.
Okay.
Yeah.
Deep learning will finally hit buzzword status.
I don't know if it did or not, man.
No, it's actually, it not only hasn't hit buzzword status,
or it did, and it went through it pretty quickly.
Like, now, back a year ago,
people were talking about it all the time.
Now it's just like, eh, another AI thing.
Okay.
Yeah.
All right.
So the prediction was around data-driven testing.
I don't know.
All right.
Well, there was a prediction.
Well, I'm gonna assume it came through then.
So this year, I'm looking over at the recording,
and I'm not seeing all the buzzy things
that were popping in last year.
So we may actually get all the way
to our predictions this time,
if the clock doesn't run out and a Brent can stay on track.
So not a wonderful recap of last year's predictions
because we couldn't quite remember them,
but we got the cafe press store up
and stuff is moving along.
I don't know if we'll have predictions
as much as goals this year.
I may think of something in the spur of the moment
coming up here in about 15 minutes, but.
Yep.
Let's go ahead and do you wanna talk,
do you mind talking about 2017
and kind of everything that happened?
Or can I start?
Do you wanna start?
How do you want?
No, so 2017, big year for us.
We had multiple different sponsors
interested in reaching out.
We had, I'm gonna go ahead and give another free shout out.
So a lot of, we had Star on the show several times
for each of their conferences with promo codes.
We had Cobitan on the show a couple times
with some promo codes.
And we're going to have some new sponsors in 2018.
And again, one thing about our sponsors is,
as I said before, we're not here to make a buck.
So when someone approaches us about sponsorship,
it's always like, is this a product that I would use?
Maybe not one that I can use now,
but if I was testing the sort of thing
that this helps me with,
or if I had the sort of problem
this is supposed to help solve,
is this something I would consider?
So we're.
Or is it something we think our listeners
would actually use?
Yeah, absolutely.
So we do try and be careful about those things.
We'll have a few more in,
and if you're listening and you would like us
to advertise for whatever you're showing,
we're pretty cheap.
Because again, thought about making money.
It's about paying for web hosting,
trying to keep great A-B testing episodes
continuing to come.
Speaking of which, this is not a sponsor,
but if any of you are thinking
of getting into audiobooks,
of course you can go to Audible,
audible.com, WAC A-B testing.
This is Alan jumping in during post-production.
The actual link is audibletrial.com,
WAC A-B testing.
Thanks.
Check out and just use that.
You'll get the first month free
and you can check it out.
Yeah.
I've been thinking about,
I normally don't like audiobooks.
I normally have a problem with audiobooks
because I can read faster.
But I've been,
that read faster. Can you?
I can usually read faster
than I can have the book read to me.
But I've been running a lot in 2017.
My goal was to run 510 miles,
which would have been 10 miles
for every year I was alive.
I turned 52 last month.
Deep into the tangents,
which for new listeners we're famous for,
between travel and the new job and things,
I don't think I'm gonna quite make it.
I'm around 460 right now.
I'm not sure I can get 50 miles in
before the end of the year.
10 miles every other day.
Done, dude.
Yeah.
But I've been thinking,
I've been getting kind of burned out listening to music.
Podcasts, I usually run longer than the podcast last.
I was thinking maybe about getting into audiobooks
and listening to books while I run.
I'll keep the listeners posted.
And again, if you do wanna hit that goal,
you'll have plenty of time.
If you wanna hit your running goal for the year,
you have plenty of time.
I have two weeks.
Right.
So back in the day when I was actually in cross country,
when we were in training season,
we'd run a minimum of 10 miles every day.
Yeah.
I'm old.
It's hard for me to go that far on a daily basis.
All right.
Okay, I will do my best.
I will be your pro fan.
So let me talk a little bit about 2017 from my perspective.
Go ahead.
The first episode last year
is when I announced I was leaving Microsoft.
In fact, it was just almost exactly a year ago
when I accepted the offer at Unity.
Wow, what a year it's been.
That year went by fast.
It did, didn't it?
And then we had a show on my very last day
at Microsoft on a Friday,
and Brent brought in some wonderful tequila,
which we drank on the air at eight in the morning.
So that was a fun day.
It was a fun day.
I had early in my Unity career,
I had the realization that what I run
isn't an organization as much as a community.
I was very, very proud of my ability to recognize that.
And then later in the year,
I went and reread Agile Testing,
the Chris Ben Gregory book that we both like a lot.
There was a chapter right in there
that said just like in one paragraph,
it talked about the exact same thing,
how it's more of a community.
I think this is the year, 2017,
if you take it all up, I think it's the year
from our perspective of the modern testers.
And yeah, because I want-
And I think all of it kind of fed into it.
You going into this, you realizing like,
hey, I wanna start something new.
I want these guys to be heading in the correct direction.
What is it?
And I think as you and I have talked on the air
and off air around what you're going through,
we've sort of formalized the sort of concept.
Yeah, and when we think about modern testing,
it definitely is a huge basis,
huge Venn diagram with Agile Testing.
Yeah, for sure.
With some plus pluses in there.
And I talked to my whole team knows that
the way I look at my role is I run this community,
I am in the process of slowly moving,
in fact, not slowly,
I moved a big chunk of my org to not report to me.
So we changed the dotted lines and the solid lines.
And they're still part of my community,
they're gonna report to other people.
Eventually, I'd like every one of my org
to report to other people,
and I will still run the community.
I will still coach them and help them,
help them educate developers they work with.
And then eventually,
when that community can become self-sustaining,
then my role is no longer needed.
And that is, I think,
the natural evolution of modern testing,
where the testers actually become full,
they don't need a director of quality
to help them be successful in their job.
They know enough about how to make things work,
and they've influenced the dev team,
and the dev team understands
how to leverage a quality and testing expert,
and what full team quality ownership looks like,
and how to use data,
and those things are just natural to how they work.
I am absolutely not needed.
And everybody knows that won't happen tomorrow,
or next week, or next month, or probably next year,
but they also agree that the direction makes sense.
Yeah, and the thing I think
that's particularly great about this,
and I've seen it over and over again,
the number one thing that slows down Agile
is command and control.
And if you wanna get your team to spin up,
you gotta have brave,
I don't know why it takes brave leaders,
but it seems to,
you have to have brave leaders that are like,
no, I am going to direct
the removal of command and control from the system.
So slight tangent rant.
Is there a tan rant, tangent rant, tangent rant?
Rangent?
Rangent, I don't know.
Okay.
So many times I see either one or the other,
or a combination of the two of Agile doesn't work,
and here's why,
and they explain what they're doing is not even Agile at all.
And then a focus in Agile on the iteration
versus the adaptation.
What I'm talking about in my role is purely adaptive.
It's the way the org should adapt to being more efficient.
The way the org should adapt to a word
we've used a lot this year,
accelerating a phrase,
accelerating the achievement of shippable quality.
We've actually talked about specialists as well,
and it occurs to me, right?
What is the head of a command and control system?
They're essentially a specialist in decision making
for that business context.
Specialists or bottlenecks in this Agile world?
I think so, yeah, absolutely.
Right.
If you,
like you say you're gonna work to remove your job,
and at some point in time, maybe you will,
but maybe also Unity grows,
and instead you end up having to scale
to several hundred or several thousand people, right?
That should be fine because you're shooting out principles.
It's adaptation.
It's looking at the context and adapting.
It's not, like I have a map in place
and I know that I talk a lot about current state
and desired state, and desired state is a moving target,
and that's fine.
I think the key to success in any sort of knowledge work,
but in software where I tend to have some specialization,
is in willing to be adaptive
and not getting stuck into a formulaic rights.
Yep.
We also talked, in talking about modern testing,
couple of my favorite episodes,
maybe my second favorite is the time machine episode
where Brent pretended to be a traditional test manager.
That was fun.
And I was the modern test manager,
and Brent tried to tell me how stupid he was,
and I tried to tell you how easy my life was,
and it was a good time.
But my favorite episode was episode 60.
Yep.
That's a shared favorite.
It is.
I think we managed to capture a lot of the things
we really care about and are passionate about
in a way that actually made sense.
So if you're working your way backward or jumping around,
60 is one that we recommend.
Yeah, if you're only gonna listen to one episode,
stop listening to this one right now,
and go to 60.
Yeah, no, I was particularly proud of that episode.
I think we really gelled a bunch of concepts together.
It really inspired a lot of conversation
on the Slack channel and other places.
And what I'm particularly happy about is,
what I observed from some of our listeners
is it really inspired action.
A lot of people were sitting around and going,
oh, well, I got time so I can do it.
And what I see is it really got people going,
you know what, I actually don't know how much time I have,
and even if I have a lot of time,
it seems like going down this approach
is gonna make my life better anyway.
And I know, for example,
there's one of our listeners that's actually doing
in his job now several of the things
that we have described on the podcast.
There's more than one, at least,
because one thing is weird, at Microsoft,
we have some listeners at Microsoft,
but when I was at Microsoft, nobody on my team,
except for maybe one occasionally,
would ever listen to the podcast.
But I have, as we've been going on here,
I've been growing the listeners among my team,
which makes me a little self-conscious,
but I don't think I've said anything to embarrass them
or incriminate them or me, so I think it's all right.
But I have listeners on my team, in my community.
None of my coworkers, employees listen,
and I think it's fairly clear why.
They get enough of listening to me babble day to day,
why would they wanna do more of it?
Yeah, and a lot of my team, of course,
because they're embedded in another team,
they interact with me for a half hour to an hour a week
during one-on-ones usually.
My leads get a little bit more time in general,
but they don't hear me babble all the time.
So maybe this is their chance.
So it's an opportunity for them to maybe understand
some of the things that you're saying better.
Sure, sure, sure.
I want to, before we get run out of time,
go ahead and dive forward into some predictions
and comments about, I don't know if it's predictions,
goals, things I think they're gonna happen in 2018.
And maybe, do you just wanna go back and forth?
You wanna give one or I'll give one,
and we'll go till we run out of time?
Sure.
Do you wanna start?
I'm gonna start.
Well, so one of the things that we normally did,
and it got truncated off as we try to predict
what episode this show will be next year.
So we did 22 episodes this last year.
We did 22 episodes.
And I think that's one of the more productive years
we've done.
I'm gonna guess it's our most productive year.
Yep, I didn't do that analysis.
I could do that math,
but I'm gonna pretty much say that's right.
But I vaguely recall, it got clipped off,
but I vaguely recall that we predicted
that we would be somewhere in the 70s this time around.
But we don't have proof.
I can't remember last week, let alone last year.
But one of the things I was thinking about is,
so I will say,
we will not do episode 100 next year.
That is correct.
And I will say, but we'll get really darn close.
So I am hoping, now I have a,
I'm gonna go beyond that prediction.
I'm hoping we're kinda close to 22 next year.
And then I did the math right.
I'm not gonna do it out for you on the air,
but we started the podcast in early April.
So this April will be our four year anniversary.
So we have a reasonable chance,
this is looking ahead to 2019,
assuming we're both still alive,
we have a reasonable chance of hitting episode 100
on our fifth anniversary of podcasting.
And that would be kind of awesome.
There would definitely be a deal of it.
No, we could do that, but I think we're gonna be
like 99 by the end of next year.
If we do 22 episodes next year, we'll be at?
98.
What do we have, 73?
No, 95.
95.
Then we do two in January, 96, 97.
Two in February, 98, 99.
March, we take off.
Ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha.
We'll see what happens, it'll be close.
So it'll happen around the right times.
But yeah, I think you're about right.
And actually, I traveled a lot,
we had some cancellations, we got in 22,
which I think is...
So I'm gonna predict that we will not do
as good as next year as we did this year.
And I'll predict that this episode,
this time next year, will be episode 90.
I'm gonna say it's going to be 92.
Okay.
All right, we'll...
All right, your prediction.
This, I think 2018 is the year of modern testing.
And I'm gonna elaborate on that.
I think it's a term we've used a lot
to describe what we think the future
of the quality specialist rule is.
Right now, today, if you were to go to moderntesting.org,
you would get redirected to angryweasel.com,
WackAB testing.
One of the things I like to do with,
not overflowing, but with our funds
and our bank account,
and paying for some transcription of our episodes,
is hosting for moderntesting.org
and turning that into a real website
with information around modern testing.
And I think...
A community site.
A community site, just with information,
with links, we'll put links to videos.
At the online test conference,
Danny Fott just gave a talk about modern testing,
links to YouTube videos like that.
Links to my decks on modern testing, to your stuff.
Of course, a link to the AB testing podcast.
I think I'd like for that in 2018
for moderntesting.org to become a real website.
And for, I think, my prediction is
we will see more references to modern testing as a thing.
And maybe I'll rephrase it this way.
In 2018, modern testing becomes, air quote, a thing.
Okay, that's a good prediction.
I actually...
That's more of a goal than a prediction,
but I'm gonna go for it, we'll see what happens.
Well, so a lot of it is out of your control, right?
It assumes that our content is good enough
and other people contribute and it goes viral.
So at the online test conference,
I don't recall his last name,
but Jesper also talked about the AP testing podcast.
I haven't seen that deck or heard his presentation.
So I don't know what the content was.
But I assume...
He was talking a lot about the shift left concept.
Okay, so that's probably aligned with the modern tester.
It is, I don't like that term shift left.
I think it's kind of, anyway, as an aside, I...
But I had almost written down
and I was trying to figure out how I could evaluate this
and see if it's reasonable.
But my instinct, so I guess this is literally
a baseless prediction.
And it's similar to what you're saying,
is my prediction is sometime in the next two years
and perhaps as early as next year,
we see a tipping point in the job title
of software test engineer
and that the rate that those jobs get opened
starts to go on the decline.
Yeah, I think that's a tough one
because there's so many trailing companies.
There are companies today that are going,
hey, maybe we need SDets.
Yeah, and again, it's entirely baseless.
I spent a good hour looking for how could I trend this?
How could I evaluate it?
I thought about going to like on air and say,
okay, here's how we can start doing it.
As of this point in time, I'm going to monster.com
and I'm typing software test engineer,
oh look, there's 43,000 jobs available.
Let's see what happens next year.
Yeah, and my team's going through,
I'm having a thought discussion,
I exercised my team to try and think of,
if we were to have new titles,
what would that new title be?
And that's going through a lot of vetting right now.
Don't do test, Ninja.
No, absolutely not.
All right, but that I didn't put down,
but I do have a sense that it's coming soon
because it feels a lot,
like the global environment to me,
feels a lot like it did when it began to start here.
Lots of discussion around this thing.
We're seeing visibility into around the world.
People are having these type of conversations,
hey, does this make sense that we change?
And once those solidify,
the tipping point really begins to happen.
My number one prediction is similar.
This is the, similar to what we talked about last,
that machine learning would be a product required curriculum.
I actually see next year AI is democratized
and service development knowledge of how to use ML APIs.
The simple ones is common
and use all, the majority of service developers
are perfectly comfortable calling ML APIs
and they don't need to do the rich data science
validation stuff that I do.
Along those same lines,
I think that 2018 is the year when we begin to see
machine learning officially creep its way
into test automation.
It's already in.
Not mainstream.
Oh, mainstream, yeah.
I think it's something that's recognized.
There will be tool vendors beginning to come out
with machine learning algorithms
or machine learning to apply to test automation,
whether it's from current test automation vendors
or widely used open source things
used with existing test automation solutions.
For example, use FUBAR machine learning with your selenium
to make your tests more robust and get more coverage.
I think that makes sense.
I think that will happen this next year.
And if it does,
then I think the tipping point discussion I just had
is far more likely.
Someone at, in one of my questions
after my automation talk at Heisenberg,
someone asked, will machine learning replace the need
for manual testers?
I said, well, indirectly because machine learning
will reduce the need for automated testers.
People who write test automation,
not people who are automated by testing.
Machine learning will reduce the need
for people to write test automation.
There will be less test automation needed.
I said it better then.
Yeah.
You and I are aware of many different projects
that are now like 15 years old
within Microsoft that was using AI for test functions.
There was one that was using genetic algorithms
quite successfully to find bugs all the time,
but it was horrible at determining
is this an important bug or not.
That's because this was in a on-prem,
this was in a different world.
Yeah.
It didn't have access to customer usage information.
Right.
That's where the marriage comes in.
That's the way exactly what I described at Heisenberg.
I said, we're really close with the democratization
and the ubiquitousness of customer data,
being able to use that as a feed
along with our test inputs and our test knowledge,
those things are going to marry
and actually use machine learning to find bugs
that actually matter and find them quickly
and find a lot of them.
Right.
I'm actually thinking about my own project right now
and I'm like, you know what?
I know my dev managers, the directors,
I talk to them all the time
and I know that they would find this valuable
and I think actually this wouldn't be too hard.
All right, back on track here.
Give me another prediction.
I will finally graduate.
You will finally graduate, yes.
And I will reboot blogging.
On reboot, I don't know to what degree.
As you know, I own my blog site brand right now,
but as you also know,
I no longer really identify with my blog site brand
so a reboot may be necessary.
Yeah, but that will happen.
Trying to think if I have another one.
It's a self-fulfilling prediction.
I'm going to let you go on.
All right, and then I would say the last
and absolutely the most important is
I predict over the next year
that Kylo Ren will be revealed as Darth Reven.
Doesn't Star Wars come out today?
It does.
Yeah.
As a matter of fact, I'm going to be,
my butt's going to be sitting down watching it
in two and a half hours.
That's awesome.
I will head out sometime over the break.
You don't want to weigh in on the Reven controversy?
No, no.
All right, I get it.
You want to play it safe.
I do want to play it safe.
We'll see what happens there.
We are out of time.
Anything else you want to cover here?
No, we're good.
All right, I hope you've enjoyed 2017 with A-B testing.
I look forward to you hearing more of us in 2018
and please email us tweets, Slack messages.
Let us know what you want to hear about
and we're always happy to share our opinions.
Yep, and if you're in Europe,
I don't think it's too late to go see Alan in Brighton.
I'll be in Brighton in March, Test Bash.
Yep.
Free plug.
All right, I am the Alan part of A-B testing.
And I am not.
All right, we'll see you next time.