Brent almost spoke first, but I dove in ahead on the microphone and the cool thing is is that even if you would have spoken first
This morning. I would have edited you out
Cuz I'm a dick and I'm Brent
My
Goodness. Oh my goodness. So we are here for episode
66 double sixes double sixes I guess sixes
There's a friend of mine
This is total non. Well, it's tangential. I'm not gonna call a total non sequitur
His friend was in a band and the name of one of their albums was six six eight the neighbor of the beast
On the same side of the street
Hey
So we're gonna say something I was okay cool any exciting adventures in your life this week
Not so far week was pretty pretty straightforward. I'm heading to Helsinki today. Oh
So not yet
Not yet flying to Chicago shy town spending an hour and a half hour and a half there in the lovely airport and then flying from
There to Helsinki shy town Chicago. Oh got chai town. Yeah. Yeah, whatever
one thing speaking of so you're kicking off your kick-ass day of
Travel yeah
Travel I'm all packed, you know, I cannot invent
self
dry self
propelling everything fast enough and
Personal self propelling everything fast enough or teleportation after we record here
I'm heading into the office just long enough to pack up my desk and move it about 20 feet away
I'm giving my desk
I have a new hire starting on my team
The Monday when I get back and I'm giving my desk to him so he can sit closer to the rest of the team
I'm sort of it's I'm overhead ish I can be moved anywhere. Yeah, that I completely understand
I do the same thing. Hey, I don't know if I've mentioned this and I'm pretty sure I haven't to you even
fairly close within a thousand miles proximity to Helsinki is
Moscow and I am heading to the Heisenberg testing conference in Moscow this December
Okay, are you gonna be hanging out in Helsinki until that time? No, I'm coming back
But I forgot I'm giving a talk. I'm gonna give
spin on my technical testing
Talk as a keynote. I started editing that yesterday because I'm gonna do another spin on it
I can't give the same exact same talk twice
So I was gonna make some small tweaks because I'm actually giving a talk when I'm in Helsinki and a meetup there
There are already like 50 people signed up at the Unity offices should be fun
I'm going to do a spin on technical testing talk I gave for the online testing conference. I
Started making some tweaks and ended up kind of redoing the whole presentation, which is good for me because it keeps it fresh
I like to change it and I'll probably do the same thing for Heisenberg
I'm also going to give a talk on the use and abuse of test automation
Which is?
Obviously related to part of my rant in that I'll make sure there's a good separation between the two for the talk
Are you gonna throw in some over the top embellishments?
for example
The reason why I ask will make the example super clear to you. Anyway, I
Think the testing community is is at a loss
Now that Whitaker is focused on how AI is gonna change. Oh, that's right
Nobody's being mad and with Bach kind of out of the picture to nobody's really out there causing controversy
Even when I go try and cause controversy and say things like the role of test automator is going away
I are I have people like Richard Bradshaw who make a living doing test automation going. Yeah, you're pretty much, right?
Or the role of tests is as information providers is going away. Yeah
like I mean
You're gonna have to like there's it there's an there is a hole there
I think you can fill it but you're gonna have to step up your game on there is
Let me think about it may not be the right audience to do that
but in my head, I just visit I just visualized a
Normal distribution curve. Yeah, and
with modern testing sort of being in the
Towards the front end of that wave of the curve, but keeping in mind that a lot of testing is
Back there right as I as I gesture
Yeah, no, no, you're I mean you're you're in the
You're in and from Mike's
Knowledge of it you're near
Outlier on the the normal distribution, but you're not there yet. You're still kind of in the oh, yes is normal
But you know high on the normal range got a ways to go. Yeah, get a ways. I mean, it's fine much
You just got to be more you know plus plus on drama. All right, I will work on the drama
Hey, so I have something that was exciting this week. Oh, hey, Brent. Did you have anything exciting this week? Hey, yes
I did. Thank you for asking Alan
I'm a sucky co-host
My mother-in-law is right
You you're like you're like mom look there's a reason why the podcast starts with a
Anyway, no
There is speaking of
Vacuous holes there is now a vacuous hole in one of the bedrooms in my house
You mentioned your last in the last episode that you're approaching a
Partial empty nest
Hey, has it become the man cave yet? No, actually what we're gonna do is my a sewing room
No, my my middle son. Mm-hmm
Is gonna move into that in terms of like real estate
And not the master. That's the best of the non master bedrooms. Ah
So someone's getting an upgrade someone's getting an upgrade like yeah, that was an interesting experience
It's kind of like when someone leaves like if someone leaves the team
Like if it's a good office someone will immediately claim it versus let the new guy have it
Yeah, so just a couple of nutshell things that I learned from the experience
first and foremost
he's going to school in wazoo and
From where we're at that is a five and a half hour drive one way
Yep, unless it's winter then it's 12. I took
Wednesday off and I did that trip in one day there help them unpack back
That was extremely unpleasant
Yeah, because it's not all for those
Even Washingtonians wouldn't know that necessarily but it's not even freeway the whole way a big chunk of the trip
It's just on a two-lane road
Yeah, yeah. Well, I mean
There's a thing I found the most interesting. So my son
while he was at at home the last few years he generally liked to spend most of his time in his room and
I've been prepping for empty nest syndrome for like the last three years
But when the day hits you no matter prep makes a difference
Right, so you talked last time like hey, yeah, no, I've
I've been since before the kids were born. I've been looking forward to when they leave and
You know what when you're in the moment
All of that stuff that you hold on to like I can't wait till they leave goes out the window
It was it was and I'm generally
Generally my EQ is quite low
People go. Oh, thank you. Carry much about me and I'm like, yeah
What is faking?
But with him
It was an interesting
For me. I'm just I had like a 10-minute speech that I wanted to talk to him as sort of the final words of daddiness and
That took me a good 40 minutes to get out
I
Print I've never known you to be long-winded. No, it wasn't was those long wind I was I kept on choking up
Yeah
and then going home
I go home and
It's still instinctive. I'm like, oh
Alex's cars not here. I wonder where he is. Oh
Anyway, yeah, that was
Life changing moments in the gentle, you know minor rites of passage
This is my first one through it and I'm like, oh, this is interesting
I got a ways to go any prediction on what episode we're on when my soon to be eighth grader goes off to college
So four years maybe two hundred two
Can you imagine? Yeah. All right
Like your youngest
My youngest is going into seventh grade. Yeah, I'm actually thinking like when my youngest
Goes goes off. We'll probably be done with the podcast cuz you'll have been dead by then probably yeah. Yeah. Yeah
love the support
Hey, you know, I'm just a couple years away from being all about ageism
No, you ageist like I'll be joining your party. Yeah
although I have to say and
You can't tell on the podcast but I look much younger than Brad
Yes, he does. All right. Yeah. Hey
Once again, I would like to thank the fine folks at Techwell and star conferences for sponsoring this episode of a B testing
That's it
Kidding I'm kidding. I'm kidding. So I am
excited to say that
Star Canada is returning to Toronto. You've been to Toronto. I have not great city. They have a great soccer team
I haven't even been to Canada in
Probably 20 years. Oh really? Yeah, I gave a few talks at Star Canada in Vancouver
Three years ago. It was just a fact. I love they take such good terror speakers. It's a great conference
Always a big fan of the star conferences. So returning to downtown Toronto in October
Which means that it's playoff time and Toronto FC are definitely making the playoffs
Just in case those two coincide I will stop I will stop promoting Toronto FC who are not a sponsor of this podcast and get back
To star so Toronto in October is star Canada
If you've not yet attended a star conference, there has never been a better time to join the fun
And I agree it will have over 50 testing sessions to choose from for a week packed with learning and networking
Opportunities and I would like to emphasize that luck always lots of great information in the talks
I think the networking and talking to people and spending time
Talking to other testers talking to speakers is a huge part of the value you get from a conference
conferring
Talking is so important
There will be keynotes from recognized thought leaders Dorothy Graham Graham who wrote a couple books on test automation been in testing for a while
Very knowledgeable Jeffrey Payne
Good. I've met Jeffrey a few times
Knows a ton about agile. I'll just put it that way. I'm really really really respect him Isabel Evans and Janet Gregory
Who is Lisa Christmas co-author on the agile testing books?
Also for the first time at Star Canada, there will be a test lab where you can break software air quotes for a good cause
In fact, the test lab is partnering with play-doh testing an organization truly making a social impact by helping the Aboriginal people of Canada
Become experts in software testing
Students from play-doh testing will be attending star Canada on scholarship and will be assisting other attendees while in the test lab
That sounds fun. I love if you've been to a conference and they do like a test lab
I love diving into this. I love getting an excuse to I'm still trying to figure out what play-doh testing is. Oh, it's right
It's play-doh, it's P L A T. Oh, oh
It's my annunciation my enunciations, which is failing
Sorry, sorry. Sorry. Sorry
Sorry
Students from play-doh testing will be attending star Canada on scholarship as I mentioned and assisting other attendees while in the test lab
If you are thinking about attending star Canada, and why wouldn't you be?
20% off your conference fees when you register with the promo code
A B testing all one word by September 15th
This is the biggest star discount offer to date
20% off and star was actually our first promo code
Yeah, and I will be I'll be doing a few star conferences coming up. I think I'm doing
star West
Next year. Oh, I'll be at some star conferences star. Oh, it's star West and a star East in 2018
I can't remember which one I'm doing first what the order is, but they're coming up
To register or learn more about the full conference program. You can go to their website at
Well dot TC whack go star Canada. I will post all of this information
In the blog post which I will likely I'll likely edit this podcast on my flight
Tonight interesting note remember to bring headphones. Okay?
Mental note anyway star Canada a be testing earbuds on the plane. That's excellent. I kind of need I
Guaranteed I'm sitting next to a screaming child or a very large person or
Someone who hasn't showered in three months
Yes, or all one person a screaming baby who hasn't showered
Hey, so one of the things before you go too much further, right?
So as we've talked about before
We don't view ourselves as a professional podcast necessarily. I think we are ebbing on
Professionalism, I don't know what you're talking about anyway continue. Okay, so we're half of this room
We're an ebbing the a half one half may be more professional than the other
but on the sponsors
We would not be sponsoring them on the show if if it's not if it was something we didn't agree with
Absolutely. We are we are
not
Anyway shape or form at a point where we're doing this
For the money we're doing this because we're old geezers and we like to talk and we want to share
absolutely and
the star
conferences
They are keeping pace. I think well
Certainly better than other conferences. I'm a perhaps
There's one other that I could think of that that is on the same line, but because this one's sponsored by Techwell
I'm not gonna mention that one, but if you're an avid listener to this
podcast because
you you value what we're saying because you think we're
Taking a different point of view that isn't
Out there. I'm gonna tell you if you want to get more information on this that is aligned with the content of what we talk about here
Consider star I agree with everything Brent said which is weird
Yeah, let's move on before you think too much about it
Yeah, I do want to reemphasize
We get spot as you can tell being a listener we get people asking if they can sponsor our show for a
Nominal fee and I'm always happy to do that if the product is something
That I think that I would want to use myself or I have used myself or something
I believe our listeners or I think it's it's yeah, it's in line with like yeah
This is this is I think beneficial happy to happy to pass on some savings opportunities. Yep
Okay, so on with the Kanban board over here the
Prioritized list and speaking of Kanban one thing I wanted to mention is
For many many years. I've used personal Kanban to sort of track my work and I and I merge it
It's it's work stuff. It's personal stuff everything from pay the bills to do these tasks
Interestingly, I stopped using personal Kanban about a year ago quite a while
And I did it because I had read
JD Myers book. I don't know if you read his book call getting results the agile way and
I was ready
I'm always ready to experiment and try something new and he and the idea is you list out. I'm putting this I apologize JD for
Totally paraphrasing your concepts down to nothing, but it's a good book
three goals for the month
That you set at the beginning of the month three goals for the week
You set on Monday morning or Sunday night and then three goals every day. I did that for a while and
What happened with that is I came I went in and out of it
There's some good things I liked and I'll come back to that in a minute
I used it for quite a while, but it ended up being more like a to-do list and
A to-do list in my experience ends up being stuff you never do
So I just I just did what needed to be done and didn't really track things that closely
I still liked doing the three goals for the month. I always did that I
Will probably continue to still do that
But the reason I bring it up is I went back to personal Kanban two weeks ago
but I'm gonna go back and give this a try and
It's like coming back to a long-lost friend my
my productivity and and
throughput are just
Thought that they were awful before but definitely accelerated
It's just it's a it's a I just wanted to give a shout out to it for those that haven't
Or haven't thought about doing it as a way to track the items that you work on but it's it's
for me, I
realized it definitely works and it's just something that it's it it's a way for me to get things done Oh
Jim Benson. Yeah, Jim Benson wrote a book on personal Kanban. I got to go to a seminar. He gave once which was excellent
and
anyway, just want to give a shout out to the concept because it's
No advertisement here
But if but it's sort of this along the same lines of it's something I believe in something
I think it would be beneficial beneficial to a B testing listeners
So I wanted to give it a few moments to share now Brent's making a face or he's I'm making himself
I'm making a face. Tell me why you're making a face. Mr. Brent getting things done the agile way and that's the implementation
well
WTF so I again
I squished an entire book which is pretty good and filled with some great anecdotes and stories down to a nutshell
It's an alternate prioritization scheme
I do and again one thing I will you want to know when I learned that party prioritization scheme
kindergarten, no, I once attended a
seminar
put on by Franklin Covey
whose job was to sell taskbooks and
This particular seminar was how to align the tasks of Microsoft Project
Oh
my like
God, I'm like
Wow, I wish you had talked to me about before you started executing that model and abandoning personal count-bound because I would have
Mocked your waterfall. What what happened was and actually it worked at the task level
It doesn't work for me. It's worked when I needed sort of meta level goals like I need to
Something that I take care of this requires multiple things for me to do the personal bond addresses that I know personal compound is much better
and so I
Basically, I just fell away. I used it for I used personal compound for a long long time and
I just for some reason I read this book wanted to try something new and I tried it for a while and it was okay
But not good enough. I wanted to keep on using it
So I fell into nothing for a while and then just recently came back to personal compound. So that's kind of my
I don't know about how you feel about this. Like you mentioned you can't do the same presentation twice, right?
I will say that my view the agile community isn't innovating fast enough for
me at this moment in time because
If I'm executing the same model over and over and over and over and over and over and over even though it's the in
My view the best model there is I get bored with it
And I'm like and this is why this is why I tried the new system because this is exactly why I don't give the same
Presentation twice as I want to even if I give it the second time my attempt is to make it better and it's worse
Now well, I changed it at least I tried something new
Same thing here. I tried something new. I always want to tweak
What I'm doing what I'm building
Anything I want to tweak and see if I can make it better
See if I can make it more interesting see if I can learn more from it
So what I've done
When I first learned personal Kanban, I I ran with it for a very long time
and then I went and did the safe training and then I took some concepts from safe and
tweaked how I did my personal Kanban, but now I'm at a point where
There's no difference between my team board and my board. I just put it all on the one
Right in as you know, I've I've done
I still have to document this one day, but I've I've
Made my own version of
An agile process that in my view is a is
It's probably context sensitive, but it's very effective for the world
I live in and it takes bits and pieces from these different models
But it's now on the same. It's all on the same board
So
Let's go into tangent bill a bit. Okay, did a little theme song for that
Recently had a discussion and a
Something I want to try discussion with one of my team members
it led to something I want to try is I
am in charge of
More teams than I can count
More features than I can count more feature teams and I can't count very high, but it's more than I'll fit on my fingers
each has their own product backlog and of course because
My team members are embedded on feature teams. Their work items are are part of the feature team
boards I
Was thinking it would be cool. I want to start
And I'll get into this tangent in a minute
I want to start finding ways for a few more cross team sort of projects and more sharing
One of the things I think I'm going to do and actually one of the things I'm going to do is find a way to tag
items effect I'm acting like this is difficult. I'm going to tag the
The quality the QA items on the individual boards so that I can view a master board of all the anyway
Actually, anyone can view a master board of all the QA items across the organization. Okay
Hoping that if people view that they might inspire like oh, this is kind of like this
We should talk about this as people are working on some more cross functional tools
across team tools find some ways to connect on those and this leads into
my team needs some
My organization services organization needs a manager who can actually complete a sentence for one
Definitely leadership to back to number one
As I show my favorite finger
Yep
My team the organization needs some
There's some tools we need across the services organization
Okay
What the engine team at unity add has is something they called a toolsmith org small number of people that kind of old miss
Toolsmiths Oh Smith's okay who work on infrastructure and tools for the testing org
Ideally, I would have a few people in the services org dedicated to that
I don't have any head count for that
I can start peeling some people toward that over the long term or
I could do kind of what I did when I was on the Xbox team
Where I had no one reporting to me but was in charge of building all of the
Organizing the building of all of the testing tools for Xbox
Okay, and I'm hoping that in building some visibility
Towards what we need across the org that I can start building some cross
Team hey, I don't want to call them a virtual team because you know, I'm allergic to that term cross
team
Initiatives to build some of those things and get people working together
It's not open source, but generally the term I use under this is shared source
Yeah, and shared initiative. This is this is my world of Warcraft guide to project management
I will say that once you break the boundary and
Between the organizations and you get people
volunteering
To do that shift magic really starts to happen. Yeah, and but it's so hard to get them to do that. I
This is where I live. I I'm a as you know, I'm a more of a community builder than a manager
I am confident and excited more excited than confident that I can get this to happen. I think I have never
Never worked with the team more eager to learn and try new things
Than this organization at Unity. So I'm it frightens me sometimes when I plant seeds and they grow so fast
if I were in your shoes
With what I understand of what you
What powers you have in versus what you don't
one of the things that I may
consider is
To bootstrap this bootstrap this along with sort of a long-term strategy, which you'll it's context sensitive
I don't have enough information to guide you on it offer a one-off bonus program where
Successfully completing and checking in work that belongs to another team
You're gonna artificially reward that with a one-off sort of yeah, I do want to
There is the idea of the spot bonus that I want to I want to be able to yes, I
I'm gonna figure out a way to make that happen. Yeah, and
The great thing is is unlike Microsoft that would be a pipe dream and ever get to do actually when I there's something
I think I want to make happen
It does it's not like automatically it happens
But usually we can find a way there were times in my career where I had the ability to influence it
But now that I'm in a front manager role the incentives have to be more Daniel pink related and not necessarily money
Yeah, and ideally which are more powerful as we as we know, but they're harder to you can do getting it across
Definitely do both
Don't do money and not
Have not and not praise you have to do both. Hey speaking of praising. Yeah, let's go on to the next topic. Oh
Yeah, which has very little to do with praising
In fact maybe the opposite yeah, so you wrote the item down
I'll let you set this up and then I'll make a face and tear it apart
Yeah, so it's it's I've agreed with you enough for one day. Just so you know
Sorry
Sorry, yeah, my
How many times can Alan interrupt there is so at Microsoft we're at the we're out of the review process and
This topic is something that Alan and I have been sort of talking about
Outside of the podcast and given our last theme was really around management and leadership our last podcast. Yep. I remember I was there. Yep
one of the things I realized that we really didn't talk about in terms of
Management philosophy and
One of the worst the most unpleasant things that managers have to do and that is communicating bad messages
Now I'll start off
basically saying at this one of the things that's a full philosophical foundation for me is
Surprises and adjectives are
criminal
Surprise what do you mean by adjectives because I've said the first statement before but
Adjectives I know what an adjective is but give me an example in the situation
This person was awesome this person sucked
The the well those are judgments which are also bad
but adjectives best worst
Adjectives are criminal when it comes to
But it certainly when it comes to communicating bad message messages in my humble opinion. Yeah, and
Good, I get that and the that first part of it is the most important. So a bad message should never be a surprise
for sure, it's
We had
And I'll bring us up a couple times because I've had even as a non manager
I took a lot of management training at Microsoft
Just because I was in a leadership position because that's to go because I was in engineering excellence as part of what I did
So I've had a few decades of different sorts of management training
I had a leadership training at unity took two days and
Of course knowing you knowing me I walked in very skeptical
Then ah, yeah, it was the best
Management training I've ever had
Nice and not to say it was awesome from end to end. There are a few points where I did ask the BTF
but it was great because I could ask the BTF and and
Just unity culture of transparency and respect if I do it. I said I don't get how this it was great
Yeah, great. Great. Um, and they there was a couple things that
One of the bits of feedback I gave they asked us to sort of invent like not invent
but think of some critical feedback you need to give someone in your team and
Frame it in this framework, which I may talk about in a little bit if relevant and I did it
But I said I told him this feels contrived because
by the time
The conversation that it would never get this far to this
I would have mentioned this to them. We would have had discussions about this five ten times before we had this
Air-quote fierce feedback conversation
Okay, so which goes into the surprise it's like
brit
When you interrupt me on the podcast
It causes me to feel blah blah blah or and and this little lot to happen
And so what's up?
So what should we what's your point? What should we do about it?
Ignore your feedback and versus just ignoring him for having going bread. I hate you. I quit
You want to bring up that critical feedback
Wait, so as soon as you need it the the punch line to this is is
To then shift to Socratic and say what should we do about it? No, I'm
I'm uh
Giving a very bad example of giving you to the point and critical feedback
before it escalates to a point where it's a
it's uh
a job ending or a review diving feedback. Yes
and
As you know, and this is one of my beefs at Microsoft is I've had
Almost every single one of my managers only gave me feedback during reviews
Especially my last one. I had one manager who I was
Maybe two months into a new job at Microsoft and I asked him. Hey, how am I doing? His response was?
Oh, wow. I didn't know you're gonna put me on the spot
Um
Yeah, I know that one too and often you talk about review season while i'm on a little bit of a soapbox and rant
Yep, as you know many Microsoft managers will customize your feedback
based on
How much of a raise or not raise they're able to give you well. Yeah, there's I mean
We got to quote unquote own the message
Yeah
but the thing is is that
and just going back to the original point is
if
you
I'm
My blood's boiling a little bit while I try and talk about this is that you have to give people that feedback
All the time. So you I you have one-on-ones with your team frequently as do I as do most good managers
That can't just be a status report meaning I
Sometimes it is I try to explicitly ban
I got I have a daily stand-up. I have a weekly retrospective
um
If i'm not aware of the status, there's something else really wrong
Yeah, it's a little different for me. Well, i'll take a little bit of status just because i'm so spread out
And it's mainly as a way for me to draw out ways that I can help help you
You as my employee. Yeah
So i'll say well, tell me more about that. Is that is there is that going as well as it could or something?
I can do that those sorts of conversations. I think if I were in your role
There's one technique an old manager of mine taught me if I were in your role
I would for sure do this
Uh, because you're you're trying to find those things where hey
I'm a manager. I have resources
Um, I know stuff
I'm talking to your peers
Let me help you and kind of goes to what I was talking about last time about
My perspective that i'm a management service provider and not a manager
Um, but the the technique is very simple
I tell tell my reports
Look, I don't care if you do it even literally two minutes before the meeting
But I want you to send me an agenda for our 101
Now this sounds super managerial
But what happens when you send the agenda and you also say
I don't give a rat's ass about status reports
It forces them to think through
What the hell they need you for?
Yeah, and I do that for yeah
I don't do that consistently
But for what I've found is when I find that that doesn't come out naturally in a one-on-one
I begin to ask for that or it sort of comes out organically for having like these
If we're not having good conversations, I definitely fall to that but I should do that for everyone on the team
Send me send me one to one to n number of things you want to talk about
Because I like then framing that is and it helps me figure out how I can help you
I specifically frame it as look i'm your msp
We're meeting
There there's some value you're hoping to to get from me from your time invested. Mm-hmm
Think about it about what?
That might be
Got it, right because so often
You have these one-on-ones and it ends up being a defensive conversation along the lines of
Why something hasn't been done?
Right, and i'm like, I don't want to talk about that in one of ones
Right, except for where actually I take that back except for where that does
That is related to that individual's career growth
Like as an example, I run a data science team, but as they've blogged about
It's not a specialist team
I have people who are comfortable with some things and they can integrate but they're developers
that report to me
And for the time period that we've been in
Up until now that's great
But it's not going to help them in the next couple of years
And so i'm having conversations around. Okay. How do you go this even further?
But i'm communicating bad messages
Hey, someone stepped over the line
Or it's just not working out. You're now at the 11th 11th time having the same conversation
And you're realizing it's not a fit and you're firing them
Or it's a review process and whatever your company's review process is
Most people look at the numbers and that is ultimately the review they care about
and
How how do you communicate those things?
now
That that particular is where I think adjectives
suck
Yeah, and my my absolute least favorite one
Oh, yeah, you're getting this because you weren't visible enough. Oh my god that adjective. I just these are my
But there is a better way of doing it instead of adjectives for example
communicate
actions
uh
One of the things that I have found
Extremely helpful in this one. I've actually so back in the day when you remember when we had these labels at microsoft
Like underperform limited
Yeah, that thing
I've I've actually communicated a ul message and had the guy thank me afterwards
Yeah
I have
any manager
Managers don't like
Giving harsh feedback. It's a difficult thing for anyone to do
But it's it's if you need to be a machine build need to be able to do it
I fired someone once I had to let someone go they weren't a fit and they thanked me as well
um
But the reason was surprising the reason was immediately. Thank you. Yes
It was not a surprise. Oh, I see because we when there's a performance problem. You need to bring it up immediately
and talk about the impact it's causing and then have
Continued conversations about that if things aren't improving and when it got to the point it was not
Just like surprises or criminal the firing was not a surprise
He and I both knew it wasn't a fit
uh, I said it's not about you personally just not it's not working out and
He thanked me in in that that entire 15 minute conversation where I
Was prepared for him to be defensive and and in my head i'm thinking now is not the time to be defensive
We've talked about you know, we've talked about this before but it was
Again, because I had had multiple conversations leading up to it
the
letting the person go
Was pleasant on both sides. I was I was
uh proud of the way he acted and
And happy for both of it both of us. I just kind of worked out that way
He will be successful and probably is successful in some other position now, but at the time
uh, it just again, it worked out like it's supposed to
I
one of the things that I have
So first and foremost it has actually been a very long time
Since i've actually had to take the step of actually firing somebody because a microsoft is moving to another team, right? No, I don't
Sorry dig dig
Well, actually so in some cases I will if it's a if it's purely a fit problem, right for sure, right? Um, there's
I I had to deal with that just in the last couple of years
Where what they like to do and what they did well
Was not something
My organization was willing to pay them to do it
I also believe this goes a little bit what talked about last time
I'll let you get back on topic is our job as a manager is to find the net always be looking for the next best
role for all of our employees and
Ideally that role is something on our teams because if they're especially they're a top performer, but sometimes it's not
No
Sometimes that next big role i'm moving one of the people on my team at unity to a different team outside of services because that's
Where their passions are where they're uh where they have a lot of excellence both demonstrated and past experience
So it's this just the right thing to do. I I I completely agree. There's an emotional argument to that
There's a there's a logical argument to as well for um, for example
Uh, so I generally take the the more logical argument, right? I don't view firing as a negative thing
Particularly with the strategy that I do where I I find surprises
criminal
Right. I well in advance like i'm pretty good at seeing at this point in time
I'm pretty good at seeing patterns and seeing the future particular individuals and see when
They're on a path that's going to diverge and and sort of the timeline when it's going to be
Negative for them. Yeah
And get them ahead and get them starting to act
And I try to stay in the coaching realm as much as possible like the last individual I talked
Was just in the last couple of years. I said look if if there isn't a change
You're not going to be talking to coach brent anymore. You're going to be talking to manager brent
And manager brent
Has to worry about his business and has to worry about how his resources are applied
And there are very specific things that he has to do when things are out of alignment
So what and we don't want to have a conversation with manager brent
So let's figure out how we solve this while it's still coach brent
So what techniques or frameworks do you have for giving if any?
For or maybe it's contextual for giving that critical feedback when needed. It's always contextual
but
there is
I will say that if there is secret sauce to this
is
Your feedback cannot contain adjectives. They must instead contain
actions
So I think of it as a retrospective
And then I go
So people want to know how do they get in this space?
Okay, so yeah, you're going to have to cover some sort of contextual
You know what lettuce here?
But what I then do in in my conversation is i'll go
Hey
You know looking back on this now
It's very clear to me
That if you had taken these sets of actions instead of the ones that you took
That would have led you to a much better place
And moving forward it is critical
That you continue to take these type of actions, but that's not the stuff I love to do
It's an often often thing because another thing that that happens
Is people like but i'm awesome
Why I why aren't I being rewarded for being awesome?
and
This a lot of times employees don't really understand this
Fitness concept it sounds like management speak
I'm like look
I'll give you i'll give you an example. Uh, I had a guy
A few years back was just a talented
Uh build engineer one of the best
But I was in an organization that gave a rat's ass
And and i'm like it's so you know going back to what I talked about last time that's that
That um venn diagram what you do
Well what you like to do and what you can get paid to do and I said look
Yeah, you know what what you're doing is valuable
But it's never going to it's never going to be in this team and the problems that we have
It's never going to stack high
invaluable results
It's just not
I want to be clear on one thing which is that when you give the critical fee, it's not always about firing someone
No, it's about more often than not. It's just about course corrections
So i'm fully it's always about course. I I mentioned in the last podcast. It's more relevant now
This book by I think it's kim scott
I forget her name a book called radical candor which I read and now i'm rereading
it's
Some of it's
Actually, it's it's very good. It's one of the best management books i've read and i'm not sure I but i'm not sure why yet
I'm trying to figure that out
It's maybe like when I sometimes I read sometimes I read a book it connects things I believe in and adds some more
Background to them, but it's how to give that
how
Some of it it's like tying
Some good frameworks for giving feedback in radical candor. It reminds me a little bit of the this
Model we call fierce feedback at unity, which is uh
Sort of what's the way I remember it is what so what now what what's next?
And they get about the action. So I tell you you did this and it caused this action and then
We discussed before I even tell i'm not going to going to tell you right away
If I have ideas how to do that, i'm gonna say brent when you do this, it causes this problem
And then i'm gonna let you talk
I'm gonna let you lead the conversation from there. So yeah, maybe you realize it. Maybe you don't maybe have an excuse
Maybe you don't but we're gonna have a discussion about it for a while and then
when
We feel like that discussion important thing on that one
Actually is that you're discussing the employee's behavior
Not the employee right when you do this what it causes when you don't get your work done on time
It slows down the whole team from getting this getting this the this deliverable done
every human being
is awesome
but
in this in in the environmental context
Their behaviors in one environment
Maybe a winning success equation and but in another environment the exact opposite
Yeah a big difference I know of for example between
google and microsoft
There's google's in the news a lot and and they're being framed as sort of a utopian
Technology company and i'm like, yeah, you know what that's probably hyperbole, but I can see where they're coming from
The google model sort of rewards
similar thinking
convergence consensus
The microsoft model is significantly more competitive
Definitely. No your idea is stupid. It's built around that it's it's too definitely to a fault. Yeah
Well, I think they're both
Dysfunctional to some degree. Let me finish with what so what now what what's next and tie that back to radical candor and maybe reasons
It's overlapping. So you have this discussion about the behavior
And then at some point you go so and this could be a five minute conversation could be an hour conversation
uh
So what do we do about it?
And maybe maybe you have some ideas become some together. Okay, then what are the next steps?
Maybe it's to sync in a week. Maybe it's to
Let me give you an example. I'm gonna try this a radical candor and give an example
One of the things you want to do in feedback is give feedback
As close to the moment that it happened than necessary like the microsoft model is in the review
When you're getting your crappy performance number you go. Yeah back in january you were a dick in that meeting
And that really affected really affected the vp's view of you. So you're getting a poor score
Well, yeah
The other problem with that is of course a lot of the times
The consequences aren't readily apparent. Yeah, so instead
Uh, I can apply that and this is very much the radical candor model is give that feedback in the moment
Say brent when you interrupt like after a meeting we walk out of hey brent when you interrupt in a meeting it
Makes people feel like you don't care about what they have to say
And this is all like in a two-minute conversation
so
Next time you're in a meeting and you have and maybe we can
Depends on the people and context we can figure out a plan for that
But in that moment give that and again, these are contrived examples
But the moment you observe a behavior or an action that you want to correct give that correction and just
Hopefully you've built a culture of trust this actually ties to the pat lynchioni work on trust
Yep
So I want to have that culture of trust and respect
So that I can just give you that feedback and you don't take it personally go. We have good feedback and I don't have to put
Pretty flowery words around it that that
Lead you they don't the problem with some of these things like a lot of times managers
Um will will do oh, yeah. No, I love you, but uh, my manager hates your guts. So, you know own the message, right?
Um, no, but the thing is I I actually agree with that portion of owning the message
because what you're saying
You're telling your employee. Oh by the way you got victimized
But it's okay. I did too
Great. You know what? I don't want to be victimized. Give me some feedback that allows me to
learn from my mistakes and and
Gets me puts me in control of my own destiny and prevent this from happening again
That's right the primary reason why I hate adjectives
because when when
when
You are told that you are awesome
Or you are told that you are that you suck
You you're not being communicated
What behaviors you have that are being rewarded or penalized?
Absolutely. So you're just as in the dark except you either have more or less money
And you don't always and this is a microsoft thing too, but uh, don't always tie
feedback to
rewards
You think they don't always say no don't i'm i'm telling you don't
Microsoft and you just in your example, you just said you do you just tied it to money again
And it's it's reviewed season. So it's it's inevitable but
Yeah, unfortunately microsoft's not
Very good at that yet. It's still part of our life blood in our culture. Yeah, and right many many episodes ago. We talked about our
ways to fix that but
I don't care anymore
No, no, so um an old manager of mine who has left
Microsoft and gone to another big company
In seattle that is not amazon. I like their review model
what they do
everybody
Gets their bonus. There's no competing for bonus
And then the manager has discretionary spot bonus money
That he can reward throughout the entire year
As that was kick ass. Here's a couple thousand
so
you have people
On a continuous basis trying to deliver awesome
versus
Spend a whole year strategizing around. Okay. Yeah, this is how i'm gonna tear alan down to make sure and again
microsoft is very competitive and a very
Nepotistic the part. Is that can make that a word? Uh environment where if you
Suck up to your manager you will be rewarded
You can be yeah, that's right. You can be rewarded. Yeah in radical candor
Talks about the google review promotion model where it's not the manager's choice at all to promote someone
The manager can be involved of course, but you put together a packet. It's called a I forget what it's called a
They call it a packet. Uh, it's a portfolio of your work
Which is reviewed by?
A peer group a level above the level you want to go to yep
And they go yay nay and if that happens great
if not, they get some feedback there and it's
And I had heard about it all of the people that they're evaluating or none or any place in between
Yeah, and so the quality bar I had heard about it before but reading the book reminded me of what a fair
model that is
It's fairer than what we're used to
But there is an update
I don't have all of the details
But much like anything else that's written word
And google contains smart people just like microsoft does
It is not an ungameable system
Every system is gameable. So with enough time and enough
Um pattern matching
Yeah, you could write your stack of things
um
that
fulfills
what is uh
Unwritten but known criteria sure and back in the day like in 15 years ago if microsoft had done this I can guarantee you
Like wrote test harness
Would have been on the list in test. Yeah, one of the things uh, and i'm surprised
Actually, if this existed 15 years ago the thing that you did where you typified everybody and created the test segments
That would have been used for so much evil for sure for sure. And I think that
I lost track of how many reviews this was microsoft had while I was there
but
Pretty much they last until they've been gamified by too many people and then they go to a new model
Yeah, and my favorite part about how microsoft does it is they go to they go to the new model
Literally two weeks after you've written the review
You know
A lot of times the whole surprise thing isn't something that uh, my company in my humble opinion
Sort of agrees with up and down the stack and i'm pretty certain that actually executives would
but it's
um, it's it's
Legal that's that that's putting these sort of constraints on there one of the ways to work through this
I'll just go through it quickly. We'll talk about this in terms of like project but a lot of um,
so safe has a model
Alan was telling me earlier that my amazon has the model that before you start doing a chunk of work
Write the press release announcing the completion of that work. It's an extension of bdd. Yeah, um
In my team we we go through this we have it's acceptance criteria
We have a process we call the definition of done and i'm like it's not done until
A customer can do these four things. Yep. I I don't care how it's implemented
similar thing
It it it works in a in a nutshell. So if in the connect
Or what we what micro connect is the microsoft review the name of the microsoft review process if in the review
So if you have some of these
It would work positive and negative
It works better if you have an official review process that's frequent
Because things in today's world change so fast
But you can do the same thing
I could say alan
You know what? We're gonna you're gonna be writing another connect in a few months
What I would like you to do
After we're done with this one is I want you to go write that connect
I want you to write up right now. Yeah
What you did?
in the next three months
Yep, I get it
that process
As long as that person's continuously rereading it or revising it or rethinking it
right, um
That's going to help them
Stay on the path towards the goal
So it reminds me one of the things that when I was doing
When I was doing mentoring at microsoft, one of the things that always have my serious mentees do
is ones are like
Obsessed with career growth or interested in career growth or wanted to do some sort of transformation
Is I said write a paragraph?
that
That is written that someone is writing about you six months from now. How would they describe you?
How is someone describing you six months from now?
And I make him write that paragraph and that would be the framework of what we talked about
Over the next n number of sessions. It's like, how are you moving toward that? How are you becoming?
I want to be an accomplished author. Well, how much are you writing? So I I I
That model is super helpful. Uh, I I love it
It reminds me of my favorite lewis carroll quote if you don't know where you're going any road will get you there
and a lot of the times with the mentees is
They don't know where they're going
And so you spend time and you say you you you get them to come up with their own way
Right the the challenge is yeah, sure. I have a lot of experience. I could sit down
I'm not your manager, but I could easily tell you where to go
But that's not what's helpful what's helpful is for you to learn how to control your own destiny
And how to align it with your business and your managers and all of those things if you don't
Employees may not think about where they want to go
Other than i'm just going to come to work every day and show up and do my thing
Right, but then those are the people who go. Well, wait a minute. I'm awesome. How come I didn't get a good review
Well, you know you decided to to track your career
Uh, you know very similar to a butterfly flying at the whims of the wind
Sometimes the wind goes in a positive direction and sometimes the wind goes straight into the volcano
right if you
If you don't like that model
Quit being a butterfly. So one of the things this is probably waxing political now, but one of the things
I grew up with a father that got paralyzed in the vietnam war
Half of his body paralyzed he went in right handed came out left handed
he does not agree
with the ada
and
a lot of these sort of
mentalities around
protecting
The disabled he his philosophy is much more along the lines of yep. You got delta crappy hand of cards
It doesn't change what you need to do in terms of play that hand the best that you can always
so us as humans
We don't have any
Control over whether or not we get victimized but being a victim is a choice
Absolutely, and some people are happier with that and that's fine. That's a good choice if that makes you happy if it makes you feel better
Having this as a label. That's fine. I'm not judging on that but but
Those choices have consequences
And a lot of times you can't have the cake and eat it too
Anyway, I think we can end now. All right. Hey, I am
Alan and i'm brent. We'll see you next time