Brant hello Alan we are back for episode. I don't know I have six oh 69
69 I had a six and a question mark up on the whiteboard it was really close if you had just finished the loop
I just had to finish the loop got rid of the dot. How you been Brant?
I'm doing super
How's that for convincing answer? That's a that's an awesome answer so I have how about you? How are you?
He's such a
Worst co-host ever yeah, yeah, yeah, so I may have mentioned this before
Great drink
Is that the loophole if we just say may my dad is up there in years had a few strokes
He pretty much can't do much on his own, but he says my brother and my sister-in-law about
48 weeks a year 49 weeks a year sometimes longer
So it's the least I can do to offer to take care of him for a few weeks when they go back and visit family
So I did that for the last three weeks
I was I like hey he mostly just naps in his chair
I make him some food hang out with him a little bit, and I worked from home. I got a ton of crap done
I totally got cabin fever by not interacting with real people
So much of my team is remote that only the local team
Like it made any difference to not seeing me around yeah, I don't think anybody else even noticed
but
it's weird I
I
Don't know if I could do if I could be a remote work. I know companies like Zapier are
Every employee is remote. They don't have an office anywhere, and I was thinking I don't think I could do that job long term
I could do it on a contract basis. I could do it for a month two months. Maybe at the most
but
One thing I've learned. It's just I need and I'm an introvert
But I do need a little bit of interaction. I think a lot
Maybe just to get ideas or two
I can't quite explain it yet, but you're in the you're in the knowledge trade and
if you don't have
Relevant knowledge to trade and that's give and take
Yeah, it doesn't surprise me that you'd kind of go a little bit crazy
I do think you know you've mentioned one or two months if you actually made it to three months you'd be golden
Because I think it takes about three months for a pattern. Yeah, I would get a routine down
One thing I can tell you though. I worked remotely once before this is deck deck not quite decades ago, but maybe
Maybe a decade ago, maybe seven or eight years ago at Microsoft. I was
Long story. I won't share, but I ended up working remotely for about two weeks at that time
It was much much worse because slack or whatever you're if you're using Microsoft Teams
for the Microsoft folks
But if slack for everybody else just a lot more a lot more that hallway communication and like I said my remote team had no
idea I was even out of the office, but
We're able to say pretty good communication that helped about three years ago one of my employees
Her father was ailing and she asked if she could go to China and
Work remotely for a month. I said sure
to this date
The manager I had it at that time
Still does not know that she spent a whole month in China
And I was I was actually pretty damn productive my day was spread out was weird because I ended up working
Probably worked
That's probably near my computer 12 hours a day getting in an eight-hour day
There's other distractions, but I got like just a ton of crap done
So it's really good from that perspective, but I'm gonna ask you a question
How much of your time do you spend doing your own tasks in soul-sucking meetings a?
Lot
But I forgot I forgot what a culture of meetings is like so thanks for reminding me
How much and given that is the hard question to answer but how much of your time do you spend on tasks?
Versus managing your team that can be one-on-ones with them or thinking about their career or the work
They're doing what's what do you think? Ah, it all park it it
Like this week. It's mostly on the task front. I would say in any given week. I probably spend
maybe 30% on the
The people career growth stuff because usually my time is spent between my people
putting out
Random fires one of the one of the interesting consequences of being on a data science team and I didn't
realize this
Beforehand, but one of the things that I learned is unlike so people want to treat us like a regular dev team
where you build a six-month plan and
If you don't stick to it you suck the that sort of philosophy that you normally get with a with a dev team
but we have to operate at the speed at which the business needs to make decisions and
So that model just friggin doesn't work
And so a lot of contradictions we get is a lot of fire drills come our plot our way and we have to figure out
How we can best effectively help make the decision
Even though we lack the six months of infrastructure that would be ideal and then lastly
Strategic thinking it in particular nowadays
I'm thinking through all right
What's the next low-hanging fruit that no one's really gotten into that's that appears to be a business
Problem as well as how the hell do I shut down these fire drills?
so
depending on the week
the my balance changed very
rapidly
On our mind the two of the three listeners still listening that that was just an answer to a ratio question
But thank you 30
That's cool
Just I didn't want to say just 30 because 30 sounds low and I wanted to explain why
I get it. I get I'm just giving you a bad time. The reason I brought it up was I think I spent
More time on I still had all my one-on-ones still help solve some problems outside of one-on-ones
answered a lot of slack questions and I will manage your stuff, but I think I probably spent more time on tasks in those three weeks
And I have in any other week at unity
usually it's a lot more because then again managing your team is just a lot of
Interaction with developers around the company especially in the Seattle office
sometimes interviews and
Just those other things there is a
Story and I'll shorten it for the podcast. There's a story. I often tell my mentees. I can tell a story
I'm gonna run to the store real quick. I'll be back. Yeah, I'm just
So back
when I was still a
part of a dink family
dual income no kids
my wife
worked at as a
Apartment manager and she had
Sundays and
Mondays off
So I went to my management and I said hey
Can I have Sundays and Mondays off?
and
I kicked ass they said yes, this is generally the bar and
One of the things for the period in time where that was occurring and I think it was close to six months
I
noticed that generally I got a
Darn close to two weeks worth of productivity in one week
And and so when I came into work on Saturdays
There was no one there to context switch me interrupt me
I would just grind it out and it turns out me me not being there on Monday
Really had no impact on the rest of the week
So I would get that's interesting. Yeah, just that one day. I when I was a sink
single income no kids I
would
often
Microsoft
Turns into a ghost town
The last three weeks of December as people realized they haven't used their vacation
They don't want to lose it and kids get out of school. And so there's nobody there. I would work often
Those especially that week between Christmas and New Year. Oh
My yeah, yeah, the shit I would get done. It was I can't believe I
Can imagine cuz I saw but I still can't looking back
I can't believe like at the end of that time like oh my god. I did holy crap. It is really
And my brain is younger. I could fit more in it's like it. I just had this
The decision to work or not during the holidays is really a no-lose. There's no way to lose
Yeah, yeah, I enjoy taking that time off now, but oh my goodness that was yeah
If you have already done all of your Christmas shopping
Then yeah, you should work
That's generally not the case for me I need that I need the two weeks off because
I
Vare
Generally in the middle of November. I'm like, okay this person that this person that this person that but then I
Changed my mind later and I procrastinate and so then I need the two weeks
This has occurred the last five years
Play the tangent theme song now
We don't have one no, you know what to me do have I
Do I do
We have a little backlog of mailbag questions, I thought we'd well three but I thought we'd talk about this, okay
Alright why don't you get through question one? No not quite ready yet. Okay. It's good to be back having that
We you may have noticed those you subscribing going. Oh my god, what happened to a be testing
They haven't had an episode in a month. I took a week. We took a recording off last taking care of my dad. We are back
Not well, we'll see. We'll see
question number one
All right. This is from Camille. The subject is how can I start work as a tester? And here is the message
Hello, I'm 33 and working since forever in the logistic industry
Few days ago. I came across this job offer as software tester. I started to
I'm gonna fix some slightly broken English here. I have one thing on my mind
I have to try and change my industry and become a tester. I found
IST QB certificate and right now I am learning working and getting information about this profession wherever I can today
I found your podcast a be testing that's us and listening to it at work one thing that disturbs me from your number 26 podcast
Is that I have TQB is a not very good piece of knowledge for a good start as a tester
Maybe not try it. We'll talk about that in a second
I am planning to start from that anyway because this is big advantage in the market at least in my region and I'll have to
Try and find some company which will hire me without any practice except certificate and some theory
I have to find company company of people like you that want to be someone's mentor to teach me the best hire me
That is thank you for the message Camille
Can't hire you yet, but what I can do along with my buddy Brent is
Give some advice. Yes. What advice would you like to give?
I would like to say and Brent and I and as many others do we made fun of the IST QB test because it's a little
the questions are a little on the redic side I think and
There's not a ton of value in the knowledge what you need is the practical knowledge
however
There are many places especially in Europe where having that
certification
can
Get you in the door. I do think and before Brent jumps in one thing I worry about is I'm
My spidey sense tingles with the IST QB
only because I see it I'm not sure if it's a
benefit the testers the testers or
more of a benefit to the people running IST QB who
Charge a big chunk of money to take their class and you know the class T certificate. There's a little bit of
Have some queasyness there that bugs me. So I
Think the answer to that question is entirely market driven, right?
You have more familiarity than I do on on the European tester
Testing market we have several listeners that could probably comment to this hmm better
If you better than I I'm thinking of you Patrick
The thing is so from from outside looking in ISQ or IST QB
appears to be a
Barrier reducer
meaning
In in a testing market if you have this
You can you can reduce the friction towards landing one of these jobs
And you're right much more true in Europe although I think less true than it was a few years ago
But still very true in Europe
I rarely see a US job and never see a US job that I would recommend to anybody that requires an IST QB
Certificate and I think even most American managers at least
People running test orgs don't care
They don't
What we heard is 30 years old they're in the logistic industry
They're considering doing the IST QB. I think you should do the IST QB
Because it again it does from what I observe it is a friction reducer
I'm going to agree it might so it's probably going to help you
get an interview
To the best of my knowledge it may even be help you get a job
But the best of my knowledge is not necessarily going to help you keep that job
Yeah, I would recommend I again
I hate think I have the same advice as much as I've spoken out against IST QB
I think in switching industries and getting sort of a basic lay of the land might be a good idea. I would also go
Read I mean you obviously
Have scoured the internet and gone to the darkest corners in order to find our podcast
So on the way, maybe you found sites like ministry of testing calm
Which have a lot of great information a lot of testers from Europe. It's headed by Rosie Sherry in
Who's in Brighton? I should mention I'm going to Brighton in March. I'm excited. So
In addition to the IST QB look and see what else is out there. Keep on learning
Try things out. There are testing challenges talk to other testers find ways to interact
If you have that seeking learning mind and you can use IST QB to get your foot in the door
You might have a I do think it shot as a software tester. One of the things I do think
So they the person's mentioned they're seeking a mentor in this space
I would reach out to the Ministry of Testing
That's much more closer to a relevant
market for for them than
We are yeah, I think it's becoming and in see if there's resources
There's a lot of you know
test meetups
Maybe there's one nearby. There is look for meetups. Yeah, so I think you know, it was funny
as
little is
10 years ago
Sticky minds is probably the best from ST from software quality engineering people that run star was probably the best resource for
Testing information. It's still a very good resource, but I
Can't think right now of a better resource for software testers
Than Ministry of Testing that is not a paid endorsement
Not even it's just an endorsement. I can't think of anything else. Of course
They aggregate blogs if you want to just scrub to one blog feed they
There's forums there's across isn't just like of course there's some traditional
Testing talk there, but also some modern testing
In fact, I should mention the reason I'm going to Brighton is to speak at test bash in Brighton
I'll also visit the unity office when I'm there, but my talk you're gonna love it
Adventures of a modern tester nice
Nice, I can't wait. I can't wait. I got a little I got a little smiley writing up the abstract and
submitted and
I'm super are you gonna do crayon cartoons like that that one girl?
Years ago with the dungeon and oh
I wonder if I should check the schedule I own I own a
Mm-hmm. It was her name. Maybe she'll be there. Maybe she can do the the art for you be great
I actually gave a presentation to my team internally
There's a weird thing
I've mentioned before with off the air mentioned to Brent that one thing at unity that I love is I I
Plant these seeds and the seeds grow very fast at unity. Sometimes a day later like we're doing this
I said whoa. Whoa. Okay. Okay, it's fine
Go several months back
I was working on getting some of the teams start thinking about working from a zero bug backlog and how that would happen and
I was gonna start with one team and show data and move on direction and then a whole office said
Oh, we want to do that. Can you give a tech talk to our devs on how to do that? How to think about that? I
said I can
And I used a lot of hand-drawn pictures in it. That's for the heck of it
What's up? All right. Let's start next question. Oh
Look who's rushing things along
Next question
This one is from David on the testing pyramid in 2017
Dear Alan and Brent. Oh
Okay
What you mad didn't say dear Brent and Alan? No, no, no, it's not
I was
Quickly loading the testing pyramid and that's what caused the uh
All right. Go ahead
Go did it have to push the ponies out of your brain? Okay, you're Alan and Brent
Because now we can run many GUI tests graphical user interface
You need GUI tests at the same time hence get fast response
Do you think this will eventually lead to more GUI tests and fewer unit tests?
If the time will no longer be an issue, isn't the depth of testing through the GUI make it a better practice?
No
next question
So
So I understand the logic. I loaded up a image on
I'm looking at lots of unit tests
Unit tests of the testing pyramid. I loaded up. Oh yours is huge
It says that the base is unit testing then component testing then integration then
Then system then acceptance then alpha and beta. No, that's that's a stupid pyramid
Yeah, the UI is not in here. I mean as I see why it's not in here
The pyramid as originally drawn that that pyramid you brought up there. I like this period that one's stupid
You're stupid don't even show that one. All right
the pyramid is unit tests system tests at the very top of the pyramid GUI tests and
what I
Have stolen from Google considering how much Whitaker stole from me when he was there
Is rather than call them unit and system and GUI? Oh this one
I even think about them as small medium and large test that is the testing pyramid as
Proposed originally so but for now
Forgot where I was
lots of unit tests
Medium out of system test a small number of GUI tests
Let me put it this way
Now that I've talked about everything but the answer I agree with Brent which is
No weird. I
Don't care if you can run a gazillion GUI tests in a second
Well, that'd be kind of awesome. But generally I don't care because GUI tests are no
No, if you could run a zillion
GUI tests in a second just imagine how many actual useful tests you could run in the second
I
think GUI automation is the most difficult to do right and trustworthy is
one of the most difficult things to do in software engineering if you have
The flakiness lives in the GUI tests and maybe it's not flakiness you can control
Maybe you can work past it very difficult
You want to write tests that you can trust that when they pass do you know the products working when they fail?
You know the products failing
furthermore
You need a set of eyes on that GUI at least once before you ship anyway
Maybe that comes from some dog fooding at the same time
Just I see no reason I would rather investigate in those super-fast
Reliable tests that live lower down the stack regardless of our ability to parallelize our
GUI testing I even found that in and friends about to talk but even on we had on teams
Oh God
Well, there's the good news taught our developers how to write test automation and they wrote a bunch of really shitty UI tests that were
flaky as hell and they wondered why the system was so gross and
This system worked fine. Oh, we'll just parallelize those tests. We'll rerun those tests. We'll retry those tests
We'll keep on running until they pass
No, they're fragile
And with that fragility you end up not trusting them and when they do fail it's a real product bug
Maybe you don't notice because it's a broken window theory just no
I do not support writing more GUI tests just because it's easier Brent. You may speak
Thank you. So the pyramid as
I have loaded it up says at the very base is unit tests then followed by acceptance tests
Then followed by GUI tests now in this particular case
I'm going to choose to interpret acceptance tests in language that we used to use which is the BV T's
From my experience all of the bugs happen at the integration layer
GUI tests sure you could write a whole bunch of GUI tests and
If you had a full complete suite of GUI tests and dev does a check-in
You will be able to
fail a bunch of tests
if they do a bad chicken and
Dev won't have to do the unit test because you know
that
the test failed
Now let me tell you a story
Years ago about 15 years ago now I joined a brand new team. I'm not gonna mention the team
It's now
Yet another Microsoft product I worked on that no longer ships
Not soon though
Which is official now. Did you hear about?
Groove dine
Yes. Yeah. Oh
My tangent size yes, it is a B testing one of my one of my predictions one of my rants from years ago
Finally came true only after spending a few more hundreds of millions of dollars on it
Windows phone is dead. I think that was announced several months ago. Maybe maybe
Internally windows phone became officially dead to the public just a couple weeks ago, and I wasn't even happy or it's like about time
it's like
Like yeah, I told you that when I was working on that stupid science project. We should just stop making this thing
This is dumb
It was just it was
some cost fallacy
Yep personified and thank goodness anyway go on. So I joined this team and
they had
Run for six years
Shipped three versions of the product and had never shipped with a hundred percent BVT passing in
That six years time
This was a hard problem to them. They did not understand what was going on
Management thought automation was just completely useless because they couldn't figure out this problem
and
Again a BVT is a build verification test it is
In today's world. It would be somewhere between an integration test and a unit test so
More complex than a unit test less complex than a integration test
Now at this point in time I had never ever ever ever
encountered a team
That didn't have BVT's
Passing at least once a week and this is a team that had shipped three versions
It's so funny. It's on me. It's 15 years ago, but yeah, it sounds like a lifetime ago. I just it I I
Can't believe we lived through that without killing ourselves. I've noticed that as I'm getting older
Time appears to be passing by faster. Maybe and this goes back to paraphrase something you've said
Previously is I think today I worry way more about quality than do about testing
Yes, and I've this is an example of that we were worried about the testing
well, so
The team was I asked to take on this as as a project. I found it fascinating
Like it is somehow I knew upfront this team had way over complicated their BVT pass
Like to the best of my knowledge up until then it was nearly impossible
to get
BVT's into this type of state
anyway
Shortening the story what I went and researched and I discovered
Exactly. What was going on
they had designed their BVT suite to
essentially be what
The person is asking us on on this question
They had abandoned it so you can take the equivalent of they had abandoned their unit tests done only
scenario-based gooey tests and
They could not get their test pass to pass
Why?
because when the scenario
fails
There was always
approximately
250 different check-ins that could have caused the failure
Okay, and you end up
Spending dev let's say the test is provably saying the products failing
The problem is is it because you didn't define the failure at the moment the code integrated
You end up spending about ten times the cost
Undiagnosing
the the problem
So yeah, this this would be a horrible idea ignoring the fact that gooey testing or gooey automation is
Absolutely
One of the hardest things on the planet to do
Reminds me of a story. Yeah
So on Xbox one which was some little pockets of agile
Encompassed in a big cesspool of waterfall cesspool is wrong. It was a fun project
But what team was this Xbox one? Oh good
We defined we're very careful about defining like
What a BVT was and our levels of testing we didn't use the pyramid as a metaphor
We could have but the BVT answered the question each level of testing answered a question the unit test answered the question
Is my code ready to check in and the BVT answered the question is this build worth?
investing any more testing effort on
So we wouldn't even run the next level of test unless the BVT is passed wouldn't bother
I use those questions. I had another set of questions as well and
my set of questions were roughly equivalent to if this test suite passes is
The next test suite have an 80 to 90 percent chance of passing as well
So in other words, not only did I use it for a gate for things like check-in and things like that
But I'm like no I want a super fast suite that says whether or not it's worthwhile to begin the next week
And different levels of testing answered similar questions until it went to beta users
So then recently recently being like maybe six months ago, maybe longer because I can't tell time anymore Noah Sussman
Did a very clever thing which makes a lot of sense. He inverted the pyramid
And did basically the same thing answering these questions
If you look at the pyramid upside down all
Basic functionality bugs should be caught by the unit tests these levels of bugs
We catch here the only bugs that get to here are ones that have failed have somehow passed all those things
I'll see if I can post a link to it. Yeah, so I
Think we're both saying the same thing particularly in the world of the the modern tester, right?
Calendar time is critical. You can't have your devs spending
a whole lot of their time
Just running through your end-to-end scenarios to figure out what the hell bug they just checked in
You also can't have your automators spending all their time maintaining
extremely challenging
Gooey their automators. I don't know what yeah, I don't know what the crazy kids call these people nowadays. I don't know either I
Ask my team to write please write less automation
Help the devs write more that is the way to go. Thank you
Are we done with that? Yeah, we made our point
I don't think you liked our answer, but we're not here to give answers you'd like we're here to give honest answers
I and I I understand opinions. I understand the theory but no I'd be too but running the regression suite is
not the
priority
No
agreed
Okay, my stop writing automation post is
Seven years old now
Yeah, I think it's I think the way you just said it is the best way. I've ever heard you say it
Because when you read it it sounds like you're anti automation and it's
You're not it's no
The people who write the automation should also be the people who wrote the code. I think so me too
One more question this one from slack channel one of the three dot slack comm
Contact me or perusee on Twitter if you want to get added, but this is from Danny thought the infamous Danny thought
For an organization that is moving to doing testing in production
How important is it to have a data scientist participating?
Does a data scientist ensure that sufficient data is available to show whether an application is having problems in production?
So really we have two questions here
one
Maybe easier to answer than the other as the data scientist
Should you answer first or as the non data scientist should I answer first? I don't care
Would you like me to answer? I want you to care?
Like for me I'm in an organization that is moving to doing testing in production
Yep, and I don't have any data scientists on my team
We do have data scientists in the org that I can and will leverage as needed
But there are some interns interim steps that you can do being
Was just a little bit of math and statistics knowledge and the ability to use or even better yet
The ability to use a search engine on the internet you can get by I think for quite a while
In moving in that direction what you really need help with in moving that direction is a nice partnership with operations
Or infra or devops whoever is building your monitoring system to figure out how you're going to
Leverage that and what are the ways you're going to use that to monitor system health tests that run in production
What happens when they fail to those fire alerts?
Getting that built up in the first place is much more important than getting the deeper analytics that come from data science in my opinion
When you're moving to testing in production, right the first thing that's gonna happen and by the way, I
Would say a good 50% of my data science team my individual team is
on a problem similar to this
But it is entirely dependent on your maturity model on
Where you are with testing in production testing in production
It has two interpretations one is the the monitoring
Stuff that you're talking about the other is
The a B testing paradigm I've seen both of these things
Classified under testing or production on a B testing
Yeah, you definitely want a
Statistician to help you with the hypothesis testing. Mm-hmm. There's multiple flavors of data scientists. Do you need an ml for this? No
it's its basic stats for
testing in production from a sense of
Monitoring do you need a data scientist? No you can get away
For a long time without one will one having one help accelerate and help avoid several problems
Yeah, it will one of the most common problems once you go to testing in production
The first problem is signal to noise ratios. How do how do we set these thresholds?
The the first practice as you set it to be static values
but then you realize oh crap this particular series is spiky and
And we only we only care if it's above the spike for 20 minutes
Well the then you go, okay. Well, we'll just add another threshold that says don't alert anybody unless it's been above this spike for 20 minutes
But then the next problem that you run into is oh
Yeah
So we did good on reducing noise
but now
Our service has been offline for 20 minutes. So when it's actually a real thing
Data science is is is really helpful in terms of
Working through the signal noise problem. I think
Answer the question also depends on
What is a data scientist you need to go and the and the canonical answer is it's a statistician who works in Silicon Valley?
But let's do you need
your canonical
Do you need like to go hire someone you who is a
Self-proclaimed or has a job current job panel as data scientist, or do you just need someone on the team who?
Understand statistics and can and can
Tell when there are anomalies and depending on the size of the team like if there is headcount here
Right and depending on the maturity level
just hire somebody that is is
Has knowledge in this space?
One or two years out of college
They will they will probably provide the right amount of ROI for this project
Right and I think that
The biggest thing is they'll stop you from doing some stupid things. It's really easy
I see this happened all the time and I'm as Brent knows I am NOT a data scientist, but I
Can fake a lot of shit and I've read a lot about statistics
I once gave a talk on a be testing and used all the right words and made Brent happy
I know enough about
Statistics I'll say that I could ask the right questions about metrics and understand how to figure out
Whether something is statistically significant and in actually in the scenario I just mentioned
The advice I just gave like hire
Somebody who's just fresh out of college
You would be able to do a lot with that person because you know
What data science can do and what it can't do to some degree you may not know how to do it
But you understand the language and you understand what it can do so you you would be able to to appropriately
Direct this individual. Mm-hmm and a lot of the other places where I've had this question answered you have a bunch of people who
Data science is the equivalent of magic. I want to hire a magician, too
And I don't think that's a healthy situation for a young data scientist
No, I don't think so another one and you mentioned the AB testing and
It's good to differentiate the fact that just synthetic tests tests that you like actual tests that you would run internally
Run those against production had them trigger an alert when they fail that stuff does not need a data scientist, but
Whether it's a be testing or just understanding more about customer usage
One thing I found that I'm not great at yet, but I'm better than most
Around me because I spent a lot of time studying this is figuring out how to ask the right questions
From data like how like that's where a data scientist can help like hey, we want to know X
The data scientist is often the best person to figure out the right data. You need to collect in order to figure out X
Brent you would think
Well, yeah, if not, then don't hire them. No, there's a new phenomenon that's coming in lately
Where I've encountered a lot of data scientists
the kind of X
backed
That all they're gonna do is is machine
Model building machine learning model building. Um, so
No one likes to clean the data. No one likes to
Do the data mining to figure those things out?
You know do those guys I essentially say, you know too bad
That's not how that's not how it works. The fun data science projects are
Messy the valuable ones are messy. I
Wonder if just like if you were to ask ten testers what they do you may get eleven different answers
I wonder if right now while the data science role is sort of growing and evolving that it's sort of the same thing it is
It is because summer I know there are ML people there are
Statisticians there are people that ask the right questions that can design experiments
I think there's a lot of nuance and expertise in data science just as there is in
software testing so
It took me a long time to come up with a definition of a testers job
I have greatly accelerated and I have a definition of a data scientist job and a data
scientist job is is to understand the relationships between
variables that
positively drive action for the business
That's not bad. I know
I know
Brett just hurt his shoulder patting himself on the back
But you will you talked so it is I've now interviewed several hundred of them
And there is a lot of there's a lot of common complaints. There is a lot of
common expectations
right
date several data scientists expect that
They'll be doing everything in Python several data scientists expect that
Someone else does the data engineering and the data mining
This is what's typical in an academic environment
right I
Am actually going to be doing a presentation
in that within the next month for
One of my one of my professors just joined a brand new university
He wants to start a series and he's calling analytics think tank
So I got to build a deck around
you know
how Microsoft
Uses data science that it's targeted the academic world
right one of the things I'm going to bring up is
It
So the thing I'm one of my favorite things and I haven't quite figured out how I'm gonna bring it up
I'm gonna bring it up. I think and I thought this back in in in the old days
That PhD CS students were useless. I'm finding
PhD data science
People are mostly useless. No, they're useful for writing papers, but not for practical software applications
Yeah, I fully agree with the former. Yeah, it's it's not enough experience latter, but I'm not surprised
There is a big push
In society lately where where there's a lot of questioning around what's the value of the university education system?
You got things like Coursera
We're more open source than we've ever been
There's a lot of open content
We don't have time for a rant. Did you see my blog post ranting about their
The security VP security the CTO or whatever of Equifax?
is blamed for
The their security breach people were freaking out because she's a music major
I
Got up on my horse because one of a music major so a little defensive but to
A university is not a vocational school. It's place where you supposed to learn how to think and
Many people do apply what they learned in their their actual degree towards
What they do, but many many don't and that's okay
Yeah, if you if you want to go to school to get a specific job go to a vocational school go to course
You know, yeah, anyway big rant there isn't a vocational data science school
Yet
Yet, but man my crash course part of my crash course in learning data science is courses on Coursera
Yeah, no Coursera is a great thing and I I actually I
I do think in in
Probably in our lifetime Alan certainly in our children's lifetime. I think we're gonna see a big shakeup in in the education
system, I hope so
But the the point I was trying to make like if you have if you if you
Have the desire
To to get into let's say data science or computer science
And work in industry
When you start off to college I do
seriously question the value of
pursuing
Bachelors all the way to the PhD before you start going into industry
Right if you want your PhD, I might I my recommendation would be
Stop at masters maybe even stop at bachelors get a job in industry
Work through that then go back. I
We could do a whole episode ranting on this, but we are
Unfortunately about at a time for today, they're not I so totally agree with you
Yeah, I I've been gonna leave it at that but maybe we'll talk more about that another time
I think we need to think hard about that. Oh, so anyway answer the question Danny
Possibly your knowledge may vary
Depends on the type of data scientists you want
Do you need one? No, will it be helpful? Yeah. Yeah
Should you evaluate the ROI based on where you are also? Yes
Yeah, figure out exactly exactly what you want to do, but you don't have to get the the the goat data science
It's not magic summit. Oh they decided to see here all of our data will be perfect and we'll make awesome decisions right away
Yeah, I'm gonna happen. Okay, everybody
If you're still here
I'm Alan. I'm Brent and we'll see you next time