morning everybody. Howdy. I'm Alan. I'm Brent. And we're back for Alan Brent testing. Sometimes
known as A B testing. Yeah I don't. I like A B testing better. I'm gonna edit that not.
How you been, Brent? I am pooped. I am working. I'm essentially, my brain is working
seems like 20 hours a day with school and work. That's right. This is your last, you're almost done
with school, right? I have, once I get done with this class, I have one more and I cannot wait.
I don't regret the decision at all. It has really helped my career but you know it's time for it
it's time for it to be done. Okay. All right then. It's time to get back into industry problems
and not the combination of both. I get that. Yep. How's your kid doing at college? He's doing great.
He's uh he's getting straight A's. The the only issue he has right now, he's not doing proper
financial planning. Like every other 18 year old heading off to college in the world? He's 19 now.
Yeah. It was a generalization. Yeah, no that's that's true. So he's he's figured out how to live within
his means paycheck to paycheck and I'm like yes son. You need to buy your own master's degree.
How's that gonna get you there? Did I tell you what I did with my son? I don't think so. No.
So Washington what is it the 529 plan to Microsoft or the Washington get program?
Yeah. So I've paid. I'll let you finish. Go ahead. So I've paid for his the deal I have with him for
college is I have bought enough credits on the Washington get program that will pay for his
bachelor's degree all the way through and his first year I'm paying for his dormitory
and his food at the dormitory and then the last part is for the next four years I'm sending him
five hundred dollars a month but I've informed him that's all. Everything else whatever else he
wants to do with his life is up to him. It's very similar so my father was permanently wounded in the
Vietnam War and so that plan is very similar to the plan I went through. I bolted on a second
undergrad degree. I ended up to be able to afford that. I ended up having to get a job to cover
rent and food and books and all of that. So I'm making him go through a similar experience
and we'll see what happens. I think that's good. My parents didn't have such a formalized plan
but it was definitely a tapered plan for my freshman year. They paid for because I lived in
the dorm with the meal plan so they paid for that plus my tuition and then the next year
I moved off campus which is much cheaper and they paid for my rent which is like a hundred
bucks a month. I'm old. Rent and tuition. No but you went to Central. But then I bought probably
still a hundred bucks a month. I bought my actually the because I'm on the alumni board there
the enrollment is so high that it is they are struggling to find a place for everyone to live.
They're they're they're bursting at the seams there so it's supply and demand means those prices
are going up unfortunately. So I think my next year anyway they paid the rent of my tuition
but I started paying for my own food so I got a job. The next year was actually the last two
years was tuition only for undergrad and then grad school is like a total that was that was all me.
Did you do all your degrees at Central? I did. Okay. So that that worked out pretty well and I
did kind of learn we didn't turn the heat on very like we kept the the thermostat because heat was
expensive it's electric heat. I remember keeping the thermostat at about 45 degrees
so the heat would only come on if we were going to die.
And that kept the bill down a little bit but it was fine because really I was so busy all I did
was sleep there so I'd come back and throw some food down and dive under the covers. Sure.
And then I've also discovered when I looked into I have 529s for my kids but Washington's is just
awful. I haven't compared I like the fact that I could pre-pay for all the units. Yeah so I
ended up doesn't that require I can't remember but this is in the financial planning show but
there were some deals about using that for in-state colleges and I can't remember the details on why I
didn't like the Washington plan. You can use no you can use it either way and so the one thing
I like about it so it can be used out of state the the but there is a doling of the units so
they'll only give out x number of units every year. Like for example my son had applied to
several schools up and down the west coast. The only school that didn't accept him was UW.
So he was when he found out that San Diego had accepted him he was super pumped up and I said
okay well here's the deal son you got to make a choice. I've already put down the money for
your bachelors so you could use this and go to San Diego and pay for one year and then the rest
of it is up to you or you can you know go to any school in Washington and and cover the whole
degree. So it ended up being a this is worth a little bit of a discussion much of the same
mind as you given the way I went to school we have a nice healthy amount saved for kids education
we'll see where they want to go. My wife is very much that well what if they want to go to Stanford
I said well they then they should get a freaking scholarship or student loan. Yeah exactly I'm not
going to write and what you'll find is you do a little bit of research is even you might say oh
tuition at x school is this number this amount of money no one pays full price in some way there's
either there's there's grants there's loans there's this and that but what I wind this back to is the
Malcolm Gladwell this was an outliers I believe I think it's an outliers where long story short
you should go to the best school where you can be in the top 20% versus trying to go to the most
competitive school where like say that the story was some woman top of her class straight A's plus
extra credit all the way through high school goes to some top medical school filled with people
exactly like her all of a sudden she's not the best anymore she gets depressed drops out of medical
school not that that one example would would dictate the norm but they do find is that if you
momentum is important it is it is that's exactly it so I'm a big fan of that and I think
we'll see what happens I got time I got time yeah it is the first one goes to high school
next year yeah I I have a sophomore now in high school for me it's it's the need to
begin to learn life in my view my philosophy is is when they go off to college right it's not
playground it's the in my view part of the point of college is to really solidify taking control of
you've heard me rant about this before I think too many people both in the university system
parents and students want to treat the university as the vocational school and I think while you're
learning some skills that may help you in your career it's the education is really at the meta
level it's life skills it's financial planning skills it's how to live how to become independent
in sort of a safe and connected environment there's so much of that that happens in your
four ish years at university that goes to me as far as a lifetime goes far far beyond anything you
can learn in a classroom yeah my oldest and I mean it was super explicit when once we finally
walked through all the finances and he understood it he said so dad what happens if you know something
comes up and and um I can't pay for it I'm like I don't know I guess uh you you see what credit
cards you could apply to or you can see if you can get a loan or something I don't know like I
basically made it very clear that he'll have my empathy and I'll support him up into the point of
where I bail him out yes but not including that point one more example of a skill I learned
that's been applicable for up to this day and then we'll get on with the podcast is
you can live on one you learn to buy top ramen and cheap bread I used to buy like the
dale bread and make uh uh and some eggs and make like uh three weeks with the french toast and
just freeze it I can put them in the toaster in the morning but what I learned is I'll give you
the example tell you what I learned from it is one I worked at Domino's so as long as I didn't
get sick of pizza I could eat pizza anytime I worked there's dinner to care if I could make it
till dinner there's food uh also what I learned is I worked in the music building one of my jobs
I delivered pizza and I worked in the music building as sort of the the building monitor
locking doors opening up rooms things like that making sure because the professors all went home
at you know five or six o'clock the building was open till 11 someone had to make sure it didn't
burn down nobody was fighting or partying or whatever in there uh so in that job I was nice
to people I was a service provider I would open open doors and let them into classrooms whatever
they needed to do even though it was my job and I was paid for it I wasn't above bartering
for maybe not even direct bartering say for example someone said hey the practice rooms are
all full can you let me into a classroom to practice there's a music department of course
and technically for a small fee technically no but the thing is you don't you don't want to make
it contingent because that's and in transference to the real life in advance if that's contingent
then it's like weird but it's like possibly illegal yeah so instead the way you put it is
I'm not supposed to but I've been there let me go let you in this room please make sure it's locked
when you leave and check in with me when you take off so I know no double check it just just a
little bit of you know covering my butt a little bit but letting him in there and then maybe they
go to leave and they I remember told him check in with me so they come check in with me I said
I asked like just conversation where you hit it now oh I'm headed over to the door I headed over to
the meal hall to get some food because they're on the meal plan I go hey uh if you remember can
you bring me back an apple or are you going to the deli for dinner great uh do you want to
can you grab me half a sandwich for you that'd be awesome and they would so again if not you
don't directly position it as tit for tat like I'll only give you the room if you bring me some
food later but just be nice to people golden rule and then conversationally see if you can
they'll want to do something for you but also it's pay it forward in a way but it works when
you're broke and you're looking for ways to eat that don't cost any money but it also don't and
I think an important life lesson there is don't be afraid to ask for what you want sure but worse
and sometimes they'd say no I said I said ah I don't know they don't like us to bring food out of the
out of the out of the cafeteria and I wouldn't come back with well I'm not supposed to open
this door for you dick you just you just kind of play it and that's no you're playing that's sort
of you're playing the probabilities that sort of negotiation is really important you know even
the professional world I will cover for you not thinking of anything I want like I'll do
something for you at work professionally I will put together a report for you I'll prepare something
for it some way I'm helping you out I'm not doing it with an immediate or even necessarily a long-term
idea if I want something back but when I do need something from you I will remember and I will
make a connection to make sure we remember that time together and that may make you more inclined
to help me out as well the actually that that's kind of one of the ways I've built my career is
basically giving if people ask for help I will give help and then after about three times where
I've giving you help and and you've rejected me I will suddenly find myself too busy to help you
the fourth time I don't know if I get that I'm it's essentially it's essentially what I want to do
is I want to go okay let's build partnerships and a partnership is somebody who cares about your goal
at the same time you care about theirs so it's about working together to build win-wins for both
sides and I call them relationships but I think you want to build those relationships and mine were
you know the example I gave was very much it wasn't a tip wasn't like a tip for tap thing
but it was within a three or four hour period but often in the professional world building
these relationships happens over weeks or months or even years yeah and and I just believe in I
want to treat other people like I want to be treated so I'm going to do things for them really
with I can't say with no thought in mind that I may get something back but it's not it's not
like that directly it's like I want to help you out because I like helping people and in doing
that we build a relationship which I know at some point I may want to draw something back from that
relationship yeah no I get what you're just saying so I do a similar thing it's it's difficult
to describe but when I realize that here's how I feel is if I'm helping people out and then
and then repeatedly you show that you're not willing to help me out I start to feel like all
the help I've done for you before was just you manipulating me no I don't that's I'm gonna try
hard not to blame that on Microsoft's ultra competitive culture but I'm still like helping you
if you if you don't like hell if if I'm working with someone who doesn't want to help me or maybe
they don't want to help anybody that is a flaw in their human nature but I don't look at it as I'm
gonna stop helping you I if I have a priority having to help someone else who's going to be
more appreciative of it maybe but I'm not going to get I'm there there is a down that path I am
at times what I call afflicted with the white knight syndrome so I do there there have been
times where people who I would say are abject opponents or even enemies that I got themselves
in a real bad bind and the the small bit of my human soul that remains doesn't allow me to
reject them in those situations anyway all right we do a podcast hey hello listeners we're just
about ready to get started with the podcast about that yeah this episode of motley fool brought to
you by Albert and Burt wait that's kind of the same name now very good Albert no I can
al and Burt a be finance it's a b test life's what's up with you in the noon they wanted to
never mind a couple quick announcements I've been slacking off not slacking off I have tapered
back my conference attendance dramatically over the last few years somehow through that
idea out the window and I will be in Moscow Russia first week in December for the Heisenberg
conference yeah we're we're almost up we're almost at the the prediction episode and I think
last year's predictions you predicted that you would attend only one conference so I think that
one may go out the window no no it's only what that's but that's only one in 2018 that I spoke
somewhere else in 2018 did I I think 2018 hasn't started 2017 I mean but I think the only conference
I spoke at in 2017 will be Heisenberg I don't think I did I go to the conference in 27 the online
conference I did the online test conference I did I did you are correct I did too but then in 2018
I will be at test bash Brighton in March okay I love test bash that was the last conference I spoke at
test bash Philadelphia was the last test bash I last conference I spoke at in front of people
and then I'm going back to star east in May talking about tools for testing a lot of web tools
I'll go over haven't quite figured them all out yet but let me rewind a little bit so Moscow
I'm giving two talks I'm giving a completely redone version of technical testing and I like
it because they asked if I could do the closing keynote with that talk and I love that because
that means I can tweak the talk based on what I see in the first two days of the conference so
that's going to be nice it will be very good I like it when I can do that and then I'm also giving
a talk on test automation where I will give all of my usual rants and also I'm going to be using
interactive testing using remember numbers my little test step my little oh man yeah yeah
I'm gonna pull out numbers I had to find the code for that and do some do a little bit of work
there but numbers will be in play and then at test bash in Brighton you should put numbers up
on github it is on github okay put a link to it okay let me finish I will link to it once I finish
this last round of edits all right uh what was I talking about test bash oh before I talk about test
bash Brighton actually I'll finish talking about test bash Brighton and then I'll go back so at
test bash Brighton I'm giving a talk called experiences in modern testing I kind of want to
change it to adventures in modern testing but I think I can keep it as experiences and speaking
of ministry of testing just last week I cheated on Brent a little bit as I usually do and I recorded
a desert island disc this great podcast from Neil Stud at ministry of testing doing a
podcast where he talks to testers about test things and the five discs they bring to a desert
island with them and I grew up you know going to tower records every week and they had this
publication that had desert island discs so I've always been very infatuated with the topic
and you're gonna bring a book too and you'll have to listen to that episode coming out
December 1st if you want to know what my songs and book are I'm not going to tell you
I don't remember them being a book no the book is an addition okay so it was fun I really put thought
into it and chose songs not only that I could listen to a thousand times not getting tired of
them but trying to span some different genres so I could uh a little bit so I could I really
thought like if I was really stuck and I could listen to these songs probably not on a disc or a
turntable but like the only five songs on my forever rechargeable mp3 player it would be those
five songs uh mp3 player that only could store five songs yes probably would have a pretty good
solar cell yeah that's what I'm thinking that's I'm I'm gonna ask you a question yeah and we spent
a whole episode on this another time but I want to see how succinct you can be one of the questions
I answered for indirectly maybe directly for Neil and uh something I'll talk about a lot at Test Bash
and Brighton is just what exactly is a modern tester so Brent can you define a modern tester
as we've been talking about on the podcast yes you said to be succinct so we did a episode
someday I gotta get to maybe I'll do that over the Christmas break is get to titling the damn
episodes we did an episode on that topic yeah just a little while back to me a modern tester
is more concerned about the business requirements and the functional requirements is more concerned
about actual customer quality and uses uh data to derive it okay that's their motivation
it's not a definition per se I think the definition that we've that we use here is still
applicable right that they use modern techniques to accelerate the achieve achievement of
shippable quality okay give me an example of some modern techniques data analysis good I put that as
a high level so now everything else I'm thinking of is a sub so let me give you the the definition
I gave Neil and we can pick that apart okay have you ever read the Crispin Gregory uh Agile
testing books I have okay so do I remember them so what I said to Neil it's very much like the Agile
tester that uh Lisa Crispin and Janet Gregory describe with a couple modifications one is a heavy
emphasis on data analysis as part of how they do their job yes and the other one is a much
deeper level of or deeper and broader level of coaching of testing and quality techniques
across the team they're much more of an expert in testing and quality than what is described in
those books the other thing I would say that's that's critical in my view is a focus on
we we shift the needle more towards reacting than preventing elaborate please uh we do not schedule
the two month long test pass to yeah and and before ship and to be clear that is not part of Agile
testing either no no so so yeah it's so my baseline of of its Agile testing with a few other
areas of emphasis I think remains accurate but definitely absolutely those those things of two
month long test passes 45 page test reports risk analysis reports actually that's not those those
still exist I was backtracking but this is a discussion of what they what's been observed
after the product has been released right so so there's still some preventative aspect to it
um and it's it's trying to communicate this this balance that's let me throw this out rather than
trying to test quality in which may be a bad way to put it because I don't think anyone doing a test
last approach thinks of themselves doing that but I think our listeners understand so rather than test
quality in it's more of we're trying to understand quality consistently yeah actually you know what
instead of trying to I like I like this framing so instead of trying to get the product to be the
prescriptive definition of quality we're trying to discover quality and shift the product in that
direction I like that idea of discover quality it's better than my understand uh no it's similar
right it's the um so I think about we haven't talked about it yet but I think about one of the
slides that I showed recently which is essentially the only person qualified to speak to quality of
your product is the customer themselves and that's one of the that's one of the ways the modern tester
tries to understand or discover quality and then help shift the direction of the product in my head
because that ties back to Eric Reese saying you don't get value from your engineering effort
until it's in the hands of customers and then I'm but even then that's not guaranteed yeah so in my
head though I'm shoving lean startup lean analytics and agile testing into a into a ball and unfolding
into a modern tester yeah and then you sprinkle it with a little test experience and I think
you're exactly right and then maybe a little bit of Jerry Weinberg becoming a technical leader which
I think is a very good book on how to coach and consult with humility trust and respect
yeah I think Jerry's we've been quoting him for years he's he has sort of directed the
principles around modern tester before we've even thought of using these two words together
I mean he's been saying quality is defined by the customer for decades now I think yeah quality is
value to some person okay so what else what else that's good I think we're in I didn't go too far
off track in my definition I think one of the things I'll want to do for I haven't even started
on my slides yet for test bash Brighton sorry for anyone there who thinks I should have but they
they've been forming in my head and I think one thing is important is you know we've been talking
about modern tester here for a while I want to kind of define it and then dive into those
definitions so you can imagine the talk is maybe a definition of a modern tester and then diving
into examples and so are you officially stating that the A.B. testing podcast is now going to
create the sixth school of testing there are no schools of testing so shut up let me repeat that
slowly there are no schools of testing except for those defined by people who want to differentiate
themselves I completely agree I just wanted to make your neck veins bulge I'm fine I'm it's
funny I don't get mad as often anymore I'm not so close to the edge as I used to be maybe
10 months ago and longer yeah I am I'm a little bit of the crotchety old man too like I
I believe in my ways and I think my ideas are sound and I don't mind saying what I believe
and don't believe in just recently I actually saw my last post on the worrisome world of words
and I kind of made fun of some of the semantic argue not named fun I dove into this is worth
bringing up here as well because some people listen more than read but takeaway was that
in the test community there's a lot of focus on oh this word means this and checking versus
testing manual versus human etc etc and while those can be an interesting discussion and they can help
convey some nuance in meeting I realized that as long as the team is aligned on mission and purpose
we know what we're doing and why we're doing it and I poked back to Simon Sinek's work on
start with why don't if you ever read that right it's it's like yeah if you start with why you're
doing it it explains it it's so much easier to get the team behind it we talked about organizational
change etc so if we start with why we're doing what we're doing what is our goal why do we care
about it and get the team aligned on mission and purpose the words you describe whether what
you're doing is called smoke testing or checking or stress testing or whatever just don't matter
or fuzzy bunny yeah fuzzy bunny testing I'm doing fuzzy bunny testing does it matter because instead
those things can be important at a much lower level like I'm going to do some you might say
I'm going to do some soap testing like I've never done it because I don't never bother to look up
what it means but it's a word that's out there I'll ask what does that mean okay I get it no
problem I'm not going to worry about a name because I know it's driving towards our goal and purpose
anyway rewinding the tangent factory back in one thing I wanted to talk about as we begin the
podcast is I had my entire team in town last week for what we called the unity services test summit
USTS about 40 people here a ton of fun more positive feedback honestly than I expected
so I'm really happy people thought the balance was good we had one an overview of all of the
services at unity because nobody really knew what they all were presented by people across the team
spread out over a few days we had some time to talk with each other we had a full day with a
few interruptions of plus a few hours of what we call hack projects this idea of doing uh what
they call them at Microsoft I forgot hackathons hackathon this this idea of doing a hack project
is very much part of the unity culture there's a hack week every year there are little hack days
here and there I wanted to make sure one that we could have some hack time together work on some
projects and that to kind of kick start some cross team projects which would also facilitate
knowledge of knowing who people are and it worked out great people work from different it wasn't
just with a few exceptions it wasn't just like one team clicking together on a project it was uh
it was definitely cross organizational efforts excited about that then of course we had a few
guest speakers we had alam rvold from google talking about life as a productivity engineer
which was good he's technical title is test engineer but he talked about what he does which
is very little testing what did he do here alam rvold was security in office and here being
microsoft for those who can't see the room we're in and then uh a little known principal data
scientist manager from microsoft burt jerson sorry brent jensen also talked about uh what
was your topic on uh building building uh i think it was called building a data-centric culture for
modern tester or something like that i forget the title all right something about using data more
which is a principle i've been driving into my team feedback on that was very good what would
what did you think about that brent i i had a blast i had a blast if there was anything i wish
i could have done differently is show up a little earlier to watch even more of the
presentations uh because i found that picking on members of your team actually helped the
presentation yeah we had someone bring up the the infamous software testing cupcake anti-pattern
yep yep but even then before then you had someone talking about you know the business criteria
and so i was able to weave that into my talk to make it a bit more context sensitive
because uh the the deck itself which uh is available on the slack channel so if you're not on the slack
channel one of the three dot slack dot com you can hit me at twitter at alan page and i'll give
you permission yep um i'll need your email address you can dm me but it it it's a generic deck but
it's missing sort of specific context for the particular business of a particular company and
so getting some context and being able to present it and then tie the dots together that was good
yeah it was good uh one of the things and i love both you and alan were able to re-emphasize a lot
of points i've been making with the team over and over and i definitely saw the takeaway if
people really get that oh yeah data is important we're going to dive in here one of the hack
groups that i sat in on i i kind of wrote i i floated a little bit but one of the hack groups
i sat in on was they called it a study group to look at our existing data and provide some
extra guidance some tutorials etc so we sat down with the we have a used presto a sql engine on
top of our data store okay i started poking through and we found some really interesting
insights which was fun i think insights are addictive we also found a lot of data quality
issues yeah so the fun part there is is every group gave a presentation and i talked a little
bit about data quality in our presentation and i got a little bit of applause when i said
i can't remember how i did it it was very spontaneous but i said data quality is an issue
and we do not have a data quality team blank faces welcome everyone to the unity data quality team
so they understand that not only do they have to use it but they have to start driving
like look these these column names don't make sense the data you're collecting here is not gdpr
compliant these uh this needs to be cleaned up or these these tables should be separate these
tables should be joined these tables should be in this schema they get that now at least it at
varying levels across the org so be careful with that be careful with that because you can
that is a problem that no matter how much energy you spend on it will never get fixed no i i
understand that and you're never going to get it perfect but they know enough the the the tipping
point that i think they're over now is they know enough about it to go to to go to their
teams they're working with and go hey i can't answer this question via data or when i try to
answer this question via data i get this column gives me this information which isn't helpful
so was there anything practice so take away i'm curious takeaways from your team specifically on
mine so you talked to that there were some philosophical principles that i delivered that
all were aligned with things that you've already communicated was there anything in
addition or anything um concrete and practical that you think your team took away uh there's one
thing i was just thinking of is yeah the the approach of how to think about the problem you're
trying to address and strung it through into into the to what data needs to be there i presented
that but it might have been at that point in time too much content no they get it and i want
off a little bit in a tangent talking about our data quality issue but i think it's really at a
meta level they to reel myself back in is a much greater understanding of how important and critical
using data is to our evolution and growth or growth and evolution definitely lots of comments
about that i asked in my opening presentation i asked everyone to leave with an action plan what
am i going to do differently because of what i learned here and i preempted that again at a
higher level saying your big takeaways are really three things see if remember what they are
is i expect you to come to walk away with a much greater understanding of how we use data to do
our job effectively now and in the future that i think accomplished two an overview to you'll
understand what services are at unity across the board and understand the variety of that and
that happened as well via that uh multiple ways and three is just get to know everybody else on
the team when i joined services org was a spread among different teams there was a small services
org but some other pieces were here and there and we've combined those teams and then grown by a
bunch of people so this is the first time they've ever had a chance to meet each other i was the only
person in the room by that could even name half the people in the room let alone all of them
and even by the end nobody could name everybody so this is all so there's a big advantage of
getting everybody together and what that was one of the takeaways so those are very high level
takeaways also then i asked we have our in our internal slack i've asked people to start posting
like parts of their action plan like what's something you're going to do differently what's
something you're going to work on and commit to as a result of this summit and a lot of things so
far are there's some things around engaging with data using our data platform more working with
developers to uh working with their feature teams and even program management to make sure we get
the right data in place that's part of it and then just some continued work on some of the projects
people did which are uh one was really cool using machine learning to uh using machine learning
Brent Brent's eyes just got like as big as like a cow uh using machine learning to detect uh fraud
in our in-app purchase system okay then they got they got to start on that uh which was fun and
they're excited to keep that going but little things like that are just exciting to see uh so
still waiting for more people to enter some of those things so uh we'll see what happens but
overall from my end very happy with what people took away uh we also had a lot of fun too we had some
group dinners together we played whirlyball yeah so everyone everyone got to see just how
competitive i can be i have never uh never played whirlyball for uh those who haven't
played whirlyball which is pretty much anyone listening it's it's a cross between uh kind of
lacrosse and bumper cars and basketball i'll explain it better you have these little short
scoops that you use like to throw the ball back and forth i'm sure they have a name a little
woofle ball back and forth and you want to scoop up the ball and throw it through this
it's like a i think it's vertical with bumper cars it's like a vertical basket so you have a
scoop to pick at the ball throw it through a hole but you're driving around in bumper cars
uh while you're doing this it's as absurd and silly as it sounds but a lot of fun but it's been
it's been team morale um events for decades yeah we have somehow i have escaped it uh my entire
career here so my team uh my team of all stars won every single match of the of the round robin
then we get to the playoff bracket and lose our first match i wanted to fire everyone you're like
but i held back you you didn't step up you you don't beat the boss you're all gone no i wasn't
mad at the team for winning i was mad at my teammates for losing i don't tolerate losers
it was a good time all week so and it worked out very well for my recovery that it was monday
through thursday last week week before last week before last and friday was a company holiday for
veterans day so i got to have a nice three-day weekend to recover that was nice and that was the
sort of the summit and we'll do it again next year uh next year we'll be in europe somewhere
i'm not sure where yet i should probably why didn't you invite me to talk at that one
uh because half my team of course is maybe more than with times ago half my team is from europe these
days and uh while visas we actually got everyone here no one got sent back at the airport visas got
worked out it was great but i think it's fair for travel we'll do it in europe next year i'm not
sure where yet i had uh we had one developer from the ads team attend and he worked on oh a
contract based the contract based testing framework which worked out really well a really
cool guy and he's and i sat next to him oh i went to a place called phogo de chao is that a restaurant
it's a restaurant okay long story but anyway i'm sitting next to him and he starts talking to me
about how we need to have our next off site in his hometown in brazil and it looks it's
beautiful pictures so maybe maybe it'll work out anyway i had a lot of fun we're glad to have
you i think the i think the deck is a solid one i think there's only base off of the uh
i think there's only just a few tweaks that i would want to do to it all right brent
i think we're all out of stuff for today's episode of ab testing agreed all right i'm
allen i'm brent and we'll see you next time