Hey everybody, I'm Alan and Brad and we're here for episode number 56
56 that's way older than either of us
Yelling counting down to episode 100 only 44 to go almost there. We should hit
I don't wait took us three years to get here. Oh
Happy three-year anniversary
Happy three-year anniversary brand
Hug hug kiss kiss
So you haven't made a comment yet, but and listeners you can't see this because the video stream is not working today as far as I know
No, it's offline. I'm wearing a you wearing a unity sweatshirt. Oh, look at you and you're in all like fancy pants
Oh, I'm up with that. I
They're not really fancy pants. You just joined the company. Are you interviewing already? They're not
I am NOT wearing jeans. I'm wearing a pair of blue pants. So
They're really soft. I would have you feel them but then
We might often the podcast would be over probably. Yeah, we have to change our rating
We get all weird and stuff
There's a story behind this particular sweatshirt
one cool thing
We're gonna need a you know, we drink when we say this before yes when Alan talks about how cool it is
I work at unity. We'll have to do something else. I'm not sure what it is. But
One of the things that's kind of fun about unity is each of their offices around the world
They have unique swag for that office. Oh
and
People in the Seattle office look at my kind of purple unity sweatshirt. They go. Oh my god
I want that sweatshirt. You can only get this sweatshirt from the Helsinki office
I have a gray unity hoodie for it from the Seattle office and I eventually I hope to collect a rainbow
so
So the sweatshirt model at unity is gives managers the ability to lord over their their travel budget
just
Being stupid so it's not just swag about I spot identity. So it's not just about
It's about swag. It's not just about sweatshirts. I also got a
unity beanie
Only available there black one. They have socks there too. They didn't have any left
Anyway, it's kind of cool. I haven't really been in the swag rooms as much
They have different swag at different locations different colors and just kind of a fun way to you can kind of spot where someone's from. Oh
Like there's like a conference you go. Oh, you're from Unite. Um, it's Copenhagen unity
Which which location has the coolest color? I don't know yet
What what color is Seattle gray gray of course match the sky, right?
Copenhagen I
Wasn't in Copenhagen long enough to inspect their swag
I was in the office for a half a day and then the next day I was there at a full day off-site
So, how does the swag thing work you just show up and like hey, I'm here
No, I had to do a little finagling and sweet-talking
So it isn't like you show it isn't like a scavenger hunt where you I'm here give me my box of stuff
Is it more like so I don't like at the Olympics like the
Athletes they trade something. I'm trying to remember what it is
Well at the end of a soccer match often players will trade their jerseys, right?
That's right
If it's all over yeah, in fact, I've I did that I walked into the office and I pointed at someone took my shirt off
And offered it to him expecting me to give me theirs, but they just kind of freaked out and walked away
Yeah, that might be a little understandable
Okay, so what do we have for our three listeners today?
For the three today
We've already mentioned episode 56. We wanted to elaborate a little bit on
the comments we discussed before around the role of quality and
How those have played out at least in my work over the last
Couple weeks. Okay, it's been a pony a month since we recorded last
I have been channeling Brent a lot recently in that I've been saying I've been stealing his line on
The role of test or quality arc whatever I call it is to accelerate the achievement of shippable quality
Yep, and the reason I nailed that right is because I actually I've really channeled Brent a lot and
Used that line because I think it encompasses a lot of what I want a quality team to do. So thank you, Brent. Yeah, you're welcome
So I was particularly proud when I finally connected those dots
So what happened was I was at an off-site and I won't go into all the details but
one of our
engineering leaders
Came up with the point
He said that perhaps it wasn't even like seeing this as an absolute says
Perhaps we should consider that all development work should create value or
Right. That what I said in the thing. Yeah, I just what all dev work should create value and then Brett
Brent
Brett's our engineering leader Brett Brent a blue. Are you referring to me or someone else? I'm referring to you. Okay
You had a reaction to that around ROI. Can you recap that?
The actually my reaction
around ROI
was
Was to a comment of what test role because right that comment is around what devs work should be
So my comment was
What test should be doing this? Mm-hmm, right? Cuz that if all dev work
I can actually connect this these two I thought you had maybe I just did in my head
I didn't it so it was a different thread, but I can connect it here, right if all dev work is to create value
One might be able to use that as an argument for for example unit test moving to test to a test org
Right unit tests on create value only product could I would argue they do they create the value that of course you would argue that
But what we're trying to do is talk about like I've had the argument
With dev on multiple occasions like it's all along with the theme of well if we dev are picking up unit tests
What does the test team do I've heard that
It's been a long long time. I've heard the exact same line
I would certainly and I don't think this is the point that we want to get into but certainly I want to be careful with with
absolutist statements like all dev work should create value
Because our create customer value
Because it's pretty clear. It doesn't take much sort of
Psychological analysis to come to the conclusion then that means dev should only be working on product code
Because that's what creates customer value. You could definitely spin it that way and
Any
developer who is on
Marching on the the side of all I want to do is write code
That's something that they're gonna use
as a
Yeah, I could I could see how it could fall down that trap and and I could see why in our org
why it would be safe to make that statement because
All of our devs consider writing tests part of writing code
But definitely you definitely have a culture in place for you to say an absolute this is not and to be clear
This is a statement. I wanted to capture out of context
To have this conversation. Okay, it's not a statement on like how unity does development and how
People are rewarded or anything like that. It was a statement. I thought oh, I think this now this is interesting
I want to bring this up in the context of what Brent and I were talking about
Accelerating the Brent and I I'm taking half credit now
Accelerating
I'm taking all credit
Accelerating the achievement of simple quality
So just I just want to be clear on that that it's not like this is the way unity does stuff
I want to capture this statement because I thought it would kick off a discussion. No, it sounds like
you you were in a
Off-site with leadership. This is what it sounded like to me and
Your executive is doing what he's
should be doing which is trying to
understand and
communicate the principles in which
He was he was digging he wants to come up with guiding principles. This is well
This is my vision or my not vision but the vision
My understanding of it inception vision. He's he's trying to create principles
You've already expressed that that unity
is
classally less of a command and control structure than here at Microsoft and
And the way you you do that at an executive level as you you create these
rallying cry type
principles that guide behavior and guide decision-making at the lower levels so many tangents in my head
Trying to control that your face suddenly just turned really red
Oh many so many so I'm gonna start do a couple of them
All right
One is you mentioned that I just have to say I had no I knew my previous manager Microsoft was a bit of a micromanager
in reflection. Oh my god over the top massive
Micromanager it is relative, isn't it?
Justice we cast some conversations around some
Personnel things and I made some gut calls that this is what I think and I'm good about taking one of the things I have
really worked on being able to do is being able to make a decision giving either a lot of data or a small amount of
data and then but it's so weird to
Make that decision or offer the decision. Here's what I think I'm gonna do or here's what I want to do and
Not have it completely picked apart and second-guessed and it's like wait that sounds right. I trust your decision instead
It's weird. It's good
But yeah, the other tangent before you go on is you mentioned rallying cry
Yeah, as I've mentioned many times
I'm a big fan of Pat lunchioni's business fables around leadership and and growth
He probably the most famous one is the five dysfunctions of a team, but probably not even in the top five of his books
One of the things he mentions in one of the books and I forget which one is the need for a rallying cry and a lot
of companies will develop a rallying cry as a reaction to a crisis and Brent and I will remember in
2000 when Microsoft was just full of viruses with code red and slammer how the whole company basically went offline for a
while a few months month to just study security and learn how to write secure software and
Build a security culture. We had a rallying cry around security. Yes
And and to this day now Microsoft I believe is
Knows more about writing secure software than most companies in the world because it's really beat into the culture
But the challenge is and what we're potentially even
Overdoing it perhaps but what I'll tell you like every third action on my desktop right now
I have to take out my badge and
Do a FA. Yeah, the internal security is great. I don't miss that
I don't miss I have a normal password on my phone. I miss type the password. My phone doesn't get wiped
I told some of my teammates
My boss and some and a colleague
About the fact that if I type my password wrong three times my phone to get wiped out and their jaws just dropped and they
Freaked out they couldn't believe that could ever actually happen anywhere. That was a tangent on top of a tangent. So rewinding one tangent
What's important for a company to do an organization is have a rallying cry even when there isn't a crisis
Have have this this ties in a little bit maybe to in lean analytics. Yeah. Yeah, the one true metric
What's the one thing we care about?
right, so a
And it can be context sensitive. I find
that it's helpful if you have for example a
An executive that has different sorts of teams
right, I
think it's okay that he gives a
different sort of
rallying cry or a sub rallying cry for that team, right
He may be focused on reducing cycle time
Right. Yeah, and that's gonna be something that's gonna be really important for
The whole business unit that may be his master rallying cry, but he may go to the engineering systems team and
Create a more actionable one. That's like hey, I want 15-minute builds
Yeah, right. All right. Let's put a pin in that because actually I have some
Principles for my team at Unity, but I want to hit those a little bit later
You want to pop the stack a little bit and come back to I wanted to set context on
The comment about all dev works should create value. Let's say that was that's not a
principle or a rallying cry of unity that was a
Statement made to start another discussion which I captured in order for us to have this discussion which we are having now and
Well, this is this is the first time I think we've ever like
Decomposed our tangential route I
Had to remember in order for me to remember what we were
Back I had to pop the stack and remember how the hell we got there
Which is really just skip over it. There's this awesome thing. We write up for the episodes every time
Just go straight to it. Yeah, you know, what would be good. I wonder if you played a
This podcast over
Over
With the sound muted the movie inception if our conversations would line up with the dream within a dream within a dream
I'm sure it does
It's be like when you play dark side of the moon with Wizard of Oz and there's another one of those
Okay. Yeah. All right, then so so anyway
You were talking. So do you want me to well, where do you want to go?
Do you want to get to the ROI discussion the nuance?
I want to discuss was you talked about ROI in the sense you can I'm gonna paraphrase it while you're looking it up on
Your phone and then you can talk about it the point you got to that if the goal of test is to accelerate
the achievement of shippable quality
Then blah blah blah the goal of test is to reduce I
Reduce the investment make it easier to achieve result. So what I said in this context
Right. This was on the slack channel and
One of the three dot slack calm
Several of the three were sort of
chatting back and forth
It started off with a question
Around us mentioning that there should be an emphasis on only working on stuff that provably increases customer value
And then there was a question. What would you do when you get into a company?
where the codebase is horrible without any automated tests and or we're running a
Linter linter a static analysis tool. Okay or some other
Similar tool. I don't have my reading glasses on I apologize
Finds all kinds of bugs or potential bugs
Would you invest any time in improving the codebase and or writing automated tests or do you expect?
Approved the direct relation of this to customer value how etc. And then there was a bunch of discussion
Amongst the three well, you're scrolling down
I'll say the first thing I do in a company like that is by a bunch of copies of Michael feathers working with legacy code
Fantastic ideas in that book for how to deal with that sort of mess
Yeah, and I would also bring in them
Martin Fowler's refactor. I find that book is fantastic. Yeah
There's a pair then what the hell might as well bring in his continuous
Delivery book I forget the name of it is a continuous deployment
Martin
Part is Martin and Fowler combined and in a fortunate way
Martin Fowler is just a fantastic author for these type of things. Alright, so my comment was
All features should be done to provably
Proveably create customer value, but they should be done in ROI order and then I state testing in this light
serves one goal and one goal only to reduce I
That and that's what I want to discuss because but when I was saying in this light it was on the conversation of
Fixing devs crappy architecture. Yeah, so
I for now you put that in context the discussion is less relevant. So I looked at that I thought yeah and
The first time I saw that statement I thought I said that's actually
Gets to the crux of your initial statements. It's a reduction of
Accelerate the achievable quality right then that made me think
Inception inception inception. It made me think that well if the goal of test is to reduce I
Then is the role of test merely a cost reduction
rule I
And and then I have tried to abstract that out and I don't think it is
And it could be in a way, but I never wanted to be counted that way
No
but if you so even my even my mantra that you've talked about here like the
That our role is to accelerate the achievement of shippable quality
Right. I picked the word acceleration on purpose
right because it acceleration is
the the act of
Taking an existing speed and speeding it up
right, so
it's an auxiliary role if you think of it from a from a
into in business type of thing it is
It it implies that there is another
element that is a
working to achieve shippable quality and
Test roles in this is to take that element
understand the processes of the missing tooling and speed it up and
Now ROI can be framed in terms of costs like it normally is
But as you're aware
Normally nowadays when I think of these sorts of things
The biggest cost I'm concerned with is calendar time. Mm-hmm. Right, but it might I I have mentioned this before
But my number one concern is are we producing business value?
My number two concern is how do we shrink calendar time?
My number three concern is how do we shrink the number of engineering hours required? Mm-hmm. Yeah
I
Think my very first blog on this topic
Was on what is the ROI of test?
in another light one that I think is more for
Might be more helpful or more lightning or more
useful to the audience is is around
risk reduction
But one of the things that I do see
tests like what was communicated on the on the channel is we see a lot of
Tests saying hey this code base sucks. So we should create a bunch of automation to
To what make it easier to
Determine when you screwed up the code base. Is that not enablement to some degree?
right at the it's
We
tests in my humble opinion, right
Really wants to construct the practices that enables
This acceleration on a regular basis
right
Creating a multi-million dollar test suite upon a crappy code base doesn't really do that
That can be a little bit of the if all you have is a hammer. Everything's a nail. Yeah, automation
I'm gonna do this what I have I'm curious to your thoughts on this now is
When I elaborate on the context of your statement, which I've stolen as stated before
I talk about it's now public domain
I talk about my love and admiration of the theory of constraints quite a bit. Yes in that
Figure out not what sucks, but what's the biggest bottleneck?
to our
Process here. What's the biggest bottleneck and not solve it completely
Mitigate it until it's not the biggest bottleneck anymore and then take on the next I will say so I like that approach
I just don't like the word mitigate
So what would you use instead? I would say
Solve enough of it. I think it's is that what it means it does now mitigate to me means
You know, hey the the buildings on fire
We're gonna mitigate the pain by just removing everybody from the building
Let the building burn. I will look for a better word, but you get it. It's like the conversation I had
With someone just last week is like our devs really want some end-to-end tests as part of their
Chicken suite and we're gonna help them get started on that. But I also have this I
Also want to make sure we get this other
multi-machine thing running for
That going in the details. Okay, and
In order prioritization, you know, it's maybe even goes to ROI from the acceleration side, right? Which one solves the bigger bottleneck?
So well the devs already have a bunch of check-in tests. But one thing we can't do is we have we're totally blind over here
Okay, do that. So we're not blind anymore. Maybe don't get all the way done
But get rid of blind spots goes through the crap out of me big ROI there
Yep, and then if the devs getting some more end-to-end tests as part of their suite is the next biggest bottleneck for our
Accelerating the achievement of shippable quality then do that but otherwise but reevaluated every step. It's a constant reprioritization right and to your point around
Solve enough of it so that it's not the biggest bottleneck like
one thing I might consider if I were in your shoes like
so you
this
This end-to-end suite right? So let's theorize. Hey, there isn't
There isn't the test hooks necessary, right? So the
from my experience
It sounds like an age-old ask of hey
I want you to build me and end-to-end test suites for my check-in tests and
And I might go well
I have this huge major thing that we're completely blind to that it that is bothering me more. But what I will do is
I will take one guy offline and
Make it make a library such that you can build that in the end test suite
That's exactly it's what we do is we bootstrap. It's it's really they have a bunch of
Unit level tests and they wanted to have some selenium tests running there as well
And but they don't know how to write selenium tests very well. It's a basically they want to be bootstrapped
They don't want they don't want please write all of our tests for us
It's like please make it so we can write selenium tests that run and then and then we can jump in and do that
yeah, and and
again, if if that if
Breaking down
The workload in the smaller tasks and you determine the smaller tasks captures
70% of the ROI for the whole thing
And it's cheap do that first if it's not then do what's next first
So on the slack channel you mentioned
That there was some nuance have we covered this then I think we have covered the nuance
I just wanted to talk about the eye a little bit and see if I think we're in large agreement
So it wasn't as exciting. Okay
Tangent and I'll figure how to edit this to its less
Penis smacking so the the one thing though they still
Do have a problem with on a just from a dev centric point of view is the statement around all dev work should create customer value
Right and the other we don't need to go into it
but the other thing that I do see as a problem with that is that potentially a
argument
For the complete elimination of architectural improvements
And you could and there's plenty of ways to blow holes in that statement. Yes, it's absolutely not true all the time
It's absolutely true some of the time and let me tell you a case where it is. I
Believe in I
culture of experimentation. Yep getting to a stage where everything you ship is an experiment and
in order to
Determine the success of that experiment. You have to have some
Criteria for determining that and that's and what you want to determine is what is the business or customer value of this experiment and
Then find a way to measure that and determine very quickly if that experiment was a success or a failure
My my success or failure did it do that it improved business value as I thought or it didn't and
When you're in experimentation
Experimentation culture you do this so often that you don't care that
Seven out of ten experiments fail or eight out of ten because you're doing it quickly enough and often enough that those two or three
That do increase value
Over time add up to massive improvements for customer happiness and love etc
You you there's another reason why you don't care about them failing is because you've crafted the experiment and that every
failure is still a win
It it's a learning experience. Yes
But so that's an example of why if all I'm doing is experiments
Then of course, but then of course everything provides value, but you're right. There's architectural improvements
There's building that safety net of a good unit test suite all those things you could say they
Supply
Indirect customer value they make it so we can give you new features more quickly because our stuff can't break
But but in the end the statement falls apart under analysis and that's okay
Which is why I want to get the caveat early on this is not a statement of how to make software not a suggestion
It is a
Often in debate or discussion. It's great to make a statement
That's partially but not entirely true and the learning comes from picking it apart. Yeah the
So like my favorite these type of rallying cry type principles
Well number one I generally
Despise
absolutist statements
Right and even things like the agile manifesto like you know very well. I hate the thing and it's it's
Because it creates a sort of absolutism that is
When it's read wrong, which it's read wrong. I know
I know it says given this or this we value both we prefer this one more right
But people therefore we should go all in on this one thing people don't read it that way and I saw a Rex black tweet
This morning. I was gonna reply. I thought I'm not gonna bother but he went off on
Basically he
He went off on is the process the software talking about all the love for agile scrum XP and
As you and I and the three know those are a means to an end
They're a way of doing things that may help you
Get customer about get better customer value to customers sooner
But if you just follow the process blindly I think it's gonna make you make great software. You're stupid blind faith is always stupid
It is a system like this is something that just drives me batty
producing software is a system and
No, if you follow if you follow the process
Just you're perfect your golden all you have to do is follow the process very carefully what process you define it except for the
First process the process Rex Rex's process
I'm being
Right because following process
blindly in anything in software in school in whatever is
dumb
improving the system
Always relies on
understanding
the technology base that we have the people that we're working with and the
Processes that combine all three and if you just focus on the process
You're gonna screw up the people a three. Guess what Brent sounds like he's context-driven
Again it's redundant just because I use the C word
All right
Anyway, it's healthy go on to the mail. I guess I'll back off the edge of the cliff here. Oh
All right good to be back recording again, you know cue that up
male
Alright, so
one of our
listeners posted a question
I'm gonna read the whole thing. I will sit back in my chair and relax
All right in the in the most recent episode there was it was a month ago. I'm sorry. Oh wait
That's not the right one anyway
All right. I'm it in the last podcast you stated. This is to Alan in the last podcast you stated that your
Mission or part of it is to create some sort of a unified testing culture across the organization
question is
How to do such a thing where I work we have a much simpler situation
Four teams in the same building all part of some sort of scrum teams
And the difference is the difference in approach and skill set are painful
How would the first steps to creating it a common culture?
would look like
bonus
How to do that without being a manager and bonus number two?
How do you intend to do that in your organization?
Where you have to gap multiple cultures and time zones all right?
Let's just take all those in no particular order at the same time intermingled
Okay in this session brand-new session we call
Alan's life at Unity oh
I'm totally
That was unlike mailbag, I don't think you could do that
Totally improvised I'm not sure if that's gonna make the cut or not, but we'll see what happens
It's good to be in control of the editing sometimes
So really I'm gonna answer that by telling you what how I'm approaching that at Unity
And I've been there just about two months exactly now if you can believe it I can
so I think the first step in doing any sort of organizational change is
Take some time to learn what's going on
Figure out
There's noise in the background it's freaking us out
You need to get a good assessment of the current state
When I think about organizational change to think about current state and desired state
And then you can worry about the steps in between, but you need to be able to find where you are so I did that I
have
Now met in person most of my team and we'll have met all of them in person face to face
Probably by the end of May and that's helped out a lot. I'm gonna do a
Interjection. Yep
this is this is a
Very simple insight that I see a lot of people when they're knee-deep into it, but they forget
They either know where they are or where they want to be
right and and then they start taking action they don't
Spend the time to figure out that other part of
We'll call it the line like if if and I use will use a metaphor like if you're in, California
and you like oh
this sucks, I got to keep moving and
You start driving and realize you need to go to Hawaii
right, it's
Not gonna help you right you didn't properly plan out that you can't drive there right another similar situation
Right I've used this metaphor
It's so we're in Washington State which is north of California, and there's many times where I observe that people are
Driving to California by heading north yeah theoretically you'll eventually get there
But it's not the efficient route right so in that case like they know where they want to go
But they're not taking the direction that gets there so
understand not only where you want to be but where you are now and
Then build a plan to bridge sure sure and it sounds obvious
But I see people forget this all of the time and the other thing is it's not
There isn't a teleportation chamber that takes you from
Washington to California not yet not yet so
Part of it. I'll go this a little bit deeper you understand where you are where you're going
You want to take a baby step that direction and then by the time you take a couple baby steps your destination may change
We may start getting down the road. We're south
We're like get on our way to Portland, and we realize that you know what we actually need to go to Vegas
So things can change so
Taking this from the abstract to the concrete a little bit
I have a pretty good idea of where we are and in learning where we are there's
What I'm finding is parts of my organization are farther along that road towards where I want to go
Which is a data-driven data-centric culture for for services
Parts of the org are actually part way down that road and some are well that sounds really interesting
I actually found one of our our teams
You'll be happy to hear this brand they're talking about how they're approaching this one sort of testing said and they said so what we do
Is we just?
I guess don't need to give any context about this
So what we do is we just run a bunch of tests, and then we detect errors by analyzing the log files
Which is what you talked about I said that's a good approach really say yeah, that's actually a very good approach
Yeah, no I love that approach I thought you'd be happy about yeah, yeah, we can do more of that
So anyway, I have an idea who my allies are and make sure do they do the do they use their
How do they analyze these log files and are they using the same tooling on prod?
it says
One thing I didn't want to go deep dive into context the thing about my you just say yes or no
It's not applicable and okay. It's NA all right because
although I
Am the director for all of quality for all of Unity services
I also
air quote own
Wherever those services touch clients or editors so basically anything that is connected to a back end I own whether that
Code actually runs on a client device or a computer or in the cloud, so I do have some client testing as well
Like we have a feet so so you own the client the service integration as well. Yes
So I own how the service connects to the editor the Unity editor as well as how?
if the service
Like we have an SDK for example for doing ads on mobile devices
So I own how that SDK works on the mobile devices as well
Okay, okay, so anyway. I've learned
Where my allies are which is important to do if you're gonna make change and also
It would be stupid of me, and I'm sure I've mentioned before to go in there and go I have ideas
Here's what we're doing. Let's go
One of the things I said to the team both publicly and privately to people is I
Have a direction where I think we should go
But I want to do it in a way that by all means does not screw up any of the good things already happening here
Which I I I just think it would be stupid of me to take a company that
Full of smart people full of people working in really good ways and then tell them they're doing it wrong like you're doing it wrong
So I wanted to share I sent some just this week. I said
I did some bouncing. I've
My team structure just you know is I have three leads reporting to me with various sized teams plus like nine ICs
nine individual contributors so I have a combination of
Areas, I'm directly in charge of plus some leads take care of some areas, and they're spread out throughout the world
So probably worth as I loop back into trying to answer this question the next five minutes or so is I
Have these people all over the world and
One thing I've told the team is that they all report to me
or up through me
But their work is almost entirely dictated by the feature teams. They work on they are everyone is a member of a feature team a scrum team
Many of them use calm bottom instead of scrum to make bread
But they remember that feature team they I suggest and most of them do already have one-on-ones with that feature team lead
In addition to me or their other lead who has one-on-ones
The the test folks the QA folks they don't already know I make sure they have one-on-ones with their feature
As well as me I I have one-on-ones with my whoever serves as PO for right because that's that's where their work comes from
They're gonna get better feedback on their day-to-day work
So I tell them I don't I'm not in charge of the QA organization as much as I'm in charge of a QA community
Okay, and the value of community and I wrote that up and then I said well am I thinking of community the right way?
So Q tech comes back
replanted to unity gosh
No
Probably maybe maybe but I didn't type the definition up here, but community is a group of people who share
common
Knowledge with each other and and and I think it's a good way to describe it
And for the listeners Q tech because I out whenever I mentioned an acronym
I always get slammed on slack channel Q tech was the name of a community that
Alan ran here at my quality and testing experts community. Yes
many years ago
Basically, I shared like here are here's how our community is gonna run. I explained like I get out of your way blah blah
But I wanted to plant some seeds to get people used to things
number one use data to understand how our features work in production and how customers use what we make and
In that I explained that some teams are using monitoring in production as testing very well
I've started them off on Ed Keys talk as a
As a start there. I'll give them some more more things after Brent gives me a good list to share
And that works on the service by getting services side used to using monitoring as testing in production they know how that works
They're gonna start thinking that way and then for the client bits using that customer data to understand
Analyzing it seeing how customers use the products
I believe that kind of moving in that direction without saying I'm moving them from data oblivious to data aware
Yep, that's that's step one. That's that's the mission right now
number two, how is that
Resonated very very well, okay. I made sure it would first I bounced things
before I
Probably worth mentioning is I would never just spout this out saying okay, please follow this direction
I made sure it was gonna work with the majority after had the allies you're gonna go this thing right to you
Yeah, let me tell you why everybody gets it. They're all on board
Okay, but I just wanted to say it out publicly and our slack channels are are shared
They're all wide open. We have a few private ones for like, you know some managerial stuff, but they're mostly wide open
in fact in my
I never use email anymore. I posted this to our public slack channel
And what's great was a lot of the likes and comments came from devs and support people reading about how we're going to
I'm structuring QA. So that was good. Number two discuss our hard problems and solutions with each other
So what I found in doing my my rounds around the world is like, oh, here's a really good thing you're doing
Here's a really good thing. You're doing Oh God, if you guys just shared this stuff and with each other
Both right beginning with the solutions, but also the hard problems like I have a hard problem figuring out how to do this
we're really challenged with this and encouraging the community to
Collaborate and just using something like slack works much better than email for this where you can find a way to have an open
discussion around anything from conceptual to
Concrete like technical solution. I want to bring up something because actually this this hit me at my work this week
And I want so on that one. I love it be proactive in
stating that
Duplication of effort is okay
but
Doing so without collaboration is not
Yeah, right
So the there's this one in and I've rallied against it in my entire time here at Microsoft
this one prevailing belief that
Duplication of effort is just naturally evil and it is is not
Because it's again very context sensitive. Yes
so it and they've already heard me early on in in not
Like stating principles for the org just talking about how I work is that I really value learning and learning from mistakes and
Trying new things out they get that so this is a natural progression. I like that. Let's share what we're doing
It's important that we learn from each other
Right. So and that's it and then I wanted I truly believe this and I wanted to be a little aspirational is
earlier in the week or last week I
Shared some of my favorite services tech blogs with them like the Netflix tech blog the Etsy engineering blog
There was a great article about engineering at Pinterest this week
I love you saw and I I share those and so they're kind of getting the idea again
Helping bring them from our team them our team from data oblivious to data aware
Yeah, and it's also you're doing the element of sort of
Greasing the wheels on
Crowdsourcing to some degree. Yeah. Yeah, it's like that look
We're here to solve problems. I don't
care
to to
Create a culture of not invented here. Well, absolutely not
Yeah, yeah, and and the last one I put is I think a logical extension of that is of all that together is
Unity has a tech blog and sometimes there are quality related posts on there mostly to this to at this point talking about
how
Like we've handled some complex testing for the shaders and the graphic stuff like you can imagine like it would be in an Xbox blog
Good stuff on there. There was one just last week on how we do exploratory testing, which is very good
But I encourage them number three was share our best technical solutions publicly
I have aspirations of
unity services blog being
unity tech blog having posts which are right up there in that group of my
other people look at as their
Tech service blogs if you look at again Netflix at sea, you know, maybe Pinterest
Unity and they get there. I think there are some good solutions already, but to start thinking about
How important those are for not just to share with the public to show cool things we're doing but to inspire customer confidence
I think
one of the reasons I'm amazed using Netflix is because I look at their blog and I know how much cool science and technology
Goes into how they do selection engines and uptime and streaming and things like Chaos Monkey and the whole
Simeon army as they call it. I think there's some good stuff there and I want to strive for artwork to be there, too
So so so whining back. Hold on because I because
the omits questions
But I think you've nailed the how you're approaching this
But then I don't think you've covered
What you might suggest if you were doing this and you weren't a manager and
And more specifics around how you're gonna handle the the geopolitical
Time's only boundaries. Okay, the second one's easier because I actually think I have covered that have the discussions in the open
transparency is key and
My org is all over the world and it hasn't been a problem people
It's so have the conversations like at your company
You're saying no don't call me and have the conversation have the conversation with me on slack channel
Right an exam everything is just transparent in the open around the world. Everybody can participate
Like like I said my team channel on my team channels. I have you know, there's QA services QA
component QA
they're all public channels and
Anybody can jump in and anybody's is
Encouraged to jump in and it works around the world
I think a tool like you heard it here first Alan Page wants to kill the hallway conversation the hallway conversation is slack
you because
Because of the world being flat and having organizations everywhere if you have a geo distributed company
Slack is your hallway
Channel we have the company of 1,400 people. We have 800 slack channels
There you go
You join the ones that got 600 more to do I just joined the Seattle coffee walk
So if someone wants to go get coffee
We we have like a great coffee machine, but we'll walk over to cafe Laudra for just to get outside in the gray sky
Good yeah, it's good and the last question was so not as a manager
It's largely the same. There's probably two things. I will add to this before we close up for the day
I'm gonna change it. Yeah, not as a manager in
a command and control system. Oh god, so I've done this before so
I've done this actually a very similar role in Xbox as an IC
most of my IC time at Microsoft was spent sort of as the
Technical assistant to the director of test or test manager person running the queue
Yeah, it's not a real IC and you know it it but it is but it's a leadership role
The thing is individual contributor can be a leader
So what I how I did this in Xbox for example largely command and control although my manager Chris was very
Definitely not a micromanager, which was awesome
Is I built a community again?
I just because you're not a manager doesn't mean you can't build a community
I could have sent this message to slack as a senior IC and said here's how I think we should be doing and
Just have my manager like it
as a as a
mode of support
But I don't believe even in a command where I worked at Microsoft for most of my career in command and control
most of my career at Microsoft was in a command and control system as an individual contributor that
Didn't stop me from attempting or trying or sometimes being successful at being a leader across an organization
That's that went even beyond my managers often almost always went beyond my managers
Organization because I thought I did the work in a way that
Was not
Dictatorial
Like a dictator. Yep, but just in this these same ways as I'm doing now
Constantly spreading seeds and doing things at a like very slowly turning up the heat to get people moving in a direction
And like I said realizing that the direction may change over time
So the one thing that I'll say
Because I've gone through this sort of conversion
Repeatedly now, right? The way I like to run my teams and the way I like to get them going when they're
running smoothly
Means the team doesn't come and ask me for to make decisions all the freaking time. Yeah, because you don't
number one you avoid the command and control
As much as I can that is around you
I mean you've almost had to do that in most teams at Microsoft
I was told that you know if you do that too much you get fired
Like if if I were to solve this for Microsoft
I would just say like look if you're a manager you have to have at least 15 reports
Because you can't do micro management very well with that
And if that's your style you'll get pruned up pretty quickly
Right, but the other thing but there's another aspect because I'll tell you one of the really hard problems around
around this when it comes to individuals
right command and control
creates a safety net it says
I
the leader the command and controller are the is the one that's accountable for risk-taking
Because there there is there is no leadership without risk-taking
correct and
really what this comes down to like what I do is I I
I boil frogs and I teach these individuals first thing that has to happen is to teach these individuals
What it means to influence and lead?
Right because a lot of times I get the questions like well
How do I do this as an IC and what they really want is a formulaic step-by-step plan that guarantees success and?
You have to have built credibility as a leader and maybe that's the answer is how do you do this as an IC you lead
You learn to become a leader. Yes, exactly. I think this will inspire some more questions
We'll get to you next time. Yep, but we should probably close for the day and
Put episode 56 in the bag or the can all right. I'm not Brent and I am
See you next time. Bye