Hey everybody!
Howdy!
I'm Alan.
I'm Brent.
And today is episode 53.
Today is January 20th.
Today is January 20th, not if you're listening.
If you're listening, don't go adjust your calendar.
But we're recording this simultaneous with the presidential inauguration and the beginning
of Alan's last day at work at Microsoft.
Yes.
We can record this and you can get it edited and out.
Perhaps people will have something amusing to do today.
It's not going out today.
I'll tell you that.
I have crap to do all day today.
We'll get back to that later.
Maybe.
Yes.
I don't know.
I tweeted this morning that I said, hey, I was watching the inauguration preparation
this morning and Obama has a staff to help him move out.
I have a gym bag in my car.
I'm hoping everything I have left fits in there.
You have employees.
I know.
Have you not really learned how to use these guys yet?
You thought I was a good manager.
Wrong.
By the way, I told you I submitted your connect.
Not yet.
I hit send in an hour.
Oh, no, they're all done.
I'm all done.
Hey, this episode of A.B.
Testing.
Big milestone.
Why?
What's the milestone?
53, is it a prime number?
It might be.
I tried to stump the math major.
I don't know.
I have to have a calculator.
53, does it divide by?
No.
I think not.
I think it's prime.
Yeah, I'm looking forward to being 53.
I haven't been a prime number in a while.
Age wise.
Yeah, I'm not looking forward to it.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Oh, I don't know what the milestone, but today's episode is brought to you by Techwell, the
company that brings you the wonderful Star Conferences.
Star, and many other conferences.
So we've talked about Star Conferences before, and Star East is coming up.
Not coming up right away, but time to start making travel plans.
It's in May.
Where is it?
It's in Orlando, the home of Harry Potter World and Disney World and many attractions.
Orlando in May.
Orlando is a good time to be there.
So that's May 5th to 12th.
And as our listeners know, Star East is one of the longest running and most respected conferences
on software and testing.
It's probably the biggest, I don't know of a software testing conference that has more
people there.
No.
And one of the things that I continue to espouse, something, say something about Star Conferences.
Preach.
Preach is the word.
Proselytize.
Star Coffee, which is not empty enough for me to be on full Allen speed, but one of the
biggest values I get from conferences is the networking and talking to people and talking
to speakers.
If you go to these conferences and just sit in the back of the, if you go to talks
and just sit in the back and take notes, you're not getting the full value.
You really need to talk to people and see what they're doing and get those experiences.
The talks will give you plenty of good ideas on things you can do.
For me, the bridge between even the most experiential talk, taking that from something
that you've listened and were motivated by to something you can do that connection is
often made just by talking to others.
The Star East, the Star Program, unlike other conferences we may have talked about on the
AB testing podcast, the Star is paying attention to how the world is moving.
So, not only will you pick up and help establish a network, and quite honestly, if you have
been in the industry, if you've been in the industry and you get to the 10 plus year
milestone, if you haven't built up a network, you're really hurting your career.
Working on that network, getting associated with people who have similar likes and tastes
in other companies grows your options.
Going to Star is also going to help you be more valuable.
It's going to help you understand and pick up the learnings of how testing is done in
today times, not 1993.
Sure.
There may be some 93 there, but not much.
The thing is, you can learn to differentiate that.
If you get enough information, you begin to form your own opinions.
One thing, first before we go any farther, I'll mention this again, but as usual, if
you want to go to Star, we recommend it, use the promo code AB testing.
AB testing, one word.
AB testing, one word, 200 bucks off.
Two hundred.
You go to your boss, say, I want to go to this conference, and he goes, yeah, it
approves and goes, and I can get $200 off.
I have that money for extra expenses and nice dinners and drinks.
Try and work that out.
Upgrade to first class, depending on where you're flying out of, I guess.
Yeah.
Lots of different topics, test automation, agile testing, which I'll talk about a
little bit more in a minute, perf testing, leadership, more.
They've done this a couple times now, but a full day bonus session on women in test,
which I think is really cool.
Oh, speaking of which, because we do tangents, there is nationwide women's
march tomorrow should be, I think it's like a million women in Washington, D.C.,
just doing a silent march down the walk, but down the mall.
And then there are every city has these things just to support, not just to
support women, but equal rights for everyone.
And some of the worries we have in the change in leadership and where some of
those equal rights may go.
And as the first day of my one week retirement and my nine day retirement,
I'm going to take place in the women's march tomorrow.
Where?
It starts in Judkin, Spark, and Seattle, in the Seattle one.
Oh, okay.
Quick flight to Washington, D.C.
Yeah.
I'm like, really?
We better hurry up this podcast.
So yeah.
You're walking.
I'm going to go do that and support equal rights for everyone.
I think it'll be largely women there, but I think, you know, people of all genders,
races, it would be silly to have a right of walk for equal rights and then not
exclude some people from attending.
So there'll be several men there as well.
My son's going to walk with us.
Whole family is going to go just to, I think it'd be a good experience for all
of us back to star again, promo code AB testing, lots of exhibitions, et cetera.
Really, if you want to get like an onslaught of different ideas and testing,
you know, I'm a big fan of the peer, the smaller peer conferences where you can
have a lot of one-to-one discussions.
You can make those happen at STAR, but the great thing about STAR is if I want
to suck in all kinds of information, it's a great place for that.
And we know that Lee also pays attention to other conference styles.
Absolutely.
Yeah.
Right.
Alan mentioned when he came back from Test Bash that Lee interrogated him on what
was a positive negative.
So I wouldn't be surprised if we start seeing some of those other aspects of
those conferences fold into STAR.
I bet they would.
Yeah.
He wants to know, when he sees that go to a different conference, he goes,
who was a good speaker?
Who should I get for a STAR conference?
He's always trying to upgrade and get some new blood in there.
Wasn't it STAR that, cause you're the one that introduced me to this concept.
Wasn't STAR that introduced you to the concept of the lightning talks?
Yeah.
The lightning talks happen every time, but it's not.
I've been doing lightning talks for longer.
Okay.
But every STAR, they have one keynote session, which is all lightning talks,
five minute talks, which I love.
A great way to, one, for people to get up and just get an idea across that maybe
isn't appropriate for a full talk, but man, talk about onslaught of ideas.
Uh, one thing, STAR doesn't do this.
Nobody does it, but when I've gone to conferences, uh, again, tangent, uh,
I've always thought that, that, uh, the hour talk is a little too long.
Some people, I would love to go...
Lots of science on that one.
Is there really?
Oh yeah.
I would love to go to a conference full of half hour talks.
Like the TED talk 22 minutes, wasn't just some number they pulled out of the
air, right?
There's research, research behind that.
So I, I'm waiting for that.
Maybe Lee, if you're, if not, if, when you're listening, there's something to
consider, maybe have one track.
That's all 22 minute talks or do one day of the conference or, or a morning
session where all the talks are 22 minutes with an eight minute passing period.
I think it would be very interesting.
There's more structure to the, to have you ever, uh, look this up?
That's not just 22 minutes.
Do I, do I look like someone who looks things up?
Actually I do.
I know you things up.
Um, just not necessarily the same things I do.
Um, there's a, I don't have the hard drive space for that.
By the way, uh, not yet, but I sent you my, my computer specs for tangent number
four.
Yeah.
And, uh, I order parts from my computer, a few upgrades from what you had and a
few things I didn't get didn't get a raid array of SSDs.
Um, I got one down the video card and what I, which is fine.
You got the, like the super, oh my God, fast mega.
There is one more better.
But the coolness was not worth the price tag.
But I didn't get an M2.
Um, I got the, uh, the new Intel Kaby Lake processor, so a little faster processor.
Okay.
What'd you do for MB motherboard?
Oh, I got, um, an Asus Z270.
So I like the Asus.
Um, yeah, I like there by, I, uh, there's a lot of tangent upon tangent.
It's tangents all the way down.
Uh, yeah.
Anyway, I, I've, I've, I've been an Asus user.
I decided to go with Asus cause I'm used to it and I knew I know the bio.
Well, you mentioned rate array.
I didn't buy a rate array.
My motherboard already had that, but I didn't buy like a whole bunch of, uh,
SSDs to just bought two really big ones and then I striped them.
Yeah.
Okay.
So anyway, oh star, oh promo code AB testing may, may, uh, Orlando,
200 bucks off AB testing.
Let's talk a little bit about a couple of the agile test sessions there.
If you don't mind, Brett, actually I'll start off.
What is agile testing?
Why it's just testing as fast as you can.
Right.
Shut the hell up.
Actually, before we go into that one.
So as, as you mentioned, uh, it's, it's Obama's last day.
Today we were recording on Alan's last day.
That is all correct.
And before we get much further, I have a gift for you.
We're still talking about star, but okay.
No.
Well, yeah, we're talking about star, but it comes with cups.
Should I worry?
This is the sound of paper coming out.
Oh shit.
It's tequila.
I think Brent and I are actually drinking tequila during AB testing today.
Happy inauguration day, everybody.
Yes.
I wanted to, I wanted to get that out while there was still an
opportunity for Alan to say the forbidden words.
We've talked about this before.
I have in my hands here for those who thought the video feed second of all,
second of all, stop looking for the video feed.
There isn't one is a nice bottle.
Oh, yes.
Uh, this is, I don't drink a lot of hard alcohol, but the hard
alcohol that I adore is tequila.
And I have a bottle of, uh, uh, patron on yay.
Oh, which I don't like the Blanco.
So very, very nice.
Oh, good.
This is beautiful.
For those it's a patron gold.
Yeah.
Holy cow.
I'll bring it home.
My, my wife also likes tequila.
She may just take it from me, but I'm going to hide it in my room, which
makes feel a little weird to have like hidden.
I'm not an alcoholic.
I'm not.
I just really love to be drunk all the time.
I don't know how to get, I'll work on getting it open while we talk,
maybe talk about, uh, get back into the topic here.
Yep.
We're doing the age old trick of using your key as a knife.
As a saw, I don't have a key.
I just have a remote that shaped like a car.
Hear that?
I'll do that again for the camera for the microphone.
So you remember, um, there's like four half the bottle in each cup.
So you remember the, the, the, uh, the drink I invented.
What's the drink you invented, Brent?
It's N shots of Patron.
I call it the group hug.
It's a group hug men can do.
All right.
Uh, to my last day at Microsoft, little toast with plastic cups.
Do a fake clink here.
Cheers, Alan.
Cheers.
Oh, that is so good.
It is.
All right.
So what do you want to talk about?
Well, I talked about this before, but
Oh, shot.
No, I wanted to dive a little bit into a couple of the agile testing sessions at
star East coming up in may code AB testing.
We'll get you 200 bucks off Orlando in Orlando.
Um, so I don't know how much you follow the work of Bob Galen.
Uh, he's done a lot of work around agile testing and agile, agile in general,
figuring out how testers of today fit into agile of tomorrow or really
testers of yesterday fit into agile of today.
Right.
Uh, given a couple of tutorials and talks around, uh, agile testing team
tactics that deliver the goods along with Mary thorn and also with Mary thorn
agile test team leadership from concept to product.
And then he's giving also a talk on test automation strategies for the agile world.
So, uh, jumping back to the question I had before, we're gonna give me a real
answer.
So what do you, what is agile testing?
I asked, cause I think it's one of those things that can mean some
different things to different people.
Um, I don't want to try to invent a concept, right?
The real, the reality is, um, so when I went to Bing, I went to the dev team,
as we talked about, um, throughout the podcasts on combined engineering.
Um, I didn't have a test team and I wouldn't go back to that world.
The, the, the discussion he's talking about here is I believe where you have
still the separation of teams, but you operate in an agile world.
Or you have an embedded tester on an agile team.
Yeah.
The, um, it's probably, I, I think that is a concept used more often.
I, perhaps you have, but I haven't observed, uh, a team that calls
themselves agile that has, um, split discipline that just, that doesn't do
waterfall with sprints.
I think so.
I think, but to me, we're talking about agile.
One of the concepts that I think you've got from safe, which I've loved is this
idea of, uh, waterfall is predictive and then you can do iterative development.
But agile is adaptive.
And when I think the role of a tester on an agile team,
which is another way of saying agile testing is their role is to be adaptive
and to do adaptive testing, figure out what testing needs to get done.
And you look at sort of the role on my current team for about six more hours.
And my role has been very much to figure out what testing needs to be done.
Uh, no matter who it's done by.
So there's like agile test leadership.
Maybe that's a little bit of it, but I think there's a lot of things to
learn around sort of what, what is the role of someone?
What is the role of a test specialist on an agile team?
If I were to decompose it again, um, I would prefer to have to see some direct
experience on this, to see teams succeeding in this, but if I were to decompose it,
like agile at its nature is about breaking things into smaller shippable chunks and
focusing on ROI first.
So with testing, if you apply that to testing, then you would have a team that's,
um, not only working on the, the high ROI, uh, dev code that we're sending out,
but also focusing on the high ROI test cases moving now.
It would also in my, uh, vision of this, it would also generally tend towards
um, reactive strategies, not preventative strategies.
Meaning much of how we do testing in 1993 was we tested everything and we tried
to stop it from shipping.
Uh, in 2017, I wouldn't be trying to stop shipping.
I would be trying to maximize the, um, or to minimize the amount of risk that is
still valuable agreed.
I just remembered, uh, that it's been like six years ago.
I was still in engineering excellence.
So at least six, maybe seven years ago.
Uh, I remember I gave several talks to intact talks to teams when the premise was
this, Hey, my team is doing agile and I'm not sure what to do.
Testors were sure what to have the testers do.
And given in, in many ways, to be clear, Microsoft is behind the industry in many
things, but as far as dev practice is usually ahead of the curve, I would imagine
that there are several, maybe not of the three because they know what they're
doing, but many, many testers out there who are team is moving to agile and
they're not sure what to do going to sessions like this.
We'll get you some ideas.
Yeah.
Where do good ideas come from?
Uh, multiple ideas coming together.
Other ideas.
So you need to go, if you're not sure what to do, go suck in the information
from all these sessions, merge it with what you've learned on your own team
and come up with your own plan on what, what is the best way to be valuable
as a tester on an agile team.
And for those going through that immediate transition that you're just
talking about that the answer to that is relatively easy.
Uh, you can even use what you've done in the last year as an example.
Your primary job is to pass on your knowledge to the individual developers.
Your primary job is to teach those developers how to do their new part of,
of these new testing requirements, uh, so that you can scale to an agile world.
Right.
Um, imagine, so if we were to say agile world, uh, with a test agile testing
in a world with continuous deployment, right?
That's the thing that, that I think testers today, if you don't have a
team that you're on continuous deployment, start researching this because.
That product development model with continuous deployment, I can
guarantee you is in your future.
And you have an opportunity right now to be the expert and help set the
stage and be ready to run when it lands.
Yeah.
I think the test role can, can be, or really should be the most valuable
role on an agile team, someone to eat that system thinker.
It's almost becomes an architect type role where you're the person looking
at how everything fits together end to end.
And I guarantee there are teams out there that say they're doing agile
and they have a tester on the team and they, everyone checks in code and
sends mail or a message to that tester saying test this, I just checked it in.
That's wrong.
You want to get some ideas on what's the right way to do that?
Uh, I think there are probably a lot of things, uh, like it's been
10 years ago at Microsoft, I introduced, uh, my team to unit testing.
Yep.
That's crazy.
Cause most people do it for a lot longer.
And then I had developers on the team saying, Hey, if we're running a
unit test, what's the test team going to do?
And after I recovered from slamming my fist into my face, uh, I told them,
yeah, um, you know, that was a long time ago for me now, but it's,
the memories are still, they come back quickly.
So I think as teams, uh, get into like, I guess guarantee there are a lot
of testers will be at start says my team's doing agile.
I'm not sure what to do.
My team's doing agile.
It doesn't feel right.
You know, it's, it's painful for the testers.
I think listening to what Bob Galen and Mary Thorin have to say and other
talks at star is going to help out a lot and give you ideas to be successful and
not just successful, but to change culture on your team.
I think that's super important.
I think one of the most important things that agile testing or, or testing
in an agile world really helps to do is again, this ROI focus, right?
You brought up this, this scenario that, that happened to both of us where we were
knee deep in a transformation stage and we got pegged with questions from Dev.
Hey, if I'm doing unit tests, what is test doing?
Okay.
And part of your ROI, the ROI, you don't get to define it.
The ROI of your job, the ROI of what you produce, you don't get to define it.
It's defined by, by those you serve.
Okay.
And if Dev is coming to you and it's a common practice and saying, Hey, if
test goes away, or if I pick up unit tests, what does test do?
That's a clue.
The ROI of testing in your environment is wrong.
The ROI of testing in your environment is to do the, uh, the crap work
that Dev doesn't want to do or to be the scapegoat for the organization.
Um, these are not valuable to any business whatsoever.
And certainly none in this world.
Totally agree.
So anyway, highly recommended, uh, regardless of whether your team is doing
agile, you're at your agile pro or just want to learn a lot about testing.
Star East Orlando, May 5th through 12th code AB testing, all one word,
200 bucks off.
All right.
Go right.
Thank you.
Tech well and star.
I'm actually, I need to do a star conferences here.
So Alison Lee, anyone, if you're listening, um, I'm open.
Just let me know.
I'd have some free time.
Who knows?
Uh, let's move on.
So as we mentioned before, I think we already covered the fact that, uh,
Obama and I both have the same last day at work.
In fact, we have to end here a little early so I can listen to the
inauguration speech on the way back to my office because apparently
Trump wrote his own.
Yeah.
Which means there should be filled with gold.
It will be on YouTube.
Be it later with auto tune, et cetera.
So, uh, let's, oh my gosh, we should talk a lot about my new job,
which I haven't started yet.
Uh, and then go to the mail bag.
So one thing I wanted to mention, not on the board, a little bit more about, oh,
by the way, I'm wearing a unity t-shirt today.
Nice.
I had a breakfast yesterday with my bot, my new boss's boss, uh, who was in town.
He's based in Copenhagen.
Oh, he's Danish.
No, I don't think he is.
Oh.
So I'm, I became even more excited.
First, the product's cool.
People love it.
Uh, but it is, it just sounds like a really cool place to work.
I have to tell you one thing, uh, a couple of things he said that were really
interesting and you can compare and contrast him with Microsoft.
He said there's no, there's so globally distributed, distributed.
They have like, they're only like, I thought they were bigger.
I thought there were 3000 people.
They're about 1400 people, about 450 engineers ish.
Uh, but they have like 12, 15 offices around the corner.
The biggest office is like 250.
Okay.
And he said, there's no way in an org like this could be top down.
Everything is bottom up.
People have, and I've talked about my role at Microsoft for the last 15 years
as I figure out what needs to get done.
And I do that.
And that's the role of pretty much everyone at unity.
Nice.
He says, uh, if you show up and there's something else you want to do that, go
do that.
And then he told me a great story, which I told my life before she cracked
up is just cause she's, uh, you know, been with me for most of my career at
Microsoft and she gets what the soft is like, but to get an idea of how
non top down they are, he says, so if you come ask me permission to do something,
the first time I'm going to go, I'm going to write it off and, you know,
give you a little guidance on, on how you can make your own choices.
As long as you're not like losing the company money, you know,
make your choices and move on.
We were blind people to do that.
He goes the second time.
I, we're going to have a long talk about it.
And if you come to me a third time asking for permission for something,
I'm going to fire you.
It was worth the exact words.
Pretty close.
He did say fire.
So, uh, which I love because I, uh, I do want to be held accountable for my
decisions, but if you, I've been doing this long enough, um, and thought that
even experience wise, but as a knowledge worker, as someone who has experienced
at all, I should be able to make my own decisions.
I shouldn't have to go ask for everything.
You shouldn't.
I mean, um, there's a way to balance that if necessary.
I'm sure that.
Yeah.
Right.
And I'm sure once I get there, I will find out there are checks and balances
in place to make sure I can make decisions that won't like wreck the
company or, or you know, cost a million dollars.
One of the practices.
Um, I did order a gold plated laptop.
Seems like the right business decision.
I did not.
I'm kidding.
It, well, yeah, I mean, it's not gold plated solid gold.
The, there's two things that.
Just a minute.
Did we talk about this before?
I think we did.
What you, your story from unity.
No, nope.
I watched one excuse, take a drink.
Oh, gotcha.
I actually had a discussion with, um, one of my peers, uh, the other day who,
who is struggling with their manager.
And he, and he came to me and he's like, Brent, what should I do?
And I said, here's, here's my philosophy on management.
Managers are split into three people, three types in general for me,
people like me, three types.
Number one manager generally agrees and does what I say, right?
Uh, from a bottoms up organization, I don't mean does what I say from like
a Napoleonic complex, I mean, from a bottoms up, there is an expectation
that I know more about my business than my manager does and that I have
experience and I'm not just guessing.
And I have, um, the right set of standards where I care and are deeply,
and I'm deeply focused on the business goals.
So one thing is the manager just generally agrees with what I say.
Okay.
Um, second, no op, a no op manager.
Doesn't really block me from moving forward.
Doesn't really help me.
Um, I'm fine with that manager as well.
Like I ideally the one that's going to help a work actively with me towards
a common goal, I'd prefer that, but failing that a no op is better.
The third is a blocking manager where they block either by their action or inaction.
Blocking managers.
And when I'm, and he went into, he asked me, what do you mean by
inaction?
I said, Oh, that's very easy.
So blocking manager, number one, if he, if he comes to you and says no all the
time, they're a blocking manager.
You can't live in that environment.
There is that's a heuristic, your style and your manager style are not aligned.
So either you'd need to change as Alan said, last time you needed to change your
manager or you need to change your manager.
Um, and Brent eventually figured out what that meant.
I did.
The, but the other style of blocking is the passive aggressive style where you
feel like you, you need to get permission from your manager and they defer a choice.
Which is just the worst.
That is the worst.
Um, and I said, like, look, in that particular case, if you feel like you
really cannot own your business and move forward without permission from your
manager and they're constantly delaying this, then try this.
Uh, for example, uh, he was told, uh, that he had an opportunity that his manager
was going to prop them up for a specific leadership team and that action
hadn't been taken yet.
And that day was this one on one.
I'm like, go to him and say, Hey, I like this action.
You haven't taken it yet.
Can you tell me who I need to talk to?
How do I reduce the friction so that the action you need to take is much smaller.
I'll go talk to them and get myself on and, um, they can come back and confirm
with you that you sponsored it.
Right.
And he's like, well, he's just going to say, Oh, no, I should do it.
And I'm like, you got to be more assertive and say, look, you said that last time
time's taken, let's move forward.
I'll take it.
You're busy.
But you don't have to be rude about it.
Hey, you keep ignoring me that you don't have to be a ass about it.
You just go, look, I see that you're super busy.
I'll take it.
It's in my better interest to take it.
I'll take the section.
Um, but if you find that you can't even do that, it's, it's time to go.
One of the things that drives me, just drives me nuts is anyone in a, and
again, there's a difference between management and leadership and, but
all managers should have at least a little bit of leadership.
So many of the great leaders, all managers should be at least
have some leadership qualities.
Uh, and to me, one of the attributes a leader needs is an ability to make decisions.
Regardless of the amount of input they have drives me crazy.
When people can't make decisions, he can make decisions.
He's make he, he made the decision to prop them up.
It's acting on the decision.
That was the, the, the problem here.
Um, and I babble long enough.
There was another point I was going to bring up, but I forgotten it.
Oh, great.
Should we, uh, do we have two mail bags?
Uh, we might, if we have the time, let's go, let's do the, um, let's do the first one
and I'll, I'll load it up.
All right.
This is the one from test Pappy or the other one.
Okay.
We'll do that one.
I have it up already.
So, oh, almost forgot mail.
Actually, there was one comment on the Slack channel that, that, uh, that I enjoyed.
Did you not hear me say mail bag?
I did.
Okay.
What did you enjoy?
I'm going to do a mail baglet.
Oh, what, and, and I'll, I'll tangentize your mail baglet and say, uh, with the
last episode, I actually posted it to the Slack channel, one of the three.slack.com.
Uh, a day ahead.
Yep.
This because I want, I wanted to give the three a heads up that about
the leaving Microsoft thing, but Brent said, you should do this all the time.
It's like the insider club.
And so we may do that.
I think I may, uh, I will, I will post our episodes to one of the three.slack.com.
I'll give the link there, uh, about a day before it goes, uh, for the blog post goes
out.
Yes.
So insider information, if you wanted, if you wanted a day early,
join the Slack channel.
Exactly.
If you don't want it at all, just, well, that one, I think is pretty easy to solve.
So could you read us, is it called a Slack clip?
Oh yeah.
The, uh, a brantlet.
Uh, it might've been a tangent looking tangent.
Canorum, norium, norium.
Okay.
Uh, suggested to me that I should try to find a different Alan at Microsoft.
Just so that we could keep the podcast.
Uh, Oh, the podcast is going to keep going just so that we can keep the
podcast, uh, Microsoft only, I guess.
Doesn't half the Microsoft only there was, that was never in our contract.
Oh, never.
And then it was, uh, there was a suggesting suggestion.
Then, well, then screw that find another bridge that unity.
Oh, that's a, there's a Brett.
Is there?
Yeah, that's my boss.
That's my boss's boss.
Yeah.
And then I'm like, I was thinking about, I was thinking about this idea about,
um, about finding another Alan.
There's lots of Alan's at Microsoft.
We have like, I mean,
now I said, you know what?
Now, if I were to do that, I wouldn't do another Alan.
I would probably, um, invite Steve Rowe partner with him on this.
Oh, it could be BS testing BS data science.
Okay.
It's like a pod.
It's like a podcast spinoff.
Yeah.
I bet you BS data science would actually get the four listeners.
And you're keeping the recording equipment in your office.
You could just like Steve come over.
One of us can figure this out.
It can't be that hard.
I bet you Steve could figure it out.
I like that BS testing.
Welcome to BS, BS data science.
Oh, that could happen.
All right.
Actually I had fully distracted myself.
So I already sang the male big song.
It seems like a long time ago, but I might have to cut and
paste it into this section.
So Patrick says, I can read it.
Go ahead.
You're not a very good reader.
This is to sound out the big words.
It's it's time for reflection.
This is, this is Patrick.
It's time for reflection.
Alan said a couple of things about reasons and all in 52.
So I'd be interested in hearing a bit about personal habits.
Yeah, I'm a little uncomfortable with that one.
You, you, I'm not, keep going or ways of doing things.
What do you want to continue doing like at Microsoft and what
would you want to change immediately?
Do you find stuff in the past where you said, Oh, I want to try this, but in my
team, I'm not credible enough for doing that, that you now pull out from a drawer
and you try to give it a shot.
Now first, actually, I find that last question interesting.
Is there, was there any situation where you had a credibility problem?
No, I wouldn't imagine not in a long, long time.
Alan does what Alan wants, including talking about himself in the third
person, which is weird.
You do it in second person.
Oh, great.
So I haven't had that problem myself.
I'm pretty much depending on the scope of the change, you may have to do it in
smaller chunks or to a smaller audience.
Uh, but as far as credibility, that hasn't been a problem.
I've been able to try again, at least for like the last 10, maybe 15 years
at Microsoft, pretty much anything I want to do, if it's a big thing, I do it in
small chunks.
I don't do like everybody were doing this because I said so.
Uh, it's, I have a, again, one of the things you do in any leadership position,
whether it's a management position, just sort of a technical leader is you have
to figure out the best way to implement new ideas and it can be an all at once
thing, but often, especially in a big org, it's a small gradual thing or a thing
that you do either the whole thing across the org in small chunks, or you
do the thing with a pilot group of small people, small number of people.
I have found on the credibility topic that, uh, in particular, I could, I'm
guessing when Patrick brought this up, but I have found a problem with that.
This seems to be common in, in test, right?
Me on an easy solution.
Typically when, when, when test joins a new team, there is, it's far too common
that I've noticed where they operate of, of, well, it's obvious that I'm the
little man on the totem pole, therefore I'm going to have to earn credibility.
Right.
And so they, they themselves start with this idea that they are not credible.
Um, I recommend the more the fake it till you make it strategy.
That is the story of my life.
And that you start from the ground zero with, no, I am a leader in this space.
You hired me because I'm the expert.
I'm the credible one.
But you can, without getting defensive, but you can make a mistake there and go overboard.
You go, I'm the credible one.
We're doing this and this and this and this.
You still need to have small victories without leaving a wake of bodies in your.
No, no, no.
It's not about being dictatorial.
It's about, but you say it's not about being a dick.
What?
Dictatorial.
It's, this is going to be all touchy feely new agey crap, but
I'm going to step out of the room for a minute.
Another way of communicating it.
But when you step in, you got to think about your body language and you got to
emanate an aura of confidence and credibility and you, and not that you
have to earn it, but that you have it immediately and it can be taken from you.
Sure.
You have to, and what you earn is respect.
Right.
And you do that by making good decisions, not pissing people off, reading body
language, paying attention to how you're coming across.
And we've talked about this emotional quotient or, uh, which a lot of people
see as, Oh, I just need to make sure, uh, I'm not being a dick, but it's really
about constantly evaluating how you're coming across these are leadership things.
And, and, and reading the reaction of people, uh, in the room and
reacting in real time, you do this as a speaker a lot in one way, but you do
it in a room full of peers or leaders as well too.
You, you can tell whether they're getting in there, approving, you can
look for head nods, you can look for eye rolls, you can, which are the obvious ones,
but there are other more subtle signs you can look for and you need to be
able to adjust the way you're coming across and adjust maybe your idea
or your goal in real time in order to get that buy-off.
So let's go back to the completely agree.
Let's go back to the, because I'm right.
The meat, I demand.
No, sorry.
So the meat of, I think Patrick's question primarily, although the, the
credibility was a talent tangent on my side.
Um,
that's so weird.
Cause we don't do tangents very often.
No, I know.
Sorry.
Um, what's something that that's a practice at Microsoft that you can't wait
to introduce unity to what's a practice at Microsoft that you can't wait
to never have to do again.
Those are tough questions because I, I haven't worked at unity.
So the way I work is very adaptive.
I'm going to look at what they're doing.
I'm not going to go in there and go, we're going to change things to my way.
The stupidest thing I could do, if we go in there and go, I have a way
of doing things that's the way we're going to do, darn it.
Uh, it's about learning and adapting and figuring out where we need to go.
Now I'm sure you're going to identify at least one practice from Microsoft
that unity could pick up and move forward on and then, and that you'll
probably take a boil the frog strategy.
That's this, this is typically how I've seen you do things.
Yeah.
I think, uh, there may be some things around, oh, wow, here's a, there's a
type of tool or type of tooling that they're not doing that would be really
advantageous and solve this big problem they're having.
Uh, but those are very situational sorts of things.
There aren't things like, Oh, I want to go make sure we have a, I'll just
question in the opposite.
I want to go make sure we have a really big bureaucratic process around
doing a lot of important things that get in your way.
You bring up bureaucratic process, but I've had several, um, friends of mine
that have left to, to their own versions of startup recently.
And it was interesting to me, um, particularly in one case, they wanted
me to come in and, um, do an interview loop.
So I went night, I did an informational and the one thing that was.
Puzzling was just how slow HR was in the getting that scheduled.
I was talking with the president, so he's a busy guy.
Um, I'm generally busy as well, but me and the president sort of closed on,
um, back and forth and whether or not I, I would be going to that company.
And then a week later, HR said, Hey, the president would like to talk to you.
Right.
So there's some of these processes that are common that I'm pretty sure you'll go.
Oh my God.
We, we went back to 1986 in terms of how we do some of these things and they
could be made efficient without being bureaucratic.
All right.
So let me go back to Patrick's original question.
So what do you want to continue doing like Microsoft?
I'm sure it'll be in, ask me in two weeks for the next podcast and I'll
be able to name some things.
Like here's something that worked well at Microsoft that actually is, I'm going
to implement in my work at unity, but there's no, there isn't like, I'm not
bringing anything with me in my bag of tricks at like, let's do, let's do this
thing.
Uh, and what do you want to change immediately?
I, again, it's the way I work.
This is a tough question for me because I don't have like a toolbox that I
use and unfold and, and the only tool I use is, uh, learn what's going on and
adapt, take everything I know going back to, we're talking about a star, uh,
the benefits you get from a star, uh, learn what's going on and reach in my,
and reach in my big old toolbox and figure out what the right thing to do
is for the situation.
So I don't have a good answer for you, but, um, but it is a good question.
So I, I think we should discuss that again in a few weeks.
Uh, I think it'll come up organically, but I don't know what
the answer is for those today.
I think the, so the way I see you operate and, and I don't know, because it's
kind of how I operate and so I may be, um, projecting, projecting, but both Alan
and myself, I think are fairly good at seeing the critical goal, right?
Uh, whether or not the team around us would agree with that goal, right?
If we, there are many times where I see, Oh, the, okay, this is a goal that
we clearly need to get to these, the guys that I'm working with do not have
experience if I were to tell them we're going to do this, they would all run
crazy scared, uh, it would bring up the credibility issues with Brent like,
Oh my God, he is well, so out there sort of crap.
Um, so once you have a clear insight on the goal, the, the next thing you
need to do is figure out where you're at.
Right.
You, you, it's like you're traveling across country, right?
The map.
Yeah.
If everyone wants to go to New York, that's great, but you know what, the
directions you're going to take depend on where you're coming from.
Yeah.
One of the models I use all the time for organizational changes, define the,
define the desired state, define the current state and figure out the map to
between and then realize that as soon as you start going down that road, the
road may change.
So if you think if you use your map analogy, if I'm in Seattle, I'm going
to New York and you say, okay, I want to go to New York.
It's here.
I want to go to Seattle.
Here's the path I'm taking.
Oh, the road's closed.
Kevin, I go another way.
I'm going to change as I go along and adapt versus just stop.
Right.
We're in Washington and for, for the global three, Washington, um,
Washington is in the Northwest of United States.
California is in the Southwest of the United States.
And if we know that metaphorically that we want to go to California, you know what?
Sometimes you have to do that by going North.
You can drive North to the Vancouver airport and take a flight.
Uh, if you have the right equipment, you could potentially find a way to
circumnavigate the world.
I don't, I don't think that's actually possible.
No, I'm just saying it's sometimes the journey and getting to the goal.
It's going to be a marathon, not a sprint.
And you can't be freaked out by that.
No.
Evaluate where you are.
Hey, I think we're about out of time, right?
We are.
Thank you very much for listening to episode 53 of A-B testing.
I'm Alan.
I'm Brent.
And we'll see you next time.
Congratulations, Alan.
Thank you.