Hey everybody, Brent is at a loss for words,
but he is in the room with me.
Hey Brent, you okay?
No, no I'm not.
Hi everyone.
Hey, what episode are we today?
59.
We are here at episode 59 of AB testing.
Welcome the three and welcome new listeners
and welcome all.
We're an inclusive podcast.
Don't you think?
I do.
So I was in, shoot, was it just last week?
I spent all of last week in beautiful Copenhagen.
I am so jealous.
I blogged about it.
Although I was in beautiful Copenhagen,
I spent most of the time indoors.
The full story is on my blog, plug plug,
but we have an R&D training week and I attended.
I haven't written C++ code in a long time
and that the assignment was C++ and I wrote a lot of code
and damn it if I wasn't gonna work till nine or 10
at night, every night, making sure I could finish
the assignment to prove that I knew what I was doing.
If I was successful, I wrote code that solved the assignment
and did it very quickly using multi-threaded code
and all kinds of goodness and then when I looked back
at the code after I was done, I realized I wrote
some of the crappiest code in my life.
That worked.
So I lost sight of the goal.
Maybe the goal was to finish it and learn
and I got the meta winnings out of it.
I learned a lot how the Unity engine worked
and I was able to make it work and if I wanna be
optimistic about it, I'll say I wrote a prototype.
If I were to do the whole exercise again,
I would focus more on writing a lot of tests up front
and doing more of a minimum viable product approach
like I normally want to do, but I'm normally not
programming something in a, it wasn't a competitive
atmosphere yet it was.
There were 15 of us and I didn't, I wanted,
there were some people that knew what they were doing
and they were getting ahead of me and I wanted to catch up.
I was actually just taking your whole thing
and thinking of it as a analogy for why waterfall sucks
and why the scrum sprint model sucks
because what you just described is exactly the code
I see over and over again when someone's given
something with a deadline that doesn't include.
So maybe the difference is that I looked back
at my code and said holy crap, this is shit
and a lot of people would just go hey it works,
ship it.
But there was more to this.
The point I wanted to get to, you can read all about
that on my blog, it was a fun exercise, I'm glad I did it,
very educational for me, I feel like I know so much more
about the engine side, I focus on services as part
of my job, so it was good to figure out how that works.
I went through one of the tutorials in preparation
for this, to build this tanks game
and just amazing what Unity can do.
I never, it's, I know I'm just scratching the surface,
there's an amazing amount of stuff, but the point
was that I, in this weird world of today,
that sounds like the intro to a bad tech article,
in today's modern world of engineering,
it's like shut up, I posted the blog and my blog
sends little ticklers to Twitter and to LinkedIn
and of course all the replies to my blog post
are on LinkedIn, because that's the way
the world works today.
And yeah, so there are no replies to my blog post
on my blog site, but because when I post to my blog,
it posts little tickler to LinkedIn,
people replied and discussed it there.
And then, I'm gonna make a long story longer,
there was a discussion about whether developers
could test their code and I said sure,
developers can test their code as long as they
wanna remain employed.
And so I said well, somebody came in and,
for lack of a better word, and I am a white male,
so the last person that could really use this verb,
someone mansplained to me, that what I was talking about
wasn't testing, it was checking.
And what developers do with their code is checking.
And so.
Wait, wait, wait, wait, I know where you're going.
No, no you don't, no you don't.
Well, I don't know where you're going,
but I already have a rant sort of built up in my head
or a suggestion, so before you add too many
of these things, I'm old, let's close one out.
All right.
What do you think would have happened in this assignment?
You said it was an assignment, okay?
Correct.
I wanna change that game.
So the game I'm gonna propose is whatever your feature
or whatever problem you had to solve,
winner of the game is gonna be defined by who
first wrote the first code, okay?
But the game works this way.
The assignment as you've defined it,
as it was laid out to you, whatever the heck it was,
you can write this solution in C++.
But you tell everybody up front that this is due tomorrow.
We're not going to tell you the next phase,
but this competition is two parts.
Tomorrow, everybody's name's gonna go in a hat
and everyone's gonna get a new feature
and you're going to have to add that new feature
to the person's code who you draw from the hat.
Okay.
The winner is going to be assigned
to the person who first wrote the code.
That may work in a different scenario.
What would it have done last week?
This whole, the meta points I got out of it,
which was grepping through all the code
to learn how the engine worked,
my hunch is that is the true goal of this.
Yeah, I don't care.
I do because I don't wanna get too much into details,
but the assignment really was to one,
write a component that will take,
that will put an action on any game object in the game.
It's write a component that you can apply
to any Unity game object and have it do this thing.
Again, don't wanna give away details
in case Unity people are coming up.
And then that one, supposed to test it
with like 10,000 objects and the time was for all of us
right around 800 milliseconds.
Fast, but not game fast.
So the idea was then is to multi-thread this
using a job system much like thread pools,
actually almost exactly like thread pools on Windows,
but cross platform for threading.
Learn how to use this brand new job system.
Not documented, but very well documented in header files,
not documented in words and examples.
Yep.
So in doing that, in learning how to use this,
the first part was fairly easy, just doing some math.
Pretty much everyone had that done the first day.
The next day's assignment and the next couple days,
we would have classes in the morning
about all kinds of different stuff,
but the, was to continue to iterate and refine this
using this job system to,
one, to really, the goal was to learn the job system,
maybe it was the primary goal, maybe secondary,
with the parallel goal, I'll say,
of learning how the engine works
by having to grip through all kinds of code
to figure out how what you're doing works.
I get that.
And I also get where you're coming from, yes.
I think it teaches code maintenance
and writing code to be maintainable
if you have to build on top of somebody else's code.
If you knew.
It's a different exercise.
If you knew, and I get that.
I'm just trying to, I'm trying to address the,
you solved the problem, screw you devs,
I can write C++ too, get that, pat yourself on the back.
But the, it's not anything that you would check in.
It's not anything that you were proud of.
So what I'm trying to think through is,
how do we change the system
such that you would have naturally said,
no, I'm not done until I know
that the next guy that's picking up my code
is going to be able to move forward.
So ask me a different question.
Ask me how I would improve the exercise
for future people taking it.
Hey Alan, I have a spontaneous question for you.
You are so damn smart, Brent.
Yeah.
Ask me anything you want.
Anything?
Yes.
Whatever comes to mind.
How about, how would you improve this exercise
in the future?
Well, thanks Brent for asking.
It's something I've pondered just a little bit.
I think I spent a little bit too much,
and some of this is worth it.
I think if you've done any amount of coding
grepping around the internet
and trying to find little samples of how to do things.
There's some learning in that
that goes beyond just coming up with the right solution.
But I feel like there was a little bit too much
of that head banging against the wall,
not sure how this to work.
I would have loved a little bit more documentation
to accelerate, still make you dig around a lot,
or at least examples of other code doing something similar
so I could still have that learning
of grepping around the system,
but made a little bit more progress.
And I would have loved if the goal was to,
at the end, your code is ready for check-in.
Meaning, not only is it complete
and you think it's ready to be reviewed,
but it has tests written for it
and you feel like it's robust and solid
and everything's done for it.
We had a couple tests that were written for us
as part of the framework,
and we could have added to that.
I never got to that.
I could have written them first,
then I wouldn't have finished,
but I would have loved to, given my background,
written a whole bunch of really great
unit and integration tests for this component
to prove its reliability, to prove its performance,
along with being code that,
I feel like this is code that really, really works,
but I couldn't get there.
And actually, only a few people got to that stage
where it was, in fact, they didn't even get any tests done.
Nobody, I don't know if anybody that had,
actually, there were two people
who work on the engine full-time
who maybe got some more tests written
and had a working component.
But I think it would have been better
if the goal was to get,
and that would have been more of a Unity developer workflow.
How to get something ready to check in,
go through a couple real code reviews
to see what kind of feedback you would give or get
and how you'd react to those,
learn from each other's tests that they wrote,
some things like that.
So we didn't get to those
because there was too much headbanging
and just figuring out how to make the thing work.
Yeah, so essentially because you got knee deep
in an infinite onion peeling exercise,
you couldn't really move forward
until you completed the onion peeling exercise
and you made a trade-off between onion peeling and TDD.
Now the question is, and this is a common thing with TDD.
TDD is intended to help you onion peel at the same time.
And but when you add in this time pressure
and you don't add in a requirement that
once you submit this, this is no longer your code,
it encourages this behavior.
That's my own thing.
And to be fair, there was no,
some people, many people didn't even finish
and there was no like belittling of that.
The pressure I put, the pressure put on me
to complete this thing and have it work
was entirely put upon me by me.
It was purely for my ego to show I could write,
I could still write C++ code
and I wasn't just some lame QA director guy
showing up to hang out.
Yeah, but here's the real secret.
What do you actually think is the difference
in your mentality here
versus 80% of every actual developer engineer
you've ever met?
They wanna prove their worth.
And I'm saying the square root of nothing.
That's exactly the same.
Now, the specific reason why you wanna prove it
to yourself may be different.
Right, and that's actually in my view
one of the roots of the problem
around this unified engineering model.
In my team, we solve this because everyone's expected
to be able to work on everyone's pieces of code.
And so it forces,
I don't have to create a gauntlet rules.
It forces a normalization of standards.
I'm gonna make a statement
then I wanna pop the stack and go back.
The statement is I think the exercise succeeded
in making us learn a lot more about how the engine works
but failed in making us understand
how to be a successful engineer at Unity.
Because it didn't go into enough of the things
that you really need to do to write quality code.
Yeah, it doesn't sound like that second bit
was part of their goal.
I don't think it was, but I think it should have been.
If I were a director in Unity,
I might suggest something along those lines.
This was really awesome.
I'd like to add another thing to this.
One of the reasons I attended as a QA director of services
to this thing geared more towards engine people
was so that I could understand its relevance
for people in our org or where we may want to differ.
And I talked to our director,
we have a director of HR assigned to just engineering.
He's just assigned for engineering growth and HR things.
He's an awesome guy.
I talked to him actually even before I started at Unity.
And we talked about this exact thing
and it's definitely something on his radar
how to tweak this training to work across the org.
So we'll talk more about that.
So popping the stack, once upon a time,
an hour or two ago,
was talking about how someone explained to me,
persons explained to me that what I was talking about
in these tests that I wrote for my code
weren't really tests, they were checking.
And then there are the checking testing folks.
So Michael Bolton especially,
James Bach isn't really involved on Twitter much anymore.
Who says that I've never seen a case
of someone correcting someone else.
You guys are just making this stuff up
and I see it all the time.
So when I saw this one, I had the document,
it's like I wrote a tweet for the record.
I just saw this blah, blah, blah.
And then I have never been in a longer tweet thread
that won't go away.
So many replies and replies and replies
and changes of subjects and examples of defensive testing,
examples of this thing and there's probably a name
for this you can think of,
but what's it called when your purpose
on Twitter or social media is to just prove
that you know more about something than those around you?
Lot of that going on.
And I look, I fortunately have a do not disturb
on my phone.
Called Blovey8.
I have a do not disturb window on my phone
from 9 p.m. to 6 a.m.
where there won't be any buzzes or anything.
And I woke up this morning,
look at my phone and I have little,
you know you have new Twitter notifications.
Sometimes there's not any and I don't care.
Sometimes there's three or four.
Last night 87, overnight.
It's like oh my God.
So the thread won't die.
It just goes on and on.
That's my checking versus testing.
Has it breathed its own life or?
It's gone in so many different directions.
Twitter needs a feature to be able to remove yourself
from a thread.
Yes.
I guess TweetDeck probably has a mute or something.
Anyway, that's my checking versus testing.
Why don't you reply to the Tweet
and say take me off of this Tweet thread?
Bedlam, bedlam.
Hashtag bedlam.
Yeah, I'm just like oh man.
We've talked about checking and testing before.
I do think it's valuable in terms of having to discuss
sort of more precisely what we're trying to do
with these different efforts.
But my goodness, it is absolutely not worth
a religious war in any sort.
Well, it's obliviating.
It's an interesting distinction.
If someone had some long winded thing and says,
the way I see it, checking is a blah, blah, blah,
and I replied simply saying, the way I see it,
some of my testing has binary results.
I think it's a way for, and I'm not sure if it's,
maybe it's because I watch testing threads more often
or I think it's really because there's more insecurity
among testers that many of them feel the need
to express their knowledge.
Like oh, here, let me tell you what I know
because you probably don't know it
because I frickin' rock.
It's like shut up.
So it's an interesting distinction that is not worth
bringing up unless the topic is about
checking versus testing.
Otherwise, shut the hell up.
No.
Let's take a break to hear from our sponsor.
This episode of A.B. testing is brought to you by Cobaton.
Remember Cobaton?
We talked about them in A.B. testing 57.
So Cobaton asks this of the three.
Is managing internal devices
one of the best parts of your job?
Doubt it.
Check out Cobaton, your complete mobile device lab solution.
Cobaton allows you to manage the devices you own.
That's right, you can plug in your own devices
into Cobaton's network and access the real devices
you need from manual to automation testing.
Cobaton empowers developers and testers
to build great products faster.
One of the things I like about Cobaton
is that you can both run automated tests
and connect to these devices and test manually
to see how things look and make sure look and feel
is what you are planning for.
Manage and access internal and external devices
all in one place allowing you to test on hundreds
of devices and configurations.
Identify and resolve issues more quickly
with automatically created activity logs.
Even centralize your testing history
to increase collaboration across teams and locations.
Cobaton does all of that while minimizing costs
and enabling you to get your app to market sooner.
Visit cobaton.com, K-O-B-I-T-O-N.com,
slash A-B testing to sign up for a free trial
and start testing in minutes.
I'll post these into show notes
but I have to tell you if you are building
any sort of mobile solution,
you have to be using something like Cobaton
to get your job done otherwise you're swinging in the dark.
I would have to say like multiple times
where if I had to do browser compat or device compat,
like we've both worked in the device spaces.
Yep.
With massive internal labs costing
not just massive amounts of money in internal costs
but also in real estate,
that space that could have been used for offices.
Yeah and you have to invent whole new protocol stack
if you want to try to,
like each device has a different means
by which you try to communicate.
It's a real pain in the butt
and you spend 80% of your effort
just putting the infrastructure together.
Definitely, I would definitely,
if I was in the space today,
I would definitely be going and signing up with Cobaton.
Awesome, so check it out.
One other non-sponsored advertisement,
I'm giving a talk, a keynote
at the online testing conference, June 13th and 14th.
I'm just on the 13th, I'm 7.15 in the morning.
Left Coast time, that's 10.15 on the right coast.
Do the math if you live elsewhere.
And speaking about a subject
that came up originally on A-B testing,
which is the bazillion different ways
you can do technical testing
or be a technical tester without writing code.
And honestly, what is a non-technical tester?
Wouldn't that be what they would say UI testers are?
I don't know, I don't know.
But perhaps-
The minimum wage kids they hire to test games?
Maybe, maybe.
Yeah, so I'll talk a lot about that and my opinions there.
My talks, as you know, are always full of opinions.
I will make sure I have lots of pretty pictures
and some stupid things to say
because I need to make sure that I can attempt
to be engaging even though my audience is virtual
and I can't see them.
I do so much better, even as an introvert.
I enjoy giving talks, but I find them much easier to do
when I can interact with the audience.
So these things are always a little bit more difficult,
but I will do my best to make it entertaining,
fun, and informative.
I definitely prefer the presentations
where we just open up, yeah, interrupt us.
We love interaction.
Yeah. Right?
But if you take away the ability to sort of read
body language, so much of my presentation style
is to be able to quickly read a body language
and go in a different direction.
Mm-hmm, yeah, me too.
That's gonna be interesting.
It's always a challenge.
If you have no idea if what you're saying
is you've lost your audience, how do you fix it?
I will just try and keep it entertaining.
I've seen a lot of, I mean, it's boring enough
when you go to an in-person talk
and someone is reading slides,
but I've seen online presentations the same.
That is a snooze fest.
I promise I will not read slides.
If you've seen my talks before,
I am famous for having about 15 words
in my entire 40-minute talk on slides.
So plenty of pictures of Brent,
and no, maybe not Brent,
but there'll be something going on there.
So check that out, Online Test Conference.
If I do my job, I'll put a link to it in the show notes.
All right.
All right, one topic we wanted to discuss
with our remaining time today
is something that's come up directly and indirectly,
and it kinda leads a little bit
out of our checking versus testing discussion,
but I don't wanna call it the future of testing.
Let's talk about what modern testing is.
So Brent, what does modern testing mean to you?
What is, let's start with that
and we'll see where it goes.
Modern testing at a very high level is essentially what?
So we agree that the goal of a test team,
a test asset testing,
actually, let's first talk about,
well, I wanna talk about their testing the process,
not testing the discipline.
So modern testing is,
testing's role is to accelerate the achievement
of shipable quality.
Shipable quality, thank you for correcting my own quote.
It's mine now, I took it.
So if testing's role is at acceleration,
it's the getting to shipable quality.
In my mind as well, there's a focus around risk reduction,
like testing is like an insurance policy.
How much do you invest in it
so that you get the correct amount of payback
if something goes wry or prevention of a wry?
And then the definition of modern in my mind is,
what is different about the opportunities,
what's available to us in terms of how software is used
and produced in today's world versus the world
that existed when a lot of these testing dogma
were first created, right?
The previous topic lit on checking versus testing,
that in my view comes from that old world.
Yeah, a lot of that old world is, I think, way too prevalent
and in many ways detracts from the evolution of testing.
There was a discussion we had on our,
one of the three Slack channel,
around this concept of tester as information provider.
And it was a great conversation,
thank you three for chipping in on that.
I believe that tester as information provider is,
I can almost call it passive, but it's a cop out.
When I look at that as the role,
the testing activity and role is so much more than that.
I don't like the idea of a tester is,
here's what I found out, you make the decision,
I'm not involved, I'll just give you the information.
I don't like that.
But.
I will actually tell you,
because I am now running a data science team.
Okay?
You're all about information.
One of the biggest problems,
I interview a lot of data scientists,
and I ask them, why are you leaving?
There are two big problems.
Number one, all I do is reports.
That's why I'm leaving my current team,
because all I do is reports.
Okay?
Number two, this is more relevant.
I am producing brilliant insights that no one uses.
Now this is very analogous to the test role.
Very much so.
If you are producing insights that are not actionable,
that aren't actionable in a way that is business relevant,
no wonder that you're constantly under attack
for defending the value of your role.
That is what I see in testing all the time,
not just with this, is that testers say,
well, management doesn't listen to me.
And assuming that it's automatically management's fault
versus you having the right information,
the right argument, the right leadership,
the way to influence them.
I see way too much of this, oh, it's what was me,
it's not my fault, nah, nah, nah.
Right.
And it sounds like sort of the same thing.
It's like.
No, it's the same thing.
I've had, there was a guy that left my last team
on Teams at Microsoft because no one would listen to him.
This was a principle level lead.
It's not no one's listening to you.
I know.
Your argument is not sufficiently convincing.
There's so many things where like,
I have seen testers long, well, you know what?
I understand testing and they fall back on this,
I forget the name of the bias,
but there's definitely a bias here.
Where it is clear that it's a positional argument.
It is clear that of the people in the room,
I know this topic more than you,
so we should be going with my gut, not yours.
And it completely ignores the whole system
of how a business functions.
Absolutely.
Right, so what's the consequence of me
going with your gut, not mine?
Oh, I don't know.
I just know, because the other part with testing,
in the old world, a big part of testing,
is the basis of our argument
is essentially a logical analysis of right versus wrong,
not a consequence to the product,
a consequence of the business,
or a consequence to the customer.
And that one is the one I think that's the most important.
Because so long we're spending all this time
defending a customer that we have no actual proof
if what we're talking about
solves a customer problem or not.
Correct.
Right, so a big part of a modern world
is in testing, is you combine
an actual customer-driven feedback loop
as you go through that testing.
This is why we proselytize the active use of data.
And even if all you got is surveys,
if your management says, oh, I don't care about surveys,
then you figure out how to fund and run a survey program
within your own test org.
Right, any test team that validates their ROI
six months after SHIP by, see, I told you so,
you should have listened to me.
I am telling you right now,
you are not doing a good job on arguing your ROI.
So I could go on and on and on
about the defensiveness of testers,
but one point I wanted to finish,
which I find interesting,
it always shuts me up a little bit.
In this, I think it was first mentioned
in the Lessons Learned book,
that testers provide information.
When I say, but there's so much more,
I forget that B&B also say that
once you're doing any of these other things,
you're not doing testing anymore.
So they've, in a way,
their definition has defended itself
for saying testing is this very small thing,
but someone who calls himself a tester
may do many other things.
I find that confusing.
I look, I am the quality and testing expert
for our organization.
Yep.
That is, I have to be that,
which expands so many other things
than information providing,
or exploration, or verification.
It's so many other things.
So the definitions just diverge from the beginning.
So whenever going back to testing versus checking,
it diving into that school's dogma
is just so distracting from what I'm trying to do.
So now back on defensiveness,
which I see a lot still,
and I see it, it's job preservation.
It is worried about what's happening next.
It's worried about management not listening to me.
And I think more testers who feel defensive
need to look at another, back at themselves more
and how they're interacting with the people
and the environment they're in,
than with blaming others for their problems.
Yeah, I completely agree.
So as testing evolves,
and one thing I like,
and I don't wanna completely pick on B&B,
they say that many people can take on the tester role
at any time, including developers, including product owners.
So I like the, it's their backward way of saying,
yes, the whole team owns quality.
The whole team owns quality,
and there's gonna be people
who have different domain expertise.
And that's where I see modern testing is,
as I described it from my team,
as I said, I was the quality testing expert
for our organization.
Everyone on my team must be the quality and testing expert
for their feature area.
It's their expertise.
It's the depth they bring to the team
that brings value to what their team is trying to accomplish.
They're either writing tests, checks,
they're writing tests, they're doing testing,
they're exploring, they're looking at data
to figure out how customers using things
to complete that loop,
not speculating for their team
and helping others on the team do those same things.
Uh oh, Brent's pulling his hair out,
but he doesn't have enough.
I don't, I've actually,
I went with a buzzer blade number four.
All right.
I think about an old blog post from Whitaker,
where the title of it is,
all of this testing is getting in the way of quality.
And I don't actually recall what he wrote about,
but that title was what stuck with me.
Right?
So all of these things that testing,
in my view, self creates,
I used to have a similar speech on test harnesses.
It's one thing that's interesting
about the test automation space,
that test has created so much language
around these components.
Like this is our logging engine
and this is our execution engine.
And there's a degree of specificity
that kind of reminds me of the fact
that the Eskimos have like 80,000 different definitions
for ICE, right?
Whereas you take these sort of oop definitions
and you take it to a dev team,
it's just like, whatever.
That's just an object that manages a queue.
Who cares?
Right?
Checking versus testing.
Who cares?
That is the thing that is important for every test team.
It is not me saying, I don't care,
don't waste my time on this topic.
I'm saying, if you're holding up this topic
as something that's important
and you don't know who cares
and you don't know why they should care,
you need to figure that up
before you hold this as an important religious dogma.
And what that means in your relationship
to customer quality.
And I like that.
Yes.
Because we forget that.
We're so caught up in the activity
and proving our value that we're important.
And if you make the customer's experience
or help make the customer's experience better,
you've done your job.
I always just about, before I went on that rant,
I was actually thinking about entering into,
you know what, Alan,
I'm gonna just make your life easier.
You as a director of quality and testing,
you're gonna say, I don't care anymore.
I don't care.
You could unit test, you could not.
But you're going to measure yourselves
on the rate at which your team and your code
increases CSAT of the customers
that are using it as measured by this.
And I'm going to do, I'm going to judge you guys
by CSAT over time, over calendar time.
You do whatever the hell you want.
And I'm willing to bet that you do something
along those lines, the right amount of testing
will suddenly start happening.
I think too many testers focus on,
I must do my activity, I must give you information,
I must explore, I must do this,
I must write a useless automation suite.
All this stuff that, you've seen this before,
and people, they generate a lot of activity
but little value.
And I worry that's happening with too many testers.
They're generating activity versus value for the customer.
No, it's even worse,
because they're not associating that activity to value.
They hold it as inherently true
that this activity is valuable.
And then when someone pushes back,
they get pissed off and say things like,
management doesn't listen to me.
Management doesn't listen to you
because you're not framing it
in a thing that management cares about.
Test is, from most management's point of view,
test is a cost.
Absolutely, that's why I think testing,
rather than being these teams of people
who are entry level,
and one of my rants a few weeks ago was,
in fact, I'll mention this in my technical tester thing,
is we take what I think,
and granted, I only have 25 years of experience in this,
but we take the most difficult thing to do,
maybe in software engineering,
which is to write reliable, good UI automation,
and we use that as our entry point
for teaching testers how to code.
How stupid is that?
Quite.
So I think the,
talking about modern testing and the growth of testing,
testing needs to be this specialist role.
Specializing generalist, specializing generalist,
but not that army of newbies thing.
If you're hiring a tester,
it's like hiring the performance guru to come in on your team.
It is a...
In the way software is shipping today
and what we're doing,
and if you're doing it right,
testing, the testing activity is no longer,
testing role, whatever you wanna call it,
what we need from tomorrow's,
and today's even, testing expert,
specializing generalizing specialists,
is...
A systemic view.
Yes, and not noobs.
I think, honestly, you could see testing as this role
that is grown into from your good developers.
Yeah.
Which some companies have done.
They've moved their good developers
into sort of what they call the QA role,
quality architect role,
and they've actually been a true QA role.
Yeah, I actually...
I'm off on a tangent,
but the growth is not from getting lots of new people in,
and this is hard for a chunk of the industry to see
because there are a chunk of consultants in the industry
that make their living teaching brand new testers
some basics about testing,
and their world is going away.
Yes, very rapidly.
We're out of time.
I do wanna pick this particular topic up
and go deeper in the next episode.
We'll see if we do that.
I mean, this is two weeks ahead planning
and that's anti-AB testing.
I was just getting around that, but you're right.
Yeah.
There is a whole bunch of other things
I think it would be good to go in here and talk about.
It may even sponsor, hint hint, some mailbag requests.
Yes.
So if there are topics you wanna hear about,
let us know in a reply to the blog post
or in oneofthethree.stock.com,
and we will pick it up as part of this
what will be a long, continued, and fun discussion.
Yes.
All right, I am still Alan.
And I'm not.
We'll see you next time on AB Testing.
Bye.