Hey everybody! Howdy! I'm Brent and we're here for episode 54.
Just like I say every time.
This is the first 54 though.
Yeah, you haven't said 54 previously.
I never would have thought when we first started this thing that I'd be saying 54.
54.
Alright, this is my first episode as a non-Microsoft employee.
And the post-Microsoft world for Alan.
It's... I have no regrets.
Oh, you're still in the honeymoon phase, of course.
But tell us more about that.
Well, they shower gifts on me every day before the masseuse comes to my desk.
It's fun. It's refreshing. It's small.
Like the internal tools.
Like the travel site is a pain in the butt.
The expense reporting site, more of a pain in the butt.
I can't submit one of my expense reports
because for the last day or two, I can't find my boss.
But it can find you.
It can find us. It's hilarious.
So I have several friends that have gone the route you have.
I mean, and one of the common things that they say is...
First thing they notice is in comparison to Microsoft,
some of these sort of common processes,
just the severe lack of automation on them.
That...
Yeah, these typical things that you're used to,
that Microsoft has greased the engine on.
Yeah, you realize pretty quickly that it's not as automated as you're used to.
Eh, it's fine.
Yeah, and they say the same thing.
And the other thing is, if for some reason you have the interest,
right, you know what to do.
You've already seen a lot of these processes function in a way
where people just move on and live with it and don't complain.
So let me give you some examples.
I have so many examples, not sure where to start.
When people ask me about it,
the adjective that comes to mind most often is just refreshing.
It's refreshing.
There's a complete lack of bureaucracy.
Just do what you need to do and don't piss people off.
Don't even piss people off. Don't be a dick.
So what I'm hearing is you have not yet encountered
any sort of critical version of,
sorry, Alan, that's not how we do things here.
No, no.
If I were to come in and instigate a,
institute a huge amount of process and overhead and regime,
then I would probably hear that.
But that's not my style anyway.
So what I'm finding is, is sure, honeymoon phase,
but my style, my philosophies fit very well.
For example.
So you're not going to go anytime soon and say,
what this business needs is more command and control.
So, but let's talk about that specifically.
My philosophy, which I've had for a while,
but I've now, I read a book by Steve Denning called
The Leader's Guide to Radical Management.
Steve Denning writes for Forbes a lot.
He's a straight business guy who sort of found Agile
and says, well, Agile is, this is the way the work is done,
regardless of whether it's software or anything else.
But one of his principles is,
give people a framework they can work in
and then get out of their way.
Which is sort of the opposite of command and control
in a very sort of Agile way of doing things.
But tell me how you would implement
a command and control structure,
or at least from a micromanagement,
when, let me give you the context of my team.
My team is just shy of 30 people in seven countries.
I have direct reports in Seattle, Austin, Texas,
Copenhagen, Helsinki, Montreal.
How am I going to micromanage that team?
How am I gonna command and control that team?
Brent's making a funny little constipated face.
So first and foremost, I've seen how you operate.
If you wanted to command and control that team,
you would find a way.
I would never ever want to.
No, I mean, just by general,
like even if you were,
even if all of that team was here locally,
you wouldn't want to do that.
We're wired that way.
No, you lay down principles,
you make it very clear how they're gonna be measured.
And then, I mean, this is too hand-wavy.
Then you say, okay, now tell me how I can help.
What resources do you need from me?
Right, and I totally forgot San Francisco as well.
Yeah, I wasn't counting.
I do think it was, you said,
Seattle, now San Francisco, Texas, Copenhagen, and.
Finland, Helsinki.
Finland, that's five.
And you said seven countries.
Well, is there somebody?
San Francisco is not yet a new country.
Those were, well, maybe it's also.
I might've been exaggerating a little bit there,
but I do have skipped levels.
And so I have, I like the combination.
I have three leads reporting to me,
as well as six ICs if I count,
right, one, two, three, four, five, six, yeah.
Okay.
So it's good to get a little hands-on,
get a little, and it's basically all of Unity services.
Everything from ads and analytics, big services,
down to like crash reporting and multiplayer
and the launcher, just technically a service,
has a back end.
So you're in it.
Anything that has a back end, basically.
Your Unity engineering services is what you're saying.
Sure.
Cool.
It's a ton of fun.
And what I'm finding out is, as I expected going in,
is there's a lot of different ways of doing things.
Different tools used, different approaches.
Some teams are very much,
are more along the agile spectrum
and they don't, they track bugs
just like they're just pure work items.
There's no real tracking a bug database
or backlog they're found and they're fixed.
As I was saying. I like those teams.
Yeah.
So as you can imagine,
my job is at first is to assess
and kind of get a story, assess the current state.
You don't have a going forward battle plan
that you want to announce for the first time today
on the podcast?
No, I'm still assessing the current state.
Getting to know people.
I've now had one-on-ones with almost all
of my direct reports, at least one.
So slowly getting to know people.
I did spend two days in San Francisco
getting to know the team down there.
Both on the test side, the QA side
and the engineering side.
I've met with recruiting quite a bit
because I have open headcount in San Francisco a lot
and then in Montreal, I have a open headcount there too.
So two different recruiters working with them.
So slowly working my way around the company.
Huge Slack usage, which is awesome.
One thing, and again, no regrets, no digs on Microsoft
but my last team, Microsoft Teams, a Slack competitor,
I think is a great solution for Office 365 organizations
who have never used Slack before.
But having used Slack for the last three weeks,
I don't think they're ever gonna get a Slack user
away from Microsoft.
I'm sorry, a Slack user to go to Teams.
It's just too much farther along.
It's so much faster, so much easier to use.
But anyway, we have basically all conversations from Slack.
It seems like their strategy is to go after the enterprise
which is a common strategy here.
And to be clear, I think that's a good strategy.
When you have a new product, you can go right after
the competitor and try and steal their customers,
very difficult, or go after the market
that hasn't been claimed yet.
And I think it's still a smart plan
but I'm loving using Slack.
I get...
I would say in general, Microsoft's gonna default
for the enterprise, because for a lot of cases,
most of our markets, we own the enterprise.
Yeah, and that's Microsoft's customer.
We're software developers for the enterprise
with a few exceptions.
So I get...
This is including anything from systems
like to approve an expense report or to approve leave
or including all those sorts of mails.
Maybe on a crazy, crazy day,
I may get five or six emails.
I think I just killed Brent.
Everything else is inside.
I think the last time I had a day like that
was when I was an intern at Microsoft and...
I hadn't been hooked up to the DLs yet.
Yeah, I get more than...
At Microsoft, I would get 50 mails on Christmas.
Yeah.
It's fun.
I mentioned I went to San Francisco.
There was a hack week for services in San Diego
where there were about 125 or so Unity developers
and testers there.
I went down there, not the hack,
but for two days just to meet some people,
accelerate some ramp up there,
and so that was cool.
So actually, I do have a question for you.
Do you have a sense yet of what your job
is going to be to add value to the business?
Yeah.
You do?
Because what I've heard so far
is the way you're thinking of driving your team,
and it's so fuzzy.
Battle plans haven't been laid out,
but you're gonna be very principle driven.
I think the mission is clear.
It's the implementation that's not,
or the execution and tactics.
Okay, what's your mission?
The mission is to...
I haven't put it into words yet.
It's a bit in my head, but it's to...
Do awesome shit.
No, no, no, it's about, and let me talk about it.
We can figure out what the name is later.
But the mission is definitely build Unity service
testing culture or establish...
Let me talk about it backwards.
Something quality culture?
No, no, no.
What we have in the services at Unity
is a bunch of different disparate approaches
to service testing.
Different tools, different approaches,
and they're different services, so it's okay.
Also what's happened is because they've never,
they've been under two or three different directors before.
This is the first time with me coming in,
they've actually combined all services QA
and under one manager.
Okay.
So by...
Ooh, functional organization.
No, just put a cork in it.
Oops.
Be quiet, Brent.
Gee whiz, Brent.
You're interrupting my flow.
What I'm doing in establishing the current state
of learning what everybody's doing,
learning how each of the services is tested
is from that I'll be able to build a plan on
what are the areas where it makes sense to consolidate,
what are the areas where I think it's fine
and I need to defend.
For example, if someone's,
there may be an old school,
someone old school says,
you have to have a bug database and track these things.
I say, well actually,
I can point out how it's actually okay to not have it
if you're fixing all the bugs as you find them.
So choosing where to defend,
where to consolidate
and kind of establishing that shared vision for that team
does two things.
One, it gets some consistency and efficiency
and how Unity tests services,
which is great.
That's sort of the tactical goal,
but it helps build the services QA team,
which they haven't felt like it
and they felt like there's no camaraderie team
and again, they're spread across seven different locations,
but at the same time, I'm building that team.
Sort of the culture of Allen,
the culture of not-
You're trying to build a team culture.
You have a bunch of people organized underneath you,
but that's far different from a team.
And because I believe that one thing that isn't happening,
I'm huge on talking about ideas and learning
and great ideas come from other ideas merging together.
They don't have that sharing culture on like,
oh, here, I found like there's,
for example, three different products.
You have seven teams and there's 18 test harnesses.
No, it's not test harnesses as much as,
oh, we use this because this
and we use this because this
and they're not really like,
oh, how about if we mix that chocolate
and that peanut butter
and make a damn good little Reese's Peanut Butter Cup
over here, I think because they're not connected
and talking with each other, that sharing isn't happening.
They're focused a lot on need to solve the problem
for my team.
So the world that you're talking about
sounds like a bunch of very silo specific,
probably organically built tooling that has proven itself.
And no, because they're a modern company
who's aren't so stupid, they build all their own tools.
They use, everything is,
they use open source tools, common tools,
but they don't know that each other,
oh, hey, you're using that?
I'm using that too.
I had no idea.
I'm making those connections.
It isn't like Microsoft 10 years ago
when everyone's building a test harness
or it isn't like Microsoft today
when everyone's building a data pipeline.
No, it's a knowledge management problem is what you're-
It is, absolutely.
So I'll figure out how to phrase that,
but that's the initial mission.
Sharing is caring.
Shut up.
And one thing that's,
I wanna tie that into one other thing
is that's a Unity review process.
Interesting.
Is, we may be talking about it more later
when I've been there longer,
but it's three questions, three times a year.
And the first question,
I'll get into the other ones in another podcast,
but it's just, what is your mission at Unity?
So it's having that in my head
as I sort of figure things out,
it's like, oh, it's becoming more and more clear to me
what my mission is.
At least that will change over time.
That's why you do it three times a year.
But here's the great thing.
Now compare this to your history at Microsoft.
I know Microsoft is a lot lighter weight.
But the three questions, three times a year-
Microsoft is lighter weight?
Has gotten lighter weight
since we used to have to write these books once a year.
The review process is literally
managers, three questions, three times a year,
you have a conversation about those things.
I think we have six.
Backup, there isn't HR doesn't require a check
to make sure you've done it.
It's you're asked to do it and you're expected to do it,
but nobody's following up and making sure.
There's nothing written down.
Okay.
This is just a conversation you have to have.
It's great.
The companies at the stage where,
and I think most small companies go through this,
I hope they can stay there as long as they can
where they want to avoid doing anything
that makes them feel like a big company.
So it's kind of fun.
See, you have your Microsoft goggles on.
No, no, no, that's great.
But I've also done some lightweight research here
and that's, so that's how a lot of small companies start up.
It does limit growth
because at some point in time you can't really scale.
And so they go, okay, they had to make a decision.
Are we happy with the growth level that we're at right now
or do we want to take some of these pains?
Unity's not public, right?
No.
Okay, yeah.
So that probably won't shift over until it's become public.
At some point it may shift,
but one thing I've learned talking to my team
is everybody just loves working there
and loves what they're doing.
Again, we'll go back to my word from five minutes ago.
Refreshing.
Let's go into the next topic
and we can talk about my team there a little bit as well.
I think actually it's quite relevant.
Perhaps.
So it's actually been a while since we released 53,
I think it was about a month ago.
What's the date today?
Three weeks ago?
Maybe, actually almost a month, yeah.
Yeah, and then during that time
there was a lot of activity on the slide channel
where what was being discussed
is a problem that was quite common back in the day for me.
I'm pretty, I don't know how.
Maybe it's super relevant to you now.
But the question is,
if you are a leader of a pure QA team,
what are the goals of your team?
And there were several things talked about.
A lot of the discussion was,
I mean, this was common back in the day for me
where people would propose KPI and testers.
One of the things that testers are really good at
is knocking holes in everything.
So that's one of the things I observed
on the Slack channel was essentially,
hey, code coverage, that's a goal, right?
No, it's not a goal.
Code coverage is a wonderful tool and a horrible metric.
Yeah.
That's my standard line there.
Great for finding where you may have missed testing,
but shooting for a target
will always generate the wrong behavior.
Hindsight 2020 for me,
so before I sort of start monologuing on my opinion on here,
like what do you think of this topic
as it perhaps relates to you?
You've spoken about it very abstractly.
Yeah.
So the question is, what's the role of QA?
What are the goals of a QA team?
And to make it tighter.
So assume that it's a pure QA team
that's perhaps partnering with a dev team.
What are the goals of that QA team
that might be independent from the goals of the dev team?
Well, I am not a,
and listen before you jump in here.
I am still remain not a fan of a dedicated QA team.
So one thing I didn't mention about Unity,
I think it's a very, very common industry.
So Microsoft has done their, Microsoft has not.
Microsoft has another combined engineering thing where.
Unified.
Unified engineering thing.
I call it, yeah,
because there's, you and I call it unified,
they call it combined.
But,
But if we do it last enough,
we can fix this.
Get rid of the testers and the developer.
We've talked about it a bunch of times.
I'll slam some tequila later in honor of this.
We talked, I also talked a lot about my role
on the teams team.
My last team at Microsoft,
where I was the quality guy to kind of
make sure that developers were doing
what they were supposed to be doing.
And that included making sure the tools were in place,
coaching, whatever was needed to make sure they were,
we were getting enough testing activity to happen.
Plus some vendors doing some manual testing.
The idea of the dedicated QA team,
that I'm thinking of the team that gets software
at the end like we used to,
or even we were on the team from the beginning,
but we got something here, test this before,
way too late.
Even if it was one month into the product cycle,
the thing we got was way too late.
We should have been involved earlier.
So that sort of.
And I spent, you did as well,
but spent almost half of my,
maybe longer of my QA career fighting that.
Yeah.
So because it's a constant fight getting those,
getting those dev or getting those PM to involve QA
at the beginning.
So that model sort of worked and it worked.
And remember I had some of my vendors
working involved in stand up
with some of the key feature areas
to make sure they were involved early.
The way Unity are structured,
which is very similar to how many organizations
doing agile software development function
is every one of my,
across to a person,
across my 28, 29 person org
is embedded in a development team.
So they work for me and I get that consolidation.
But as far as the day to day work,
and they maybe have a lead that works for me
who kind of make sure that they're coordinated,
but their day to day work,
they're embedded in as the test expert in a feature team.
The test expert or the test bitch?
Expert.
Okay, that's fantastic.
I have great conversations with product owners already,
our POs about,
like I had one,
this guy Andy came to me this week and said,
so you're not Monday.
Oh, you're not supposed to mention names.
It's fine.
I'm not throwing them under the bus.
I can talk about them when they're awesome.
All right, fair enough.
If I don't mention a name,
doesn't mean you're not awesome.
But anyway, he said,
so how do I work with you?
And I said,
and he said,
so what do I do about,
should I come to you when I have work,
I think that those,
your guys need to do?
I said, well, that seems stupid, doesn't it?
My job is to offer,
is to look for consolidation,
everything in my mission we talked about.
I'm looking for how to consolidate testing.
I'm gonna coach them on how,
maybe how to get things done
and what tools to use and learn from them.
But as far as prioritizing their work,
that's not my job.
You know, the PO could take care of that.
They know what testing or what quality work needs
to get done.
And they're empowered to do that.
Unity is huge on empowerment.
And you do what needs to get done.
So these guys are definitely not the test bitches
or the test experts.
I like the idea from-
But they're not the ones doing all of the testing.
Absolutely not.
They're the ones looking for,
they're the ones testing the things that,
testing for the things
that probably no one else could find.
I have both people,
everybody's air quote technical,
but they do have the concept of the SDET and the STE,
the test developer and the tester.
I have some of both across my organization,
which is fine.
But they, everybody does kind of everything.
It's a, they're bought,
whether they use it by name or not,
they're bought into the specialized in general
and by the time I get through with my little,
part a little bit of Allen culture across my org,
everyone will know what a specialized in generalist is.
I've already talked to them about
the five orders of ignorance.
So there's some bits of my tool bag
that came out naturally.
So anyway, they're embedded in these teams across the org.
That by the way is one of my favorite parts
of joining the new team.
It's starting all over on your series of,
these are the speeches I use every time.
So anyway, I mentioned embedded in the teams.
I like the idea from Google of experts,
not just in testing,
but in improving developer productivity.
So I kind of expect them,
again, everyone's different getting used to the team,
but for the most part,
they sort of get the necessity for efficiency.
Are there better ways to do this?
So when I poke and think,
oh, here's something you could do,
in most cases they've already done it.
So there's a backend service for CodBuild.
Can you build the Unity app?
Oh, by the way, and I've built the Unity,
I'm working on a game.
I have a little shooter I'm building in Unity.
It's interesting writing a game.
I don't know if you've ever written a game before, but-
Long time ago.
I spend more time in the editor working with physics
and lighting than I do actually writing the code,
just to try and make it look right.
So it's an interesting little shift for me
in my software development.
What kind of shooter are you building?
Is this like a FPS?
No, like a Galaga type game.
It's based on one of the demos.
Oh, good.
But anyway, but I'm using all of the services I can
with this thing to get used to how they integrate.
So each of these services has a entry point in the editor.
I was going somewhere with this.
Oh, and then there's this cloud build thing.
So I can choose to build my project in the cloud,
which is pretty cool.
And I can target any one of Unity's zillion 30-ish targets.
I can't build for Xbox or for Samsung TV or for Windows
or for Android or whatever.
And then there's all these different versions of Unity's
and things that I thought,
well, how do you handle the combination exploration of this?
And they already, they know about combinatorial testing
and they have some stuff to go directly on the back end,
beat out, make sure all these things
continue to work all the time.
So it's, and sure enough, the builds have,
again, my project's pretty simple now,
but they've worked out great.
Little bit of a tangent there.
Let's reel it back in.
Neat story, Alan.
Hey, what are the goals of a QA team?
I think they're buried in that story.
I think the goals are to,
and I don't want to fall back on Jim Morris, the remainder,
but it's not entirely it.
It's not being the test pitch.
It's finding-
I will kick you in the shins on the podcast.
And you'll miss my-
I hear that.
And you'll miss my shin and hit something more important.
Goals of the QA team are to increase developer productivity,
identify risk.
Let me just stop there.
I like the idea of the chicken little,
part chicken little, part Eeyore.
Okay.
It'll never work.
This guy is tall.
I'm just, I like-
I don't, I don't.
I do like the thinking behind the people with that,
but I find it's great to think that way.
Don't communicate that way.
Oh, I agree.
So it's one of the things that I heard
based on what you're discussing.
Like, so right now, I absolutely adore your model.
The-
Aww.
But the one thing I think that is an opportunity here
is for you to also put in
some form of sticky obligation
for your guys to proactively communicate
and share.
Because I think the, you do run the,
so empowered local teams is fantastic.
But if without any sort of thing to balance it, right,
they're going to become siloed
and this knowledge management problem
that you're going to have is just continue or get worse.
One of the things I think you should consider is,
and it's fuzzy in my head,
so I don't have something concrete for you,
but what are actually the useful things
that aren't going to start a bureaucracy engine
that you could tell these guys,
hey, useful solutions that can be shared across,
I want you to feel morally obligated
to think about those generalized patterns
and contributing to a solution.
Because I think one of the things,
as every team is focused on that,
you're going to be the guy that goes,
oh, you have that problem?
Hey, my team that's 1200 miles away from you
will actually just solve that.
So, again-
So then you become a knowledge command and control bottleneck.
I think we've talked, just a minute ago,
talked about learning from each other as part of that,
but let me take a moment back and talk about,
not my mission, but Unity's mission.
Three principles.
Now, let's see if I can remember them.
Democratize development.
Okay.
Solve hard problems.
Enable developer success.
Everyone at the company lives those principles.
Okay.
It's about sharing and enabling others,
picking, not just solving the hard problems,
but picking the right hard problems to solve,
which is very much reflective
of what you were talking about.
It's like, yes, people are expected to identify
and solve and share the hard problems.
And then I think one that if it's QA more than,
again, I'm getting used to calling it QA,
they call it QA Unity, but we call it,
oh, I called the test and there's, I don't care.
I don't either.
Okay.
Actually, I do care.
We talk about-
Engineer.
When we talk about enabling developer success,
it's enabling our end users or developers.
We want-
Oh, okay.
So, you know, from working on Xbox is
primary customer is not the end user,
it's actually those developer making those games.
The easier we make it for developers
to make games that make them money,
money, money, so-
Money and Unity.
What do you call money at Unity?
Money.
But the easier you make it for them
to be successful developing games,
the more successful we are.
Right.
That the-
So, anyways, but going rewinding again, backing up.
Yes, absolutely agree with you.
That is definitely a goal.
I want the team to solve hard problems
that are hard problems that maybe other parts of the team
haven't recognized yet and be able to benefit from that.
Yeah, it reminds me, there is an Agile model,
I'm forgetting the name of the company
that published this.
So, not only do they
have,
I don't know if you guys are calling them
Scrum teams or whatever,
but we'll call them the little Agile teams
that are working together towards a common goal.
But they've also created a secondary series
of these teams where
we talk about specializing generalists,
generalizing specialists,
but this is specifically targeted around
getting specializations in a community on a weekly basis
and getting them to work towards a common secondary goal.
Whatever they invent, right?
But I actually thought that was a,
when I first read it, I'm like,
really, this is gonna be massive overhead.
But I think once that rolls and you make it very clear,
no, you're really on,
and strike the balance of the fact
that you're telling them to be on two active teams,
which is generally frowned on.
But one is depth and one is breadth.
And this breadth one is,
if you do it right,
then knowledge correctly and naturally starts bubbling out.
Yeah, that's a good idea.
I forget, I'm even forgetting.
They don't call it squads or just wacky.
No, it doesn't need a name.
And I think that's important also.
This is part of building,
I think we'll have to do things like that
to build sort of the services team,
even though everyone's embedded elsewhere.
Already, based on a conversation I've had
with one of my leads, they are going to put together,
they're gonna take their team offline for,
not offline, but take a couple days with them
and sort of go through a little workshop
on just among themselves trying to identify
the current state and where they wanna go,
which is great, helps me out.
And they've sort of taken it on themselves
to do that, which is great.
I think there's going to be many opportunities
to do things like that.
It's honeymoon phase, but so far,
it's just, I haven't met a person that,
like everyone from super,
I don't call them senior,
the organizationally, it feels very flat,
which is good.
I've-
And where there's hierarchy,
with what you describe on the,
how empowerment actually,
that empowerment is an action,
not a management buzzword.
It's gonna feel even flatter.
Because part of the thing that you're essentially saying,
unlike, let's say, your former company,
where-
Oh my God, yeah, I have thought about-
One of the expectations would be,
so your role here,
if you were to go into a role like this,
you're gonna be expected to, every week,
join, I don't know, 567 status meetings,
where you have to represent the progress
of your whole entire organization.
And I don't get the sense
that you're gonna have that requirement.
No, no, it's about sharing and learning this.
Yeah, no.
But I think, you know, hierarchy,
I didn't realize it till I left how,
at Microsoft, how huge it was.
It's like, you,
sometimes you couldn't even email someone
based on their title.
Like, oh, I'm too junior to talk,
did you go directly to them?
Yeah.
That just doesn't exist.
And again, part of a small company too.
If you're a company of 1,400 people,
with 500, 400 engineers.
Yeah, but-
We both have been in teams that,
like I've been in teams that are smaller than that.
And so did that, the rule that you're talking about,
persists.
Oh no, don't waste his time.
Yeah, oh, I worked,
and I had someone who worked for me
who talked to my skip level directly,
and I got shit for it.
You did?
Yeah, because my manager came to me and said-
Why is this guy coming to me?
Hey, he went and talked to Tom directly.
That, if he has stuff he needs to talk about,
you or to me,
you can't go up that many levels of hierarchy directly.
You know what?
Yeah, I know you made up the name,
so maybe I'll talk to you after the podcast.
But stuff like that just ticks me off,
because that is a dude who is trying to do PR control.
All right.
Did I answer your question eventually?
We don't have direct yes or no answers here.
Well, no.
So in terms of what are the goals of a QA team?
My belief, again, is a QA team,
and I think you described it,
even in your organization,
you described it differently,
but a QA team's responsibility is to accelerate quality.
Yeah.
But quality from a customer point of view.
I actually remember you had that definition
for many, many years.
Yes.
And you see I successfully didn't use the forbidden words.
I don't think you've talked about it on the podcast.
It's been a long time if we have.
No.
So my view, if you have a dedicated QA team,
first and foremost,
it's not a goal per se,
because usually when people ask goals,
they want something that has a KPI in it.
But if you start off with the idea
that a QA team's role is to accelerate
the achievement of shippable product quality,
framed very tightly with that,
my definition of quality has the square root
of nothing to do with bugs.
It has to do with customer satisfaction.
Then you can take the context of your current team
and break it down.
The, it is very context sensitive in my experience.
I do not like goals of, I will automate all things.
The problem with that,
when you are in a leadership of a QA team,
the best thing for you to do is number one,
realize that the sort of the definition,
the vision or whatever you want to call it
that I just mentioned,
then take the business KPIs
that your executives care about.
What are the needles they're trying to move?
And then convert your goals,
something that leverages the skill set of your team,
but says, hey, you know what?
I'm gonna take ownership of knocking down 3%
of whatever this business KPI you're caring about
by using my team's assets.
Sure, right, in my view, there's three general things.
Business value.
Now, if you're in a QA team,
business value is going to be
whatever you're doing to measure customer satisfaction
around your product.
That's QA secret sauce.
We're good at customer satisfaction,
but drive it, not from theory.
Second, calendar time.
Calendar time, once you've lost it,
you can't get it back.
You can't hire more months in the year to scale up.
Calendar time is a critical resource,
particularly in this services agile world.
And then probably the easiest one,
but also, well, depending on the organization,
it might not be as valuable as the prior two.
And that's engineering time.
Much like what you're talking about,
you want to improve developer productivity.
Which is actually quite close to accelerating quality.
Well, actually, I'd take that back.
Because when you were telling the story,
the word developers overload it.
Because the developer is not only your Unity's customer,
that's the class of people, their game developers.
But they're actually a title within Unity.
So when I first heard,
when you, you know, half hour ago,
when you were talking about developer productivity,
I was assuming it was the in-house developer
is not your customer side.
Maybe I interpreted entirely.
No, actually, when I was talking about developer productivity,
in that case, I was talking about in-house developers.
Right.
To be clear.
Yeah.
So that's sort of the engineering time.
If QA is, can eliminate waste on that front,
I'm not a big fan of that.
I'm not a big fan of targeting efficiency first.
I'd rather target productivity.
But as part of that, if QA can eliminate waste,
and that results in a shorter calendar time,
which results in a happier customer.
Efficiency will result in shorter calendar time.
Efficiency will, productivity will.
Efficiency is about reducing,
well, generally, my definition of efficiency
is about reducing time wasted.
Right, time.
But there is another pivot, and I agree,
there is another pivot on efficiency
that I find is actually used most often,
and that's the elimination of idle time.
And I don't wanna go into it today.
We don't have enough time, but the studies have shown
that if you wanna move fast,
you need to make sure that there is actually idle time
in your people's daily calendars.
A metaphor.
A fully utilized freeway is known as a parking lot.
So if you fully utilize all the resources on your team,
you're gonna go slow.
And if you don't believe me, Alan's looking at me like,
I don't know if I should make fun of you.
You can look it up in Rene Anderson's book.
If you don't believe me, you'll believe him.
I believe him way more than I believe you.
Fair enough.
That's Flow.
What's that book, Engineering Flow?
The Flow of Software Development.
I forget the exact title.
Principles of the software development flow
or maybe just development flow.
Yeah.
All right.
Is there anything else to talk about?
Are we done?
I think we're done.
Where we at?
Hey, more stories of unity coming up?
Yep.
But not today.
Nope.
All right.
I guess we're done.
I'm Alan.
I'm Brent.
And we will see you next time for 55.
Double naked.
It's not.