A B. Test
The Modern Testing Podcast.
Join your hosts, Alan and Brent.
I am mindless agile robot.
I must iterate.
As we talk about software engineering, software quality,
leadership, and whatever else comes to mind.
Now on with the show.
Hey, we're back.
Howdy everyone.
Hey, welcome to another episode of A B testing.
This is what I thought when I drove to work this morning,
95 that it is not in this episode 94.
Nope. 95 is our infamous.
End of the year extravaganza.
Right.
Where we try and come up with predictions
and you know, predicting things is hard,
especially about the future.
We'll also review some of the things we liked and loved
about 2018.
I don't know if you saw my tweet.
Did I just tweet this?
I put it in our channel as well.
You slacked it.
I tweeted it and slacked it in one of the three.slack.com.
Do you slack it?
I'm going to say I slacked it.
I was searching for, I was actually looking for something.
It was based on a conversation we had
where I was trying to find my strength finder information.
Did you?
And I did find it because it's weird.
Probably one of the only accounts I have left,
I'll probably keep discovering more,
where it used my Microsoft email address as the login.
So luckily I remember my password
because there was no way I was getting the password
with the email that to me.
Did you, oh, so you didn't do the blog search,
I suggest, because you do your blog on it.
And I did the blog search.
I did not find a blog on it.
I don't think I blogged it.
So while you remember that,
but what I did find interestingly,
interestingly it was what I found
is some predictions I made about trends
in software testing in 2014.
And I made it as a result of someone saying,
these are the trends.
I thought, these aren't trends.
These are established things.
Like one of the trends was mobile testing.
It's like, what the heck?
Oddly, you can go find my tweets
because I've forgotten what the things are.
But you posted it on.
I did post it on Twitter.
20, no, 2014 was when I think the date.
Yes, it was mid 2014.
So three and a half years ago.
And it ended up being a lot of things
that we're seeing a lot of,
I was actually right for once.
But I don't think it was a tough stretch.
It was stuff.
No, this is.
It was stuff we had been talking about.
Even before we, at that point,
I don't think we had named modern testing.
No, no, no.
But we had talked about it indirectly
because we had talked about our struggles
with traditional testing.
We just hadn't come up with the opposite term yet.
But anyway.
We had to come up with names.
It was interesting to look at.
It was funny, I got a comment, a fresh comment
based on the tweet from someone who didn't realize
it was three and a half years old.
It said, oh, these are good.
Some other trends I see are blah and blah.
I think you missed the point.
Yeah.
Time out.
Timing.
You were gonna get me a cup of coffee.
No, it's cool.
It's cool, I'm just saying.
I'm just saying.
I was.
I epically failed the coffee.
Anyway, go on.
I don't know, five, six years ago.
Not Whitaker, so this is a story about Whitaker.
Not his current.
Matt Whitaker, the Ace Attorney General.
No, James Whitaker.
Oh, James Whitaker.
Not his latest book on stories,
but I think the tours one.
Yes.
What was the name of that book?
I think it was called Exploratory Testing.
Oh, right.
Mainly to piss off some folks.
Yeah.
Successfully done, I might say.
And yeah, that was funny.
I wrote the forward for that book, by the way.
Did you?
That's the best part of the book.
The one thing.
Arguably.
So it was one of the last few times
James had a regularly scheduled lunch with me.
And it may be possible that I pissed him off
on my comments on this one.
But I'm like, James, this book
is exactly the same as How to Break Software,
except with this tour spin on it.
And one of the things that I, yeah,
he didn't appreciate that comment,
but he did accept it.
And he's like, dude, you know what?
Sometimes you just repackage the same thing.
And I'm like, I think about that a lot on MT
and I think it's related to your stuff.
I think MT is going to be contextually relevant
for much longer than either you and I have patience for.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Right, I think it'll still be relevant
potentially five years from now.
Oh, I think it's-
But if you and I are still talking about it
five years from now, we either came up
with something really fresh that excites us
or this podcast is gonna be super boring.
Going to be, continue to be.
No, this is a relative discussion.
A couple stories, we do have one topic today, one,
but a couple stories which are relevant,
this is not the normal preamble you should skip,
so get your fingers off of the fast forward
plus 30 seconds or plus 10 minute button.
A few more stories about walking the talk.
I'm continuing to shrink my team.
I'm finding new places for them to work.
One of the things, one of the techniques
I should probably mention I haven't gotten into is
I do regular one-on-ones with all of the Dev Leads
I work with and that's been super helpful
in kind of keeping the culture going
and enabling the people who no longer work for me
to continue to be successful.
So I met with another Dev Lead this week
and we talked about moving one of my leads
to work for him and what that meant
and part of the deal was that I of course
continued my one-on-ones with the lead
and I would begin regular one-on-ones with this Dev Lead
as part of this transition for indefinitely.
And I think I've got to a tipping point
where I haven't counted, but I believe
I have more one-on-ones, and these aren't just chat,
these are about careers, about solving problems,
it's about mentoring and coaching.
I have more one-on-ones with people
who do not work for me than people who do work for me.
Is that primarily because you've made them
stop working for you?
Yes.
Okay.
Yes, but we still meet,
because they still find,
that's one of the primary questions I get,
which is as I move people away,
it's like can we still meet?
I said yes, of course, I think it's necessary.
But I also find that one of the techniques
I use that we haven't talked about
is meeting regularly with those Dev Leads.
Culture change until it sticks
and is able to run on its own volition
needs a lot of care.
I think it's, yes, and I think the value of communication
and keeping lines of communication open
and establishing trust are severely underrated.
There is...
Not in my particular business,
trust is everything for what I do.
But you're talking about trust of the data.
I'm talking about trust of the people.
Not just the trust of the data,
but the trust of my team.
There is still a high degree
of data science and magic are synonyms.
There's a quote about this.
Yes.
And when people do not have the time
to get deep in the math,
they don't have the patience to do it
anyway, a large number of people don't wanna.
But I am asking them to change their decision-making process
based off of a human, me, my team's analysis
of what the data is saying.
But I'm talking, I am talking about
a different kind of trust,
because that is definitely needed there
and I understand what you're saying.
I'm talking about this foundation of trust
you have to have that enables us to have conflict
and sometimes severe and active conflict,
meaning we'll argue.
But it's not, we don't matter to each other,
but we can have, because we have trust,
we know we're flushing out the idea.
And I believe that only the-
The difference between debate and argument is trust.
Very well put, very well put.
And that's where good decisions and good ideas come from.
The way we've talked about where ideas come from
while other ideas get together,
the way you get them to get together
in a more meaningful way is to have debate.
Yes, debate, it doesn't sit right with me,
but I think I'll, I think I'm going down a semantic road.
You are, you are.
I completely agree.
And I'll go back to conflict.
There's a fear of, I just talked to someone this week,
one of the dead leads has a massive fear of conflict.
And one of the things I, my job is to do
is to draw that conflict out of him.
But I have to establish that trust first.
So we do it slowly.
I don't just say, what the hell were you doing?
I have to draw those things out.
So I met, speaking of meeting with Lee, dead leads,
Brent wants to say something.
Yes.
What is worse, a yes man or a no man?
Oh, that's actually a very good question.
I think, I have no preference
because I think they're both,
they're both equally bad is my best answer.
I don't know which, I can't decide if one's worse or not.
Do you have a preference?
Yes, man is absolutely worse.
Cause their last rider wins
when you don't have the ability to.
But at least somebody wins, but the no man, nobody wins.
No, the no man is predictable and trust,
you can trust what they're going to say.
And they don't always say no.
The long-term being a no man, the risk is of course,
that you'll establish a reputation
of not being a team player.
But the yes man, when they say yes,
it's just a matter of time before, they'll say yes,
but then their actions is actually a no.
One of the attributes of leadership
and actually one of the people I talked to
that's been working for me, asked me,
we were talking about the quality culture transition model,
which someone called the constantly improving quality model,
which is pronounced Sycam, which I kind of like.
But he said,
I thought you didn't want it to be a model though.
What about his transition guide?
Yes. Okay.
He said, what would that look like for leadership?
And the problem is, is there are leadership models
and they suck.
So I'm a little afraid to do it,
but in thinking through it,
I promise I might think through it.
And I think I will do something that I'll share even
on a much smaller basis.
By the way, I am not going to dump,
at least in the time being,
the quality culture transition guide to the masses,
but it has been shared in our Slack channel.
So you can join that or ask me
and I'll give you a view of a draft of it,
but I'm not just gonna dump it out on the blog
or the website at this point.
But I was thinking about this growth path,
this transition guide for becoming a new leader
to an experienced leader.
And one of the attributes is,
this is actually all coming back,
is decision making.
And a yes man can't make a decision.
Well, they can't make a proper decision
because everything's yes.
So anyway, I was talking-
They're deferring to a different decision maker.
Yes.
And they want to please.
They don't want to cause conflict.
They want to please,
but that's not the way to be a leader.
It does not help anyone.
So I was meeting with,
there's a story I'm getting to here eventually.
I went to San Francisco Tuesday for the day,
met with a bunch of important people down there.
And one thing,
and a lot of them are just normal,
like talking with leads on how things are going,
getting an idea of how their quality is going,
quality, culture, et cetera.
Not that exciting.
One interesting thing happened internally lately.
We did a little bit of a reorg,
nothing to do with my org directly,
but we moved where some of our internal tools,
substrate engineering happens,
to work through the ads team.
And tell me if this sounds familiar.
I want to get back to that point.
You moved into Microsoft GitHub?
I'm guessing not.
Your body language says no.
No, we use, what's it called?
Azure DevOps?
You're right, Azure DevOps.
Is it Azure DevOps for GitHub?
Great name.
No, it's not a great name.
It's the stupidest freaking name in the world.
This from the team who brought you XT.
Oh God.
Yeah, yeah.
So we moved around.
So there's a central tools team,
it's the best way of putting it.
We made a small reorg.
So central tools team now reports
through my ads organization.
And while I like it,
it's in a much better place
than the lead was, I knew was good.
I worry because, and you can relate to this,
how many times at Microsoft
do we have some sort of tool used
that was or set of tools
that were to be used by the whole company
but were owned or owned and managed in a specific org?
Okay, now Brent's making a face.
How many of those were successful?
Brent's counting on his fingers.
Yeah, so I was understandably worried.
But, so, go ahead.
And then, because I,
there is a happy ending here.
I don't want the Unity listeners to go,
oh my God, what comes next?
So get to your thing and I'll evolve my thought here.
No, so there's systems ebb and flow.
Okay, and then this is a particular,
what you're talking about is a particular system.
I have been aware of, particularly at this company,
and I think it's more than just this company,
almost within the first few years.
And that is the pendulum on how engineering tools
should be built constantly swings.
It goes, oh, duplication of effort.
We should centralize.
Well, and then that over pivots
because then once it's centralized and it's valuable,
these guys stop having a relationship
with the actual consumers.
And they start doing make work exercises
to adjust their continual existence.
They eventually get called out
because their dependency teams aren't able
to solve the problems that they need to from this team.
And then that begins to swing back towards decentralization.
And then it's just a matter of time
before duplication of effort.
And it just goes back and forth and back and forth.
Microsoft especially likes to swing pendulums
in its decision making.
There is a way to do this in a centralized manner.
No, and I agree with that.
And I'm actually, I'm 100% confident it will work
because the thought models of the lead in charge
of this org and I are super highly aligned.
That's one reason I think it will work.
But also, let me ask you a question, Brent.
What are the Microsoft values?
Yeah, I never knew either in my 22 years there.
No, I mean, they've changed so many times
and unfortunately here I am, I will absolutely-
I can't name a single Microsoft value.
I will absolutely state with high confidence
that if I had it loaded up, I would agree with it.
Because every time when new set comes out,
I look at it and go,
I first evaluate it against some manager buzzwordy stuff.
I don't know why I still do that
because it passes that test 100% of the time.
But then I go, okay, if I look at the intent behind this,
do I agree?
And more often than not, I do.
But while that part is good,
the way I look at it is you have a vision or a mission
for what you're doing and what you're going to be doing
and the values guide you in how you make decisions
along the way towards your mission and vision.
So if they're not really,
if they're not accessible,
if they're not part of how you make decisions inherently,
and maybe the big thing, maybe the challenge is there is
a lot of times when I worked at Microsoft,
I felt Xbox One was a difference.
Windows 95 was an outlier.
I always felt like I was too many degrees
separated from my customer.
Sure.
So anyway, back on track.
I would argue that was mostly because
a lot of that was number one,
you were in a test role.
Number two, you were in a traditional test role
most of that time.
And number two was...
Was that two number twos?
On-prem product.
No, I was...
Yes, yes.
And so...
No, I get it, I get it.
So anyway, so I am going to loop this back in
and get to our other, our mailbag question.
We have four values at Unity.
Value one, then there's value two.
Yes, users first.
Okay, that's okay, whatever.
The customer is the only one able to evaluate
the quality of the product.
Best users first.
So yep, I can totally support that.
Yep.
Meanwhile, actually the people that argue with that one
don't listen to the podcast, so we're cool.
Best ideas win.
This is where conflict and trust and actually
doesn't matter if you're the hippo,
as Ronnie Quavie puts it,
the highest paid person in the organization.
The best ideas win.
Yeah, the problem with that one is often who gets to judge.
But if you have...
As a value, I completely agree.
I'm gonna refer directly to it
because I eased around it,
but Pat Linceone's book,
The Fight is Functions of a Team,
probably his most popular business novel.
I've read all of them.
I'm a huge fanboy of his.
It talks about if you have that trust,
you can get over the fear of conflict.
You can then have people,
if they feel like their voice is heard,
even if they didn't go with their decision,
they will have buy-in and accountability
for achieving whatever or acting
on whatever decision was made.
So I believe all that works together
and that's where best ideas win.
Come from the judge is maybe consensus.
It may not be,
but at least you feel like your voice was heard
during that discussion
and you weren't like stifled out.
It's like, shut up, newbie.
Doesn't happen.
Yeah, I'll stop testing your principles
because I do agree with them.
There's no such thing as a best idea either.
Okay, now I'll stop.
Are you sure?
No, but I'll try.
Anything else?
What's value number three, Alan?
And for the sake of time,
I'll skip to the fourth one,
the one that I wanted to be relevant.
I probably should have just mentioned this one
and skipped to the other one
so I could not have your damn value testing,
but in it together.
When I think about this,
and again, these values can be words on paper
that you can agree with,
but as a culture,
the company does work very well together.
People try to and want to help each other
regardless of what division they're in.
And while it has improved, admittedly,
the org chart cartoon
that shows all the divisions pointing guns at each other
is still partially to largely true,
or at least it was two years ago when I left.
And that's what I saw on these tools
or these systems that were developed in one org
but shared is when push came to shove,
100 times out of 100,
the work was done,
the preference was for the local team
versus helping the other teams.
And sometimes people would get worse.
I watched at Microsoft,
teams would get completely bought in
and committed and integrated into using a tool
developed by another team
who wanted to be used by everyone.
And then they decided they were too busy
and just stopped supporting it
and said, no, you're on your own.
Freaking committed,
we built all our adapters on our end
and now we're screwed, thank you very much.
And said, not our problem.
Yeah, there's...
That happened, that happened.
Did you get the culture
that your incentive model inspires?
Yes.
Absolutely.
I was thinking about,
what is it, Jack Welch, right?
A lot of the foundation of this company
was based off of Jack Welchian philosophy,
which I do think probably applies to sales.
But unfortunately, one of our big leaders
in the history of this company
was just a masterful salesperson.
And I don't think the culture
that they put onto the company,
I don't think enough thought was put into
as to whether or not
that is applicable outside of sales.
Oftentimes, I don't have the data here,
but I hear that it is often the case in sales
that the top 10% of your sales force
is providing greater than 50% of the value,
the business, the sales.
And so there's this idea of,
well then we should reward that.
I don't know that management science
has found a good solution for this one yet.
I do know, for example, they have discovered
that if you wanna grow company performance,
you randomly promote people.
You randomly switch between the best employee
and the worst employee,
because a lot of times the worst employee
isn't suited for the job that they have.
They should be in more of a strategic role.
No.
I've seen it over and over again.
Okay, whatever.
Anyway, I'm not sure why your microphone
is not pointing at your neck,
but I'm just gonna ignore that.
And we'll go on.
I have a question from a coworker.
Actually, if I could draw better,
and I've been working on it,
I really should do better.
Monty, Monty.
We got a cartoon, we need a comic strip
to go with this recording
that just goes through the hell
I go through every week.
Every other week, or sometimes every third week.
So a coworker asked a question,
and one thing I wanna mention is,
an odd thing, and maybe slightly uncomfortable
for me thing at Unity is,
despite Unity being 1 1 hundredth
of the size of Microsoft,
I have more podcast listeners at Unity
than I did at Microsoft.
And sometimes it's surprised like someone.
As a percentage or as a person?
As a number.
And maybe there were more Microsoft listeners
or there are than I think,
but there are a chunk of Unity listeners
and hey, shouting out to you,
this is for you.
Well I hope if I say things that piss you off,
you tell me.
That's all I'll say.
But anyway, Klaus.
Who was awesome?
Klaus.
I love the name Klaus.
I always have to say it in a German accent.
Yeah, he's Danish.
I am too-ish.
You're something-ish.
Anyway, in general, Klaus asked if we could talk more
about how the context-driven testing principles
compare, contrast, interact, whatever
with the modern testing principles.
Sure.
So I will quickly read through,
actually Brent, should I go through all seven?
Actually, if you can limit your,
no I'll read them.
And I want you to comment,
but I don't want you to comment like
the diatribe story upon story interwoven
into an inception-like view of the world.
I just want a few comments on each one after I read it.
So one commonality between the modern testing principles
and the context-driven testing principles
is that we both have seven.
Yes.
Number one, the value of any practice
depends on its context.
Is that a principle or a statement of fact?
Between the-
I guess it's a principle
because you could actually,
I would phrase it differently, but yeah.
Remember how I said I was gonna let you comment?
I'm sorry.
Yeah, so I think it's not a principle.
I don't think this is what we should do
for the CDT stuff, but for me,
a principle is sort of a philosophical,
unproven vision direction setting.
This is the direction we're heading.
To me, the principles kind of reads more like a proof,
mathematical proof.
Yep.
Like, is there anyone who would say
the value of a practice doesn't depend on this context?
That would imply the value of,
there are some practices where the value of the practice
is context-free.
I can't think of an example.
I actually can't either.
When I talk about the modern testing principles in,
and actually I gave a webinar on Thanksgiving
to an audience in Ukraine
because I had nothing else going on.
By the way, happy late Thanksgiving there to you, Brent.
Hey, thanks.
And I've done this, I think,
in all of the presentations I've done on modern testing
where I go back and talk about why I decided to start
with modern testing principles
and it goes back to,
I happen to be reading a book by Ray Dalio called Principles.
And then you think, yeah,
I had, of course I had known about principles before.
So I use that as the starting point.
So I use Ray Dalio's definition of principles,
which are principles are what allow you
to live a life consistent with those values.
Principles connect your values to your actions.
And when I look at the,
anyway, I don't wanna critique,
like these aren't principles all day, but that one's.
No, I don't wanna either.
Cause the one thing that I've observed with,
with another commonality between CDT and MT
is they both target testers
and testers just love tearing things apart.
So let's not do that here
because what I see with MT is when that happened,
the message gets lost
because everyone's busily piecing through semantics.
Right, so the value of any practice depends on its context.
I don't think MT says anything pro or against this.
Agree?
Agree.
So these are more of beliefs than principles was my point.
There are good practices in context, this is number two.
There are good practices in context,
but there are no best practices.
Okay.
Again, MT doesn't say anything for or against this.
Correct.
I do agree with it.
Yeah, yeah, because you said something about it earlier,
which was actually interesting.
And it depends on your definition of best.
And if you use the dictionary definition,
yeah, I agree with it.
There's always something better.
People working, number three, people working together
are the most important part of any project's context.
That's very similar to agile principles.
What?
It's people over, oh my,
fuck, edge today.
All right.
So one day I will come through on my promise to Periscope,
one of our sessions.
Again, you must experience the hell
that is an A-B testing requirement.
Oh my God.
People working together are the most important part
of any project's context.
Dude, you need some meds.
People working together.
So people working together.
I don't disagree.
And we could potentially argue the community principle
is related to this one.
They don't contradict.
In terms of the most important part,
that would be something,
so the spirit of it, I agree with.
The literal interpretation,
I'm not certain I agree with yet.
And I don't wanna spend the time thinking about it now.
Number four, projects unfold over time
in ways that are often not predictable.
True?
I think that's a bit of a tautology.
But yeah.
I guess it really lies more with an agile principle.
We believe there's something about being adaptable.
What is it, principle two?
Continuous deployment and-
Continuous improvement.
So MT does sort of address this.
But in terms of more of an actionable thing,
like the continuous deployment theory of constraints,
that is an MT principle because we agree with number four.
So this was interesting.
Number five, the product is a solution.
If the problem isn't solved, the product doesn't work.
And this actually aligns exactly-
With the customer principle.
With the principle number five of the MT principles,
which is the one, well, they're like saying,
if someone who is a believer or follow these principles
did not like number five,
it would be like them saying the product,
if they believe this, that the product isn't solved,
the product doesn't work,
well, only the customer is able to tell
if their solution is, if their problem is solved.
I am willing to bet, I have not done the research,
but I am willing to bet that there is
as much controversy on this one
as there is on our principle.
Interesting.
But to me, it's just like, yes,
we've talked about the Tom Popendike quote
about customers don't want software,
they want their problem solved.
I believe that 1 million percent, if that was possible.
I could imagine it would be,
but in a certain context, it is a solution.
So does that mean the problem,
I could see that they-
Oh, listen, this doesn't make any sense,
but I wanna say it.
In a certain context, is a context really a context?
Not enough coffee, dude.
Okay, there's not enough in the world.
Number six, good software testing
is a challenging intellectual process.
Good software development
Good cooking is a challenging intellectual process, et cetera.
Yes.
Good, and I will object-
Place verb here.
Good knowledge work.
And often we forget that testing is just knowledge work.
I shouldn't say just, but testing is knowledge work.
Yes, yes, it's a challenging intellectual process.
I guess it's, again, a belief?
No, it's not a belief.
As you just called out.
The one thing I think where we might disagree,
we will absolutely agree that good knowledge work
is a challenging intellectual process.
I don't think we fully agree with what I interpret as
an implied over ascension of the testing rule.
Because specifically calling this out is interesting.
Why did they say testing and not knowledge work
or development or whatever?
Right, they're trying to elevate it.
When I see this principle applied even from whoever,
whether they're followers of the principles or not,
it's more them trying to justify,
what I see more often is a justification of their role.
But my job's important, it's actually very, very hard.
I wasn't there for the development, so I do see that,
but I don't know that the developers
of these principles intended that.
There's some things I wanna get beyond here.
So number seven, only through judgment and skill,
exercise cooperatively throughout the entire project
are we able to do the right things at the right times
to effectively test our products.
Which is kind of a summation of a lot of these.
But how is this trying to figure out
how it fits in with modern testing?
If it fits in with MT principles
any more or less than the others?
It occurs to me that there's another similarity
between MT and CDT here.
And that there is only one principle
that contains the word test.
Very interesting, that's good.
And actually one, and remember these are much, much older
than the modern testing principles.
I believe, I think the first time I saw these published
was when lessons learned came out.
They may have been revised since then,
but that was many, many years ago.
But the one thing I like is when many people have read,
and despite those of you, again,
you listeners aren't the art.
Besides those who have argued
with principles number five and seven,
a lot of people, many people, read the principles
or see a presentation on the principles and go,
oh yeah, that's just common sense.
And I think maybe at the time,
and maybe for some people today even,
these read like common sense.
Because you can nod your head and go, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Again, I think this was, so looking at it now,
and then thinking it through the light of,
you know, if we change the word testing in number six
or the word knowledge work,
the spirit of this is probably nothing
I would disagree with, right?
But might even argue it's a bit of a tautology.
But.
There's not much here that I could think,
I think you mentioned number five,
but may cause some disagreement,
but I don't know where disagreement,
again, so much has changed in the 10 or more years
these first came out.
And that's actually the point I was gonna next make,
is essentially when these were developed though,
and if there's something,
this is something we have explicitly called out
in the modern testing principles.
We fully acknowledge, we don't know when,
when we observe it, we'll both stand up and say,
yes, this has happened.
But we know there's an expiration date
on the usefulness of the modern testing principles.
We know, we don't know what it is,
but we know there's an expiration date.
This came out in the, I don't know,
the golden age of traditional testing.
Oh yeah, for sure.
I'll show it.
Right, and one of the problems that happened
back in those days,
people were hiring armies of.
Unskilled testers.
You know how to turn on a computer?
We needed a tester.
I was there for that.
Manual testing happened all of the time.
It was heavily unskilled.
It was a thoughtless process.
You still see a fair chunk of that in the gaming industry.
Hiring people at minimum wage,
to bang through a game over and over and over.
And quite honestly, I don't have a problem with that.
I don't either.
If that is the most efficient and cost effective way
of going from A to B,
A, knock yourself out, business.
The thing I'm actually,
but when I look at this now,
instead of looking at it from a historical point of view,
from a historical point of view,
I think this helped add value.
It basically said testing is knowledge work,
not a thoughtless exercise.
I think it helped solve that problem.
I think it did too.
One thing maybe missing is the wrap up.
We have accelerated the achievable quality
and the principle support that mission.
Yes.
I wonder, and I'm not gonna scroll through the whole page
here, but there's some statement that wraps all this up.
But yeah, I'll agree with what you said.
I think there's nothing wrong with these.
Some are a bit tautological,
but given the time these came out,
yeah, totally valid.
I'm not gonna dive into,
if you go to contextdriventesting.com,
if I'm smart and I'm not,
I would add a link to that in our show notes.
There's illustrations of the principles in action,
which we will,
I don't wanna dive into
because we will disagree with those in many ways,
but they do support the principles
and they do support the time
in which these were written and came out.
Yeah, I would say, looking at it now,
there's nothing in here I really find a problem with
except for potentially the highlighting,
or what I was saying about-
Testers have to be smart.
No, it's,
this is,
these are in alignment
with modern testing,
except perhaps how you interpret number six.
I completely agree,
good software testing is a challenging intellectual exercise.
If you use that to justify your position or over elevate,
that is where I'm going to disagree
with using those words.
I completely agree with what's written there.
My biggest gripe when these came out was,
I read them and said,
yeah, but all good testing is context driven.
I think at the time though,
there was a lot, a lot of bad testing.
So the authors felt the need to find a way
to step out of that.
And it's kind of the,
it's ish is a way we came up
with the modern testing principles.
We viewed traditional testing practices,
whether they're context driven or not,
as a bad way to make software.
You could actually even argue MT is following
the principles of CDT.
We could say that MT is the context driven solution
for shipping software at scale to millions of users.
One of the things I was gonna say is that
one thing that is common between these two sets
of principles is,
and I don't think MT actually explicitly calls it out.
And I would actually argue
that's pretty much all they're doing in CDT.
In that taking the systems view is critical.
Now we've laid that out as a fundamental basis
for how we develop this.
I actually kind of look at this now and go,
that's actually what they're saying, right?
You have to take a systems view.
And system view has multiple different moving parts.
We agree, totally agree.
One of the things I would actually say is MT
is built around the context has changed.
We are now dealing with a new context
and the traditional methods are kind of not applicable.
What got you here isn't gonna get you there.
Right, but context has driven that fact.
Yeah. One could say.
I think we're out of time.
So that was fun.
Thanks Klaus.
And hopefully that answered your question.
Anything else to add, B man?
No.
All right, we'll see you next time
for our end of the year extravaganza.
Please send us your requests for things you want us
to make predictions about or talk about or reflect on.
Otherwise we'll fake it and do it ourselves.
Yes.
I think I'm winning an Emmy this year.
Not sure, I think I am.
Okay.
All right, that's my final.
Congrats.
Okay, see you next time.
Bye.