Hello everyone howdy I'm Alan I'm Brent and we're back with a be testing one more time
I'm Brent. I'm Alan
Hell oh one more. Oh, we're back for one more episode
Episode we are episode 77 pair of sevens double sevens. You can't roll those on dice unless there's two eight-sided dice
Or more or ten yeah, yeah
We
Are the podcast about things like software quality software testing modern testing agile organizational change?
Random stuff squirrels and what else Brent?
It's mostly the squirrels mostly squirrels. Yeah. Yeah, how you been Brent? Oh, it's been a rough week
How about you?
Well all my weeks are good. I was skiing last week at Whistler had a great time
Home this week working away
Working away next week working away the next week, but working from Brighton while I go to test bash. Yes
Where in the world is how is the weasel you gotta work on your prep there?
Yeah, the weasel will be in which means we need to move our podcast vigil around again because I'll be in Brighton
That's fine. Gosh. Nothing much else going on. I'm taking the gear you're gonna do another not taking gear if there's gear there
I'll use it, but no I'm gonna spend day and a half at unity. I'm going to
Workshops on Thursday conference on Friday
Unconference on Saturday as I believe that I'll leave Sunday morning. That sounds like fun
Yes, that's my plan is to have fun. It's test bash officially our favorite conference now
Test bash is officially my favorite conference. I don't know about you
Officially hands down and they are crazy. I cannot believe this grassroots thing and has they think they have five
Conferences, maybe it's more
That's great. They're doing their first ever test bash in San Francisco next year. Nice
I believe there's one coming up in Australia. Yes, there's one in Sydney. I think oh
There they just pop up all the time
I'm just excited to be part of it Richard Bradshaw who I've met I
Think I've only met him in person once twice
I've been in person twice because once at test bash Philly when I went two years ago
Then before that I met him at Euro star
Was I giving oh I went to euro star a few years ago not to speak at euro star
But to speak at the mobile conference they had the following day, you know euro star I
Haven't heard that in a long time. It's still around. Yeah still around
That's a you picked up on what I was thinking
Yep. So as I get ready for
Test bash god head brain. I have a dentist appointment this morning
I like to be nice to my dentist and not pound myself full as much coffee before I
Have my teeth clean does I normally do so I'm a little I'm not quite on a full tank
You want coffee? No, I can get you know, cuz I have to go straight from here to the dentist and oh
You're going to and I don't want coffee breath for other for I like but like be a nice to my dentist because I'm sure they
Smell worse things. Oh, no doubt
Okay, that's a tangent. I'm not going to explore
So test bash is coming up a couple other announcements around
Talks that I have coming up in the where's the we're in the world is the weasel thing
probably worth
mentioning so I watched your
Abuse and misuse webinar
I did give a webinar two weeks ago on the abuse and misuse of test
Have you done another one since I did I did one on Tuesday on the future of test automation
Which is also recorded and if I am a good podcaster, I will put the recording to both of those links
Links to the record whatever I will put links to both of those recordings in the podcast
So that's kind of cool. Yeah, I'm interested in hearing that
The your last one was with the
That's the pan or the two-person panel one. Yes. Yeah, okay. So what else do I have coming up?
Let me talk about a few things. I screwed up this year. I
Usually am good about saying no and after several years of doing one conference a year one talk
I am doing way too many and I I am saying no to anything else, but I
So one I have an in end of
April beginning of May I'm giving just a workshop at star East on web tools
Which will be fun, but I forgot that when you sign up for a tutorial at star they book they automatically book you
Twice so I'm also giving the same
workshop at star West in
October do they
And I forgot I feel bad I want to
Maybe not do it, but I'm going to do it
So that happened just record the first one and have them I kind of thought it back the second time
I didn't like I like even the same talk twice
So that's happening. I'm going to I'm not officially announced yet, but I will be speaking at a conference in
June on the East Coast I'll leave it at that for now, but I'm giving two workshops there
Interesting to our listeners maybe I'm giving workshops on managing the modern tester
nice and
Community builders guidebook so things that we've been talking about on the show the show will large will dictate
large amounts of the content also giving a keynote there on
Don't exactly remember
But that'll come up later once it's official and then finally I'm going to be giving
Yet another iteration of the adventures in modern testing based on
feedback feedback
Learning more experiences. I'm going to be doing that at PNS QC in October as well
the one of my favorite conferences one of
In Portland so all kinds of weasel information, but
Let's reel it back in
Real sound effect brand bridges bridges stairs at me. He goes shut up Alan the clock
Just shut up actually shut up and don't talk just just shut up
No, just keep talking okay
Okay
in preparation to
Give these talks on modern testing and a and just think about modern testing in general and to maybe bringing up
Content and make modern testing org a real website that does that just doesn't redirect to the podcast website
One of the things I had been thinking about for a while is what are the modern testing principles?
what are the principles of modern testing and
a couple things came in mind while I was creating these and these are not
Brett Brett and I are gonna vet these a little bit on air
Maybe make some edits as we go so I can get these two
I feel a little bit more confident in them
I read them last night again, and I'm starting to feel pretty good about these
But I know there's some things that aren't quite right so in preparation for this I looked at
the
Agile principles and you know what the agile principles are Brett you have memorized no how many are there?
Isn't that the one with 12 there are 12? Yes. Yes, and
You pick this up from the agile manifesto
I did I did Lisa, and I did not want to these are from the agile manifesto
I did not want to
Repeat these directly that would be
Plagiarism yes, and I didn't want to for the same reason
I didn't want to just make them all about agile testing because I see
Modern testing very much as an extension or an evolution of agile testing in many ways
Yeah, my view it kind of view it as a
Subset maybe yeah, maybe
In my mind not sure yet because I know Lisa says that she really likes it
She wants she grabbed on to the idea of the tester as a coach and that's coming up a lot more in conferences
we saw some feedback from a conference in Australia on Twitter over the weekend and
Katrina colloquy whose book I still over review on it's a very good book on on testing in DevOps and
She pointed out some theme. She had heard in the talks and
Yeah, much like much like modern testing it freaked some people out. I thought oh, those are pretty good things
They reflect they reflect some of these principles of modern time. No I
So I have her tweet
Loaded up right now and and she summarized that at cast 18
that a lot of them
themes were around testing being a bottleneck and
they were trying to come up with solutions which and the ones she had listed were
Essentially reduce the amount of testing done push testing to the users
remove tester as a roll and
Removing step-by-step test cases the last one I'm like
I hope we did that a long time ago. I thought we did so
Out of out of context you could look at those go. That's stupid
But within the context of modern testing a lot of this you go yes, of course
So let me blast through a few of the agile principles for context
You get an idea of what principles are and by the way
I highly recommend if you want to read a good book about principles in general and how they're developed
Ray Dalio's book called principles is very very good. I read it reread it every few years. So here are a few
I'm not gonna read all 12 of the agile principles
Our highest priority is to satisfy the customer through early continuous delivery of valuable software
People are nodding their heads. Yeah
Welcome changing requirements even late in development agile processes harness change with for customers competitive advantage
I'll do one more
Deliver working software frequently from a couple of weeks to a couple of months with a preference to the shorter time scale and they go
On but you'll read these you go. Yeah
Yeah, those are things we try and do when we do agile or if your team is faking as you go
Yeah, we don't do that. But
But again
I want to get some context on what principles were and then I want to talk about what I've come up with as the
Modern testing principles and Brett and I are going to figure out live on air
Where some word changes may need to be made where we may need to remove one because it just doesn't it's
Maybe it doesn't reflect
True modern testing principle or it's not part of what we should be the subset or maybe there's some things that are missing
So, how do you want to do this? I'm gonna go through one by one or just read them all that's
So I have I have this printed out as well. Let's start off with
What which one of these do you think is the most important?
They're all important there. They are all important if you look at the agile one
Right. I our highest priorities to satisfy the customer through early and continuous delivery of valuable software
I I do I don't know where we going because I
Yes, that's very important but all the agile principles I think number one should be number one, okay
Good. Yeah, the order makes sense. I have
Let's put it this way. I have changed the order of these around no
No, no into an order that I think makes sense for the cause of modern testing. Okay, so let me let me be clear
I don't think what you have listed here is number one is actually the right number one
Which one do you think is the right number one with what you listed here?
number three
Okay, I could we could make that change
So number three is number one. I'm gonna start with number three. Are we just gonna do the whole podcast talking about bullets?
Yes, so let me start with number three then I'll go one two four five six no other changes
So number three is interesting
But get it is the one what I was gonna get when we got to is gonna bring up is
Really most like one of the agile principles. So I want to talk it. Let's do number three first
Let's have a discussion on why it's important in the modern testing principles in addition to some of the similar things that are in
The agile testing principles sound good. Yeah, let me just do one
Blip and then every lister is going please just tell me what you're talking about number three
In my podcast ever
Yeah, if you believe that please go back and listen to episode one
In my mind modern testing that what we're really trying to do is number one pull up principles
not
not not
Alan has written out a definition principles are a fundamental truth of proposition that serves as a
Foundation of a system so it's not the system. It's it's essentially
the skeleton of the system
These principles are what hold it together
Yes, okay
Guide is guide me completely
So I view when I think of this I am thinking of
three
concepts
combined together and that's where the principle should be formed and that is
the testing discipline
agile itself and
the business as it is
interpreted from data
So that last one is sort of a business data thing and I haven't quite gotten the good name on it
then like I do think that the principles of modern testing need to
like the fundamental foundation whatever the
the skeleton of the skeleton is
a
t8 or a ta
OSQ
Right accelerating the achievement of shipable quality. That's that's
the job
so I think the modern principles need to flesh that out of around what we mean and
and inform the
The skeleton for the next phases. Okay tactics and such should form off of this
All right, I'm done go. Okay 20 minutes into an episode on modern testing principles. We're gonna tell you what one of them is maybe
You're so awful so new number one
Squirrel the customer is the only one suitable to judge and evaluate the quality of our software
Yes, so that's do you think that that's the only lead with I think that's number one. This is actually
Paraphragm something you and I have both said before you probably said it first
This one is obvious it does overlap the agile principles as well. I
Feel like it's still worth bringing up here because I agile is a lot about the customer
But I think the role of the modern tester is to
Magnify to help magnify shine a light on the customer
yet the
So this is these are words that were in my deck that I presented to unity
and
What I wanted to call out in particular with this so
Test is not qualified
To evaluate the quality of software only the customer is yes, right? So the the point of
As it relates to a modern testing principle
It's test has got to get off its its high horse on
Being the at I think of your slide the champions of quality
the slide he is referring to for those of you that are
Wondering why we never talk about anything in particular is I have these slides
I've used in the past having used him in a while talk about testing the champions of quality and showing these superheroes
I say you know
You're the gatekeepers at the end and then I show these people shoveling horse crap at the end of a parade
Yeah, is that what it is? I've always imagined them shoveling elephant crap. It could be all for ya
I don't see a lot of elephants and parades so
Sure, okay. Okay, then I will again if I was a good podcast coordinator I would
Promise but I will try my best to print these out
For the show notes. So any wording could change there. I don't think so. I'm gonna call it good
I'm gonna read it one more time. The customer is the only one suitable to judge and evaluate the quality of our software
Yeah, the only one
The so when I when I wrote this originally
What I struggled with is the word suitable because I really wanted to say qualified
But then having qualified and quality in the same sentence
Triggers the only lesson I remember from sophomore English. Okay, I'm gonna keep it as suitable
And then I know I've heard that I feel like I've heard this somewhere
Before you I'll dig it out sometime. Okay. All right
So the we can look at my if if I stole it from somebody it's it's quoted in my deck. Okay
Consciously it would consciously sold it. No, and so I don't if I paraphrase some I will I will attribute
If you remember no, I do it when I do it right in the deck
You don't have to remember what I'm saying
It oh is that perhaps sometime you maybe read this or saw it in a presentation
Oh god, I gotta get and then it didn't register like oh, yeah
And it kind of triggered a thing under this shit all the time and my brain is not as screwed up as yours
not quite I
That could be another episode I firmly disagree with that
I'm old but I drink a lot and helps preserve the brain cells
The the formaldehyde
Let's do another one. Oh god
the anticipation ooh
We accelerate the team by identifying and mitigating bottlenecks
Particularly if the bottleneck is testing
captures part of ATA SOQ it does
the thing I don't like about this one is that it it
Focuses the acceleration and I don't think that that's I don't think that plays out
You were right in my thinking what you brought up a few minutes ago was apparent in my thinking
I did want to support accelerate the achievement of quality
Yeah, so that's where this came from and why it is the original number one
What would be a better way to support that? I think it's important that we are
We apply theory of constraints to identify a bottlenecks to identify where the slow parts are in the system and
implement processes tools
Discussions as needed to help optimize and make those bottlenecks
Less of a bottleneck and more efficient, you know
Since you invoked the theory of constraints and you know, I'm a invoked. I'm a
Wholehearted believer in it, you know what? I'd so I like the the principle you're trying to get across I
Just don't think it's getting it across
What's a bottleneck and maybe we don't need the words a bottleneck is an inefficiency in the system
particularly one that slows
People or the process down so they actually now I think it messes with our ability to get quality software
frequently to our customers, I think I figured out what what I
What my gut is telling me is missing on this. I'm gonna test this out
Live and see right the theory of constraints essentially is all about number one. It's it's you
it's you can only go as fast as
The bottlenecks in your system in essence. Yes, but it also calls out an approach in techniques around identifying
Which bottleneck so here?
That's the thing. I think is missing. It's around
investigating identifying and I didn't and then working through the bottlenecks in
Business order
Yes, I get that because the line I use is you want to mitigate your find your most severe bottleneck and mitigate that not till it
Solve completely but tell us not the biggest bottleneck anymore
Yes, so we're missing a word in there. Yes, we're missing a I think it is just a word by by identifying
Prioritizing and mitigating bottlenecks. I like how you just phrased it where it's essentially
What we're doing is we're
constantly
reevaluating and removing
the next current bottleneck or the next biggest bottleneck we
could say
And welcome to the brainstorming session baby testing we could say we apply the theory of constraints
to
identify prioritize and mitigate
bottlenecks in this from the software system. I love that
You should type
I write slow
Make sure the word accelerate is in there and the word system is in there
What did I say? Do you remember we apply the theory of constraints?
To and then a whole bunch of other words
We apply the theory of constraints to identify prioritize and mitigate bottlenecks from the system. Yes
Okay, so that one sounds very David Debbie
the first one also sounds
Debbie
Okay, fine. So we have somewhere in the principal is we got a cover
What is?
Tests secret sauce. Well, let's actually get through all of these
Okay, and then we can figure out what's missing or if we need to add some spices to the others
So we have now for number two is we apply the theory of constraints to identify
Prioritize and mitigate bottlenecks from the system
I like it and what I had before was particularly if the bottleneck is testing which we can add a salt later or something else
Let's let's let's leave it as it is for now without that tag and see if we have to go back and add something to it
How about just a separate principle?
Testing should never be this a bottleneck
It's funny. I've said that before many times actually several times. I should say over the last few weeks is
What was the quote? I even put it in our slack our slack channel. I said QA is never the bottleneck
But really testing is never the bottleneck
Testing is the bottleneck all the time testing is never really the bottleneck
Explain if testing is the bottleneck. It means you've likely messed things up elsewhere. Oh, it's not the cause of the bottleneck, right?
Yeah, it's not the root cause of the bottleneck. Let's come back to that
let's leave this one as is and like I said if we get to the end if
We can go back and add something around testing frantically take some notes. I'll type them up later. So the next one is
Our primary focus is helping the team create higher quality software. Is that going to be redundant with the others now?
The thing I don't like about it. Is it soft it is soft and it isn't
disambiguated
from
Traditional testing I wanted to capture the coaching role we use so much in modern testing
Yet, so I picked that up and what you're really trying to say
We're testing word and it kind of piggybacks off of the bottleneck
Right if the bottleneck is that devs don't know how to test their own shit
Then it is better for the modern tester to sit down
figure out what makes it so hard for them to test their own shit a
Modern tester this is how I've kind of viewed the thinking of a modern tester none this front. Okay
it is
important to drive
code correctness upstream it is it creates a bottleneck
when
We let the code get all the way down to
Amid to low-level tester to then write the unit tests. We're slowing down the system
Modern testers role is to figure out why code correctness isn't moved upstream and to make changes to make that happen
so for example
One complaint I get from does all the time is they don't know how to test
Fine, we sit down and teach them another one is look. It's my job to write dev code. I
Need I need the ability to write these unit tests or whatever super
cheap
Right good when they starting off. They're gonna view them as a high cost
So I think I think a tester can help in terms of teaching can help in terms of reducing the friction
I get it and actually something I've been saying recently since I first wrote these which has actually been a few months
Something I've been telling people on my team
Which I think is going to tie into this is that you are not responsible for quality quality is owned by the team
however, you are responsible for the quality culture of the team and
That ties in a lot to what you're saying because I'm gonna babble some words out here
Then we'll figure out what they're what the right principle is
Okay
is that I do count on the modern testers on my team or the soon-to-be modern testers as the as they grow and mature to
Figure out what?
Like what's the testing we should be doing and where should happen in the cycle?
Which is a little bit of a paraphrase what you just said
Yeah, if there's better unit tests need to be done
They're going to dive in and help make that happen whether it's coaching or just identifying where missing tests are
identifying
What are the integration? What are the what are the?
Tests that we may be missing around maybe there's some stress or load tests or some performance testing looking at the what I call
The all aspects of quality
Maybe one thing though and and I don't disagree with what you're saying
But maybe this is one thing that we need to explicitly call out
Software quality and code correctness are different things
That's while true. It's not really a principle. I know no, I don't know where to integrate it in but the
I'm okay with with software
quality
That test being accountable for software quality. I am NOT okay with tests being accountable for code
correctness and
What I think somewhere in here is we should say
Something up to the effect of part of our job is to push code correctness
upstream
Right two years from now. I don't I I would very much not like to see
your team at unity
You know writing test cases to make sure the dev didn't introduce a bug
Right. Dev should be focused on that
So this perhaps needs a tag but even a better phrase pulled out what I just said that I liked for changing from
Our primary focus is helping the team create higher quality software. Let's get rid of that but
This may need a tag like I said, but what if I just said what I said before
We are responsible for the quality culture of our team. I like that and just leave it at that
Could we have a tag?
We are responsible for the quality culture of our team
Hyphen comma semi-colon including
coaching
Blah and blah the thing I still think is missing from this and I think this is an important principle
Because when you just say software quality quality as you know, just like the word test is ambiguous
No, but that's in the old one you lost me. I said we are responsible for the quality culture of our team
I did not say software quality
Software quality was in the old one the old ambiguous one. Okay, we are responsible for the quality culture of our team
I guess the old so others be more explicit
Something in here needs to state in a way that's helpful that we we hold some accountability
for
teaching
Others how to fix their code correctness issues
But we are not the safety net
Something in here needs to guide people to realize
That a modern tester is no longer the safety net for code correctness issues
Yes, and I and I think we add that as a separate that I have an idea here
Okay. How about this for this principle?
We are responsible for the quality culture of our team and are accountable for helping and coaching the team in this regard
Next principle added and perhaps in this order. Maybe maybe it goes first
In between those two is just straight out. We are not the safety net for software quality
That can be given the definition of principle. It's viable to leave that there or to have that as a principle
I love that if you replace the word quality with correctness
That is done. All right. I'm feeling good. We are halfway done
With the principles and we'll read them out. I'll read them out in order as
When we're done on this list, what did we do one through four one through three?
Dude, we did three then one and two now we're doing four. All right number four
We use data to deeply understand customer usage and customer pain
Yes, good with that one. I I am okay
number five booyah
Continuous learning and adaptation both as an individual and a team is critical for success
And maybe this falls into that vague category a bit. So let me talk about what I was trying to capture as a modern tester. I'm
Deeply care about the retrospective. I am probably it's this could be some my personal bias
I think that learning the learning organization is so important for software quality
now it's trying to capture the modern tester role in that process and also the fact that as
Specializing generalists we need to constantly be learning new things to be successful. So that's what I was trying to capture
I don't think I quite got it, right?
So this is what I need some help. What do you think?
So I figured out what you're trying to do there and I completely agree
Continuous learning is important
however in my sense
Like what I would love to see the principles tie out
Or when when you look at the whole set it helps to clarify
What is the ROI of a modern tester into the business? Why do you hire these people?
Right because that's been a long-standing problem in in the test community
Test doesn't even know what the health test does
Now continuous learning
It's not really a
It's not a ends. It's a means
Right it is but adaptation in my mind is an ends and we've talked about this
multiple times
So if we're focused on accelerating we can't accelerate
way and and have a you know a year in between the
The cadence points where we get any sort of feedback from the customer whether it be verbal or as we stated in the prior principle
via data, I do think that is
critical and that is
So here's what I'm thinking in my head something along the lines that says
We will move forward with a goal and a plan
That what I'm gonna write or what I'm gonna say is is gonna be too verby
But the idea is we move forward with a goal and a plan
But we're constantly paranoid that it's wrong
We test it and adapt
There's something there and it reminds me a couple things
I want to bring up one is I use this phrase a lot in my current job is make sure people have the I say
Some people do or do not have what I call the appropriate level of paranoia. So that reminded me of that but
test
traditionally has been a cost center people look at it as a cost there was a book that came out it I
Don't want to trash on it because maybe some of the listeners contributed to it
But it was called how just the title I want to talk about how to reduce the cost of software testing
What I see as a modern tester is it's not a cost a modern tester is a force multiplier a modern tester
You can often tie dollar signs to their contributions which we only could apply negative dollar signs to testers
So I don't know if I want to capture some of that
But that thought came out in my head to me what I'm trying to communicate. I thought it might that's why I babble
So say it again. It's Kaizen
K-a-i-z. I know Kaizen is yeah, and and I'm trying to find the the
interpretation
Believe someone once shared with me
Wikipedia is not validating this but I believe once someone once shared with me that Kaizen was literally
translated as
llama lines of being chased by a tiger
That the that you're you're trying to improve but there is a sense of urgency
around it so
Wikipedia just says it's the word for improvement
but
The way it was once described to me was more around there's a sense of urgency around it
The the other aspect that you were just talking about as it relates to adaptation
And as it relates to a cost center and it occurs to me
This could combine with what you've listed first for number six
modern testing strives to be an ROI Center not a cost center
So how do we continuously adapt to remove the wasteful practices from our system?
It is a wasteful practice to test
The last month before we ship. Yes, it is a wasteful practice to have a bug database
These are all wasteful
practices that that
encourage
manual human
philosophical interaction
Whereas in the modern world you don't need this
You don't have to be theoretical you can ship you can get your data from your back-end database and you can
Hypothesis or do hypothesis testing and prove or disprove which approach is better
That is way too verbi for a principle. It is
how about something like
we
Apply we something about
We apply continuous improvement
We use continuous improvement. What's the right verb there?
We use continuous improvement
I did a couple blog posts last year after based on my time in teams not not as
Anger inducing as my last one about teams, but talked about two problems that team had
the fallacy of now customers have to have my feature now and
Failure to launch meaning well, I got to get it perfect before they get it
I was too common in those two principles in a team culture is
just death
Yes, so what I have now and it has to be perfect
So with a and and you have two different either we want to stop both of those right we want to
One
They don't maybe they don't need to have it right now and we need to be able to identify when that's not the when that's
The case also we also need to identify with something. We have to get feedback on this. It's useless
Because of a previous principle for us to just iterate on this forever without getting customer feedback
So there's something about finding that balance
maybe
This you triggering a thought of this speech. I give my team and that is
the
single most precious resources I
Am worried about it's calendar time
then engineering time I
cannot scale calendaring time and I can only scale engineering time to a degree and
Nothing
This is what I want this principle to sort of call out because nothing pisses me off more
Where I have one of my superstars heads down on a project for three months
We ship it and we realize no one cares
particularly when I have a backlog of
A hundred things that I could have done instead can I throw another one? I am yeah
Doesn't use adaptation, but let's try this
Continuously as this lot. This is a lot like the second one accelerating the three of constraints, but a little different
Continuously solve problems for the team enabling them to optimize calendar time closer or farther away little of both I
Think it's net farther away. I like calendar time in there
Yeah, I think what we have here is better better
Yeah, the thing I'm trying to I'm trying to do an emotional plea here really honestly
Does this principle need to be I am the quality guy?
My customers in pain
Their pain is continuously moving. How do we adapt to solve the customers pain?
That brings in the desperation and the pain part, but there's an important aspect here and that is
Test shouldn't just be focusing on preventing customer pain instead of just figuring out. How do we make their pain go away?
How do we figure how do we apply our talents to make the customer happy?
What if I said this and just give me the the farther away farther away or closer?
Ensure that the team adapts and optimizes in order to solve customer pain in order to solve customer pain
Something there should be a time constraint in there in order to I like that
Better so that's closer. I don't like the ensures the team part because then that it sounds like a guy in an ivory tower
You guys will
adapt
What if I say embrace continuous improvement and help the team adapt and optimize in order to solve customer pain?
Yeah, I think let's go on to six or the next one and then I think we'll we'll do another round offline
Because I want to now see what all of these what the whole set looks okay
I'm gonna leave it as the original one. I wrote with my notes here and number six is
We strive to reduce or eliminate the need for a dedicated testing role on our teams by increasing testing abilities and know-how across the team
Yes, I think I'm okay with that one as is yeah, it's too long because really what you're saying. It's not that long
I think it's shorter than any of the agile principles
What am I saying? How would you say you're saying in essence what we've said on the podcast?
It
We're here to eliminate bottlenecks a
Testing specialist is a bottleneck a specialist is a bottleneck in general. Yes
testing is an activity that
Can be taught and be incorporated into a specializing generalist system. That's essentially what you're trying to say. Absolutely
I like the shock value around
Testing specialists are a bottleneck
That's this that's what this is saying that is what you're saying
But I can't just that that as I've shocked value doesn't explain the principle behind it. It's a it's a statement
No, yeah, it's it's that by itself is only useful when it's combined with the prior. We hate bottlenecks
All right. We'll go with that. Let me read them off in order
Okay, and then we'll have a little bit of a recap on that and then I think we'll be pretty close
We may be tweaking that one for a while. So
There's one other thing that's I think not
Called out. What's that? So the thing that I am finding more and more
validated by external content is that test is shifting to be much more focused on
Business KPIs then code KPIs. That's not a principle, but I think we're missing something. I'm not now
I think that's captured here. Okay, I think
The customer is the business and that may be coming because you're doing a lot of stuff with business KPIs. So that may be
Brent influence over modern testing influence
That's fine. Let me read these in order in the new order
Number one the customer is the only one suitable to judge and evaluate the quality of our software
Yes, number two. We apply the theory of constraints to identify prioritize and mitigate bottlenecks from the system
Number three we are responsible for the quality culture of our team and are accountable for helping and coaching the team in this regard
Number four we are not the safety net or the modern tester is not the safety net for software correctness
We use data number five now we use data to deeply understand customer usage and customer pain
number six
Currently to be changed
continuous learning and an adaptation both as an individual and a team is critical for success and
then number seven for episode 77
we strive to reduce or eliminate the need for a dedicated for a
Dedicated testing specialist on our team by increasing testing abilities and know-how across the team. I think that's good
I think those aren't bad. Yeah, it's what's triggered when you said that last one or the number six again
What triggered this time around?
When I go and help when I am doing doing the agile coach thing and I'm walking people through how to think about agile
Okay, I
Bring up
It's about adaption not iteration. Yes, right?
But that's an agile thing. It is an agile thing
But what's the difference between adaption and?
iteration
constant learning
That's the implementation. It's about changing the goal
Iteration you don't need to change the goal you just
Iterate correct adaption is your your changing the direction of the system. Yes, of course
So the continuous learning and and all of that right if you combine these things
What is our role in the system is to adapt the system towards a more positive customer goal?
continuously and then when you say that I realize that that principle is
very much
Probably a lines with one or more of the agile principles exactly. So it's not unique to modern testing
It isn't
but
That's true for several things. We've listed here not entirely not entirely constrained that one
Specialists no, no, I I disagree
Wholeheartedly the rest of these are all about modern testing. All right
The fact that they do it within an agile mindset is one thing but they're all about modern testing
These are things that most testers on agile teams won't say all
But I'm gonna say many I'll say most the other six now are things that most testers on agile teams are
Not doing it's the difference between agile testing and modern testing and it is a it's a gradual change
It isn't like you're in one school or the other
But if you're on an agile team and you're doing it right and you're not doing fragile continuous learning and adaptation
a part of what you do, but the other things we mentioned are things that are
Slightly different to most
testers working on agile teams so they do specify some difference between the agile tester and the modern tester and
So I'm thinking my thinking is is when I print these out. I'm going to remove that one and
With the one we added about the safety net we'll be back to say and then see how it hurts and see how it hurts
That's what I'm gonna work with I feel good about these I'm going to print these I'm going to vet them again with the test bash crowd and
Then because I feel much better about these and then we'll at that point all that's left is maybe is a little bit of tweaking
Which we can do
Again based on feedback. We the principles are great because like everything else in agile
they are
fallible and they will be
Adjusted as needed as we learn more information about our customers
That's the one thing that once we publish these things if this if this ends up
being a thing
one thing I want us to do that the agile manifesto did not do is continuously iterate it as
Think flaws are discovered. Absolutely. I cannot work any other way. I am incapable of doing anything perfectly
I recognize that and embrace that so I figure I will just throw stuff out as it's close as we did today
It gets better which it did today and it will continue to improve as we get feedback from smarter people than you and especially me
It just occurred to me
We could use the principles of modern testing to test the principles of modern testing. This is like inception
No, we could we could shoot this out to to the three
Then we can evaluate as they are
Who's the customer of these principles?
We have a customer. Yeah these principles the three is a is a
good set of them
So what I would suggest as we wrap up here is I'm going to write these out in the blog post
They'll be a test bash. I encourage lots and lots of feedback via email the slack channel Twitter or whatever and
We'll take that and
iterate and learn
Okay. All right
Once again, I'm still Alan and I am Brent. All right. We'll see you next time on a be