New Year everybody I'm Alan. No you're not. You're Donny. I'm not happy. I'm not happy or I'm not Alan. You're not Alan.
Who are you. I am Brent and welcome to the A B testing podcast. So what's the deal with you going by your real first name all of a
sudden. You didn't you didn't read my follow up tweet. I changed my name on Twitter to Don Page. Yes. My middle name is Alan.
I'm aware of this. My first name is Donald. Yes. My dad is Donald Laverne Page. Oh so you're not a junior. I'm not a junior because that
Laverne name was not going any farther in the family. But dad passed away last week. Oh so it's an honor. It's my mini tribute. I'm
going to be Don Page for a while on Twitter. I'm sorry to hear you dad passed away. You're remarkably sparky today given that.
Well it was sort of mixed feeling sort of thing because he was his quality of life was not good the last few years. For anyone observing it was sort of a
ticking time bomb. Probably not the best analogy. There's both. There's definitely mixed emotions there. Yeah. So one thing I realized and I
thought we'd do one thing I know we haven't done enough is take just a minute at the beginning of the episodes and talk about what A.B. testing is for any new
listeners. So Brent what is the A.B. testing podcast about the A.B. testing podcast is about being a voice for change around how software
quality is can be or should be delivered in the current time. We're going to we're going to work on that. We're going to come up with maybe a little a
little paragraph maybe to talk about what we do. But but maybe I would add another twist on that and say that we are a software testing
podcast for everyone. Meaning that we're not necessarily a podcast for testers although we realize it's a chunk of our audience. We believe
that software testing is an activity that should be done by all members of the engineering team. Yeah I would I guess I would phrase it just
slightly different but a software quality podcast for everyone. Definitely a software quality podcast. And we also talk about this thing that we
call modern testing and we'll talk a little bit more about that later in the episode according to the the Sharpie marks on the whiteboard.
It's not Sharpie marks dry erase pen marks on the whiteboard. Yes yes. And we often refer to our three listeners if you are listening you are one of our three
listeners. So thank you again for listening. I gave one of my employees a sticker last week and then they asked me later what is one of the three
mean I had to explain it. I feel bad. So we should talk about our three listeners. You are one of them. You are one of the three. Thank you very
much for listening. Tell your friends. They will also be one of the three. No matter how many you tell. It's like a TARDIS math of one of the three. Yes. I think it's it
started. I mean it started off on episode number one which as an aside I've started re-listening to all the episodes because I'm slowly but surely actually
titling. And I told you as one of my employees at work I mentioned this in our last podcast which was ages ago. Yeah. He was listening to our podcast. He
wanted to start from the beginning and I said no don't start. You can if you want. I think starting from the beginning. I like it starting from the beginning
because you can absolutely see you can see our growth very rapidly. Yeah. In lots of things in our in our thoughts our ideas our passion even on the technical side the
earlier recordings just sound kind of like crap compared to what we have today. I got a compliment on the sound quality. I've gotten gotten several over the over the last few years but I got a
compliment recently on the sound quality of our podcast so. Yay us slash me. Yes you've done it. You've done a great job on harassing me on the additional noises as well as we
got we got new mixer gear compared to where we started with and we've learned how very quickly how to not make it do that. Yeah. Except for one situation.
I'm not certain we've yet mastered the art of remote guests. Oh oh oh oh. Now your comment has just turned into the bullet point up there on from the Kanban board backlog. However
I want to refer to it. Some plans for the podcast in twenty eighteen. Brent was a little concerned this morning little distraught because he had saw a tweet he had seen a tweet from me recently where I said big plans and I'm not quoting exactly because I don't remember what I said five minutes ago let alone a few weeks ago but big plans for the A.B. testing podcast in twenty eighteen. Stay tuned. Yes. Lots and lots and lots of big. We have huge plans. Well we have a big plan.
We have some plans. Couple things I want to do and these I guess timing wise I could have brought up in the last podcast of twenty seventeen but there's that time little time off thinking about things couple things I want to do one is I want to have new I want to have some guests and I took a I took a chunk of time to do some research. Buy a little more equipment. Nice. Because I like my stuff.
I would like to try some remote guests this year not I don't want to be a guest every episode sort of podcast but I would like to do a guest once in a while and I think we may maybe experiment with one of the three as a guest at some point sure. Just so I can get used to setting up the equipment make sure I get all the cables put in together because I want to do I have high standards for sound quality.
So I want to make sure that we get a good solid recording from the other end and there are many many many ways to do that but I think I have a way that'll make it sound good and be easy on the other end. Sure. I mean I think you so we've also overloaded one of the three if you like what you hear and you want to hear additional content you can sign up to join our slack channel one to three.
That's slack dot com and on there there are several other podcast publishers that that are listeners and I've joined the slack channel and it's a very interesting set of conversations on the topic but around the tech and I think it would absolutely make sense to enlist a couple of those guys who who actually know how to do the remote.
There are a bunch of different ways when I did the the testers island disk recording with Neil stud for Ministry of test last month we use then cast which we tried to do with the Hans Buell the episode but it just never worked on his end.
I think also in looking at the Zencaster audio they do a whole bunch of compression that I don't like so I don't like the sound quality of Zencaster it's a while it's very convenient platform if it works.
It sounds like I and the test or island tester island this you can tell that he's talking to somebody remotely it has it has sort of that the other person's on the phone type sound to it and the only other way to get rid of that so I need to you need to find the compromise between internet compressed audio quality and ease of use the best sound quality is if someone on the other end has a set up exactly the same sound quality.
And then he has a set up exactly like ours plugs all this crap in records a straight raw wave file to their desk and then sends me that wave file which I can then merge into our end that's going to sound like we're in the same room to me that's not convenient it's massively inconvenient for the folks on the other end if I was if our moat guest was a a podcast with a set up like this sure I'd ask him to do that we still need to take care of even in that situation though.
Think of the fact that they're talking we need to be able to hear what they're saying you'd be able to integrate the stream so right so it sounds like a conversation yes yeah so what we'll do is I bought some equipment that can let me patch in a pretty high quality well a very high quality recording through Skype so still be Skype compressed audio but I can record that directly into the mixer will have more than one.
And then I'd like to have some guests in on the show at a not a consistent but a more frequent basis I really liked when we had Steve Rowan we've only had two different guests on the show we had Steve row twice.
And then Hans Buell all the ones which. Honestly wasn't wasn't the greatest first foray into a remote no recording. I like of course the people are around the red and belvy area love to have you on the show let us know. But I think we'll give it a shot.
And see what happens that's plan number one for. Twenty eighteen. What were my other plans are I got I barely got the test cap that the cafe press store out in time. Brent didn't bring his coffee mug today but that's up. Oh yeah no it's up in my office that's cool that's cool yeah. We have a lot of questions for you.
But anyway what what we say while the three is a significantly large quantity of three I would like to get it'd be fun to get some more listeners this year I want to see what we can do to do this.
Actually I never really cared before make a little bit of a goal. See if we can get more regular downloads. We have finally have enough reviews on iTunes. Until you have a certain number they won't actually show your your star rating or any comments. But we have I think we now have an official review of the three.
We have a lot of reviews on iTunes. Until you have a certain number they won't actually show your your your star rating or any comments. But we have I think we now have an official iTunes rating which I believe is five stars which is great.
That shocked. A little confirmation bias there with the crew thanks for doing that. What else did I have in plan the rest will come out. I'm sure there are more. I don't think getting more listeners is is a is a goal from me per se.
The reason I'm going to interrupt the reason it's a goal for me is because and we'll talk about this throughout the show I don't want to dive deep into modern testing topic now but modern testing is kind of starting at least in my circles to become a thing.
And I think getting this voice out there is and getting more people to understand what we mean by modern testing I think is beneficial for the industry. So that's that's the reason why I like more.
I was I was about to sail on those lines like just the act of getting more listeners not not necessarily a goal but I definitely see signs that the industry is beginning to sort of similar changes that we've already gone through.
And I think we can help people get get through the change or have an idea of what to do next or to reduce some fear and uncertainty.
Yeah.
Get it. It's it's going to sound vain even if I say I want more listeners not for vanity but as a service still vain. Yeah.
I want to dive deep much more deeply into modern testing but before I forget practice test has recently released their survey for the 2018 state of testing.
It's quick it takes 10 minutes. Did you do it. I did it. I did not. And as as you know and Joel puts on the website I was one of the question reviewers.
We both were. Yep. And as a data scientist we help review the questions. You and I haven't talked about it but but I helped him to modify some of the questions modify the answers.
There was a perspective that I didn't like in terms of an overarching theme around questions.
I'll just say like a one arch overarching theme around the questions I did not like was it was it was talking about testing the community not testing the activity.
And so he and I had a back and forth. But as in the next phase is once the survey is done we're going to be part of the the review team to look at the results and help to analyze.
And I started going through the question because I wanted to see what the final product was. But then I'm like am I biasing the results. So I didn't submit because I have no idea how many people are in there.
And the first thing is like job title fairly certain that I'd be the only one that would put data scientists. Right. So I it raised the back of my neck hairs and so I didn't submit.
As a statistician it should because first of all go fill it out. I think not all of you are as unique of a little snowflake as Brent. What I do in my job is as a modern tester is much is different than probably much of the rest of the community as well.
But I do find it this is the only survey per year that I do fill out. I think a lot of them have sort of leading questions and they kind of know the answers they're looking for before they start.
So I'm glad you're involved on the analysis end is to see if there will be any huge insights. We may see some trends which will be interesting. Well so you've and that's what I want. I would want to get a lot of data and a lot of input on this.
So maybe there's something interesting that will come out of that. Yeah I think it'd be good listeners if you could go take the survey that's fantastic. I presume you'll put a link to it in. I will try to remember. Yeah. In addition to that ask your friends to do so as well because if we there's a there's a selection bias concern. Right. If all of our listeners go and do this then they could publicly announce a brand new trend which has been a big trend.
Which has to do with the fact that it's a selection bias and often that's true in Internet polls and Twitter and it gets the people the people who are engaged in Twitter people who are engaged in Reddit or the people are engaged in any Internet community.
They're already they're they're learners people seeking knowledge. Yep. And that crowd will give you a different answer than the community overall. So if you can involve some other people who maybe aren't as engaged they could go take the survey. Send it out to your team at work. Maybe you're the only one who gets out on the Internet and learns about testing or thinks about testing other than a nine to five job. So it would be good to get their feedback as well.
There's already some sort of a selection bias in the process as well. Right. Much like I would expect people with the title of data scientist to be a rarity on the results I'm I would expect given how they advertise the poll sort of people who grew up as a traditional developer if they're in a combined or unified engineering world they're probably not.
I'm guessing they're going to be underrepresented in this poll. Yeah. I will put the link on the web page those you really get this over RSS feed just search on practice test data testing survey and I'm sure it will show up or you can hit me on Twitter. Alan Page and a L A N P A G E and I will point you in the right direction. So I know some people just get the this downloads they don't look at the show notes and I want to make sure they find it. Yep.
So that happened. We're going to go whole random all over the place. I haven't seen like in a month. It's been a month more than a month more than a month. So while since we last recorded. So I got something for you. You can open the steps in a box international priority mail. I am opening the box. It says customs declaration. So this was shipped from someplace else. Yeah. It came from a very poor country known as England.
Sorry. Oh I sorry British listeners. Oh very cool. So I have in my hand the Ministry of Testing charity calendar and A B testing. And one thing is this is a all agreed the bottom part all proceeds. Oh I'll proceeds go to the nays cancer fun which I think is a great cause. So we at A B testing bot calendars.
And if you already have a calendar and you flip through to April January February keep going. Don't start the pictures too long bread. Yeah he gave a little bit too long into February. Yeah. Everywhere is a little disturbing. And when you get to April. There we go. There's a little orange A B testing promo. I'm expecting a surge of listeners in April when that comes up. Yeah. And you know why I chose April for our month. No. That will be all. That's our anniversary.
That will be our four year anniversary of A B testing. So we'll bring it up again then if I remember because I hope that we have some new listeners. Yeah. But I expect to have some in April as well. We should have bought the whole April. Yeah I like this. This is fantastic. So great idea great cause. And I hope you have your own calendar already. Otherwise how would you know what day it is. That for me it's easy.
It's easy. Your calendar tells you every day is Monday. I had a great conversation someone on my team who disbelieves in jet lag. This is what you believe in it. Yeah. It's all part of a airline conspiracy wherever you get. That's what time it is. Doesn't matter that meeting times change because those times don't matter. Just go to the meetings when Google Calendar tells you it's time to go. OK. I like it. I like it. I like it. I don't get the disbelief. And I mean.
Biorhythms and stuff. Yeah. Let me talk about an event I just did some events coming up. Angry weasel Allen out in the public earlier this month. It almost seems like that should have a theme song. Weasel weasel. Where is the. Something like that. The wheels are spinning. And the where is the weasel segment. Yeah. Where in the world is the weasel segment? Yeah.
Where in the world is the weasel? All kinds of ways this could go. Yeah. Recently flash earlier this month. Well it's been so long. I have so much to catch you up on. I gave a talk at a local QA SIG where I gave an early version of a talk that I'll be giving it. Test Bash in Brighton in March. Plug plug plug. On the adventures of a modern tester. I'm actually really excited about this talk. Me too. And I love when I
have a chance. I'm going to do a keynote when I have a chance to do. It's not even a dry run because I can't give the same talk twice. But it forces me to kind of organize my thoughts. And I get a little bit of reaction. I figure out what works what doesn't work. For a dry run though I was pretty happy. There will be some changes. And some and some streamlining. But I'm pretty happy with how it came across. But anyway. So what you're going to say then I'll give you some more. Well so you. So Allen and I. Allen started prethinking this.
He then floated it past me. I started contributing to it due to. I'm very interrupt driven at the moment due to a certain set of events happening to my family. But I think I think there's a lot of interesting discussion there. I think it might even be worthwhile.
You and I setting up say an hour to just specifically sit in a room and knock it out. Because I think there's a couple of things that you should tweak. I think there's a couple of things. I did show the slide deck with you didn't I. You did. He did. And so I think you've put enough of a skeleton for us to very effectively brainstorm and solidify it very quickly. And I think we should do that. We could do it as a podcast.
The visual people didn't see the visual part but it may be interesting. You think about doesn't have to be. Sure simultaneous me standing up and writing notes on whiteboards. I don't think he's going to play very well on the podcast. But hey. You know probably worse. You're probably right. You're probably right. Yep.
So anyway I gave the talk and I was pretty happy with it and I realized I've come to a point in my crotch the old age in my career was as a place where I want to be where when I say some of the things that are happening in modern testing and I talk about the fact that I am actively working on eliminating the need for my role.
I get a good mixed reaction. I'm right in that sweet spot where I get some head nods. Yeah that's where it's going. And some people going shut the hell up. Yeah. Traitor. What are you talking about. And I get a lot of people describe this. I see what you're saying but I'm a special snowflake. And I that kind of tells me and I've equated this a lot to the diffusion of innovation curve that made.
Popular in crossing the chasm and I believe that modern testing is in that in that far left of innovation ready to and we see to cross that chasm into early adopters. There is man that just reminds me. So there's a book I ordered at the moment. I have no idea where it is. I ordered it in December. But Al Shalloway as you know is a buddy of mine who's the CEO of the company.
Net objectives although the acquaintance maybe because he's no longer lives in Green Lake. He moved to California and I got no advance notice. So I don't know. Maybe buddy is too strong a word. Anyway we're not in the far left. We're in the medium left because the far left people are are those who are inventing ideas out of the blue.
We're not talking about things that that aren't well right and true. I don't know. We're not in the super far left but I don't think we've crossed the chasm where there's enough. I don't know that there's enough people doing what we call modern testing. Now.
To be in that in that part of the curve. I. Here's how I kind of. So we've talked about Gladwell. I think. Surely we've talked about glad. Well I'm sure. And the tipping point. Here's what I actually think.
We realize.
That what we're.
Aspousing.
Is super valuable. We.
We realize that it is actually in tried and true but it is it's the minority experience for people in the industry today.
And I think we're just trying to.
Pull people towards the tipping point.
Because once it once this hits the tipping point.
It will have its own momentum.
And once it hits that point I think you and I will be done with the topic because I think we have a preference.
To just slightly lead from the front but not way out into the you know crazy talk front.
Yeah sometimes crazy talk.
No but I think actually what you're saying is there's a.
That you're right it's a sweet spot because when you make this statement.
Half of the room goes yeah that's absolutely we're going the other half goes crazy talk.
So the way I tell this story I don't want to give away too much but the more I reflect on how we got here I realize it's.
This inevitable set of events.
So we watched.
Microsoft.
And Yahoo did the same thing but we watched firsthand Microsoft.
Just.
Basically shove teams together and say OK now you're one team figure it out.
And we watch that fail more often much more often than it succeeded.
Yep.
And then when I joined team but no one actually reverse direction.
Right so it wasn't a smooth landing no it wasn't what we talk about modern testing a lot is the transition to this world to prepare you to move that direction when I joined teams.
They hired me as they were already combined but they wanted someone to help.
Supervise the quality and make sure people that's a bad way to put up it to be the quality guy and help them learn the test better that kind of worked but it was a little bit of swimming upstream because there are already a lot of.
Bad habits in place what I'm doing at unity which I.
In Sunday in hindsight I'm going to realize there's even better way to do this but we have.
A quality team a test team and I would like to slowly and in the process of slowly merging that team.
First the leads into their respective development organizations but then the individuals as.
I that quality community become self sustaining and that's actually happening but the.
The mantra I share with them is there's this is the right direction there's no hurry let's take our time and do it right.
And do it right and they get that that's fantastic and it's really and the you would have you would have held back a tear I met with all my leads in Montreal last week and we're talking about.
We did the people discussion which was my best people discussion in like 15 years of people discussions it was do is the right level of depth and didn't drag on but towards the end we're talking about you know directions of a bomb and a lot of these topics that come up and.
One of the least my newest the newest lead on the team looked up with this big doe eyes and talk about what I talked about everything I wanted to do goes pause goes I just I wanted you modern testing.
I wasn't certain where you were going to go with that right yeah.
I'm sitting back and actually paying attention to see what happens.
What happens to hear about what happens to unity with respect to the data stuff.
Yes this is I think 2018 is going to be the unity year of data I'm saying that right.
I forget her name but one year leads who asked me a ton of questions I'm like okay she's she's pushing back but she's pushing back because because of a thoughtfulness.
And I'm like yeah if I were Alan I would be investing more effort on the data space with that one.
Was one of my leads or somebody on the team.
So many leads okay but I know them I don't have one female lead so okay hey there hello shout out that one.
I do try and give him some sense of privacy not call him out by name but many of them listen to the show so so there and this particular lead says she listens to the show when she needs to fall asleep so.
Make sense yeah.
So she probably hasn't made it this far that's probably how we got the five star rating.
So better one of the things I want to dive into him this time but one of the things that came out of my thought about the adventures of a modern tester were the principles of modern testing.
And still a work in progress and we should probably once you and I hash them out.
That's what I want to talk about yeah.
Is is they're not quite right there a work in progress I shared them briefly didn't spend a lot of time on the slide but kept them in the slide deck that I shared.
The last one which talks about the last principle that in my current list which talks about the goal of reducing reducing or eliminating the need for test specific roles.
Yeah and ice that's the one I believe in the most in the right direction to go to and then.
that's what one of the things where I share that people go yep makes sense if you do and a lot go yeah the rest but not that one no that's that's just dumb and I think that's the right place to be.
That that'll be fun to work through because part of me goes no I like that sentence because sort of got a Whitaker S shock value the to sort of wake people up and that's one of the things I think that's actually valuable.
Is to listen to our show is is when we make a statement and we can back it up with the experiences and details that sort of wake people up to take action.
This is the thing that I've the number one thing I've observed from from the various other times we've gone through this transition like Microsoft it is a whole.
But not every team did it at the same time and I happen to be in three different teams I had during that period I helped three different teams.
Go through it you know that the what is the physical law an object emotion wants to stay in motion and object that that's not doesn't and if you can wake up the people like going look here's the deal.
Yes you can make that decision now but there is a decision coming and you need to understand that failing to make a decision is a decision.
Right so you can even either decide your own destiny or you can let destiny decided for you cool.
You know it short story yeah we should hash that out sometime before March I will be going to Brighton in March to give the matured.
Version of that talk but it was nice to get some feedback I feel like I'm in the right direction I feel like I have a great start on.
Not that it was not that the QA sick talk wasn't good I got tons of positive feedback which is exciting for me because I know I can polish and mature and really nail something.
What do you think very very interesting and engaging for the test bash crowd in Brighton what was the biggest negative but constructive feedback.
I think I mean nothing in particular about modern testing I wanted to show the principles but I knew there were work in progress didn't spend a bunch of time on it so I did that thing that I don't like in presentations where you can show a slide so you can read this later and went on little things like that was more of the more about the presentation than the content.
Okay now I mean I like I like your idea around presenting that there is sort of a trial.
Yeah and I reflect back on the key notes that I've done that have gone the best they almost in fact they all had a trial run somewhere with it with a talk that eventually matured into.
Can't give the same talk twice I will change probably half the slides but the content is right the stories not quite right.
I don't like just presenting slides slides slides slides slides I like to try and tell a story and make it all kind of linked together I had parts of that.
But I saw wasn't until I gave the talk I realized okay I can do this here and this here just kind of make it a little better story just like it's just like editing a book you write a draft.
And this is pretty good you go back and editing go okay this is a lot better.
I have a book where I'm about maybe two chapters in the thing is my ADHD also applies to my book reading.
I go new shiny book and I get it my start reading like new shiny book and then I get it and I start reading and so I.
Darted.
I don't know 10 books right now.
But this one is around how the process in the model for how to do the Ted talks.
Oh yeah and if you don't have that you're welcome to borrow the book because it's all about telling a story.
And.
I think you're right that's exactly what we're trying to do here.
I think the we're trying to we're trying to educate.
Show that there's light at the end of the tunnel it's not doom give a give a.
I think we're trying to reduce fear uncertainty and doubt.
Around the direction that test is inevitably going and the way a software quality is inevitably going.
Yeah.
All right.
What do you want to do.
So we're still believe it or not on where in the world is the weasel.
Oh.
We're in.
I'm going to work on that.
I'm off to.
I'm off to London next week to hang out and do some more meetings for unity back in the town.
Ski vacation in fab not interesting to the listeners March we talked about.
Oh in February before I go on my ski vacation I am giving a webinar for a ST on the use and abuse of test automation.
Oh I should talk about test automation I have more stories to tell there.
It's a talk I gave before I of course I can't get the same talk twice so I'm modifying it.
But I will try and post a link in the notes but you can just search follow me on Twitter you'll see me post it.
But I will also try and put a link on anger weasel dot Tom anger weasel dot com wack A B testing that is coming up.
I wrote slight tangent here after all my rants about UI automation and not totally against it.
We should be very careful when you do it.
You know what I did yesterday for a couple hours.
I wrote some UI automation.
It's not.
It's not off limits.
It's not hip hop grateful because you've you've you and I have both stated over and over again that the default should be no UI automation.
But if you're going to do you are automation you put an expert on it.
It was fun and I learned a new framework called test cafe.
I was going to write the test in protractor which I'm slightly familiar with.
But as I did it I realized there's got to be a better way and I got a little frustrated and I use this framework called test cafe which I'm fairly impressed with.
It's a little newer not as many examples on the Internet to draw from but I was able to get done what I wanted to get done.
So basically the reason I'm doing it is we have many many many websites but one of our websites has a lot of testing not a lot of UI automation not a lot of end to end tests.
So I thought I bootstrapped some stuff.
See if I see what framework is best basically do some some investigative exploratory work for the team.
I'll get that bootstrapped up with a few sample tests capture sort of the men's set of end to end tests which is actually a very small number of tests and let them take it from there.
But I've been very very happy and excited with what I was able to do just in a couple hours yesterday.
Pretty excited as as an aside I'm becoming a Java expert.
Oh really.
Yeah.
So my that's the only reason I worked on that stupid thing to make Android app from a Windows phone so I can spend some time learning Java and Linux.
So my my middle son is is in AP computer science and in high school and he's going step by step and it's fun.
So when I when he has a problem I try to sit down and without looking at the help file see if I can guess what the right classes are or the right construct because it's very much I'm finding Java to be very much sort of a a syntactically sort of a cross between C sharp and C.
I'm very pleased when I go well I think it's going to be this and then I hit compile and like ah it was that you know what when I first learned C sharp the vert when C sharp first came out I didn't learn it I used it for a while but I also found that the method and class names were very intuitive.
Like I type what I thought it would be and that was the right one this is before auto complete.
Yeah there's some things there's some things I was like just last weekend I was trying to teach my son around refactor I was able to use this speech that the best developers don't write code they delete it.
Yes you said that originally I don't know okay not me and he had some crappy copy paste code and this copy paste code it took a member variable.
There were three member variables and this copy paste code was doing a validation check of hey.
Was what the user entered valid and if so then it would set the member variable and it was the same thing over and over again I'm like oh no you need to make this into its own function.
And then I'm like okay now he's got this own function now we need to pass these member variables by ref Java doesn't have by ref and I'm like all right yeah I'm never using never using Java for any of real project just by that I'm like what the hell how do you not have a by ref anyway.
Where were we did we finish up with where in the world is Alan.
I don't know oh no we didn't so you can sing the weasel song again.
No still working on it I still work it on that all right where we live off so webinar webinar on automation February 13th will do a link off to Brighton in March I am like in twenty seventeen I did one conference.
Twenty sixteen I think was one conference as well so I am kicking off the year strong with stuff and also in May I will be at star east I'm going to give a workshop on tools for web testing and I.
They asked if one to do a full day or a half day and I realize I have so much to get through a publish it on a full day will make it a half day and just.
Not go quite as deep that will be fun and I'll also take part in the lightning strikes the keynotes and give a whatever it is a two minute talk there on something probably modern testing ish.
I like the lightning strikes thing.
And then after that I have no plans hope that's enough I was invited and I'm still debating whether to go or not.
Or if I can if I can go but I was invited to speak at a software quality conference in Kiev cool.
I'd like to get in more on on doing the conference circuit I may be I'm being worried about it or whatever but.
So I don't want to talk about it on the podcast obviously but you know about the family issues and really with.
And it yeah I got to make sure that I got time for that.
All right yeah.
And I have.
Really it's I don't have a quota on how many conferences or places I'll speak at really it's just a couple criteria.
Is the conference in a place I think would be interesting to go to that has some weight.
Orlando sorry not the wind but I do I'm a fan of the star conference so I'll always do.
One every few years either a workshop or a keynote.
I think you've been doing it and you have time to go and there's a great Tim Ferriss to become a big fan of recently talks about I think he mentioned this first a lot of people he talks to mention the same thing is like if I was asked to do this next Tuesday would I say yes like if I could would I be.
Because a lot of times you'll agree to things that are far out in advance and you get to that time you go why did I ever say yes to this is ridiculous so I kind of put that in my head they asked me to do this it was next week when I do it.
So yeah oh I like that rule of thumb it's a good one it helps me say no.
That would save me from so much.
Well that's a free tip from the weasel to you yeah third one is is I will not do.
Pay to speak conferences I won't get my employer pay for my travel or hotel if you want me to speak at your conference and I'm just asking pay for my food or a stipend.
While those are welcome really well I all I want is if you want me to speak at your conference I do expect you to pay for my my travel and lodging and that's it and test bash is fantastic about that.
I'm actually saying a few extra nights and I'll have unity pay for that because unity is it has an office in Brighton as well figured it.
You'll go but that's it and I think that's a that's a fair set of criteria for anyone but would I do it next week if I was asked is the one I.
The one I pass on to you and to all the listeners know that's fantastic.
So tie you up Brent let's call the first episode which is what episode number.
Oh yeah we didn't cover that episode number seventy four that's okay if you if you're listening it's displaying in your on your podcast player right now which is likely your phone but I don't know.
So one of the things that that I have started to do and I don't know if you notice that I'm sure you have I've started actually going in and titling episode I didn't notice that you actually started.
Yeah wow I go check that out now so seventy three is titled.
There you go oh yeah look at that so oh you do you've titled yeah some of these are hilarious intermittently normal tangential.
This is good thank you Brent good start this is why you're listening yep.
So I started the title the episodes in addition to that I have also like this episode episode forty eight Allen hosts the three at test bash Philly which was my then in forty nine which is good because I asked Brent what episode it was you was forty eight and I say wrong because I did it without you.
So the other thing that we get from our listeners is.
That and I've as you guys may or may not know Alan does all of the technical side of this so one of the things that I'm going to contribute back to the podcast is helping people solve the search problem.
I've gone through I've trained I've gotten transcribed a bunch of things I haven't finished going through manually editing stuff at this point in time I've just going to use the same service and just finish it off and then need to come up with some sort of practice of how we stay clean once I get us to clean.
And then once I have the the transcription assets we should figure out how we can hook the right way to hook it up and so that people can search it now what I am not doing.
Is I am not going through and fixing up every stupid little error from the transcriber.
I haven't gotten to the point where like some of our really bad audio recording right I may just snip that out and put bad audio.
So it's going to be if there's still going to be a lot of errors because my time is super valuable but maybe we can come up with a way of enabling people to if they see an error and they can fix it themselves.
We should you know in programming is our longest outro ever in programming like when or in testing when you find an error you fix it.
We find something you fix it you want to make sure you have a process in place to make sure you don't go back and make that same error again have to fix it again.
Like if I find oh I'm passing no to this function then they go find other places where the same sort of error might occur and make sure it's part of our process so one thing.
I will put you on the spot today but rather than have you go back retroactively listen to the episode and figure out what to title it we should try and figure out the title of these episodes as I post them.
Yeah no no I like that idea so I won't make you do it during the podcast but I do think that if you have an idea for what's in this one you can send it to me in slack which is our main method of communication now welcome to the 21st century right and I'll make sure it gets posted when the show goes out on Monday.
Oh you can't wait to hear our lovely voices I usually almost always by practice post our podcasts to the slack channel one of the three dot slack dot com a day or two before they go out so I'll probably edit this tonight or tomorrow and it'll get posted the slack channel as soon as it's done and then I post on Monday because why post the podcast link on the week on the week on the weekend whatever okay.
That must be it I am believe it or not still Dawn slash Alan and I'm Brent thanks for listening.