Hey, everybody. Howdy. I'm Alan. I'm Brent. Still, huh? Welcome to AB Testing. Especially
welcome to our new listeners. I did a webinar last week and picked up a few new listeners.
AB Testing is your best podcast in the world for, oh well, actually nothing. AB Podcast.
Going gently to sleep at night. AB Podcast is a possibly interesting podcast for those
interested in software quality. Agile testing and what Brent and I call modern testing. We
talk about everything from test management, leadership, agile quite a bit, software engineering,
tools, favorite colors, squirrels. And data science. And data science. Look, Brent, someone's
talking about data science. We did pick up a few new listeners, as I mentioned a moment
ago from, I gave a webinar on Tuesday. Was it Tuesday? Yes. Okay, that correlates.
Because Webinar Wednesday rolls off the tongue where that alliteration did not happen. You
know what? It really should be. I mean, that works perfect. Well, interestingly enough,
I don't even know which direction to go. The tangents are going to start. I gave the
webinar on Tuesday for AST on the use and abuse, capital AB for AB testing, abuse. Test
automation, give a lot of my rants, got some good feedback on that. I was really happy
with the way that went. Webinars are always tough because you can't read the audience.
And just to challenge myself again, doing another webinar next Tuesday. Not the next
week I'm skiing, the following Tuesday, the 27th I'll be giving a webinar. I put
the link on Twitter, but I'll put it in the show notes today. It's on the future of test
automation. I'm doing it with Orin, whose name I can't remember, who is the CEO at
TestM, test.im, who make a tool for applying machine learning to testing.
Nice. Yeah, I need like that part. But yet we have some different ideas on where things
are going. My ideas are very much aligned with what you and I talk about with modern
testing. I was a little concerned when you mentioned
that you're doing two person panel for that one. And I'm like, okay, who's this guy?
But now I feel a lot better about what this panel could be.
And what's really cool if you want to watch it is there will be a demo of his tool at
the end, which normally I don't like, ah, marketing thing. But he and I, we've actually
prepped for this thing. We spent some time talking about questions that may come up
and actually preparing for this thing, which is a new thing for me.
Wow. There is crazy crap going down the diesel end. How does that work?
So it may actually be all right. Nice. We already have a lot of people signed up to
help more of the three listen. Brent, again, for the new listeners, I've mentioned
the three a few times. Can you tell our new listeners what that means?
Yes, it's very simple. We have three listeners and we affectionately refer to them as the
three. And if any one of you asks a question, we say, oh, you're one of the three.
Absolutely. It's kind of like, I don't know, Jimmy Buffett calls his guys the parrot
heads. And then Justin Bieber has one. Who is this Justin Bieber?
Some stupid kid from Canada. Yeah, that sort of thing.
I'm going to Canada next week. I can't say dumb things about Canadians, perhaps, are listening.
Or perhaps they'll just apologize for Justin Bieber.
Well, yeah, they have several people to apologize for.
Oh, like we don't? Like we don't?
No, no, for sure. For sure. I was thinking Celine Dion. Anyway.
Oh, Brent, Brent, Brent, we're going to make so many people mad. We're going to have
two listeners next week. We always have three.
Early on in our podcast, Brett and I would joke about our three listeners and then people
would. It was actually our first episode.
Was it really? It was.
Maybe we'll get three listeners. But then people, we kept on stuck and then people would
go, hey, I'm one of the three. And it kind of developed. So that's where that came from.
If there are other things you don't know about us, you want to know, you're welcome
to ask us questions for the and Brent trashed hands on this for the mailbag and some ways
to get mailbag questions to us. I know Brent's going to bring this up in a minute. So I'm
not going to leave even an ounce of silence in my talk.
So he cannot get any words in. But the way you get information to the mailbag and to
us to answer your question, to give us something intelligent for once to talk about is to
either ping us on Slack. I'm Alan Page, A-L-A-N-P-A-G-E. And Brent is Brent M Jensen, Jensen
with an E or you can...
You have to breathe sometime, Alan.
...email me at Alan, A-L-A-N-P-A-G-E. And I'll take it there. In fact, I had one question
there from the webinar I was going to answer today, but I'm not going to. I'm going to
save it for another mailbag and I'm really not going to give you a chance. And we're
going to go on. In fact, the rest of the show...
I'll just sit here in time.
We also have a Slack group, one of the three.slack.com. You will need to use one
of the aforementioned communication methods to get me your email address so I
can send you an invitation. Happy to have you there. All three of us discuss
things about the show, about things related to the show. It's a good little
micro discussion. And as I found out this week, some people join the Slack
channel just to get an A-B testing sticker. And yes, if you join the Slack
group and you find your way there and you join the channel called I Want a
Sticker and you post your address, eventually, usually fairly quickly, but
eventually I will send you A-B testing stickers. If you are listening and you
posted your... You didn't think I'd do it this long, did you, Brent? If you are
listening, I had three people post their addresses this week and those went out
in the mail yesterday, so look in your mailbox. Okay, Brent, I have to breathe.
And in the episode, this episode comes out... Oh, actually, I can't predict.
You gonna finish it today? Yeah, I'll get it out. It'll come out on Sunday, probably.
Okay, so... It may come out... If you're listening to this episode, you'll need to figure out
how to go back in time because Alan committed to shipping all the stickers
out today. Yeah, if there's any more posted today, I'll get them out tomorrow.
I'm driving to Canada on Sunday, possibly according to the weather
forecast in a snowstorm, but we'll see what happens. Whistler? Going to
Whistler. Nice. Favorite ski place. Last time I was there, my 19-year-old was three.
I've gone every year for about the last eight years. I really... Yeah, it's my
therapy. It's how I get through the winters. Okay, oh, is this episode 76?
Episode 76. Not that we're counting. So, what would, on your webinar, what was the key
things people were questioning about? I can post a link to the recording. I have
to remember now. So, the webinar was about all my grabs about test automation. In
fact, much of it was based on many of the things I rant about in the A word, free
on Lean Pub. Yep. You notice how, like, I had AB in the webinar, AB testing,
abuse and misuse of test automation. One thing I did on purpose that maybe was
too subtle is in the A word, that the A and the W kind of squished together a
little bit like angry weasel. Look at you. I'm all... Subliminal. I'm the
Illuminati. Questions were the typical things about what if management wants me
to write UI automation? Well, you can change your manager or you can change
your manager. Often, in the answer, of course, we talked about a lot is pilot,
use data, don't be complacent, don't be afraid to make change.
I... Branch? There's definitely... You asked. I know, I know. That one, if your
manager wants you to write UI automation in particular, right, then you as the
knowledge expert that he has hired, I think the onus is on you to correct
your manager's understanding on the ROI of this topic. Sure, sure. And I've told
the story, I think it was in How We Test Software at Microsoft. Remember that
book? Yeah. Yeah. And, but I've mentioned a lot of times, it's my very first day at
Microsoft, I was given a list of test cases and asked to run them every day.
I said, when do you need these automated? They said, oh no, we don't have time to
automate. But I automated them anyway, because it was the right thing to do.
And I just did it... There are things like that where I will automate it,
because I am not doing this again manually. Well, I think... Boy, we could go
way off into tangent, you want to get to the main topic of community, which we
started last time and didn't get as far as we wanted. So we want to go a little
bit farther there. Yep. But as far as... We've talked about command and control
and the spider and the starfish and empowered people and all these
different things. But I think in knowledge work in general, one, management
doesn't work if you just tell people what to do and just give them exact
destructor. Here's what you do all day today. We're not building widgets in
the factory. But that freedom, being able to take advantage of that freedom
properly and knowing when to push back, I think is part of being successful in
knowledge work. I don't think most... So management as a whole, right, is a
command and control structure. But I don't think most managers are really
wired that way. For example, every manager I've ever worked for, let's
imagine... I work for you, Alan. Let's imagine I come to you and say...
Oh, wait. I got this. Brent, you're fired.
All right, great. So I work for another Alan and I come to him and I
have two options for R101. One, I say, hey, Alan, I'm done with this. What
would you like me to do next? Or two, Alan, I'm done with this. I'm thinking
these next three things are the next things I should work on. Is there an
order that you think would best value the business? Right? It's one of those
things where I'm just like... A lot of the times, particularly I see it in tests,
I think a big part of it is the... Well, we talked about the enablement loop or
the disablement loop, where I think a lot of tests is just used to just getting
instructions and they've gotten to the point that that's how they operate.
I don't think... The optimist in me likes to think that's not as true as it used
to be. I know it's not as true as it used to be. So delving deeper into
Tangentville, I mentioned last time or time before, but anyway, sometime last
month I met with my leads and then again met with my peers to discuss just people
in the org and how they were doing. We're talking about levels and
internally Unity has some levels which we're figuring them out so we
don't really communicate them to people, but just helps us talk about
people the same way, which I think is fine. We're in that part of growth.
But what came out of that, and this is true of levels at Microsoft and
those are the only two I'm intimately familiar with, although I've
talked with people a lot about levels at Google and Facebook as well.
But the point is that the point I was eventually going to make sometime down
the road was that when someone's brand new, maybe out of college or
barely or changing disciplines, they need more instruction. They need
more hand-holding. They need to be sometimes like that first
person you described. And then there's a maturity where they start figuring out
what work to get done and they come to you to bounce them off you, get
prioritization. And then there's that maturity continues. I spent until my
last job, I spent where I was a little bit more of the micromanagy. Actually,
even there I still figured out what I did still define all my own work. It
was just a little more stressful environment. But I spent my last 10,
maybe more years, maybe 15 years at Microsoft, defining and prioritizing
all of my own work. And that was the expectation for someone at my level of
seniority and maturity is that I should figure out what's the most
important thing to do. And I was better suited for prioritization than my
manager was. I made balance ideas off of him for bigger scale things like
that may involve organizational change or affect a big number of people to
get some feedback. But it was more of a discussion and brainstorming than it
was a prioritization. So anyway, taking the subject away from me, because
that's not what it's all about today, at least, is that that maturation
happens. And I expect as people get more senior in their knowledge work and
more experience that not only do they seek out and figure out what the most
important work is to do, but they're able to prioritize it correctly most of
or all the time. There is, I don't know if they're still active, but one of the
best topics I've ever studied on this is, well, classes rather is situational
leadership, which walks through the manager employee relationship on a
particular task. And it's very similar to what you just talked about, right? A
manager's job is to direct initially and then try to shift it over to more of a
coaching style and then get the hell out of the person's way. But I don't think
it's a person level maturity, but rather a topic level maturity. People at any level
at any time are more than welcome and welcomed to with the tools that they
have in their tool bag, identify problems, try to connect it to something that the
business cares about, and then also bring forward with a solution. That's one of
the biggest things I push my people towards, like look, as you and I have
said on the podcast, ideas come from other ideas and good ideas can come
from anywhere. You have to create an environment in which you encourage
that to occur. So one of the things that I think is actually relevant to the topic
today. I thought you were just about to lead into it. If ever we bring it up. You're practically
segueing until now. So ideas can come from anywhere. The environmental
context can help suppress people coming up with the ideas or sharing them. And at
least I, and this is one of the issues with command and control, particularly with
new managers. I see this a lot with new managers. They go, I am accountable,
therefore I must make the decisions. Whereas my approach is I am
accountable, therefore I must make decisions that are correct. And I don't
necessarily presume that my decisions are. If there's a timeliness stuff, right, I
still hold veto power. One of my favorite phrases on my team. As you know,
I run a, I execute via a Kanban style. All the things we talk about around no
specialists, no generalists. I live and breathe that on every single day. So I've
created something. I don't know fully enough of how what Lisa talks about when
she says whole team. But I certainly know the concept. But nevertheless, at
times my team is reminded that I spend a lot of time and effort to make my
team feel like a democracy, but it's not. So it's interesting to bring that up. I
was just at a conversation yesterday as someone gave me actually a lot of
parallels here. The one of the people on my team was going over his suggestion or
he was working with the dev team and I'm, I'm hands on hands off. I'm hands
on as a coach hands off as far as I think the team makes the decisions. I
will give strong suggestions, but I won't very few if I can recall any, I'll
bring them up, but mandates like we're all gonna do this. Like let's go in this
direction. You're on board? Okay. I'll help you get there. So the question was
around setting up a Kanban board. Okay. And I had some suggestions on like if you
don't, I think if you don't do this, this will happen. But it goes, so it
sounds like you want to do this. I said my suggestion is you have a way to
handle this and here's one way to do it. The decisions yours. And I realized I do
that a lot. I try, I don't try and make decisions for people even if they ask me
to make it for them because I want them. One of the things I think helps people
grow in maturity and grow in leadership skills. I think when you're in modern
testing and you need to be influential over your team, having leadership skills
are important. And I found the only way to get good at decision-making is to
practice decision-making and practice making changes that people may not be
comfortable with. The Heffetz quote from leadership on the line, I use a lot. People
nod their head. They laugh and they nod their head. His leadership is disappointing
people at a level they can absorb. And Brett just nodded his head and laughed.
That's what I get every time someone hears that. And it really is. If you're
just complacent, not gonna get changed. If you're, I know leaders who say this
we're doing this, this is what we're doing, and people are, they're not
on board. It's too much disappointment at once. And the right things
don't happen there either. But you want to keep people, I mean, for organizational
change especially, there's a level of uncomfortableness where you actually get
the most productivity and the most change. Something to think about.
There's almost every book on the planet around business project management. We'll
talk about that. That you make them just a little uncomfortable. You get a lot
more productivity. I often change absorb to tolerate. I think leadership is
disappointing people at a level they can tolerate. I think it's, to me that one
works a little bit better, but it's the same thing. The issue though, like what
you brought up with your discussion. And I do think it, this is an
important one. Like if this individual had come to me, they would have
start getting my speech on leadership. Because there's, you cannot
come to me and ask for permission to be a leader. Right. It's no, like what
they're saying is really, can I be the decision maker and hold you still
accountable? No. That's not what leadership is. All right. Shall we start the episode?
Sure. Okay, I'm gonna hit record. Just kidding. We wanted to continue our discussion from
the last episode on community. A couple topics on the board, but I'll let you
kick it off. So, because you have some notes Brent. Well, it's just the agenda.
Last time we started talking about community and building community and
Alan shared a lot of his experiences. But the question that was asked of us
was rather deep. There's a lot of subtlety there and we felt it was
worthwhile bringing it up again. I don't have the question written down, but in
essence the question was, hey how do I create a community when my target
audience is essentially testers who the person has observed don't see the
need, aren't engaged, and want to be spoon fed. And I think the prior topic
that we just had, well, it's not as much of a tangent on this one. Did we
accidentally talk about something relevant? We did. That's so weird. Yeah. So,
Alan, what are the problems that you see in constructing a community from
ground up? Like we did spend a lot of time talking about the vision of how you
build a community, right? You need to, and we talked about your approach, which we
resolved as essentially we want to shift from a spider organization to a starfish
organization. That's the vision. Now, today let's talk about the specific
context, the test community that he's referring to here, and what would
be the first step. So, I've spun up, we talked about my communities in Microsoft.
I've spun up several, without realizing it, without intending to, I spun up
several communities at Microsoft and then probably the best, as far as the
most mature community, as far as any sort of community maturity model is my QA
slash test community at Unity. But starting from scratch, you need a little
bit of a shared, like what is the purpose of the community? First, we have a nice
little mission statement you may have heard of at Unity, accelerate the
achievement at Shipable Quality. I have heard this mission statement a couple
times before. And it gives you a thing to rally around. And then, but even beyond
there, one thing I've done at Unity, I probably do this by heart, but maybe
three months in, about the time I was realizing it was a community, about
the time I knew enough about the org to want to develop some rallying cries for
us, I realized a couple points I wanted us to rally around. One is moving
towards data-driven culture. We will use data to evaluate the quality of our
product in production and use that to make decisions, get us close to the
customer, etc. The paragraph follows that. But everyone knows that's very,
very important. And I'm going to come back to something in a second. We will
share our successes and failures with each other and use those to learn and get
better. And that's pretty much it. And then I use the community, it's
self-fulfilling, because the second one's about community, but I use the
community to make that happen. And then there's some tactical things I've done
to help build that community. And I want to go back and reflect on this
process with some of my Microsoft communities as well. I think it'll be
fairly similar.
Let me change the scenario briefly, right? Because you have an advantage in this
particular case, because you're the boss, right? If you need to...
I thought you were going to say you're incredibly good looking, but I'll be
the boss, okay.
The last check that you sent me hasn't cleared yet, so there'll be no
compliments today. And when you have a role of authority, there
is absolutely an advantage, particularly if you know that this is your vision.
My job is to create this community and then get it self-sustained and get out.
So let me finish the Unity story. Then I'll go back and reflect on my
Microsoft communities, which in no case was I the boss of.
But also a scenario I want you to think about, and maybe it's aligned
with that second one, is let's imagine that Tony, who asked this
question, hired you to be a community consultant.
Okay.
And you were going to go to his company, spend a week there, and create a
thriving community and then disappear.
A week.
So let me go through those scenarios in order. So let me finish the Unity
story. I found ways to reinforce community. And this is weird. I did not
come up with this idea myself, but the leads...
Beer.
My leads and I came up with this, mostly them. In fact, maybe all of them
at our offsite last August. We had talked a lot about community before them.
One of the things we've done, just sent out the 20th weekly newsletter yesterday.
And the newsletter is, in this case, it's sometimes, not always, it's
just something everyone needs to know. Like, or something about...
We ship your thing.
Here's our vision. Or no, because it's too many things going on. No.
I don't welcome new people. I don't say things shipped. A lot of the
initial newsletters were promoting something else we did for community,
was get everyone together from around the world in one spot for a
couple of days. That helped build community, helped get everybody on
the same page, get everybody in alignment on things.
A lot of times I just share articles, web articles about
software quality or about being data driven, about things that align
with our mission. And it adds some commentary and those are taking
off. I start getting replies like yesterday, I sent one out and today
I got, oh, you mentioned this. Have you seen these articles and some
really cool articles? So that was cool. What I try to do, I don't
do often enough yet, but remember my goal around sharing each other's
successes and failures. So I try to, and each one, I don't get
everyone, is to get someone to share something going on in their
team. Like, hey, I use this. The last one was last week, a guy on
my team put together, who's also occasionally one of the three.
He was playing with using Grafana to map out web errors,
50X errors from one of our websites and saw an interesting
number of 503s that shouldn't have been there. It's a static
web page. And he dug in and found out, oh, this is a bug.
And worse yet, it's a bug that could be exploited as a security
issue. So it was just a nice little issue of like, I'm going
to use this tool and I'm going to see what I discover. Ooh,
look, I discovered something bad. And then here I wrote this up
on this page in our wiki page on how you can do this yourself
and test your own stuff out. So it's really good for sharing
an experience of what you learned. And I like those things.
Those things help build community. So I do some things
like that. I make sure I celebrate in Slack, in our
company Slack, the things that people do that align with our
accelerate the achievement of a quality or moving towards
being more data driven.
Let me go back to Microsoft. I'll get to Tony eventually,
where I ran a couple of different communities. Some from
the beginning, some I joined and sort of took over. For some
reason, I've fallen back on writing newsletters because I
can do it very quickly. I enjoy writing. I can get
newsletters people like done. So when I was in engineering
excellence at Microsoft, I would send a monthly test
newsletter to all testers at Microsoft.
I don't remember a single one of those.
Yeah, thanks. And we started doing a newsletter with the
testing quality experts, quality and test experts
community. I would include like bug. It was just some
ways to get people interested as trying to grow, make
that community self-sustaining got partially there.
Eventually, someone took over the newsletter for me for
that community died when TCN died. And I also did that
much less frequently for the test architect group.
But an Xbox also had a weekly weekly every other week. We
did a frequent newsletter was that one was a lot of fun.
It worked. I had a lot of people contribute articles and
ideas for that. It was a way to share ideas, tools,
concepts across the org. I did one of my best April
Fool's newsletters was was in the Xbox org. I really
need to dig that up sometime. Really happy with that
problem. But it's just finding some ways to get people
together. It could be meetings. It could be events.
It could be beer. But finding a way to get to have
one you have a mission or vision, a thing you want to
accomplish together and a way to encourage people to be a
part of that community contribute to the community
and leverage leverage people leverage the community to
grow. I think a community is a means to discover what
you don't know. You don't know. You also get out what
you put into the community. If you contribute and
share your ideas, you're probably going to find more
ideas that inspire you and help you create new ideas.
So a bunch of things I want to. OK. And then I'll go
on to what I do if I'm I'm a consultant for Tony.
But go ahead and add your your stuff. Yeah. And
it'll be good because I think it'll help frame your
next topic. So a lot of the communities that Alan
just mentioned. I was a member of one in particular.
I'm thinking about the test architect group. There
was one phenomenon that that that I noticed in
that whenever it was the scheduled day for the
community and Alan couldn't make it it got canceled.
Right. So part of the problem in this particular case
is Alan loves this stuff. He's very effective at it.
But he ended up being the virtual leader. And when
the leader wasn't there it didn't happen. And so
one of the things why I say self sustaining right
often is the goal. It's also saying is and one
of the things I would I would actually. So a couple
suggestions I have for you based off of the
experience and what you just described for me. OK.
Create a community of the newsletter producers and
your first task is say hey I want the newsletter
to go out every month. I want us to first figure
out what is the principles around how it's going
to be built because I want people to look at
that and not tell not be able to tell that it
was a different person sending them each month.
And then the next thing we're going to do is
figure out a rotational model. I was I will do
the first few of them until we are happy with
the iteration. But by the end of summer each of
you guys is going to is going to take point
and we're going to rotate through and you're
going to own sending this. What you have to do
is then use that command and control to force
them to learn and to spread the next phase
after that is how do you get them to want to
maintain the rotational model. It would take
longer than two podcasts for me to go through
suggestions on that one. And I wouldn't even.
I'll build on that. The last thing I would suggest
to you is make a key section of your of your
newsletter. Are you sending out monthly weekly
weekly. OK. Make a key section of your weekly
newsletter. The most glorious fail that occurred
in your team and figure out a way to send that
person a gift card or some sort of little
incentive. Yeah I do agree that one thing we
could do more of is I mentioned in my my
principles is celebrate our successes and
failures. Actually both internally and publicly
I want to post more of what we're doing around
quality and. You know services on the unity
blog and we're getting there. But we don't
celebrate the failures enough and we I do
want to do more of that and it's harder to
get people of course to to recognize those
and thankfully we're not making very many epic
failures. So that's good but yes I agree
those things should be there. I agree that I
want to add. No it's my turn now. And I also
agree that. You do want a community of people
distributing the newsletter. And I do agree you
want to have a group of people that can send
the newsletter. Kicking it off here for the
first several months. I've been happy to do it
I think it's the right thing for me to do it
to establish a cadence to prove we can do it
weekly to prove that we can get value from that.
I'm stepping away next week and people are no
problem. Stepping in and making sure there's a
newsletter done while I'm gone and eventually
they will contribute more more. They actually
all contribute the article ideas. They they
they get ideas for articles from their team and
I play editor. A lot of times. And sometimes
for light on stuff I have no problem just
kind of writing a little mini blog post about
because I read a lot of articles on the
Internet that I find this to be interesting for
the team. Let me add a little commentary to
get them engaged in it and explain why it's
relevant to our mission. And then they are
pretty good about jumping in and getting some
new ideas. You want to say something I want to
talk about what I do for Tony's team. If I'm
his consultant. Go ahead. Talk about Tony. OK
Tony hires me to come in to help me build the
community. I don't come into Tony's team and
say OK I'm going to give you a newsletter.
That you only have a week. I have a week. So
the first thing I want to do is find out from
Tony what's the goal of your community. We
get paid six months later after they seem the
result. Fine fine. All right. Good fine. I want
to find out what. I would start with why. What
do you want to accomplish. What's the reason
for having a community. And I'm going to
hypothesize that it's we have a lot of silo
ism people aren't we have people working on
the same things because they don't know what
each other are working on. We're not people
aren't learning as much as they could if they
had a way to connect with each other. I say
OK great. So let's come up with a. What's
the mission of the goal for the community. And
maybe it's we want given that criteria. We
want to have a means of discovering what we
don't know we don't know. And maybe we'll work.
I'll work with Tony a little bit. This is all
like over coffee in the morning. We'll come up
with. As a test community of practice at
Rungco widget factory. We want to share ideas
with each other and use those ideas to develop
bigger ideas that help us accelerate the
achievement of quality or help us achieve our
quality goals or help us whatever have a purpose
for community have and something that's
compelling and you think if I told people that
the sum I think they go yeah that's something
that we should do. I would start with that. And
then I would meet maybe team by team depending
on the org how big the org is now structured
is I want to get some information from people
on what their biggest challenges are and are
their challenges being with their challenges be
addressed by this community or would some of
their challenges be addressed by this community
and find out if the community idea makes sense
for solving their problems. Chances are it will.
But I don't know that I don't want to. Last thing
you want to do is think OK we got to really
push this community thing when it's not the
biggest problem. Eventually community a
community of practice if you will at a small
scale. Someone pointed out an article this week
on communities of practice I was talking about
communities at a very very large scale which I
think is a different beast entirely. So within a
company that a small organization this community
of practice can help solve a lot of problems. So
anyway I've talked to people talk to some
people on maybe maybe people that aren't even
going to be in the community say what do you
expect if we had a community of the testers
in this or what would you expect that
community to accomplish that they're not
accomplished now and chances are if community is
an issue they've seen things like well I talked
to Joe and Cindy and they're both working on
the same thing but they don't know they've
there's no desire for them to connect and learn
from each other. So once I have all that. Can
you talk briefly. Because I think our listeners
know very well we we care very much about
learning organizations. But we've also spent a
lot of time this episode and the last episode
sort of framing community as something that is
inherently valuable and I don't think it is. I
think community is a means to an end. Sure. So why
would the business care about you building a
community. The business cares about continuous
improvement and I think the business cares
whether they know it's called this or not a
learning organization. I think the business cares
that about efficiency and I think the business
cares about results. The last one community
helps indirectly but everything else community
helps directly. The community helps. I think it
helps directly for results. Yeah. I think the
biggest reason to form a community is to create
a means by which people don't know what they
don't know. OK. So community solves a knowledge
sharing problem. If you if you're a bit you run a
business and you realize that there is rampant
duplication of effort you have two choices.
Generally allow it to continue and let your
leaders run their business as they see fit.
Build a central centralized organization that's
going to be responsible for this duplication of
effort and force everyone else. I call that the
WTF model. Windows test framework but a community
is no less. It's more of an in between when it
comes to business results. I realize as I we've
been talking that I wonder if this community
evolved for me over time and I wonder if
starting with the idea of I need to build the
community isn't what I in my consultant role at
Tony's org isn't what I do. I would actually focus
on. I would do everything I did before but I may
leave after I talked to everyone leave Tony a list
of here's some things you could do on your team
that would help grow community potentially. But
I maybe you have to plant a bunch of seeds to
get the nucleus of the community going versus
going. We're just going to start a community.
Let me give you an example going way back. You
reminded me that around the turn of the century
seriously when I was working on starting with
Windows Millennium and then moving on to Windows
CE when I again actually I was a lead back then.
So I had a fairly large org. One of the things I
did was a weekly it started off as a group code
review ended up being sort of show and tell and
it isn't the kind of code review where you'd
look at every single line and the kind we do
day to day pure code review. This was more of
a group show and tell where we'd sometimes
mostly walk through code like here's architecture
of how I built this thing or here's how it's
working. That knowledge sharing a lot of it was oh
there's a DLL that does this thing you're doing
or don't you find some more big sweeping things
those great opportunity for learning and
sharing. But sometimes I had PM's on my team at
the time program managers and they would go
over more conceptual things they're working on
like here's the way this framework is going
to work. We had a CE test kit we gave developers
and a PM on my team in charge of that and you
talk about the direction and what it was going to
do for our customers etc. But that show and tell
we had a community again I was in charge ish but
that even that was a form of community. So I'm
going to leave Tony with is based on the
problems there from his team. I'm going to
look for ways where knowledge sharing may
help and I might start right with knowledge
sharing. You should do this group code review
thing just get people doing it get it regular. I
think people will latch onto it. It could be
maybe we're going to do a test talk once a month
and some someone or maybe it's Tony starting at
first. We'll see if we get a few people signed up
that have some good ideas and we'll get them
to once a month talk for a half hour we'll
bring in some snacks get people connecting and
maybe a list of things that may help build
community but maybe not even start with the
goal of community because communities the means
to an end on becoming a learning organization
on getting ideas to mesh and learning new ideas.
But I think if I had a week to kind of get
things going I would and I'm going to be
evaluated on how things are going in six months.
I'm going to give Tony a fairly tactical list
of here do these things for the next six
months. It should take a fairly minimal amount
of effort. It's going to take some effort. And
let's see what's in the sea what builds over
that time. Sure. Sure. I mean the
value I would add to that I think I'll tell
you the one thing that I've learned from Google
and I've still not seen Microsoft do this. Tony
talks about testers aren't engaged because they
don't see the value and what you had to do is
boil the frog here and find ways to get
people to see the value on their own without
you telling them. And I didn't say that directly.
One of the reasons I want to talk to the
individuals on the team find out what they're
interested in what would engage them and make
sure we have. I think if you might see someone
is unengaged until you find the topic they
care about the topics they care about and all
of a sudden they have an opinion. Yes. Like the
biggest problem with siloism is since your
siloed you don't know what other people know.
And I can guarantee you in any organization of
sufficient size there are two people working on
similar things that would prefer to work
together to get it done faster. And the more you
can use find those folks and get them connected
and working together towards a common goal.
That's your seed. You just need two people.
Two people to use as an in-house case study and
motivate them to succeed. Google does this
practice. I don't know if they still do it but
the weekly status report as I understand it
everyone in Google every day or every Friday
writes a status report. You and it goes into a
public index. I love this idea. Which is then
searchable. It's searchable. I people can go
how many other people are working on a similar
concept. Now you don't use terms like duplication
of effort because that's jurisdiction and
command and control and gets people defensive.
You cannot build a community of defensive people.
It's just impossible. But you can encourage and
say hey maybe you guys can learn from each
other or maybe you guys could kill this
faster. One my particular team highly values
knowledge sharing because I started off with
pushing command and control. No you will write
this doc. You will put it in one note. You will
blah blah blah. And then they would discover
like oh crap I had to fix this bug. I didn't
write this code. Thank God. One note had
documented who did it. What their approach was
and what they're thinking. I could go and search
one note and I got the answer immediately and I
saw it and they knew it's that knowledge sharing
actually had just saved them five hours of
searching through get. So you start small and
you begin to break down those barriers and
that's how you get engagement going. I like
the status report idea because it's then it's
very easy to go. It's just scale and figure out
which people have sort of a similar bent on
topics of interest. The there is a great book on
this topic. It's called influencer how to
change anything. And it goes through and it
talks about a very tactical set of steps that
they've done studies on. And if you follow the
steps it's a complex framework once you've
practiced it a couple of times. I have deployed
it multiple times. It is extremely effective.
Their answers or rather their numbers show that
it's a greater than 90 percent success rate in
terms of executing a change. Influencer how to
change anything again is the title of the book.
If I'm fine good I'll put a link in but the rest
you know how to use a search engine. Yep. To build
a community you have to address simultaneously
the extrinsic value. Why you're building a
community. What what problem for the business is
going to always start with why. And you also have
to address the intrinsic value. Why is. All right.
I'm going to build the community because I think
Alan and Steve need to knowledge share and that
the business is going to benefit be more productive.
That's not a very good why. No. But you also have
to address why Alan and Steve care. How you're
going to get what's what's their motivation.
What are they going to get out of it. And if
you have a model and an approach that addresses
both of these concerns and it's going to be very
context sensitive. You can move forward. You know
that it's a test community. If I were going into
doing a test community I would start on something
very tactical probably on the topic of modern
testing like Alan's got this webinar. Hey check
out this cool machine learning test case. I just
spent last week and did your team's entire job
using this tool. Yes I agree. Yeah. Find a way
to get people engaged and think but first think
about the problem you really want to solve and
understand why building a community if that's your
goal or what are the ways that will solve that
problem. But always start with why. What are you
going to do with it. And then of course make
sure people are engaged understand why it's
important for them. We are out of time. I am
still Alan. And I am Brent. Thank you. We'll see
you next time. Bye.