Hello again, howdy, hey, I'm Alan I'm brit and we're back with another episode of a B testing
Does it have a number are we up to?
87 we are
87 welcome to the 87th episode of a B testing if this is your first time listening to a B testing
Welcome, please go back to episode 80. You may want to back up
We've been diving into the modern testing principles on you can read those on modern testing org
We've been spending this is our sixth episode going through the seven principles will hit the
the last one in two weeks, but this podcast in general is your
guide your gateway your information Center for a lot of things about software testing a lot of software engineering
Quality and of course the aforementioned modern testing. Yes
It's all that so that's the plan for today if you'll hit the fast-forward button now you can avoid our chit chat or
Since we don't work together anymore. This is our chance to catch up, too
So what's new with you? Mr. Jensen? Oh
The biggest thing that's new is
Baseball seasons over
Not for the professionals for your children. I assume yeah from my son although that reminds me
I need to sign them up for a fall ball. I keep forgetting that you want to stop and write yourself a note. Yeah, he actually
Totally going to do that
Like yeah, cuz if I miss the date
let's see
Okay, then yeah, talk some amongst yourselves the Bellevue which is also called the Seattle
Unity office because outside of the Seattle area. No one knows where Bellevue is. We are
moving offices we are vastly outgrown both the
Physical space and power and AC limits of our current space so
Another month or two and we'll finally be in our new spot pretty excited about that. It'll be pretty and nice. Where you going?
Six blocks away. We're going to Lincoln Square South. Oh, okay again for the locals everybody else like shut up and talk about modern testing
Lincoln's is that the same building you used to be? No, no South it's
Three blocks south on the it's the newer one that went up on the corner of fourth and Bellevue way again more local trivia
Okay, we'll move on here has a lot of restaurants
Had they put anything into that Toys R Us yet? No the toys our s space is still available
Okay, so anyway, so anyway, I thought I'd just cuz I was thinking about it on the way to work
I have a bit of a
Where is the weasel update? Oh?
I'm I mean I'm at the I was I was waiting for the song but oh we'll come back to that
We'll go back to that, but you weren't done. I forgot that you just took a pause to
Write notes on your phone so that I can read that we now return to a quick update from
Brent Jensen yes, so the the next biggest thing that's happening is
So my oldest has been home for the summer
He's got an apartment where he's he's gonna move into his apartment on Saturday in Pullman in Pullman
He's already pre-warned
Things like he may not be home next summer. He may not come home for Thanksgiving
So I actually think even though he's not willing to say this and he may not know but just because you know
I've gone through the college experience. I actually think this is
It I think this is him actually moving out
That's congratulations on a successful early launch
Yeah
It I I hope I hope I and all of our listeners with children have the same experience with all of our kids
Yeah, no, I don't think I'm gonna have this same. No I can't wait. I can't wait to get rid of them
Move out they're obviously not avid listeners to the podcast
No, but they have heard me tell them that as soon as as soon as the younger one goes to college that
The house is being sold immediately and we're not leaving a forwarding address just a PO box
That's you know that's not a bad strategy
But you can mitigate it. Just you know if you if you'd like where you live you know just change the locks
Thought about that thought about that, but I think it's better just to actually I don't like
The house is fun. I like the house. It's a nice house is beautiful
I am I have not adapted well to suburbia
We became suburban to get the kids in better schools and all that but I I would like
Living this cookie-cutter house. It's nice
And it's big in the three-car garage and lots of room and have a huge home office
And it's awesome a great place for a dog and everything that's cool, but I
I
Suburbia takes attacks on me
I need I need a neighborhood or a building with character that sometimes only a more urban
Environment can provide yeah
You and I are so far apart there. I can't even see you from where I'm saying
I want a house with so many acres. I don't even don't even know which direction my neighbors are
Yeah, that actually would be pretty sweet
Yeah
Yeah, not cool for me not cool for me
I want to go outside and run naked in my prairie. Oh god you that God confidence
Could you move to Russia and do that?
No, okay. I don't want that happening within a thousand miles of me
Too late
All right, so yeah, so that's that's a that's a big deal and then the next thing that I'm
So school should start back up for me on August 20 you get a finally finish
You didn't go for it get the home stretch done
You know
I'll just I'll just submit to everyone on there. I just don't
Want to do it?
I want to be done with this thing and I don't want to do one final burst of pain
but yeah, so I'm kind of
Constantly flipping that coin in the air and picking it up and re-flipping and picking it up and re-flipping
Yeah, it's it is the last time but the idea of
Going through another four months of all of my nights and weekends
gone
No pain no gain. Yeah, but I am thinking first you've already got most of the game. I am yeah, I've gotten all of the game
That's the other thing too is I'm so wired for for return on investment
right yeah, I am too old I am too old and
Not from the the weariness part, but I'm at a stage in my career no one will actually care
About this degree the only reason to do it is to be done
It's not gonna get me a job in the future
Right. Gotcha. It's not it's it's I've gotten what I wanted out of it. Yeah
Anyway, there you go. So
School may start for me in August. It may also start for me in January
All right. We'll see how I will finish
I have six years from the start to finish
And I still think I have five or six semester starts left
Alright, excellent. That's now I'm done. Okay a quick update of my fall travel schedule because it just got a little ridiculous
In fact, I just in fact, I haven't sent the mail. I just made the choice last night
To turn down I almost went to a conference in November because in Korea and I really wanted to go there
But there's too much else going on. I'm heading off to Iceland next week
Shouldn't that next week? No, not the week after and then in October. I thought I was going someplace in September end of September
Very beginning of October over that weekend heading down to Anaheim to give a workshop at Star West
popping back up north be home for about four days heading down to Portland for a couple days to
Give a talk on modern testing and also a workshop at
PNS QC which is one of my favorite conferences
I think the size and caliber of presentations is usually pretty good. So I'm excited about that in
Later in October. No. Yeah later in October. I'm home for like two weeks and then I'm going to
Copenhagen and Helsinki on a work trip
Home for about three more weeks and heading to Sweden for a week for a work trip and that should close out the weasel
2018 travel schedule I would have had to shove that two more weeks later hit that Korea trip
But I was like that's I think it's enough. So doing that
So shall we you have a sub in Korea or is that a no? No, the Korea trip was a conference
request speaking speaking request
And I thought about doing it because I actually I am trying to
not
speak at any test conferences in
2019 I may speak at
Given the right opportunity. I'm trying to get out of
If I've talked to you about this before I want to get out of the test. I
Want to get out of the test conference speaking except for rare occasions. I will always speak at ministry test because it's like
The test batches because they're really good and the audience actually gets it. It's it's a proper audience. But I
I think I want to
If I do more speaking I will do it more at
Development center conferences. I think that's where my mind and content is is what improving
software quality through better engineering and development practices
so I think I may start focusing more there when I speak and just speaking a lot less in general because
It's fun and it's great and people clap at you and they ask you questions. You feel all validated and stuff, but
I think I want to focus my efforts elsewhere. I think I think that makes sense
based on my
My knowledge of you and your passions. I think you're done
Sort of teaching testers how to test
Yeah, right exactly. It's kind of not where we're going with modern testing
I think it makes sense to start you going through and say okay
No, we need to start teaching devs how to test
Although I don't I think that may be premature quite honestly like I would suggest to you
that
No, there's still value in you going to the test conferences and teaching testers how to lead
I think yes, but I'm gonna do that selectively test leadership conference in the one I did in New York
That has some validity to it test bash as I mentioned before
like an agile testing conference I could do but
Again, I'm gonna be much more selective. I'm I'm
I am done talking to
Junior testers about how to get started in testing and test careers and all that stuff
I want to help I and I think a
Lot of what we need to do with testing is about
Being a modern tester and someone just asked me on Twitter Jim Holmes. Hey Jim about
Give a description of what it's like to be a modern tester. I like given the tautology answer of
Well, actually it says no such thing as a modern tester
But we do recognize I spoke for you. So we do recognize that
Someone who leads the team towards following modern testing principles. I'm okay with calling them a modern tester
Yeah, it's a leadership position and it's a position that I am happily grooming
Most are all people in my team towards I mean they're they are
Whether they know about modern testing principles or not. They're all kind of in a modern testing role right now
In terms of like the the tipping point I I I don't think we're done here on this topic
until
We get a sufficient amount of the test community
to understand that
The content after the semi-colon in principle 7 is not only a good thing
But something they should be working towards. Yeah, I want to walk
Yeah, there is a lot of fear and people see it as it's like the controversial part and we'll talk will
We're all the good time talking about that in our next recording. Yep
But yeah, yeah, I think so. All right, so we do this week. Yes, we shall we shall and let me start let me start by
Saying that I slapped I don't know if I CC'd you on this or not
Maybe I mentioned it in slack
But I did slap a creative commons attribution share like license on the modern testing principles
To encourage people like it's totally yeah do whatever you want with them. It's so people have asked like can we copy these?
Can we translate these? Yes attribute the source and do whatever you want change them for your team
If you want attribute the source, it's totally fun
Took out the middle man. No longer need to ask just the licenses there follow along
I would be careful about changing for the team though, right? Some people could change it and turn it into something and that supports
Traditional then it will yeah, it wouldn't really be modern testing anymore
It says that would attribute the original they would go. Oh, okay, you've you've changed this
There's a license give us the right to tell somebody to take it down if we discovered
No, I don't want that. I want people if somebody wants to bastardize. I don't think they're going to I am a truster
All right. I'm a truster and an enabler
Maybe that last doesn't sound right. Okay, let me read to you modern testing principle number six. Oh my god
It's been so long since the podcast started. It's about freaking time. Okay
Number six we use data. Um, he thought I was gonna start didn't you you can read these at modern testing org
number six we use data extensively to deeply understand customer usage and then close the gaps between
product hypothesis and business
What does that mean? Well, we'll dive into a deeper
Give it to me
How would you
Paraphrase that back to me. What does that mean? We do or and we meaning teams following modern testing principles or teams
delivering software in this way
Why is
Actually, let's talk about why why is this important?
Before I go on to that, that's a great question and we will get to it
I want to read you a tweet
that that I
Don't know how I got it
Follower of a follower of something and I'm gonna tell you
This is relevant. Okay. Okay. I am listening to your tweet reading
exploratory testing is
the key to high quality software
semicolon a highly intellectual and
time-consuming activity
Often pushed off to end users. How do you feel about this tweet it?
And again, it's relevant. It is relevant and I had a similar tweet
Exchange that just to continue on this morning about the same topic it reeks of ignorance
To me. I am NOT first. I am NOT against exploratory testing total value in that
Using data to understand customer usage and to close the gaps and monitoring etc
Has nothing to do with shoving buggy software on to customers because you don't give a shit about them
And there is a and I'm gonna get on my soap boxes. I'm pissed off about this because there are people in the industry
Some with loud voices who tweet about the new tweet saying that or speak saying that
Having customers, you know letting customers find bugs even if they're not actually finding them directly
It's monitoring that's revealing these things is a horrible thing and it's lazy
I had I saw one author. I can't call him an author one article writer
Because in the internet, I guess everyone's an author
I had an article where they mentioned testing and production as a last quote
Maybe I'm quote me. I'm not quoting but as a last gasp resort to find bugs using the customers as testers
so so anyway, that's why you triggered me because I see a
very big lack of understanding on how to use monitoring how to use data and how freaking valuable it is done, right and
They think it's just this lazy thing teams do because they don't want to do testing where that's not the case at all
Was that the answer you wanted or did I kind of go?
close
You know if if
If this
Tweeter
Had not used the words pushed off to end users. I would have had no problem. I
Actually, I totally agree with the first half of that. I mean again to be cool. Yeah, anyway
I'm gonna I'm gonna you talk I'm gonna breathe. Okay, it is not pushed off the end users
So the the principal talks about validating the hypothesis
Actually the way we word it is better than the way I'm remembering how we worded
We close the gaps between the product hypothesis and the business impact. What does that mean?
means when we wrote code
We had a theory around what is valuable to be clear
We had a hypothesis
Right. Yeah, right. Well, I'll just say yes, right?
Well, no, I'm a data scientist in my world
Hypothesis is overloaded but I'll just say yes because it's not worth going into but
There are for the record I win. Yes
We have talked about this before in that is
the problem with ET
Now is it the key to high quality software?
Probably now, but they're saying exploratory testing
Okay, if this is something that's pushed off to an end user
Then I'm gonna say it's not exploratory testing anymore. It's actually this clever thing that we call
using the product
Now when a customer is using the product, is it highly intellectual? Maybe
Now I will say most products if it require highly intellectual
You probably have a usability problem like customers don't want to have to think too hard to get their solution solved
the time-consuming activity I also have a problem with a
traditionalist point of view is we try to
We try to prevent harm to the customer and we see it as as us
Again, it kind of is like the the champions the champions of quality slide that I keep referring to that Alan has produced
Right. We're a superhero team. Why are we letting that poor pregnant pregnant mom?
Take the bullet instead of us. We should be doing it. That's not actually the reality
today, I will let me share a
Story and then I'm gonna go into a lot more on the the what why and how after you do you share your story?
We'll comment actually have another tweet thread
Highly related. I want to read to you. Okay, so we should do a whole episode of Alan and Brent read tweets
No, actually would be fun
I'm already vetoing the idea. Anyway, go on story time. All right
it was my last week and bing and
I'm sorry. I need to interrupt just for the the new listeners Bing is like Google. All right, go on
All right, but Bing Bing Google's things really well, it's fine. It works
moving on
It was my last my last week in Bing
my
Executive had set up in all hands on the Wednesday and we had
We had an individual from a partner team come in
And they did a presentation because we had worked we had done a co-development project with that team and it and
Finally shipped it well
It was best essentially shipping a Bing app in in the Windows Store
at the same time
Google
Was shipping an app into the Windows Store?
in and this person told a story about
about how
We finally got this thing across the wire
and one of the things that they owned producing was a sort of a documentation on how to streamline and get things into
the ecosystem and
They decided to produce us a slide deck around what not to do now
they decided to use the Google app as an example because
a month prior when they were first onboarding the Google app, they went through and they just found bugs everywhere and
Much like I think this individual
Would have done is just mocked how crappy the software was
There were just bugs and bugs and bugs
everywhere in the Google app, okay, so
I
Again fast forward a month later
She's she's producing the streamline thing and she wants to get screenshots of what not to do
so she's like aha, I will load the Google app and
She loaded it. It of course had updated by that time and she failed to find
any of the bugs
that she had found earlier and
She she actually commented on
Yeah, it was amazing how how quick
they were I do not understand how they did that and I pulled her aside and I said
That is why Windows is having a problem
The traditional point of view when you're in a world where you have a lot of software in
your reaction time
Like when you and I grew up in this company in this company
Windows shipped every three years
Everything shipped every three years, right? You did not you had to get it right the first time
Did we ever?
No, do we have any idea of how much we got it right the first time that didn't matter
We have some like a
Episode or two ago. I talked about kin right that was last time. Yeah, that was a traditionalist
That started off in a traditionalist model
Right and it was an unsuccessful product
right
Would the company like to have had?
That time and that development money back you bet
We talked multiple occasions about lean startup and the metric that matters and the decision to pivot and persevere
This is what data brings to the party data
allows you to
Understand what parts of your product is being used
What parts of the product isn't being used?
And it allows you to scale the team by focusing your limited resources on
The parts of the product that matter. Yes
Yes. Yes
there is a
12 minute answer to your question. Why?
Data is critical to scale now
If you combine these with the other principles, right?
So this the the individual I was talking about before was amazed that she couldn't find any of the bugs in Google
Right. I'm not
Because I know Google instruments the crap out of everything
They worked through
When they saw errors coming in I know because I interviewed with Google years ago
Right. They have a two-week release cycle. They go to or at least back then. I don't know what they do today
Yeah, and again not Google in general says Google apps
Mobile apps in this case. No, but this was this was this was the Google philosophy all up
I don't know if it is still today
but back then
What they did is after the initial release they had
They would have an individual or team of individuals after the release
They didn't start working on the next features
They the after their release the deep dove into the telemetry and go what is the problem that we have now?
they're even smarter right because they
they follow the practice of
Continuous integration which means the number of bugs so you you you do end up shipping bugs
But when you do continuous integration you have as long as you have the right monitoring in place
As long as you have the right telemetry you end up turning around and fixing that bug the next day
I think that's the piece that's missing from the mindset of people who see it as pushing things off
Quick story on data then I want to read a tweet stream to you is
When I worked on the project that I refer to as a stupid science project to make Android app. Yeah, my windows phone
We had an offshore team of five maybe testers who?
We just gave them who would test apps just
Various Android apps they'd load on they'd side load onto windows phone
They'd run them reporting about they found so we could figure out what was up with our system
It got to a point to very very quickly where we said actually just stop entering bugs
Run the scripts overnight because we knew from the data every morning when we come into work exactly what bugs they hit
We knew where every single incompatibility was yep
It was faster for us to look at the data and figure out what the problem was and dive in and and fix the bug if we could
Then it was for them to enter the bug report. Oh, this is I know we have talked about this on multiple times on
Before we actually even started talking about modern testing, right?
It is absolutely my belief that the best way for testers right now to write automation is
Write the automation as low generators. Yes, and you their validation from the product telemetry
Let the telemetry be the Oracle
Yes
And I've always said in fact this may even be in how it does offer at Microsoft the Oracle is the hardest part to write
The part that figures out whether the test pastor failed let the telemetry figure out what's going on
Yeah, it's much easier because what I often ended up doing was but I remember having a whiteboard conversation in
1997 to discuss whether I could use get pixel to test set pixel and
I thought and what I ended up
You know taught at least whiteboarding would never doing was we whiteboard it out basically an implement a new
implementation of get pixel to test set pixel and and luckily even in my
Niamhiti was smart enough to think that was stupid
And you know why?
Because it was stupid. Yes, because it
Exactly, let me read you this is actually it's interesting you brought up that tweet because
To read to me because I don't know if you saw this tweet for me last week
Or I said I did see something relevant
Just because a team relies on customer data to understand or evaluate customer value or quality
It doesn't mean that the team is relying on that customer to test the product
To the people who keep saying the quota part of that sentence, which is the last part stop saying that then someone said
Analytics are great, but they don't reduce the need to verify correct system under test behavior before shipping
Unless your software doesn't matter much to people like a free game on your phone
And I said actually in a lot of cases example web services
It's much more efficient if my monitors detect changes and reject new code appropriately than if I took the time to verify correct
Behavior before shipping. Yeah, and
The reply I got back was how is it more efficient to break customers?
All the information is available to you before shipping. You just have to look and be smart about looking
what services do you ship broken and
All kinds of the point I want to focus on there is no you
Have all the information available to you you you don't know how the customer is gonna use your product
You could never know that and to quote Eric Reese
Show me a product that ships zero bugs and I'll show you a product that shipped far too late
Brent we will not be able to show Eric Reese a product that shipped with zero bugs
number one period
right
I'm sorry even even you know the simplest stupid tic-tac-toe app. I can guarantee you it shipped with bugs
right the and the reason why and
I'm bet you the developer knew it
The reason why is because they made a decision these bugs don't matter oh
Oh my god, really shipping a bug
So the Google thing so here's the secret here's the secret
customers want their problems solved and they want the least amount of time spent on
friction due to bugs
Okay, so code paths that customers don't use
Guess what they don't care. It's not shipping a bug
It does not mean the customer is broken. I know I know I know this reminds me actually I gave them presentation on metrics
Well at least ten years ago if not longer and one of the joke slides. I made was a
This is back when product is I can tell how old it was because remember had a mock-up of a product box
when used to buy software in boxes yep, and
For the bullet points in like bullet points of features like you know twice as fast as our competition
Whatever I wrote like a bunch of stuff customers don't care about like over 20,000 test cases run
76% code coverage
No customers don't give a crap about that stop thinking that customers give a shit about your testing effort
They don't they don't care about your testing effort. They want their problem solved
Yes, God and just get out of the mindset. I don't know why people think that
Again, this was ten years ago back then when tests last
Software and functional test teams were much more common still they didn't customers
Don't care what the testing effort was as long as the software
Allows them to solve their problems without making them want to throw their computer against the wall
Yeah
Right the reason why in the old days we would do all of this testing upfront is
Because we didn't have the ability to react right today. We do right we had we would wait
I mean the ability to react was wait for the bug reports to come in from the enterprise customers
And then eventually build a service pack
Right or a hot fix. Oh, yeah, if important a hot fix
me um
and
Here what I'm essentially saying is
Treat every release as a hot fix
Yeah
the
Ship frequently ship small look at the data to to describe to you where to go next
Let's get back on track here. I see you referring to your notes. So we're of one mind
So the angry part is over for now. So the key it start no, no, no the key why is
The data tells you where to focus. Yes
Yeah, and as we've talked about many times before
Speed is what's important in today's world. Mm-hmm. If you want to compete you need speed now
caveat just like everything else
We're saying this is the general rule
There are exceptions
Right even even in your current product, whatever it may be
There's going to be a set of
Hey
even in a small
Flight environment like with continuous integration you're shipping the prod constantly. I still recommend flight rings
Where you're looking at monitors and then you you you then slowly widen the number of customers that can get it
Let's move on and talk about a little about a little looking at the clock
What is how does the modern tester lead a team to do this? Like like, how do you?
How do you make your team use data in a way that that?
Closes gaps. So we we did episode 82. Yes, and that was actually a good prequel
So at this point you could pause go from the 82 and go. Oh, that's a good idea
Huh, so the how is actually covered really well in 82 you're right. It is in terms of
evaluating
Your your your product hypotheses and the in
That's what's important like we would rather
Test focus on how to improve the business
How to improve let's say the value or the revenue of the business
Rather than what they're accustomed to which is how to reduce the cost. Okay, but that said
You know
I don't know that any test team would ever do this. I think it would be really freakin smart for test teams to do this
But then so once their product ships, so let's say they want to go through and do the prescriptive and preventative testing model
once
Now go back and look at the data and
Try to evaluate how much of your time was wasted. How much of your time? Did you spend testing enough?
Testing a feature that got three users
still, you know go look at the place that got a thousand users and see what problems they're having because
That's probably what's more important. But if you go back and you go what miss if you take the product telemetry and say hey
Where did the
So but let's pretend well, you actually you're a test director. Okay, so
Our quality director
So yeah, cuz I don't care about testing. I care about quality. Yes
so but you still and I don't know if it's changed but as of
What was it a year ago when I came and presented to your team?
Right you had testers sure. Okay from a management point of view
You're accountable
For where your team invests its time. Yes
I
Your philosophy is to sort of delegate those decisions, but ultimately you hold the accountability
Like because you made a decision to delegate those decisions. Sure. I'll not disagree
It'd be worthwhile to go. Okay, where did your investments pay off?
Right. It's a few had a month-long test pass that was scheduled
I
Just I just threw up all over the conference room
It's hyphen never never again in my life. Would I do something like that? How dare you even mention that? Yeah, you may continue
All right. It's worthwhile looking at the data and then
Okay, so maybe maybe you're gonna go done down this this this path, right? Maybe we've opened your eyes a little bit to
Hey, there is a better smarter way
Maybe you're in a position where you're like, hey, how do I convince my executives?
Right the data helps you make this transition as well
You go look, you know what? I don't think this is the right way. I don't think this is the efficient way
For us to deliver quality software. I think we need to get continuous integration going
I think we need to get I did the data
right
This month-long test pass cost our business
Depending on the size of business like it wouldn't be uncommon and
For a month-long test pass that costs well over a million dollars just in payroll let alone the hardware costs
right and
Look, we got three customer clicks on this feature
Right. I don't think we're using our resources efficiently
The other thing is
Customer it is
not
true that
Shipping bucks of customers is breaking the customer
It is also not true that it's a violation of some unwritten test law
Also true in in the modern testing thing we want devs to be held accountable for code correctness
We want QA to be held accountable for the quality culture
and the delivery of quality and
It is definitely not the case that if is I could see someone responding to this effect is like
Hey, if just one customer hits the bug
Then it's a big, you know catastrophic problem
Catastrophic problems are things like customer does something and it deletes their data store. Mm-hmm, right or it corrupts their OS or
It publishes their credit card
Numbers to the dark web. These are
catastrophes and you
It is absolutely true that you should still continue to prevent though that type of code from going up into the wild
But a lot of the times the the product hypothesis is wrong. We've we have talked on multiple occasions
that
Who values your product often isn't even like in a v1 situation. This is very often the case who values your product is
Often not the customer you're targeting
Yeah, and again for the third time probably on this podcast will refer you the chapter 8 of the lean startup
With the pivot or persevere chapter with all the different kinds of pivots you may make based on what you learn from your customer
About how they use the product you learn from the data
Who your customers really are and what's important to them? Sure completely agree now going into
Into data I'll add
You know one one caveat
Right once you go into the data, there's a whole rich rural infrastructure on on this right privacy
You can go too far. I think once you start getting into the data world. I think we need to start talking about ethics
Yeah, right
We want from a quality world we want to
benefit the business by making our customers happier
doing things with the data that they generate that
If they knew about it wouldn't make them happier is a likely ethical problem
Yeah
But there are other requirements and then we know you know we
GDPR
Government requirements. So going into the data space does come with its own
bureaucracy
But it is vastly better particularly when you combine it with the other principles we talked about the theory of constraints
continuous integration it ends up being a less risky in a much better way of
of
building product quality. Mm-hmm. Let me our
Conversation so far reflects a lot on web services
Now we can ship multiple times a day and get this data very quickly and hypothesis driven
I want to talk a little bit about how these things apply to
slower
Shipped products. I don't think there's much of anything that ships every three years anymore
No, but if you're a product that ships I mean there is
Download fatigue from customers even with apps that they're seeing
updates every day for your app, although it can happen in an area in if you're having some bad bugs coming in but
There's a level of fatigue or ship
There's a level of download fatigue users can go through. So aside from that let's say you're gonna ship your product every two months
Two weeks. It's okay every two weeks. Thank you
You may
Have a brand new feature you want to get out because customers really need this and it's really easy for people to
Sort of hand wave around solving a customer problem by just saying a customer asked for this. They gotta have it
I gotta get into I'm gonna ship it and I say great ship it to them
Do you have how do you know if they're going to like it? We're gonna call them and ask them
Yeah, I would say if you're shipping every two weeks or especially if you're shipping everything
three months
But if you're going to ship something new because you think it solves a customer problem
You better damn well have the data to help you figure that out
I think what you may not be able to so on the data front, right? Sure call the customer. That's the data point
Another common thing is is either a proactive or a reactive survey
Sure, just understand that both of these things are considered to be very low quality data
Yes, and the point I'm getting to is
Sure, all this stuff works in a lot of the examples you see from talks on the internet and articles are around shipping web services
Or websites things that can ship and update where you can react very very quickly
But the point I want to make is even if you have something that can't react very very quickly
You still need to use your better serve to rely on that data to help you understand
much much more about
customer usage customer quality customer experience
Right and the other thing is I find
we started the podcast off with this sort of concept and I find that people take a
Take a strong stand on on a principle basis. So for example
You know shipping bugs to customers is you know, apparently
Just natively evil, right?
But even if you're in the situation where you where you only ship once every three months
That doesn't mean you have to accept
That that's the way it should be the next time we ship right? There are always ways to improve this
so for example, I I my phone is
an Android and
I've noticed that there are two different sort of update models. There is the
There there appears to be a model where an app will indicate it needs to be updated and
Android will will just silently handle that update for me
But there also appears to be a model where the app itself you launch the app and it says
Hey, I need to be updated and it didn't signal to the Google app management system
To do the update for me
right am
that in place app that in app update
That irritates me it should right the one where the app or the
Update happens, maybe you tell me after the update that hey I updated right
I got that one of these this morning said 14 apps were updated. So you're all cool. Yeah, then my
But then for me it seems like four out of five of the times I have to do the in app update
It's then a Wi-Fi required. Oh, I haven't and actually I've never seen that one. So
I would imagine it happens when the app needs an update, but the Google Store hasn't
propagated the update yet
Yeah, so in that particular case if I were an app developer and let's say it was Google's problem if it wasn't Google's problem
Then I would I would be looking at our code and going okay
How do we make it Google's problem because it is a better user experience in my humble opinion to just let Google manage the updates
but if it if it is already Google problem and so maybe
Maybe Google only does the update, you know once a day or does that check?
Once a day and and the app just updated three seconds ago
Right. The app is telling me hey, I need to be updated
That situation what I would do is is is talk to Google and say hey, how do we make this experience more seamless?
right the
You're right
customers have update
fatigue
But what I'm saying is that doesn't mean you stand on the principle and say we don't do updates
No, we figure out how to do the updates and we remove the fatigue
Absolutely, and you see all kinds of apps do that. It's pretty common now for apps to have an update or
To just download silently or and install patch style updates in the background. I think it's totally expected
It's okay, let's hear on Windows and every damn single one of them requires a reboot and that's annoying, too
Yeah, okay. Get my windows jab in. Okay
Let me summarize
Data is important. It it means you actually care more about the customer not less about them
It's actually a more efficient way to evaluate
the customers perception of value or customers
Yeah value of the product
one thing to bring up here is
People ask me what's different about modern testing versus agile testing and this it's a lot the same
It's a lot about whole team delivery. One of the things we really call out that's
not called out explicitly or at least not that much in the agile testing books is this use of data and how important it is because
You and I and people who believe modern testing principles and a lot a lot a lot of engineering teams around the world
realize that data is critical to
Understanding and using data is critical to understanding
customer quality and production
Using data, so you just made a point using data
It I forget how you say it but some of the lines of it is not actually harming the customer
It is actually better for the customer. Right, right? Am
And still and just because it allows you to
Scale up your let's say it's a pure traditional testing
Facility it allows you to scale up your testing resources on the things that actually matter to the customer. Yes
Right, you can help you target your testing. Yes
absolutely
Yeah, and what might maybe let me add this metaphor
Well, if you have time is in the old days way back in the 20th century
We may look at code coverage and we'd figure out where we had missing tests
And we still do this today in our unit test and go make sure we have tests for the areas that don't have coverage
We can use data in a similar way to understand if you look at customer
Usage patterns as a method of coverage. You can look and see where they're using the product and make sure
We have and actually that may help you target. Okay customers are really using this 30% of the product
Let's go invest some of that time-intensive intellectual exploratory testing there. How about this?
How about it? You set up an experiment that
Routes 10% of the traffic to a co coverage instrumented build. Yes. I've done that before
Right, and then you compare the co coverage of your test suite to the co coverage coming from your usage suite
Yep, fantastic
Now that means now you have a decision, right? Okay. Should you solidify where there's existing co coverage or
Do you fill the holes?
right, so if you see that that oh
This one one class is just used like freakin crazy
But there's a couple of lines of code that don't have testing right you maybe you you bolster up that unit test before you
You cover the test suite that that usage doesn't even hit right?
Matter of fact, I would I'll tell you what I would do in that particular case. I'd like hey
Do we have this feature turned on?
Right. There's this whole library that's not even touched
First off is it is it actually instrumented? Do we screw up when we deploy this thing? But assuming it is
Right. What is this code doing? Is it turned on?
if so
Okay
There's something wrong with it because customers can't find it customers aren't using it
Let's figure out if actually this is something we should continue. Yeah, that's an example of we're gonna look at the data and and
Prove or disprove our hypotheses on how we think the product works and it's being used
Yeah, the
You know another way of making
higher
Quality code here and talking about code correctness another way of making high quality code
one of my employees says and I like this the difference between a a
four star and a five star developer
five star developer
Doesn't add code. They remove it. That would be one attribute. Yeah. All right
Okay, I hope we have beat our opinions and thoughts on data and it's important into your heads and next time
We'll cover the to some not all slightly controversial
Principle number seven. Okay, I am still Alan and I'm Brent and we'll see you next time