Hello again everyone. Good morning. He's Brent. He's Alan
Welcome to another episode of a B testing happy to have you here. Good to see you Brent. Good to see you, too
I'm recording on a Monday. How is your weekend?
It was great. I finally won some points from the family
Did you just spend the weekend away from them?
No
Did you at this point in time? I still have my daughter who still likes me. Okay, that's good. Yeah, good. Just
Just make a bunch of food for them what you do. How'd you win some points?
I did actually make something about tell me about the point scoring system. I finally put the pool up. Oh
And it perfect time is supposed to be hot hot hot it this week
It took me two days to put the pool up
Yeah, because I could only stand being out
side doing
Manual labor in the full Sun for like an hour at a time
Well, there are things called mornings and evenings where it's a little cooler. I had the plan to do it in the morning
But my daughter got up and wanted to play and that sounded like more fun than putting up the pool. I suppose cool
This is episode 86 by the way
It is if you're new to a be testing this is the podcast by Alan and Brent that's the a and the B
Where we talk about?
Testing sometimes a lot of software engineering software quality
Of course modern testing principles have been the topic
For the last many many episodes. Yeah, you can go to modern testing org and read those
And we have been doing recently some deeper dives medium dives spending about an episode each discussing them
Drill ins drill ins we're gonna call them. Is that a Microsoft term?
Maybe maybe well, it's definitely management
Management-speak. I like what they say. Let's double click on that here that one. Let's double click and shift left
Let's I want to shift out
Shift out. I'm gonna just gonna drop. You know what I'm gonna do shift up
I mean, there's so many directions to shift I know and I don't have nearly as many meetings
In fact, I have one-on-ones and then like two or three other meetings a week
But I wish I had more cuz I one thing I would like to do cuz it's fun. You wish I'm sorry
No, no, no, you wish you had more meetings
I wish I had some bad meetings cuz I wish I I wanted it go like
You know to my car just just to go to meetings and have some of the bad ones again
Where I could just drop random buzzwords that mean nothing and see if they catch on
like we should shift out on that or
That'd be great
Hold on a second. Let's right-click on that and
And get some more context
Yeah, so the trick is to come up with something entirely new though. Oh
Yeah, yeah, cuz everyone's
You know, they're just evolving
Like why is it left shift? Why isn't it right shift? Well shift, right? Right
Correct. So, uh, I mean you got the double entendre with right. So if you shifted right
Right, the direction doesn't matter and you it could be implying, you know, you're going more correct. You're shifting to correct. Oh
It could be it could be so I need to think for a minute. What's that? What's like a computing term?
It hasn't been used in a managerial speak
I'm thinking something like a long lines of distributed networks. They're all the rage right now
You got big data, but you know if you try to invent something now, you're like five years too late
Alright, I'm gonna come up with those so you can send those in to the mailbag at a B testing
Sure yet another place where a B testing adds value to the world. We'll start creating whole new buzzwords. Sure
Sure, that's our that's our value to the world in between last time and this time. I
Spoke to the internet a little bit about
Modern testing again. I did an AMA and asked me anything for a Ministry of test and
I will there is a recording of it available
I will put in a link if I don't you can yell at me on Twitter
But I will try and remember when I post this show to put a link to the recording where I answered a bunch of questions
Hosted by our good friend Vernon and I answer questions about modern testing
Yeah, I went back and I watched that video first off it was your video I threw it worse
I forgot it's a video. So I totally shouldn't have picked my nose so much. You really shouldn't have
And it was shocking. I'm like, oh my god Alan's face. I'm like is the whole world ready for this
There's a reason we do a podcast. There's a reason we do a podcast
Yeah, mostly me but yeah
for sure
I am certainly glad I did not join you in that adventure because some of those questions were really hard
I'm glad you didn't join because you give really long answers and I gave longer answers
We got to the end Vernon tried to go rapid-fire, but I couldn't let it go
Sometimes right there was one time you were like no
And then I elaborated
We're going to dive into
principle number five five of seven and this is the one about the customer and
Surprisingly, there's a little bit of controversy around this one. We'll go into anything else before we dive in
You know, let's go to go. Okay again. You can read these on modern testing org, but principle number five says
We believe that the customer is the only one capable to judge and evaluate the quality of our product
Agreed. Yeah
Okay, and thank you for listening to a be testing
Yeah, yeah, that was one of your questions on on AMA
before we reflect back on that
briefly
Tell me and I'm gonna go to the controversy to the controversy the question, but before we do that, tell me
Why is this the principle? What why is this worth bringing up along with the other six?
The number one reason and I've cited this over number one
The I've cited this over and over again. One of the things that I think
especially
true for those of us who have been in the industry for a long time and
It is sort of seductive to believe that hey, I've been doing this forever. I know what I'm doing
You've seen a lot of folks along those lines
but there is a
forgetting is how I'll call it as I cited from Tom Popendike over and over again
No customer ever in the history of the world has ever wanted software
Correct in any way shape or form
What do they want before you go on they want their problem solved?
Absolutely. We need to remember that that means
There is a risk and I have observed this and I'm highly certain you have as well
that there is
trust in
the test community that when they're given a requirement stock or when they're told something from
their PM
that
That actually is going to solve somebody's problem down the road
A big portion of this principle is intended to force people to think about
What are they doing?
That is actually solving a customer problem theoretically
versus actually and it's it's to force the
The modern tester to go
No matter how right I think I am
It's still just a theory
It's a hypothesis. It's a hypothesis. You want to pick up? Yeah, sure. So what I've
What I've seen and to build on them
We can both reflect and probably anybody who's been doing software for a reasonable amount of time
Reasonable amount of time or any but probably a lot some of you
Maybe this week last week
You are on a team or you've seen teams who build software
Because they think it'll be cool
Or we're doing this feature because the we like it without often thinking about what problem are you solving?
It's amazing sometimes when you talk to teams and just ask them that question
What problem are we solving with this? They'll eat they'll use it that isn't solving a problem
And well, what's what's what's the customer value of this?
they'll use it and
Well, I've seen this over and over and Brent's laughing but you think about it. It's it's they're not quite sad because evil
but in my experience, but generally darn close I I've told the story for years about shimmery blue menus and
and
There was a time at Microsoft and this is a
A joke I used to make when I was teaching courses ten years ago
It's been a long time about shimmery blue menus because shimmery blue menus are not a real feature
I'm just these are my canonical example of something you're building because you think it's cool
But nobody really needs it and what happens is the program manager
Wants thinking about features they need to do they go what about shimmery blue menus
You know, huh? We should do shimmery blue menus and then someone will say
maybe we'll say
Problem does that solve and they'll say uh customers need it and they'll justify it
They'll go to a customer and say hey, do you think we need shimmery blue menus? They go sir, whatever
Customers are demanding shimmery blue menus. They're waiting for this feature. We got to go do it
maybe that's a little bit of a stretch, but there's so much reflection in my past of doing features and
The build it and they will come mentality field field of dream software. Yes, we're gonna build this thing and
We'll give it to you after a long development cycle and we trademark feel the dream software
and even though feel the dream is probably and in the end you will like it, but
Right, oh this part I've seen over and over again I have
This is hyperbole, but there is there wait hyperbole on the a B testing
Whoa, I'm gonna be careful because it's modern
We're much more modern world, but let's just say I
Don't know five ten years ago
it was impossible to have a conversation with the PM and not walk away with the sense that
They were the next Steve Jobs. Oh god, right? It's it's
requirements stock what a lot of the requirements stock is is built off of
Processes similar to what Alan just described. It is hey a customer
PM
they have their own day job to do and sometimes it's calling out the customers and
They will call out to one or two and and establish a pattern off of that
Now is that a pattern? No, of course not
however, their job is to get new features in and
If they they've encountered a new
Requirement that they could build upon that's fantastic
right that they're able to do add that requirement into the dock and and
Get engineering rolling now, it's interesting because you say shimmery blue
I've actually
Had to deal with that and it literally was blue. It wasn't shimmery
Years ago. I was an MSTV and Microsoft was building the software for Comcast and
Comcast rejected our our
Software not once but twice
Because we had the wrong
blue in our CSL and
And I'm like
Wow really
Yes, and again twice
There's a design choice there and there's plenty stories about Google trying out 50 different or ever in shades of blue
It was for their links for they chose the right one
In the case of of
Comcast right blue is part at least it was back then now they got this red black and white team with their Xfinity stuff but
blue
Blue was part of the brand Donna get ditched cable. I don't know. I was gonna bring something
Oh, I had a little I glazed over for a minute there while my PTSD kicked in on when just showing out
When the job his book came out or the first couple jobs books came out after he passed away. Oh
Oh my god, so many when there was one in particular
I'll finish my thought a bunch of people decided to start comparing themselves to Steve Jobs
Literally, and there's one high-level
Test director you and I both know I won't shame him on the air who who in a meeting
no
metaphor aside flat-out said
Because I'm making this choice this is what Steve Jobs do he basically called himself Steve Jobs
And that was that was like oh god, please please let it in please let it in but even Steve Jobs
I'm so whining back. I'm like
We don't know any test directors
Because they're gone
We did they were Peter principled up to a level far beyond the capability and since retired once
Once in the new world figured out they had no, you know, it's funny
I'm because we know so many of those folks and
Several of them are alike. I
Cannot guess who it is at the moment. I'll let you know off-air. Yeah
I have several guesses. Yeah, I'm pretty sure all of them having that conversation. I'm pretty sure I'm pretty sure you could nail it
wasn't Steve Jobs who when there was the
camera which iPhone it was but there was an antenna issue and
Wasn't he the one that said it's cuz they're holding it wrong. I don't think
That I think that was one of his but that's a great example
I mean it doesn't matter and the customer customer is the only one capable to evaluate quality and they
Can't hold the phone. However, they frickin want to hold the phone, right? Right
This is still prevalent
In today's world like I have conversations similar to this over and over and over again
This principle is essentially the modern testing version of the customer is always right
Perhaps perhaps and so let's talk about which it makes so much common sense, but let me play
Simon Devils advocate. I'm gonna bring up the controversy and let you there's believe it or not. There is controversy around
this testing principle
Probably this one is
Probably second on the if you're gonna rank them in order of controversy behind principle number seven
Some of you are going how the hell can this be controversial? But let me bring up a few points for you. So
Here's the easy one as testers
We are the customer
We're the last line of defense Brent. We're the only ones capable of
Sympathizing and making sure the customer is getting it. So really as a tester. I am the customer
No
So
Yeah, that that's a little bit of a softball, but no, I mean no no, it's just no you're not the customer and and
I'm I figured this part out years ago, but doesn't matter how much you're trying to replicate. Here's an example
Do you remember int int?
Remember data type no int the integration environment. Oh my god
There is a time early in the services world of Microsoft where there's this massive
Ridiculous integration environment that was done
It was people tried to do testing there and they wanted it to replicate production as much as they could and it never even got close
never ever ever ever and
and
They held on to the theory that it would
Hindsight 2020 I'm not at all certain why
But the biggest cause
And this was actually something that test played into it one of the one of the problems with with our
Automation
We would target automation that would deploy out in it and one of the biggest issues with it with a with a
non-prod int environment
Particularly with how automation was deployed is it was always covering
the clean room
Scenario sure and I have nothing against integration environments and doing testing in some sort of pre-production environment that there's
Plenty of reasons to do that
But do not ever kid yourself and think that your pre-production environment
Whatever you call it is a reasonable facsimile for production. Yeah, absolutely it it is
It simulates production environment exactly once in its lifetime
And even even then not exactly because it's not running on the same hardware
It's it's it's running differently in production. It could I mean, I mean that's still it's still possible
Do your teams at Microsoft use Docker? Did teams use Docker at Microsoft? Oh my
God, you know what just before coming in here. I was gonna I was gonna share with you off the air
around
Dude, I don't understand how we got stuff done back in the day without containers
because that that Docker has been one example where it's
Containerization has helped with test environments making them much closer again for one time only
But giving you a much closer to production environment as much easier and quicker to set up and tear down. Yeah containers
my experience with containers
they keep talking about
Those of us in the cloud industry we keep talking about
That it's some future date
Compute will be the fifth utility
behind water and electricity and
So
You don't have to spend much time with containers
To go. Oh, I see how that's gonna be possible
containers
They just work and they just do the calculation that you want them to do
Right and it's just like whoa. I didn't have to configure crap
I didn't have to yell at IT for rebooting my container. I didn't have to do any of this
No, like it's just friggin fantastic
From a platform side and from a developer side. I will say
That does create problems for us in the cloud industry
Because we have this sort of generic
compute interface at the top, but yeah underneath it it's running on different pieces of hardware and and
Each component and that hardware could be could be
very different
Right. We have a new generation of hardware in Azure
And it took us months to realize that there was this one
memory chip vendor
who had
poorly manufactured it for us to figure out that that was what was causing these containers would
To reboot even though they shouldn't
Let me really back in to the customer. Yep. Ask another question. So
What if so testing is not the customer testing is not the customer and that
Above and beyond everything is what we want to get across
Okay, but but but but but but but but okay my I have a B2B business
So is whose mic so I'm meaning I business to business
I my software just for the listeners who may not have heard that acronym before
but so I'm making something for another business to do something with or and then they have a
customer
Who's like which one's my customer?
What are my choices?
this business I'm delivering software to or
maybe the
Is it who I'm delivering it to or the end customers? Like is it the end user?
like if I'm giving a
platform to some company and they're using it to build software for
Maybe their internal systems or maybe for an external customer
How does that work?
Who is who is my customer? How do I figure out who my customer actually is?
In a platform situation that can be challenged right because you when you're a platform foot. So for example
Unity I want to bring it up directly. I'll let you do it right unity is a
I'm sure you guys I think it's a little easier in our case my customer. Well for most of it the vast majority
This is actually a good question unity holistically our customer is the developer the developer making unity but not in every situation
You definitely have two customers. We do we do and in the B2B play you also definitely have two customers
Right in the case of unity
Developers who want to design games
They don't have to go to unity
There are what five to ten major game engines out on the market
They don't have to go right your company. So what differentiates what differentiates is the capabilities and
Well, so there was a long experience could be capabilities and features or ease of use lots of things. Yeah in
one of the in one of the
Analyses I would do at your company is
Go and look at okay
How do we grow the attach rate of of the developers on the unity platform? How do we once they once they try us out?
How do how do we get them to stay?
How do they get how do we get them to engage with us directly on on on feature requests?
This actually was the Microsoft play back in the 19 early 1990s. Sure
Right. Um, it was we got the developer we got the world
but the other aspect is as well is
These developers are building software
for end users and it's that end user where
Ultimately
Your guys's paycheck comes from correct. Well, I mean
Yes, ultimately yes, but it's a you can draw a feed you could there's a nice feedback loop there
Yes, we need to enable our developer customers to give
Their customers something world
Value awesomeness and then that feedback comes to them and then comes by us
Do you can I can't draw it on a podcast but there's a nice little there's a nice little loop there, right?
If your platform has performance issues
So for example in
Or if our if our game engine components crash
right, you're not
You're basically going to be a platform that gets abandoned because the the developers who are using your platform
Can't make their customers happy. Correct? Correct. So in that particular case
The two sets of people who are your customer are your developers and are the developers of your platform in
True and I think it's gonna be the same for and the end their customers
They it's gonna be same for I would imagine that's the same for any sort of business to business type thing as well
any any place where it's essentially a platform component that's
Indirectly talking trying to think where it would be difficult to figure out who your customer is, right? But I
Honestly, if you can't figure out who your customer is if it's that difficult I
Think is a deeper problem there in your software company. I
Yeah, I think I can understand why it would be it could be difficult to get feedback from an end user
but here
But there are still ways right it
There so in a B2B play let's let's say
Actually, this was this was big news recently Walmart and Azure are joining hands
we
You could it's very easy to see
That
Walmart competes with Amazon in the retail space
Azure competes with Amazon on the cloud space
So does does Microsoft want Walmart to improve and and winning in their particular market you bet
Right now
That's probably the as far in the details on that particular topic. I can go into on any of these indirect things
On a platform you live and die on the ability of the people above you to satisfy their customers if you don't have direct customers
Now one of the things
That I've seen on the B2B discussion is oh no
So so some company comes down and leads on requirements
And I'm just gonna say anytime anyone delivers
requirements
You're better suited to treat those as hypotheses
Let's let me loop this back may need to deliver on those requirements because the contractual agreement. Let me just finish there
but
That's the bare minimum and you should be gathering
Whatever data you can if you think one of those requirements is baloney
You should be gathering whatever data you can and go back to that contract and say hey
We actually think our relationship is better going in this direction and here's our
information that back set up
One of the things I think can help
Someone a team practicing modern testing principles or someone leading the team in that direction to
Really nail this principle is to have those conversations around things like requirements talk about
Or ask what is the problem we're solving? Yes, and
From that requirement and may change from that. I think requirements end up being a lot versus
being a lot of want to versus need and
asking questions like
What problem are we solving will help will help vet that out?
There's a question our good old friend and sometimes listener Jim Moore used to ask all the time
But someone would would get come to him with some long request
Or some complex request something they wanted
He would follow up. This is a great question
So imagine you had all that what do you do with it?
And they give an answer and from that you can figure out what they really need and go. Okay. Could I just do this instead?
Oh, yeah, that'd be great and and you need a
Team following modern testing principles who embraces this principle are going to be very good at asking the questions
Whether they're around a requirement slash hypothesis
customer request from a forum for example
customers engaging online tend to be a
Just loud majority of your customers but not representative of all your customers. So you don't just want to make them happy you want to figure out
What customer problem can we solve so learning how to ask questions around?
Problems you're solving trying to understand need versus want can really help make your team excel at this principle
For sure. That's my brief little soapbox on this. Yeah
For me the best thing I have found is anytime someone has communicated
requirements
To me I will echo back the requirements, but I will use them
Okay, so what you're requesting from me
I will change it to the word requests in my communication back and then in my thought process
I view the word requirement and hypothesis as synonyms and
I find that that last aspect whether or not you do it publicly or doing it privately
I think that aspect is actually really
important
Because it'll it forces you to consider
That you may be doing work that does not achieve the ultimate goal and that
Goal is where all these precision questions that Alan just referred to come from
There are many times where I have been told what to do and in general that is because that's that's that
Individuals best gets as to what can be done
And I have found that more often than not
That if you can decompose that and figure out what it is that they need
Mm-hmm now sometimes
You'll do exactly okay. I get what you need and yeah, I can't think of a better way of doing this for sure for sure
In in my scenario with you know, they're coming to me to do it generally because I'm the knowledge expert. I
Know more things about this space than what they do
Which gives me the opportunity to go. No, I think actually what you need is this. How about if I do this instead?
what you end up doing when you really execute on this principle is
You solve customer problems in priority order like what's the biggest problem you understand
What's the biggest problem we can solve for our customers and you solve that you help that you help them solve that
and you move down the list so
It's as much about
Misdelivering quality
by or
delivering value to the customer by
Solving their most and most important problems first
Yes
Now let's talk about scorecards
No, let's not
Okay, fine. Let's talk about scorecards. Thank you. I know it's one of your least favorite topics
but I think it's I tell stories about why I hate them so much, but let me
But go I think I think we should talk about it right the the if we're saying the customer
so the controversy with this principle is
What is the definition of customer? Okay, and what we're saying?
It is a human who is taking a dependency on what you are
releasing and
That human is the one who's making a decision as to whether or not it is quality
Okay
So if you have a business to business
Contractual agreement that's not a human who's taking a dependency. That's a piece of paper
Now it may specify
Hypotheses around this and the maven specify legal consequences if you don't deliver on those hypotheses
But just recall that there's still a hypothesis
Now we could have a scorecard that says that we delivered on it. Okay now
So let's say you delivered a scorecard all green and it released to the wild and you're in this B2B scenario
You still run the risk
Because you delivered what that other business wanted instead of what they needed
You still run the risk that they pay you for your contract and then leave you
Sure, because and there are probably I didn't dig any out in advance
But anecdotally from my experience I can tell you this happens or happened frequently or not rarely
Not yeah, not really. I've seen this happen as have I
Trying to remember that stupid phone product Microsoft built Oh kin. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. It was kin. Yeah
That was that was a required. It was essentially
Someone or some set of someones had this idea of
producing a a
Hybrid dumb smartphone
Yeah, right. It was smart enough phone, I guess. Yeah
It was where we could keep the price point super cheap and the target tweens sure that's talk about it was for right
This is a great example of building something that doesn't yeah building the wrong thing
Right now the if we were part of the business team and doing a retrospective on this
Right. We would want to go back and go. Okay. What could we if
We've now learned that the market doesn't want one of these things
Right. What could we have done earlier?
to come to the same conclusion
During that time and I ran the last test pass on kin. Yeah, I did not know
And you're still I didn't just flat out fire the whole team
That's why I ran the last test pass. Oh because we had
It was a special deal with Verizon
Verizon wanted had all of this hardware stock and they wanted to to sell it out
And so though yeah after yeah, so they changed they changed some of the software
To turn it into this is after I mean, this is a product that was out on the market for a week or two
And then just given up on
And I want to literally spit state. I literally ran the last test pass
I literally executed the very last set of test cases on this one and this was me as a back then
I was a test manager
But it was one of those things where I wasn't going to assign it to one of my ICs
Not if I wanted to keep them on the team, but what a great example of just shipping the wrong thing
This is well and that's part of the the learning lessons here
Is
We did ship the wrong thing and we spent a lot of costs and if we had gone back and we had said
Okay, the customer is the only one qualified
to make a judgment call here, how can we
How can we test our?
Hypotheses here
Much sooner much. Yes
Yes, before going all in on this this is maybe the canonical example of field of dreams engineering
Yeah
now there was
We were in transition back in those times a lot of the lot of it was a very
predictive
software development
But that doesn't exist anymore. I know well now I did want to merge doesn't need to exist
I think that back we don't have the infrastructure requirements to force a
Get it right the first time when your delivery dates three years from now, right? That's just that's
Foolishness in today's market it is I was just gonna note that it's incredible that
After the failure of kin that Microsoft was able to turn things around to become a world-class phone business
Yeah
Yeah, you know so I don't have any
Information here that's not
public knowledge I keep seeing news reports about
the surface phone
right, um
And I keep I'm curious about this this one because every time something else comes out. It still does not
claim
That the project's been abandoned
Right and the M. I'm curious about that is like, okay
so if we're not abandoning it are we going down some sort of intuitive route or
Have we learned from our our prior mistakes and there we leapfrogging?
And I really don't know. I don't know either
I did want to there was a little state if I don't think anyone on the business team listens to the podcast
But pretty sure they don't if they do
Like if it doesn't directly contain say the Android app store or
The iPhone app store. Yeah, like what are you doing?
so I think we've made our point that
Absolutely customers important we as modern testers or people driving modern testing principles need to help our teams figure out
what customer problems were solving and
Drive the team in that direction and talk about some different ways we can do that
Anything else on this topic talk about asking the right questions prioritizing
Treating it as a hypothesis that that your work should prove or disprove
You can go with a negative aspect and say I'm not going to just trust the requirement
But you can also think of it from principle number one
Hey, so this requirement stock is a list of someone's
Hypotheses around how we can build a better business
principle number one
test is not just
Test is no longer just a cost
Reducer no, we're looking at we're also looking at how do we drive revenue?
Mm-hmm. All right
so with these hypotheses in play
Okay, and and with our knowledge of
What makes customer happy and what solves the customers problems?
What can we do to?
Prove or disprove these hypotheses and the ones that where we gain knowledge. What can we do to grow those?
The biggest aspect I think of modern testing is they shift to
being a
More active portion a more active participant in the business and are concerned
with growing that business
It's not about
Preventing customer harm anymore
Certainly, that's important. It's about how do we if the customer is the only one qualified
to define if it's a
Quality software situation and the quality software situation as we covered here over and over and over again
Sometimes customers care about bugs. Sometimes they don't
They care about their problem solved. Correct. How do we how do we take that and
help the business
Grow faster. Yeah, I think its principles a lot about just
Re-emphasizing how important that customer prioritization is in order to make quality software
There's a there's a model a bunch of variations of this that show
The CEO at the bottom and then managers and then individual contributors who are making who are making a lot of decisions
And then on top of that the customer
Yeah, so the customer leads the way and being able to drive the team towards
recentering the team I guess would be a good way of putting it of
Continuously recentering the team around the importance of the customer and the importance of solving their problems
if there's anything around
This one that I would say we
The test community should walk away with is we are abjectly saying
No, an end user is
The single most important in an indirect situation
There may be other people's opinions that are important on if it's a quality but ultimately it's the end user who's benefiting from the
From whatever you're producing
your solution to a problem
number two test is
Absolutely not a
Representative of the customer they are not the customer. They should stop pretending to be one
For sure. I think we're good. So thanks again for listening. We'll dive into number six next time. I am still Alan
I think I think so too. All right great. Yeah, whatever. See you next time