Hey everyone and hello Brent.
Hi Alan, how are you doing?
I'm doing great.
I am actually feeling excellent given the fact that I just flew in from Reykjavik last
night.
Landed around 6pm.
And what foreign country is this in?
Dude, you have the geography knowledge of an American.
You know, someone's got to keep the stereotype alive.
The Reykjavik is the capital of Iceland.
Oh cool.
I knew it was the biggest city in Iceland and I knew Iceland didn't have that many people
but I wasn't prepared for how small Reykjavik is.
What could I compare it to?
I was thinking about that the whole flight home.
I took a picture so I could think about it some more.
I don't know what the population is, I'm not going to look it up.
One of the three can do that.
But I was like in the tallest building in Reykjavik with 8 story hotel.
Cool.
And it is small.
I don't have a good comparison.
It is amazing how, this is probably too philosophical for our podcast, but I find it amazing how
life always seems to find a way.
It does man.
Right, you're in the middle of, there's multiple middles of nowhere where suddenly communities
just start popping up.
Yep, yep, yep.
Hey, I was in, I got to do the right segue slash pin here because I was there for a meeting
with my manager and my peers to talk about people and how they're doing, go over some
strategy stuff, basically a two and a half day off site.
Probably the best off site of my entire career.
Was there candy?
Yes, in the form of fermented grapes and a glass.
Oh, well there you go.
Not only are we super aligned on what we're doing, I mean, if there's one thing I could
go to improve the last three days, was I'm a big believer that great innovation, actually
this happened at one time, that breakthroughs happened from disagreement and having an argument
people you trust, it's okay to have that argument.
I think great things come from that.
Now that I think back, one of the great insights we had and the thing, this idea
that just exploded upon us as a few things converged, did come from argument.
So, wow, it was great.
But one thing during the people discussion, I want to pin, because something came up that's
highly related to the principle we're going to discuss today.
Okay.
So I'm going to go make a note on that on the whiteboard so I don't forget where we keep
our notes.
And then, Phil Miam, what have you been up to since the last recording of A-B testing?
Oh, by the way, A-B testing is ...
One of the things on my backlog is to actually record a proper intro.
I think I'm going to change the music and do a proper, fancy podcast intro.
I don't approve of changing the music.
Okay, I'll figure something out.
I got to figure out how to ... I want to do a proper intro for A-B testing so I don't
forget to say crap and we can just start off talking about crap.
Are you going to do your best practiced DJ radio voice?
A-B testing.
A-B testing, let me tell you.
Wow!
No, no, I will do something though.
Anyway, if this is your first episode, probably not the best place to start.
Although if you want to listen, go ahead, because we're talking about modern testing
principles out of the podcast.
We talk a lot about software development, software quality, software testing, Agile
software, leadership, management, bunnies and squirrels, and this thing we've been
talking about for the last, holy crud, like six months, eight months, a year, year and
a half?
At least a year.
A thing called modern testing.
And modern testing isn't modern in the sense that it's flying cars, it's just modern
as compared to traditional testing.
Anyway, I'm going to let you read the back of the Kim Koehner book while I go
put a note on the board.
So, Brent, what have you been up to?
Nothing much.
Okay.
Yeah.
All right.
There is very little excitement in my life at the moment baseball season's done.
You mentioned that last time.
Yeah, I know.
You've talked about this before.
Agreed.
Things I can't talk about, I mean, there is a lot of really exciting stuff happening
on the work front.
Yeah, I got some of that too.
Well, at least in mind I can chat with you a little bit about after we stop
recording.
Yep.
And you probably have secret stuff because you work at a big secret company.
I'm sure you have secrets too.
I do.
I have plenty of secrets.
Oh, I have stories to tell.
Yeah, I can't bring them up now.
But anyway, sorry about that.
So your trip to Iceland, was that a work trip or a?
Were you listening to me?
We just had a three day off site in Iceland.
Oh, right.
No, I generally don't listen to you.
Holy fudge sickles.
Man, what's the name of the podcast?
It's the 88th episode of A.B.
Testing.
And why don't we just dive right in to the seventh of the modern testing
principles.
Is that cool?
That's cool.
All right.
You can read modern testing principles on modern testing dot org.
And this is maybe a record and that we're only about six minutes in once I edit out
Brent's brain farts.
And we are actually talking about the topic of the day, which is fantastic because we
have a whiteboard full of notes.
OK, number seven is the one that to me is becoming less and less controversial.
Just absolutely makes sense.
But it still causes a few heads to turn.
What do you mean to you is less your observation is no.
In my context, it's like it's making where it made sense before it is rock, freakin solid.
You could not convince me to back off on the second part of this one, which is the
part that people see as controversial.
No, we're going to dive into that.
I feel like I'm talking around it.
Let me read it and then we'll talk about crap.
You have a place you want to start from notes on the board so we can get now start with
reading the principle.
OK, here we go.
Principle number seven.
We expand testing abilities and know how across the team, understanding that this may
reduce or eliminate the need for a dedicated testing specialist.
So with this principle, we can focus on the first half and this ties in with principle
number four about the quality culture and driving the quality culture on the team.
But where this one is different, this is about for me, make sure on the same page
here.
This one's about making sure the team knows the test approaches, test techniques.
They know teaching them that bugs lurk around boundaries, teaching them how to design chips
for designing test automation.
Let me take a different approach.
OK, let's just take the controversy head on.
But I dude, I said let's take care of the first part first.
We can talk about why the controversy isn't controversial most of the episode.
But what is the essence of how does this maybe you're going to get to this.
But I am all right.
I'm going to let you go.
But you kind of principle seven.
Yes.
So the question to me is essentially it's the final straw in I think the modern testing.
Well it's the final principle in the modern testing principles.
But the observant amongst the most observant readers of the modern testing principles will
notice that we don't actually address testing until principle seven.
That is true.
And what principle seven is essentially stating is the modern tester doesn't test.
In a way.
Yeah.
Because again I stand by our statement that modern testing is a transient role.
I'm sorry a modern tester is a transient role.
Meaning they are someone who helps the team adopt modern testing principles.
So for me essentially what number seven says is everything else above is executed so well
and the quality culture does cover some testing as well.
But the team understands testing well enough across the team spread throughout the team
that they may not need that dedicated testing specialist.
It's a culmination.
There's purposeful and developed and careful overlap between the principles.
They build on each other both sequentially and randomly.
But number seven as you mentioned it's the pinnacle.
It says if you are a team following modern testing principles and I remember modern testing
isn't about testing as much as it's about how you approach quality in software development.
It's modern testing as opposed to traditional testing.
And if you follow those principles and the team gets what testing and quality are you
may not need a dedicated testing specialist and that makes perfect sense.
I think in this episode you're going to be playing good cop the entire time.
Therefore I will play back up.
One of the comments one of the pieces of feedback I've seen a lot of people will read
number seven and run the risk of bit flipping the whole modern testing principles.
I agree.
And saying oh my God.
Brent and Alan are just on the same.
They will say we don't respect the craft.
Or no we're on the same meme.
This is what I'm talking about the same test is dead meme.
And one of the things I want to say is that I'm actually we're not saying that.
I have said I think it's on its way and the thing that I will say is in this particular
case you can you can either be the butterfly or you can be the wind.
So those who interpret this as a test is dead message and respond from fear like the one
thing I will say on that front is like first off fear actually isn't real.
This is super philosophical but fear isn't real.
It's about what might be not what is.
And so the intent on this one going back to the first half of your of the principle
is like no you can control your own destiny.
If you if you understand the prior six principles you will understand that your job and your
business is better suited by you taking up the role and spreading the knowledge of how
to do the testing activity.
And as that testing activity is spread throughout your organization not only will the business
benefit but one of the consequences a testing specialist just won't be needed.
One of the things I've noticed from those who dig in their heels and say this is who may
reject this principle or modern testing principles because of this principle is there is a belief
among many in testing and I'll interject and get my stack correct.
I am happily blown away by how many people agree this is the right direction or tell me
we're already doing this.
Thanks for putting a name for what we're doing.
It is not some fad that you it's not an echo chamber of you and I talking about this
thing.
It is actually happening.
It was happening without us.
We are just trying to put names to the things we see that are happening and encourage others
to go in this direction.
So the fear or the worry I see the biggest thing that comes to me from people who are
digging their heels in on no is they believe that testing skills are a unique thing that
is only learnable and practiceable by people with a unique mindset and people that do
specific areas of practice and they believe that they are I don't want to say special
snowflakes you may but they believe they are uniquely suited to software testing and that
skill that the developers programmers of code do not have the right air quote mindset to
do testing and what I've found what what shifted me over this direction was I found
that teaching developers to test was not only not that hard it was fun for me and it
was fun for the developers I worked with I have done this now on three different teams
and indirectly so now I went through two teams of teaching developers to test and now I am
teaching people to teach developers to test and it is it works developers can learn to
test it isn't a unique unteachable skill that needs to be done by a dedicated specialist
you know I've been doing this now for so long I'm beginning to forget what it was like when
I held that belief like to me is just absolutely clear in my mind that testing is an activity
and not a job yes right and for me from a business point of view it's a testing activity
that dev not only should and can but must do and when I say must I mean there are so
many product related benefits by getting dev on this you end up with a much better design
of the product there's accountability and ownership they're like oh yeah I thought of this test
I want to do this test but accountability ownership just quite honestly I'm gonna say
that those are useless criteria I don't think so when people think of something themselves
they want to do it more the biggest problem I have with accountability this is an aside
the biggest problem I have our podcast we're all yeah the biggest problem I have with
the term accountability is that so I have pay attention to simultaneously the word choices
people use and then I pay attention to the actions that are associated with those word
choices and what I've come to conclude is that when people the majority of people use
the term accountability what its purpose in life is is to publicly identify who to blame
when it all goes to shit and I don't care about that no I care more about self accountability
I'm not talking I'm not talking about yeah I'm talking about self accountability when
I mentioned that so yeah I don't like that either the I don't even associate that word
that way anymore so the way I would phrase it slightly differently is that once the devs
understand this they realize holy crap it's actually not as hard as they thought right
because actually at this point in time the testing has been around for so long there
are multiple devs that have been in the in their arena or in their discipline for decades
that have never actually owned testing and so to them it's this mysterious burden but
when they realize when it gets demystified what you find is that no it's a benefit to
them because it allows them to control their own destiny allows them to reduce surprises
at the end of the milestone it allows them to control you know how many sleepless nights
and weekends are working and gain confidence that when they did their check in it's done
and it's not coming back yes right and so these are these are all strong benefits to to
the actual developer whether it informs you know creates accountability or ownership I don't
know that that's really important but what I do find from the human condition what people
want is to control their own destiny and that's exactly what I'm talking about right
they want to be the wind they don't want to be the butterfly yeah and I could reiterate
and say exactly what I'm talking about so we yeah I want to tell a meta story about
modern testing it's going to lead into this okay I realize that I have to it's actually
going to be beneficial to tell the meta story so of course I talk about modern testing a
lot on this podcast I have never once gone to my team and say here is modern testing
is what we're gonna do some listen to the podcast hey everyone they go yeah we want
to do modern testing but what I do on my team instead is make sure that the principles
not in name like follow this principle but it guides what we do and we've been focusing
a lot recently on the quality culture and and not just on my team across all of unity
one of the things we discussed in our offsite last week is how our people in QA our testers
they are accountable and to use that word again for nurturing as we say in principle
number four that quality culture yep and we talk about the quality culture a lot and
people and they get that everybody everybody all of unity QA is on board with yes we
need to improve the quality culture and here's some approaches on how to do it I
talked to them that's worked on my team everybody's fully on board that's good so one
of the things that came up in the offsite we had a people discussion it's not like a
Microsoft stack ranking we just talk about what people are doing how they're doing the
twist on this is on the potential category we talked about people's potential we talked
we framed it a little bit around how well around leadership skills and how well they
could drive a quality culture or modern testing principles across the org so
that's the main part on how I push or guide the team towards modern testing
principles both on my team and outside of my team but I had it I was a little
afraid to say it out loud but I did and I wasn't too afraid I want to see what
would happen I was ready for a discussion but I when talking about one
of my employees I said pretty much something like this blah blah blah they're
working on this and this is probably the first person on my team first person on
my team who probably won't do any testing as part of their day-to-day job
and everybody got it I said okay cool yeah I didn't have to explain that
nobody went what's the it was like okay cool that's great no the I see I see
why you think they're great that's awesome yeah no the fact that you are
basically saying this guy is probably going to be the first across this line
and when that happens that is a win for the business right in the fact that that
seems to be universally understood unless your leadership team does what I do and
that is ignores you when you're talking no no no we are good at calling we are
good at calling each other out I think if I would have said that six months ago
in our meeting there would have been more discussion but in this case it's
head nods oh that'd be cool yeah awesome it's like you doing the right thing
there yeah that's that's great to see in terms of this stuff I mean that that
might be relevant what do you think what do you think because what in
principle seven we're basically saying you know what it doesn't matter if
testers is dead or not you doing this shifting the testing activity to the
whole team especially the development team and removing the the bottleneck
around the testing specialist that benefits the business sure and what you're
saying is hey you got tacit agreement in your business that either they observe
that or they seek or they observed the promise of it which do you think it is
and how do you think you got there I got there because we took off we loosened
the tourniquet versus ripping off the band-aid we talked about this before
where many teams have failed moving to a no tester team is by ripping off the
band-aid and blood spurts everywhere and people that yep metaphorically this
has been a very gradual change and I believe that's the reason it's working
and I believe that's the way it will work for 99 or more percent of the teams
out there the gradual change in your in your pace of gradual can be more or
less than mine but it's worked because both on a individual level people
reporting to me on the teams they work on and then on my overall management
team and the weird part is I'm in a separate basically division from the
rest of my peers so we don't overlap that much at all okay so it's
services are for the most part just completely separate from there's part of
my org that overlaps but largely separate so they have begun to see what's
going on over here on on my team over over on my team and begin to adopt some
of those things but I think as far as my peers accepting that was just seeing
me we've been talking about quality culture across the org together I think
they see it from that they get where we want to go what building a quality
culture roadmap has helped me to do we can maybe dive into this in a future
episode is it's it's a framework or a model that's worked to get everybody on
the same page with what we want quality to do across unity and it's again I
haven't it's a model all models are wrong some are useful but it's helped
to drive even teams outside of mine towards something that looks like modern
testing like you saw a rough you saw an early draft of this yeah this is what
we're working from no and it reflects many or most of the modern testing
principles and moving from the left to the right in the for better for it's
not the right word for the maturity model I built no I know and I think we'll
probably end up talking about it on the podcast because I think it's a good
follow-up like this you know episode seven or the series that we're doing
right now is around what the hell do we mean when we say this right right I think
in the next series of follow-ups will probably be more practical around hey
this is the phase this is what it means like again it's this whole concept is a
living yeah yeah breathing thing on it although I will say in advance I think
we better do a mailbag episode 89 to catch up on a lot of questions I agree
then we'll figure out what to do after that but what do you think was there
anything so I get your approach I get the strategy but for the listeners like
what is when you if you were to do this all over again knowing what you've
learned now because you were kind of also making it up as you went along if
you were to go back and say okay if I were to start this all over again what
would have concretely been your first goal given that you were trying to ease
into it I'll have to think for a minute while I talk but my gut reaction is not
much it wasn't as much as that I figured out what I was doing when I went
along of course I always adapt and adjust as I go along what I've done as
I've moved along is tried to document how I'm doing what I'm doing maybe I
would have dove into building that model earlier a lot of it the reason that I was
able to spit that out the reason it's been pretty adoptable without a lot of
editing by a large part of the team is because it was all in my head first
well so yet so one of the things that I know it explained what was in my head
so I had to sometimes it to dump out what you do intrinsically for people to
understand it and you understand definitely had a vision yes right and
over the last year plus I think we've put a put a name to that vision in
combination with what you're doing now as well as my own experiences on this
front right your experience is you slowly loosen the tourniquet right yeah my
experience I guess it was it was a band-aid rip right right but in I was able
to succeed through it because I had testing experience and several of my IC's
had testing experience so like one of the things I think helped me deal with
the the band-aid rip is with the fact that I was in charge and I had this
balance experience yes and that would help too so one thing to keep in mind is
and again I go back to the phrase from heffetz disappoint people at a level
they can absorb which is also loosening the tourniquet at a level you can
handle there are parts of my org in fact a big chunk of my org where things were
going fine we had the right leadership in place both from executive leadership
as well from people on the team that knew what they were doing that we did
eliminate the test role so parts of my team we've done that and was the right
time it's worked out very well I'm not and I know which parts of my team that
will happen in next and I know which parts will take a while longer but it's
so my role is a lot about keeping an eye on how much bleeding is coming out
on the tourniquet continually loosening it to keep the metaphor going and
finding out when the right time is to take it off completely so I'm parts
of my team it's just a very gradual experience to make sure we get it
right and parts of my team were there and I've done it and eventually as I
mentioned before on the podcast if I do my job right and we get this far I no
longer have direct reports and I do something different I unity I have a
hypothesis here okay and it's it's entirely anecdotal and based on what
I've observed over the last couple of years here at Microsoft and I think it
potentially aligns with what you're saying I do think this push towards a
combined engineering model is unstoppable the unified engineering sorry thank you
unified engineering model is unstoppable it will eventually be more common than
not but that means a lot of companies teams are gonna go through transition
and my hypothesis presently is when you do that and you have a separated
discipline you're gonna have a different ordering or you're gonna have a set of ICs
on both sides and a set of managers on both sides and the task is how do you
intermix this my hypothesis and I will say it is absolutely untested or
unproven but my hypothesis is if you form this up and you have a former dev
manager as the manager of the team now you have to take the the the boil the
frog approach but if it's the other way around and you put the test manager in
charge as long as he's worth his salt and management no I think I think you
can rip the bandy I that's my hypothesis I think that could work um the they may
not even be the the test manager I think a leader you need it need a leader with
the experience on the team so probably the manager but one of the things I'm
doing on all my teams is making sure we have those leaders in place to help
work directly with everyone on the team to make sure they know what to do
because right now we have dev managers in place I think is fine
dev managers in charge which is fine but they need you know this is what I did
this is basically what I did on my last couple teams at Microsoft I was the the
quality guy yep air quote and my job was to make sure that everyone did the
right types of testing and eventually we did some of that for them through some
vendors but long story so yeah I think your hypothesis is correct you need it
doesn't work if you don't have people on your team who deeply understand testing
to help with the transition no yeah for a while for a while you need a deep
specialist to help the team become generalizing specialists and I'm now
thinking through why do I think that when you when you if you do the reorg
model where the former dev manager is the one that's still in charge why do
you need to to ease the frog or boil the frog it's essentially because you're now
actually also you not only need to also teach the dev the new development nice
he's or the new unified engineers you know how this quality culture works but
you need to teach that guy or gal what is the measures that now defines success
because in some regards it's gonna it's gonna fly in the face of their
experience right a lot of the times is you know how how accurate are your
estimates right right but now you're actually making that guy a little bit
more holistic and when I found actually is is test managers moving into that
role already get the dev side of it yeah right I believe that's true and that's
that's that's the modern tester role right so let me talk about DevOps for a
minute and this again I will I will dive jump it on the outside and send her
back on the world some company did a survey recently that irked me a little
bit because they and I have I have semantic buttons that you can push on me
all over the place not as bad as some but bad enough so they're talking about
DevOps and they were surprised in their survey that only 50% of the teams they
surveyed had dedicated DevOps teams and I thought what the fudge sickle because to
me too high or too low well to me as I learned DevOps and I studied DevOps
DevOps is a culture it is but you could have a DevOps team that would help the
team drive towards that culture so what I tweeted a while back which I think is
relevant here they said after reading that I said I'm in the DevOps is a
culture not a roll camp yet I'm only slightly annoyed that there are DevOps
roles or teams as those people in teams are there to create a culture of DevOps
on the team eventually the team will have a DevOps culture and not need a
DevOps team yeah so I don't correct I don't need elaboration so then I tweeted
again and I replaced one word see if you can tell the difference I'm in the
quality is a culture not a roll camp yet I'm only slightly annoyed that there
are quality roles or teams if those people or teams are there to create a
culture of quality on the team eventually the team will have a quality
culture and not need a quality team WTF is the difference you just replaced
quality and DevOps but it still makes sense yeah I guess the only problem I
had with what you said is if you had said everything and said the word test
but you're right I don't think you need a quality role either so going back to
that survey to me it's I think they were if you take it from a more
respectful point of view and you go okay this company whoever did this they had
some expectation that the majority of companies that had DevOps were in let's
say the first maturity phase of going to a DevOps system right in that first
maturity phase it's brand-new knowledge yeah you need to bring in
specialists you need to bring in experts no I and I can teach the others
yes and a lot of the times that experts gonna be doing the lot 80% of the work
because it's all a bootstrapping effort yeah it's bootstrapping and leadership
absolutely it's bootstrapping and leadership which leads to a question I've
heard about this which is a good question I think with an obvious answer
based on what you just said at least in my opinion I've had people ask me
hey angry weasel they say because that's what they call me a lot of people do
yeah a lot of people do so let's say I have a team that gets to a stage where
they don't need a dedicated testing specialist and we go on for a while and
there's turnover and the team changes and that knowledge of testing is lost now
what do they do well one you retrospect on why that knowledge of quality and
why that knowledge of testing was lost on the team and figure out what what to
fix doesn't just shouldn't just go away but two maybe maybe you do go back and
bring in a consultant to your higher you don't go higher a test team because you
forgot how to test but you can bring in a air quote modern tester role to help
you get back on track right it's same as you'd hire a like oh man our DevOps
went to shit sorry sorry I to answer it's got already really you do it
again yes right but but I think you're absolutely right because in that scenario
it's hypothetical right because I'm like how would this suddenly how would this
knowledge suddenly just yeah I don't I don't think it was a hypothetical
question right if you do it right in a way you go from a modern tester helping
the team transition if the whole team understands modern testing principles and
we don't do this stuff just for that the modern testing principles aren't
important just for the sake of following principles they help you make better
software yeah there is like if you are kicking butt on the principles nobody's
gonna want to go backwards god I want to do so much testing it was more fun when
customers were bitching all the time it's been a while right where I brought
up the the monkey's experiment which there's debate as to whether or not
it's actual experiment or just a modern a sub s fable but this is the one where
with the monkey's and the latter electric shock and the and yeah yeah yeah right
and where essentially there is social pressure to conform so once you have
built up the quality culture and it's and it's achieved this it's tipping
point and it's now part of the subconscious most muscle memory of how
your team does business how does that go away well the only way it goes away is
if you get rid of all the people who have learned this muscle memory and
start new or isolation if you have the same people and suddenly isolation comes
into play hopefully that's because of some business imperative that's temporary
but if it's not then you're out and get rid of it again and one thing to be I
want to be clear on is modern testing principles or modern testing as we talk
about it isn't a huge leap forward we've been doing agile for a long time pretty
good at it few holes then Crispin and Gregory the agile testing books fantastic
talk about them all the time it like okay that's how testing works there they
talk about the whole team quality approach we're just essentially taking our
experiences and what's worked and extending on that even farther and
doubling down on the whole team approach yep and raising the value of the
importance of data so there was a Twitter feed or a slack channel
conversation I forget which at this point in time where people were like yeah
this is all all you know pipe dream philosophy so and then the thing is I
completely ignore those things because even though from their point of view it's
theoretical for me it is long since stopped yes yes no for the thing to
again we're in a little bit of an echo chamber here if you yeah if you're
listening to this episode you're nodding your head going yes yes but what has
been interesting to me and I mentioned Caner's book earlier because we walked
into our recording our recording studio and someone had left a copy of Kim
Caner's testing software in the room so it just kind of funny to see where we
come from traditional versus modern testing yes but for everyone that's like
you know pipe dreams and dumb and you know this is wrecking testing or
ruining the craft the number of people nodding their heads and saying things
like we're already doing that or I had there was one person I mentioned before
on the episode where I'm sorry on the episode on the podcast where they showed
my talk at test bash and to their dev team and the devs said things like it
seems like common sense to me yeah it should it should be common sense we're
trying to just like I did with the culture stuff that you've seen on my
team we've tried to take things that we have been talking about in essence
boil them down to principles they've tried it to document what it is we're
saying so you have to listen to you hours and hours of podcasts to kind of
get what is it we believe about where about where quality comes from that is a
whole additional philosophy I think it's something we should just go deeper
and on that the first thing is in my view if you look look back and think
about the summation of the modern testing principles what we see is hey
there is a lot of value in this community in terms of its ability to help drive up
customer quality and that there is a lot of value in driving up that that
customer value to the business we also see number one testing is is on its way
out I'll just say no way don't split that way testing is not on its way out
no testers testing specialists that that's it is on its way out testing is
still necessary thank you for that correction but the business more
benefits at this transitional stage by us sitting with the developers and
helping them to own it yeah and then us doing something that's even more
valuable pursuing value versus reducing costs and going all right now how do we
take our strengths and our skills around customer advocacy make them real and
focus on what actually makes these customers happy what actually pisses
them off and carve a new role for these folks yeah yeah and to be clear as I
mentioned this person on my team who I said would be the first person to
probably not do testing as part of their job I'm not firing them they have
they are still a testing specialist they are there if a testing expertise is
needed but they're focused on some of these other things that bring value to
the customer and doing some feature work as well there is another thing that I've
observed so now I'm gonna have asked you to go back to the days where you
still worked at Microsoft you and I survived and there hasn't been another
big hit to test but that's mostly because at Microsoft test is there's still
some pockets but it's mostly gone but in our careers here we went through major
several major transitions to the test discipline right sure one you know get
rid of the manual testers to there's a several others I'm forgetting but the
one pattern in you and I actually talked about this long ago in in the test
architecture group that used to maintain one of the things we observed is that
after a year or so after that transition all the doom and gloom that was
predicted didn't happen no it didn't not only that but it caused a lot of
sensationalistic tweets from the outside looking in it did but not only that the
people who went through that transition personally ended up better fitting more
sure right we saw that they were considered more credible we saw
promotion rates as a community as a whole actually moved right shift that is
correct and in this case it's no different what we're saying but I'm
actually saying is it doesn't make sense to own this anymore that seems to
be the trends if you are a modern tester and you are leading this
particularly if you're in a manager role start working with your guys and
easing them into the transition and give them a new place for their career to go
and that new place is a more positive one yes and I think like I'm repeating
myself here but if you're worried about your you like I like the principal but
all my job to go away I like testing still I would expect none of my team does
more than they all do far less than half the testing on the team from that point
it's a sensible transition where they do less and less the only parting wisdom I
would say on this particular topic is within Microsoft and I know because it's
it's now documented I saw the signs of this occurring around three years before
it actually occurred right because I saw the where the momentum was going I saw
what would be the obvious conclusion and I also saw what the bottleneck was
the bottleneck was executives were unsure and they needed someone to show
the way and I knew that once that occurred it would be rapid and I had
people come back and accuse me of being prescient and I'm like no I
wasn't foretelling the future I just analyzed this hindsight 2020 though
during that phase I spent a lot of time arguing with people who who held on to
white knuckles with their current thing and I realized now that I was pretty
much a waste of my time so some people are going to merge into it some people
are going to be open and spend your time influencing those but I would recommend
a three strikes your out rule on the folks that are just defending the set
as quo you can't save everyone and the ones who don't want to be saved your
time is better spent on investing in the ones that yep do one hopefully that's
good one parting comment is we want to do questions next time about modern
testing principles around data around anything you want you want to know about
color my hair is I'll tell you it's the same color it's always been great a few
more gray hairs in there you can either join our slack channel and go to anger
weasel.com wack AB testing and find that or you can just email me at Alan at
angry weasel calm and I will make sure your questions hopefully get answered on
the air yeah all right I'll bet I got the code next time mail for sure we
give that a shot all right I am Alan I'm Brett thanks for listening we'll see you
next time