in the testing podcast with your hosts Alan and Brent.
I am mindless agile robot I must iterate.
This is the place to discuss software development,
software quality and testing, agile, leadership,
organizational change, and of course modern testing.
You can read more about modern testing
on moderntesting.org and join our Slack group
in the link on the same page.
Now on with the show.
Hey Brent.
Hey Alan.
We are back for another episode.
We are.
There's no number, oh 91.
91.
Hey what do you think of that new intro that just played?
Yeah that was great.
That's time travel because Brent's heard it
but he hasn't heard it in context.
But you've all heard it now.
Let us know what you think.
Or not, whatever.
Yeah is it too much reverb?
Probably a little bit too much reverb on my voice.
We can tweak that later.
We can take a listener.
We'll let the three decide what they think
of the new intro.
The nice thing about having three listeners.
Yeah.
It's either unanimous or majority rules.
Sure.
On any voting decision.
This is great insights from a math professional.
Holy crap.
Yeah, yeah.
What have you been up to?
So we have a big hackathon that's in place for support.
As I think I mentioned in the last podcast.
That's kind of, that's one of the places
where my team is focusing on data science.
We're doing all kinds of cool things
with natural language processing.
NLP.
And I did a presentation last Wednesday
to a bunch of folks.
And very first question I asked is,
okay, anyone here ever worked
with a data scientist before?
And there was about four people that raised their hand.
And I looked at the four people
and became very clear that I was the data scientist
that they had worked with before.
And so I changed it to, and that data scientist wasn't me.
And they dropped their hands and I said, okay, great.
The positive thing about this is none of you will know
when I'm lying, which got a brief little chuckle.
And then I clarified, I'm like, okay, no.
There's some data science slides in here.
Just making sure that I have to communicate these concepts
without using those terms.
That's why I asked the question.
But it was interesting.
So I did a data science presentation
to a bunch of people who didn't have data science,
got a lot of people coming and talking to me after it,
which we've talked about, imposter syndrome.
This is the sound of me nodding my head.
Yeah, that was, I went home that day on a high.
I'm just like, so I didn't actually lie to anybody.
I got my concepts across and I got a lot of people engaged
after the conversation, after the presentation.
So for me, that was just a massive presentation win.
Cool.
For someone, oh, and the other thing too
is all sorts of people came up to me afterwards
and they were like, oh my God,
that is one of the best presence.
I've seen, the majority of PMs can't do presentations
that good and I'm like, yeah,
I don't know what to do with this feedback.
My presentation self-esteem is still too low for me
to be able to accept it, but I appreciate it.
What I found as we segue this conversation
to talk about me is that people really appreciate
practical, pragmatic advice.
So I'm guessing your presentation had some of that.
It did.
See, I turned that from me back to you.
I was gonna go to me, but I bounced back.
I'm gonna make it shift back to you very quickly.
Ah, damn it.
But I do actually, here's a lesson I learned
a long time ago.
I'll just ask you a question.
What is the number one goal of a presentation?
It's entertainment.
That is 100% correct.
You are constrained by the content,
but the presenter, your job is to make that content
as entertaining as possible.
That is the point of a presentation versus a document.
Damn.
Now I'm having like...
Acid reflux?
Oh, something's going on inside because I'm thinking
of the opposite of the presentations
where people just read a bunch of slides to you
because they've turned their presentation into a document
that they read to you.
Yeah, I attended a class years ago.
He calls those brick slides.
And one of the things in his presentation
is what he calls the squint test.
So when you look at a slide and you squint at it,
you should still be able to sort of
have a glimpse at the message.
So he's a big fan of...
I forget what they call them, but the shapes.
So if you're about to message sort of a journey,
there should be something that has
like little blocks and arrows.
Yeah.
Whereas bullet point slides with massive amount of text,
they look like bricks when you do the squint test.
All right, anyway, what's up with you, Alan?
Well, I was gonna segue that back to me.
I was at Star West, got back on Tuesday night.
I was just down there to do a workshop.
I went down early, went to Disneyland, that was fun.
Hung out, worked all day for my hotel room Monday.
Gave my presentation on web tools,
which is just me leading people
through a bunch of my favorite Chrome extensions,
showing them how to use Wireshark and DevTools
and Chrome and Firefox and a little bit of security testing.
So it's a flash through a bunch of stuff,
but I massively screwed up.
I looked at the little piece of paper on my table wrong
and let them out for their coffee break
as the coffee was being put away.
They weren't nearly as mad at me as they should have been.
And then afterwards, a similar thing,
I had a bunch of people come up to me
and say this is the best tutorial I've been to ever.
Honestly, it was fine.
I think a lot of times in testing,
people forget that there are many, many new things to learn.
So the goal, in addition to my entertaining stories,
ranting on UI animation, for example,
and the idea that technical testing means UI animation
through a couple of directions.
I ranted on that for a while.
Wait, wait, for our listeners.
For our listeners.
So the segue I gave people go,
testers need to be more technical.
And by technical, they mean they need to write automation.
And by automation, they mean they need to write UI automation,
which I think is stupid.
So we talk about a bunch of tools they can use
to make their lives easier, a little bit of scripting,
but just a lot of different stuff.
So pragmatic, practical things.
The goal is, I tell them at the beginning,
the goal is that everybody can go back
and find three or four or five things
they can use back at the job on Monday,
and they usually feel like they can do that.
The other thing I did is I'm giving this workshop
one last time, next week, at PNSQC.
This exact workshop?
Well, I'm gonna tweak it a little bit
based on what I learned,
but pretty much the same workshop.
But also one thing I did at Star,
and I'll leave it in there for PNSQC,
because I will never give this workshop again.
I just slapped a Creative Commons license audit
and said, if you ever wanna teach this to yourself,
if you wanna, in fact, I told them,
if you wanna just do this at Star next year,
I'll help you get to submission in,
because I'm done doing this workshop.
No, just you beginning the explanation.
So I've now worked with you.
It is a 101 level course.
I've now worked with you for long enough
where I can pick up your body language,
and you're like, doing this workshop is an obligation.
It is absolutely not something you're excited about.
I don't like doing the same thing more than once.
And I don't like workshops in general,
because I kinda like to adapt.
Even my presentation style is adaptive.
I would rather change things based on the context
of what people wanna do.
A couple years ago, I gave another set
of presentations at Star, Alan on testing.
Those were fun, because just be doing whatever.
Of course, they wanted me to prepare slides.
So I think I did Star East first and then Star West.
It might've been the other way.
But I prepared slides, and then what I did
for that entire workshop was I went,
I just took sickies.
What do you guys wanna know about?
What do you want my opinions about?
What do you wanna learn about?
And we put them on the board,
and we con-bond them, we prioritized,
and con-bond them out and went through them.
And then it was fun.
A couple people though gave feedback and said,
the presentation didn't match the slides.
And I thought, W, T, capital, exclamation point F.
So what I did, this was interesting how well
this worked out and how similar people and challenges are.
I redid my slides based on what I presented at Star East
in the pure ad hoc manner.
Did the exact same exercise at Star West
where I asked people what they wanted to hear about.
We voted on what they wanted to talk about.
And the slides, not perfectly,
but pretty well matched up anyway.
So that was fun.
So I like doing presentations like that
where I can just-
A la carte.
A la carte, much like a podcast.
Yeah, the one thing I was actually thinking
as you were talking, another thing that you and I,
I think are, and I think we've even talked about it
on the cast, there's so many different ways
to separate people into one of two things.
In this one, so often you hear people talking
about starters versus closers.
And-
I wouldn't say often, but yeah, I've heard it.
Go on.
All the time.
It's like daily.
Yeah, I heard it on the radio today.
Oh, nevermind.
I've listened to the radio in years.
Anyway, go on.
And I think you and I are mostly starters.
We both recognize we're not exclusively,
we're specializing generalists
or generalizing specialists, one of those things.
And starters just are allergic to repetition.
Yes, oh my God.
And one of the things though I've learned
that's fantastic is when you make an investment,
when you've captured 80% of the profit,
it's essentially, and here, I mean in a generic sense,
but it applies to real investments.
But like what you said with a creative license,
you've gotten out the value you care to get out of it.
But there's still plenty of value in that content
for someone else who wants it.
Always, when you do a handoff, don't get greedy.
Always give something for the next owner to...
Yeah, and to be clear, I want to...
Get rewarded by it.
We have a lot to talk about today, believe it or not.
I don't know if anybody there will take me up on it,
but Star did ask me if I would present this,
again, at Star East, and I said, no, I would rather not.
But if any of the three want to,
I'm happy to give you the slide deck,
give you the link, walk you through what I do,
and I'll help you with the submission, whatever.
I'll even, if it's...
I'll probably just endorse you, if you don't mind, at Star.
So if anybody wants to do it, just let me know.
Ping us on the Slack channel.
Which you can get to if you go to ModernTesting.org
or Angewheasel.com, WAC AB Testing.
You can find a link to join our Slack team
and hang out with the other two people.
All that said, shall we get on with the show?
Hey, we just finished topic number one, didn't we?
We sure did.
And we're gonna do something a little bit weird.
We're going to do our mailbag session
early in the show today to make sure we get to it, I guess.
Sure.
All right.
Mailbag.
Do you want to read it?
Do you want me to read it?
I got it up.
Is it too many big words?
No.
All right.
I think I can cover this.
I will let you try it.
All right.
Go ahead.
This is a question from Nicholas Shaw.
And he asked, you've both been in the technical field
for a number of years and seen a number of transitions,
both industry-wide and personally,
or in personally, sorry, looks like a comma.
I wonder how you stay invigorated by the field
and ensure you enjoy coming to work most days.
I'd especially be curious if reinvention
is the key to this.
For example, Brent's recent foray into data science.
I'll let you answer this first.
Okay.
All right.
I don't know if it's reinvention as much as its adaptation.
One of the things I love about what I've done in the field
or my approach to the field
and really what's kept me interested,
this actually, we didn't plan on this,
but you know from me that I hate repetition.
I hate inefficiency.
The thing that's kept me invigorated is that I've-
I also know you hate idle.
Yes.
The thing that's kept me invigorated
is that I've always been given,
or at least in the last almost 20 years of my career,
given a green field to play with
and knowing that big part of my job
is to discover what work there needs to get done
and then go work on that.
And then always knowing that there are new things
for me to discover.
For example, I've done a crap ton of different things.
At Microsoft, even though I was there for 22 years,
I probably had 15 different jobs.
Brett used to tease me about changing jobs every 18 months,
which was, which remained remarkably accurate
even though I denied it.
But it was always for a new challenge, something new.
The moment I got bored,
and there were very few times I got bored on a job.
I was very bored working on that science project
to make Android apps run on Windows Phone.
But for the most part I had exciting-
By the way, I still get feedback from random people going,
man, I do not understand why Microsoft canned that.
And I'm like-
Think about it.
I do to some degree, I understand.
And turns out my podcast partner was on the team.
Yeah.
As a tangent, there was no way that could ever ship
and our PMs were just idiots, just freaking idiots.
They thought, they were adamant.
Yeah, people that have built Android apps
will just want to be in the window,
well, because Windows Phone is so awesome,
guess what, they all came from Windows Phone,
that they will just want to resubmit their Android app
to the Windows Store with no testing at all.
And it'll be in the Windows Store.
And it's like, think about this, just think about it.
Look at your market.
Oh my God, it was idiotic.
And then we had the Windows Phone developers too.
And while I'm on a tangent rant,
the number of times, this is Windows Phone, mind you,
I'm in a meeting and there's somebody
making an idiotic decision, I go, why are we doing that?
Hey, we did this on Windows Phone and it worked fine.
I just face-palmed the shit out of my head.
Okay, so anyway, the thing that keeps me invigorated is
there's always something new to learn.
I have written features, I've fixed static analysis issues,
I've implemented, I've done a ton of work
fixing build systems, I've written test frameworks,
I've written testing tools, I've written adapters.
One of the coolest projects I did on Xbox One,
which was a lot of fun, because you're building an OS
kind of based on Windows or adapted from Windows.
And this was a, gosh, this is a long story,
but I'll make it short.
Often in Windows, you would write programs
to elevate the process.
You wanna grab an admin token or an administrative token
and elevate the process.
I had the opposite.
We had these modern apps that would only run
in session one as a guest account.
So I had to take a system token running in session zero,
all look up sessions, and de-elevate that token.
Do the opposite so our test could run properly.
Because our test harness ran at the system level
with full privilege, but we didn't want our tests
to run there because users don't run there.
So anyway, that was, I know, I knew,
I've forgotten most of it now, thank goodness,
I knew a ton about the Win32 API,
just from all the compatibility testing
and API testing I did on earlier versions of Windows.
But that was a fun, fun challenge.
Had a lot of, eventually it worked,
as far as I know, it's still working for Xbox One.
One of our Xbox One listeners can tell me if I'm wrong,
but that was a fun project to do.
So I like just figuring out what the holes are,
what needs to get done, and it could be anything
from technical things to project management,
to testing, to development, to solving what I do more of
in my, probably the last five years,
is solving people problems, which is fun.
So what keeps me invigorated is that if I do my job right,
every day has a new challenge and a new way to learn.
And that's what keeps, and learning every day,
that's what keeps me invigorated.
I'm gonna generalize it.
So I can't pronounce the guy's name,
we've talked about it before.
I, well, Chevallet-
Oh, the Flow Guy?
He's Flow, yeah.
Yeah, okay, yeah.
Usually we say Shama-
He's got like 30 character names with like three vowels in it.
First off, I will share a little brief perspective
about me, where I come from, but I will also share,
this is not a born in attribute of me.
I have actually taken this and I've mentored folks
and I know it is teachable.
The old phrase, turn lemons into lemonade,
is 100% true in this case.
So every time some big change occurs,
it is absolutely true that humans will respond
with a great sense of fear.
But those who can push down the fear,
as I mentioned several episodes ago,
the problem with fear is fear is not real.
Fear is the, fear is about what might be, not what is.
But is this such a strong human instinct
that it's just natural for people to freak out about that.
But for those who don't,
and realize that every time there's a change,
there's an opportunity.
I kind of equivalent to what Alan is talking about
for the part of my career, every time I change teams,
what attracted me the most were the teams
that I knew nothing about.
Because for me it is fun to say,
it was fun for me to go and figure out
how I could make my prior experience benefit
this new thing that has nothing to do with,
with anything I've ever done before.
And every single time I took on that challenge,
I won that challenge,
and I was able to create something new,
which excites me, but also new to that team.
Because most teams are very deeply focused
in how they've always done things.
So when you get a fresh set of ideas coming in,
it ends up being an accelerant.
That's stuff I love.
The important thing I would say here,
in terms of our discussion of modern testing,
is that we have gone through multiple transitions.
And Alex, or not Alex, Alex is my son's name, Alan,
years ago, actually did a great deck on this.
And one of the things that we realized
is literally every single time we went through
one of these huge transitions,
the most common feedback was,
you know I was afraid of it,
but my role is significantly more rewarding
than it was before.
Every single time.
True, true, true.
And I think we went through three, four major transitions.
One of the most common bits of career advice I give
employees, people I mentor, is not constantly,
but every once in a while, at a frequent pace
throughout your career, you should be in a place
where you're scared, you're not sure what you need to do,
and maybe you're worried you might get discovered as a fraud.
Because when you're in that position,
you're forced to learn, and as you crawl out of that hole
and begin learning and figuring things out,
that is invigorating, it's exciting.
You go, oh my, and it's a huge, it's a stair step,
not a linear growth, it's a stair step growth
in your personal and professional career.
The only caveat to that one is
you want it to be a healthy fear,
or a healthy motivator.
So dangling the carrot.
I do admit, you could be so scared you're afraid
to go to work, but uncomfortable is I think just fine.
Well, uncomfortable actually is perfect,
and that's what the flow guy says.
You want to-
Chickset me high.
Say that again?
His last name, Chickset me high.
I have the inability to prove or disprove that,
so we'll go with that.
His first name is Mihai.
That one I can do.
Mihai, Chickset me high.
All right, well done.
I'm sure the three will correct me if I'm wrong,
but I'm pretty sure that's it.
What you have to pay attention to is two things.
One of the reasons why we're talking about MT a lot
is so that, so as most of you are aware,
Alan and I are, we can't really say when.
I'm still paying attention to a tipping point,
but to at least me, it does seem
this is the direction the industry is coming.
What we're doing is we're trying to get the word out
so that when it hits you, if it does,
but when it does, it's not a surprise.
You have time.
You have time to train up.
You have time to grow yourself
so that you're very prepared.
Alan and I were talking about this
within Microsoft three years beforehand,
and we very much saw how the wind was blowing,
and I had multiple people.
When it actually hit, I had multiple people come in and say,
damn it, I wish I'd listened to you.
I have no doubt that there are people
listening to podcasts that might post that
when that time comes.
Our goal, so fear plus surprise
constructs an irrational response that is not productive.
As long as it's sort of a healthy fear, great.
Ideally, fear motivates people.
My preference is that people figure out
where they wanna go and target that
instead of what they're trying to avoid.
But this ties into the theory,
and we can move off the mailbag after this, I think.
The Heffetz book I mentioned all the frickin' time,
leadership on the line, has the quote that I use
way too often, but it's worth it.
Leadership is disappointing people
at a level they can absorb.
And there's a diagram or a discussion,
I can't remember what from the book
that talks about an organization, not just the person,
but we can talk about it in the organization level.
If an organization or a person, I'll add,
is complacent, your productivity,
actually your interest is down,
therefore your productivity is down.
If an organization or a person is too uncomfortable,
they're at that boiling point, they're freaked out,
they're frozen, they're not getting anything done either.
Works true for the person or the organization.
What you wanna do as a leader,
and what you wanna drive yourself to do,
is live at that simmering point
where you're slightly uncomfortable,
but you have an idea what you're doing.
That is where productivity happens at an organization,
and that is where growth happens as an individual.
And then if you add in some sort of program
that boosts employee engagement from a positive angle,
because happy, uncomfortable employees
are absolutely the most productive.
Yeah, for sure-sies.
Yep.
I can't believe I just said that.
So thank you, thank you very much for your question.
If you have questions, you can email them
to alanandangrewiesel.com,
or join our Slack channel and ask there.
But thank you very much,
and we appreciate those.
Little bit of a transition here.
You mentioned that we're getting the word out
about modern testing,
and one thing I wanna call out is
for those of you not in our Slack group,
for those of you, maybe the fourth listener,
if there ever was one, I can't imagine that happening.
Dear God.
I'm a little freaked out and blown away
at how many of the three
are sharing modern testing principles
with their teams at meetups,
and how much the MT Army, should we call them that?
Or maybe- No.
Okay, the MT Clan.
No, the Clan's not right either.
We'll figure out, hey, three.
Okay, the three.
I'm happily surprised-
Wait, I wanna, I do not want to associate MT
with any sort of thing that is based on
an irrational belief,
because I think that's one of the biggest problems.
Yeah, I'm just, you know words come out,
and then I go, ah, not the right word.
So anyway, how much people are sharing
and giving us the feedback and sharing what they've learned.
We just added this morning, we, meaning Salty Gunner,
just added a lessons learned channel to our Slack team
to talk about lessons they've learned
from rolling out these principles.
I'm just blown away, happily blown away.
People are looking at these and sharing them.
People have posted to the group
and posted to me privately,
things they're doing, what's working out,
the feedback on their team.
There have been people that have
shown my Test Bash video to their team,
and had discussions based on that.
Amazing, just, I'm, wow.
So, that said, I was invited to be part of a webinar
yesterday as part of the Test Masters Academy
webinar series, and I think the topic was something,
I forget the exact title,
but it was talking about modern testing.
Okay.
And modern testing round table.
Big M or little m?
Well, in the title it was a big m,
in reality when I joined the call,
it was a little teeny itsy bitsy m.
Did you notice Lisa's tweet yesterday?
No.
She talked about modern testing,
little m, little t, and double quoted.
All right.
I'm like, hmm.
Huh, hmm, huh.
Yeah, exactly, hmm.
So, this was an interesting round table,
or panel discussion, because I thought it may be
about modern testing, capital M,
and it was about what people,
I mean, it was about testing
and random future testing stuff.
So, I was definitely shaking things up.
We had four of us on the panel.
One person was your very typical test manager.
At the point, I won't go in order here,
but the point where I mentioned,
some of my teams no longer use a bug tracking database.
He just about crapped his pants and said,
that just will not fly.
You have to have that, it's necessary.
Another person, test architect, sort of roll,
I think that might've been her title,
was all about, this was Microsoft 1999, 2000,
we need to architect automation frameworks,
and all the testers need to write automation all the time.
And then one person, even more traditional,
and oddly, been in testing since 2003,
and was very, and again, nothing,
how shall I put this?
Because I'm not ranking on waterfall,
but that's what modern testing.
That's my job.
Well, put it this way, that's what modern testing was,
and I said modern testing is an antidote
to the discussions around traditional software testing
that are popular in the 90s and before,
where the testing was done at the end of the product cycle.
Yes, where the testing was done
at the end of the product cycle, quality was tested in,
and we're talking about modern testing
as a way to combat that.
She had Migo, the moderator had Migo first,
and then as I'm talking, I'm watching,
the other presenters kind of go,
and I never saw so much head shaking
while I was talking in my life,
throughout the whole webinar.
And very much embraceable,
I have a product that requires waterfall,
and waterfall's not a bad thing, and blah, blah, blah,
and it's a great, own it, own it, own it, that's fine.
Both of those statements are false,
I'm going to assert it, and I don't know anything about,
you do not require waterfall, and it is a bad thing.
I chose my battles,
but I was firm to the principles of modern testing.
Did you meet it in a room, or was it like a,
No, virtual. Four-way virtual.
Four-way virtual.
And it was fun.
And it was good.
I would love to do, I could do one of those
every single day, I don't like giving that many
presentations, but someone's put me on a panel
of people that are from a more traditional background,
and the most closest, the closest to modern from the group,
there was one of the test managers said they did Agile,
but it was all focused on iteration, iteration, iteration,
and nothing about actually learning and adaptation.
So, but it was fun.
One of the things, maybe the final question,
I won't go through them all,
I don't think there's a recording, and I'm glad I did it,
it wasn't what I expected, but I'm glad I did it,
and I had fun.
Oh my God, it was fun, because after a while,
after watching all the headshakes and the disagreement,
and it was just kind of fun to just talk about what I see.
And the last question I was asked is,
what is the, we're all test managers or leaders here,
what is the feature of the modern testing manager?
And I go, please, please let me go first,
please let me go first, please let me go first.
Alan, what do you think?
I said, my role is to work myself out of a job.
I have, I joined my current company with 45,
whatever people are working for me throughout my organization,
I'm down to about 12, and I say within the next three,
six months at the most, I will no longer have QA
reporting to me because I think it's an inefficient way
to run a modern organization.
I added some more stuff in there, it's like.
And the waterfall guy said, oh, he said,
I agree with you, and at a good answer,
he said, I agree with you, we all should be working
ourselves out of a job, but I don't know if he believes it
in the way I believe it.
No, so.
And I wanna talk a little bit more about the last question,
because I was thinking about this since I said that,
so again, another reason I love this
made me think about why am I doing that,
and what makes me feel like that's an okay thing to do.
And one thing I've done, and I may have mentioned this
on here before, and I do have, for a transition,
I have one other comment from the presentation
or the roundtable to talk about,
but I realized that as I coach,
I coach my team on leadership and how to influence
the developers they work with to embrace quality,
to write tests, to embrace the quality culture.
At the same time, I meet, along with them,
in a lot of cases, I meet regularly with most or all
of the dev lead that I work with regularly.
And I realized, in retrospective, that I treat them
the way a traditional test manager may treat a test lead.
So the dev leads I work with are my virtual test leads.
When I talk to them, I find out what's going on in the team,
we'll talk about how things are going,
whether they feel, it's like a one-on-one,
but then I'll also have questions about quality,
and what's your approach to quality here?
What do you think you can do better?
What are some things you think you can do better?
I'm treating them like they are a test lead in some ways,
and now that's in my head,
I'm thinking I want to do more of that.
I want to have fewer QA people report to me,
and more dev leads that I meet with
to coach on them leading testing and quality.
So anyway.
You need to teach them the value of them
asking the same question.
Yeah, and they've learned that.
That's how you go viral.
And it's interesting, because I start to see that happen,
and it wasn't until this reflection
from this round table yesterday,
I realized, oh, that is what I'm doing,
and I see why it's working where it's working.
So I want to do more of that.
Anyway, you were going to say something earlier,
I'll cut you off, please jump in.
Glad you did that.
I wonder if you won anyone over.
I don't, there was a relative tiny audience,
so I don't know if I won them over.
To be his credit, the waterfall guy,
he sent me a note afterwards saying it was great to,
and it says great to hear your opinions,
nice meeting you today.
So he was very cordial about it,
even though we were on different sides of what testing is.
Yeah.
Sorry, I gotta add one more thing.
Go ahead.
Another question was,
what skills should someone getting into testing today learn?
I said a lot of stuff besides testing.
Ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha.
And I was serious, but oh my God, the looks.
Yeah, anyway, go on.
Yeah, I know.
I had to look at that webinar.
Right, you're having too much fun
rethinking it right now,
and of course the problem is,
if you're not careful,
then you can come across as all you're trying to do
is screw with the other panelists.
Right, and I don't think I...
And that's not our goal.
That wasn't my goal.
I answered the questions as honestly as I could.
I wasn't screwing with them.
Right.
And I let them have their piece.
I didn't argue with them on everything I disagreed with.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
We have a different perspective,
and it's one that I've repeatedly vetted out.
You're going in a direction I have never gone,
but I think you'll succeed in that.
I've never been a director of QA
trying to get rid of my whole team.
Right, and still make...
But that's not your ultimate goal.
It's essentially, how do I make this business function better
and then recognizing the way you need to do that
will result in your team disappearing.
Exactly, the goal isn't to get rid of the team.
The goal is to...
What's the first principle of modern testing?
Business first.
My goal is to improve the business.
I'm improving the business
and sort of making principle number seven happen
because it's the right thing to do for the business.
Absolutely.
I didn't even pre-think that, but holy crap, that's cool.
We're expressing, even with Agile testing out and Agile out,
I still accuse the Agile manifesto of this,
but essentially, with as long as it's been out,
there's still far too many people that are polarized.
There is absolutely no valid place for waterfall.
It never should have existed, even in the paper.
It says don't do this.
I used to highlight that, yeah, yeah.
And granted, most people doing waterfall
are usually doing something closer to spiral model, but still.
But a lot of folks have come up with a definition of success
based off years of experience, and it's still very true.
When you have years of experience of solving problems
using a particular toolset,
you kind of generally tend to look at all problems
with that toolset.
And then at some point in time,
you're just basically trying to solve problems,
and oftentimes you don't actually have the time
to sit back and say, is there a better way?
And the waterfall approach today, in my view,
they're sort of taking an evolutionary approach,
and I do think the time is right
for taking a revolutionary approach
and rethink the whole system.
And that's what I think modern testing is about.
One other question, and we're not gonna get
super deep into this, but this is gonna kick off
a nice discussion for the next podcast.
Yes.
Is another, it wasn't a question.
Oh, I use this line, which I know I've used
on the podcast before, probably when talking about
the principle around our job
as nurturing the quality culture.
I think that's four, I could be wrong.
Josh, why did we number them?
Yeah, we even had the Ministry of Testing
even created this fan-
Wonderful poster.
Cheat cheat.
Yeah, yeah.
We should just...
Oh, by the way, Ministry of Testing,
three of all heard of them.
You know they have the boss boss,
which are Bradshaw, they also have different bosses,
different features.
They have an editor boss, Melissa Eden.
Yep, I just hired her for the Unity office.
She's gonna work at Unity Austin
and make awesome things happen.
You couldn't talk about it last time.
I couldn't, but she announced it on Twitter.
Oh my, this is like, I'm building the dream team.
This is good.
So anyway, back on topic.
Oh, the point I made, I said something very close to this.
I'm sure all the other panelists will agree
that it's not testing's job to own quality.
One of my few head nods.
Said, but I do think people on my team are responsible
and accountable for building the quality culture.
That was my quote.
And then to tie us into a conversation before,
as my team slowly moves into reporting to dev,
they're not going away, I'll still meet with them.
We're just swapping the dotted lines and dashed lines.
I will begin to hold those dev leads,
my virtual test leads accountable
for growing that quality culture.
And someone might say,
how do you hold them accountable if they don't work
for you?
And I can hold them accountable.
I know how to do leadership.
Anyway.
The answer is leadership.
Yeah.
So one of the panelists, a waterfall panelist,
I'll call him out by name, said, well,
you can talk about that,
but the quality culture is abstract.
And I said, well, if you just call it quality culture is,
but I think you can define attributes of a quality culture.
And these may be different contextually for every team,
but I don't know, I think you can define them.
And in fact, and I'm sure I've read these before
on the podcast,
but I think we'll maybe do some deeper dives into these.
Beginning next time.
I think I can define them knowing full well
you have already.
I was in a conversation with my peer managers at,
well, yeah, some other quality managers at Unity
and I brought up the same statement.
I do believe I hold my team accountable
for building the quality culture.
It's been in the principles for a while.
I fully believe that.
And it wasn't so blatant disaster.
Well, it's abstract.
What do you mean by that?
It was like, well, what does that mean?
How do we, how do we grow that?
Me looking for some work to do said,
let me see if I can define that.
I sat and stared at my computer and said, oh crap.
I don't know how to define that.
And, but then I thought I, I do at this stage
in my career, I do so much of my job,
just in my head, walking around thinking
and after am I myself, just cause I'm not typing
into keyboard, if I'm thinking
and maybe I'm actually working,
but I just reflected and thought for days
and then some things started forming in my head
and I wrote up and you've seen a copy.
When I sat down to write up what turned out
to be a little bit of a capability model
or a maturity model, if you will,
it spit out in an hour.
And we've used it a lot at Unity.
We've begun to use it as a way to identify
how a team is going to grow their quality culture.
And so far it's worked remarkably well.
Made a few edits, a few tweaks,
but it's being used by a lot of teams
and working very, very well.
So I think we'll dive into what the full maturity level is,
but I do wanna walk through
what the different capabilities are,
what the different things I think a team
with a high quality culture should exhibit.
And those are in order, and we'll take a little bit
of time to comment on each one,
but we'll dive in deeper later.
The first one is testing breadth.
And this is about, there's a lot of teams that think,
well, my unit test passed at 100%,
we must be ready to ship.
Just recognizing that there are different kinds of testing
the team needs to do, things to think about.
The agile testing quadrants fit really well in here
as a model, but thinking about not just functional testing,
but thinking upfront, are there security applications here?
Should we do a threat model?
What sort of reliability or stress testing would we do?
How is this going to integrate with other components?
Thinking about those things upfront
versus just writing a bunch of functional tests.
I think teams with a high, with a team,
an organization with a high quality culture
will consider those things strategically
and comprehensively throughout their product sector.
I think anything worthwhile classified
under something called a maturity model,
regardless if it's abstract or not,
is gonna evaluate the system at play
and essentially try to advance people
through the maturity model and the highest ROI.
To be clear, I hate maturity models.
I hated, pardon me, hated writing this
because I knew it would be,
I guess the problem is maturity models are,
the problems I've seen is one,
they're treated as a scorecard, which I frickin' hate.
Then rename yours.
I try to call it a capability model,
but everybody keeps on calling it maturity models.
I don't call it a model.
Maturity guidelines.
I actually know what we call it.
You know what's caught on with my peers?
We call it the thing, for lack of a better name.
Awesome.
So another one is quality and test ownership.
Who owns quality?
A team with a low level of thinginess,
maturity, capabilities.
A test team would own all the quality on the team.
They test quality in.
Whereas a team that's very mature,
like principle number seven,
may not have the need for a quality
and testing specialist.
Actually, I don't think that's the lowest.
The lowest is you've hired a test team
who doesn't actually own it.
They just serve the role of being the ones to blame.
Which is, as you know,
the way there's still a reasonable amount
of testing out there like that.
And I heard about it yesterday.
How the team deals with technical debt and maintenance.
Not just bug backlog, but technical debt in general.
Is it pile up?
Yeah.
We'll talk about this more.
But for me, that one,
that one right there.
In terms of my own transition,
the three have heard this story over and over again.
I left test, went to dev as in Bing.
And that one, if there was one single decision
that just friggin' solidified me on this,
is getting rid of the bug database.
Yeah.
That one thing,
you get rid of the bug database,
yeah, it's gonna freak out Waterfall Guy.
Right?
Because it's essentially, well, how do we keep up?
No, the only way you can keep up
is to stay clean all of the time.
Yes.
That is the only way.
So, and the thing I talk about with my team is,
now everybody's fully on board,
on their way to getting the zero bug backlog.
But the thing they're thinking about now,
in our digital conversations is,
what other debt do we have?
What's our other debt?
And thinking about that,
because there are other kinds of debt than bugs.
Code quality and tuning.
Can I tell you?
There's code quality, oh, you're not gonna go on?
Okay, tell me.
So, the next thing is,
once you get rid of the technical debt,
then what you need to do is
evaluate your ability to scale.
Build a KPI that you trust,
and it's context sensitive,
I can't give you any firmware guidance in this.
Build a KPI that you trust,
that indicates whether or not
your current system can scale
to the predicted load three months from now.
Yeah.
Okay, and that's all you care about.
You wanna know, the second it goes under three months,
you go, okay, we gotta make a change.
We got three months,
because we can't scale now.
Code quality and tooling,
and this is mostly about,
again, these are contextualized
from the things that I wanna see happen,
but this is, what's happening in CI?
What's happening in the check-in gates?
Is it, do we have analysis tools running,
which again, create debt,
these things like principles overlap,
and you'll see that these attributes overlap
with modern testing principles as well.
The development approach,
we've all seen bad Kanban and bad Scrum.
Enough said. Fragile.
Enough said.
Yeah.
So, there's a level of maturity there.
I am fascinated at the number of distinct variants
of the said two.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
I forgot to periscope this one, like I said it would.
Maybe another one, but there was a face palm right there.
Learning and improvement,
and this is for a respective time,
think of a team doing really good retrospectives
and acting on them,
and that's being a high level of maturity,
and teams that just kind of go through the motions
and don't ever learn.
Build, measure, learn.
Not build, measure.
Or just build.
Build, build, build, build, build.
That's iteration, right?
Well, and sometimes the worst would be
you have three separate teams.
Oh, we build, measure, learn.
That's the build team, that's the measure team.
There's the learn team.
There's a meta point around the quality culture,
and which involves leadership support.
And does leadership give a,
there's a weird growth where leadership doesn't care.
It's like, whatever, do what you want.
There's a stage where they care too much,
and they're driving quality through scorecards
and trying to micromanage a bunch of these things.
Then there's a level where the quality culture
is part of what the team does,
and they stay out of the way.
So it's an interesting curve
of how leadership support is needed.
You need leadership to supply a rallying cry,
and to emphasize that it's important.
And then, like one of my favorite authors, Steve Denning,
says, you give the team a framework to work in,
and then get out of their way.
And quality culture is a very good example.
You cannot escape without that framework.
That's actually the fundamental difference
between the first stage and the last stage.
Yeah.
All right, so maybe in the next podcast,
we'll talk a little bit more about some or all of those,
little deeper dive.
I think we should go deeper.
Yeah, for sure, but not today.
We're out of time.
Agreed.
All right, thanks again for listening
to the AB testing podcast.
I am still Alan.
I'm Brent.
All right, bye.