Hello again, howdy
Hey, we're sitting farther apart today. It's odd for me here. Let me move closer. Okay. All right
One day we're going to release the video version of the a B testing podcast people will see our faces and never again
It'll be the final episode
Maybe for number 100 we should do a video
Okay, I'm kidding people don't want that. Yeah
Welcome to a B testing
Yeah, we just put an explicit flag
So anyway a B testing the podcast for software development software testing
data stuff experimentation leadership test management quality quality leadership and most lately modern testing and
Brent's laughing at me which is par for the course if you're new welcome if you're not you're used to this stuff. So
Thanks for tuning in again, I think it's episode 85. Is that correct? It is 85
But really we didn't figure it out till about 60. So maybe it's only 25
There were some good ones before then. Ah, you know 60 is when we really started off on the the modern testing theme
I don't want to say 60 because we'll come up with something new eventually
That'll be the the shiny thing for a B testing and then we'll say that's the new number
Sounds good Brent, right?
Bringing up I got it while we're podcasting here
Uruguay and France are playing I just need to check on the score. I have lost it
I'll bring it up sometime when Brent's talking. It's halftime
So yeah, it's work up time. I'm gonna cheer for
worldwide ah
Viva la France
Talking about the modern testing principles which you can read on
Modern testing org and today we're gonna talk about number four which we'll get to in just a second any
Thing else I should be caught up on before we get started, right?
No, let's just dive in this time. Wow. I know people are so you need it up people are gonna fast-forward
They're already talking about it what happened to their stories of bunnies and squirrels
Okay, Brent. Do you have principle number four loaded up where you can't see it?
I can't because the company where you work Microsoft is too cheap to let anyone who doesn't work there have access to Wi-Fi
While they're in the building unless they get like someone to hold their hand and sign their life away. So anyway, I have no eggs
Freakin two clicks. Yeah and wait for an email to come through those shitty exchange service. Yeah, you have a phone
I'm looking at it right now. Yeah, it's it's a phone. Anyway, I'm done making fun of Microsoft for now. So
Okay, number four share principle number four
number four
We care deeply about the quality culture of our team and we coach lead and nurture the team
Towards a more mature quality culture
Awesome two big takeaways for me. We're gonna dive into I want to make sure we talk about the why it's important
Talk about what it is and a whole bunch of how but there's two big pieces one is quality culture
We're gonna have to define the crap out of that because that can mean about ten different things to five different people and the other
One is this aspect of leadership
Where I think people
leading teams towards modern testing principles whether or not that's the
current or former test slash QA person
We need to not be passive and not wait for work to come to us
Like maybe we did 15 years ago in leading a team towards a modern testing culture
There's a lot of aspects of leadership. You need to be able to do to get that to happen
and the third call that I'm gonna say that
I think one of our earlier iterations had this
explicitly
But principle number four is
In our list. It's the community principle. So the leadership is not just
You know leading by example and being the best tester creating a community of quality. Yes
Creating and sustaining a community of quality anyone can create a community
Let's start with quality culture
Since that's probably gonna take 85% of the episode today
In various forms
What is a quality culture?
Will gets three different answers of the quality. Oh, very good. Very good. We are also the tautology podcast or not. Oh
Ponder ponder ponder
The one thing I think I think
I'll put in one. I think it would be good idea
Here because between the two of us
Right. It's it's
Alan is
By far one of the best community builders I have ever worked with seen and observed
But the one thing I think is super important when we call out here
any time
there is
and I think this is
This is missed a lot and I think we probably need to explicitly call it out
Anytime we talk about
The word quality just want to make sure the listeners understand. I am NOT talking about bugs
I am NOT talking about code correctness
These are
Separate concepts not mutually
But they are separate to me a quality culture is
around
how do we
build up a
strong a
active and a
For lack of a better word a non into it in intuition based
And I'll just add another useful
View of user empathy within the organization. This is about
For lack of a better word feelings in a lot of regards
Caring about the problems that our customers have
Remember care and quality are two sides to the same coin. They are they are I mean
quality
It's you know, there was a
An old podcast that you mentioned something from your music history
about art and
You mentioned that art is something that
Creates emotion or
The quality of art is in the interpretation from the user. Yeah, you mentioned some piece
I'm sure you you have it on the top of your head where there's like 17 measures of just nothing but silence
well, there's the John Cage four minutes and 33 seconds, which is just
in three movements, which is
Just silence but the but the music the art is the audience's reaction to that silence
there was a thing in the early 20th century called danger music where
the music the art was
Maybe these boxes you had to reach your hand into you couldn't see inside and some had
Fur and cotton and some had broken glass and razor blades
but the art was in your interpretation of your reaction to
The the value is in your reaction to the art
Quality is that not a very similar definition?
It is it's it's a lot of it is is the user reaction
Mm-hmm to what you've built right and you've made the metaphor or maybe it's not a metaphor
many times like what's what's higher quality the product with very few users, but no known bugs or
The or the feature product with a lot of bugs but a hundred thousand users
Yeah, I like to talk about Christopher Alexander Alexander when I when I bring this up, right he talks about
These positive and negative forces right and then
Do the force are the forces?
Aligned such that
That the person interacting with this the system at play or the in his case the architecture are they?
Guided towards positive thoughts or or negative an example. I'll bring up is
he once got called into a house and
They had a kitchen with two double doors
from the double doors from the kitchen you got to a patio then there was a staircase down to a lower patio and
He put or the there was a little picnic table on that lower patio and he found out that no one used it
They never they it was clear from the intent right they intended to have outdoor meals
But they didn't and so he looked at it and he just said oh, okay
He got a crew put the picnic table up on the upper deck and that fixed the whole problem
the issue
That he identified is hey one of the forces is in order to have a meal there. You had to transfer the the food and
Going up and down the stairs created enough of a friction
That they didn't enjoy
The table and it didn't take much like you could go oh, it's so easy to work around this
No, it's it's if you just have a little bit of negative
Force it just changes the entire scenario
Agreed. So let me rewind the stack a little bit. I think I like the way you brought it
upper or the you mentioned community because community and
culture have a lot in common, it's
shared mindset shared practices shared values shared vision shared goals a
Lot of sharing a lot of sharing but because you want a culture means people are a
Quality culture can't just be the a person going. Let's have higher quality. No
No
This is about you know as Barney says sharing is caring and
knowing that the muscle memory of
The group of folks that you are working with is heading towards
the same
For lack of a better word goal because a lot of the times these goals are emergent. They're not
Clearly understood up front sure we've talked about this before
They're adaptive challenges versus technical problems technical problems. All it is is an implementation thing
You got to figure that you got to look up some algorithms, whatever you're done adaptive challenges
You don't know the answer when you start you have to learn it as you go along and a lot of culture things fall in
That direction you have beliefs for sure
But you don't
You don't want to stick to them if you if you you want to be able to adapt to new knowledge gain
Yeah, when when starting a culture and I'm gonna get into my definition in a second because I actually created one for better or worse
But I'm reminded of a Weinberg quote where he says unless and until all members of a team have a common understanding of the problem
Attempts to solve the problem are just so much wasted energy
I think quality culture fits into that as well as a technical problem. You need to have
There's this ad car model which fits into this as well. Let me talk about that for a minute. This is from
consulting company called pro-ci
Anyway, the model seems to work pretty well for culture change talks about awareness of the problem like okay
We need to have higher quality. There's the desire. Well, actually awareness is the act quality is bad. There's a desire to change the problem
Okay, we want to improve but until you can go each step builds another one once you have awareness and desire you need knowledge
You need maybe it's knowledge of tools or things you may need to implement
And then you need ability
You need the ability to do those things
So maybe you need some training and how to learn how to use Jenkins for CI or or whatever
Maybe you want to put some other?
Tools into your CI pipeline. Maybe you just want to get maybe people need some coaching or training on some agile concepts
Or maybe they just need practice. We have you have awareness desire knowledge ability and then finally you need a way to retain
those practices you need repeatability, so it's a it's a
Model that I like to use for thinking about how to move through changes awareness desire knowledge ability retain
Okay
Usually when I go into these speeches, I start with just two it's it's motivation and ability
But I think that a motivation definitely well it
You can't have motivation without the without the awareness. So it just puts a few extra
Stats around those. Yeah. Yeah, so the definition of quality culture I wrote and there are again, it's not perfect
It's the one I use
It's a shared mindset that delivering high quality software to customers is our top priority and that all of our practices support this effort
Yeah
I'm absolutely fine with that
Because it's vague and means nothing until you dive into the detail. Yeah the one thing
Mate, this is the thing. I think we need to hit hard on on
As I've already mentioned in this episode
right
What is quality and or more importantly? I think perhaps is what is what isn't?
quality
right
so
It is quality. I can't hit this enough. I think I'm gonna be repeating this until I die
Bugs and quality are not in any way shape or form
Sinner nims or antonyms are related one of those nims. Okay. Good
so point made yeah, I the way I think of it is
getting people closer to
Understanding
the the problems
That users are facing
how
The software organization is geared to solve it and how we're staying current because as we as we release we've already
talked about
The the need for continuous deployment the need for continuous integration
small batches
Those are small little
tests
to say hey customers are you happier and
Then and then sort of a discussion around
Okay, why or why not?
You have backed into an important question we need to answer something to interrupt with the question that you continue
Yep, so why is the quality culture important?
You actually already started answering it if you didn't realize it. Why is it important to have a quality culture?
Why is this a principle? Why do we think it's so important?
Okay, do I help you out? Yeah, hi. I'm not connecting the
So
The reasons that a quality culture are important and small batches contribute to a higher quality culture
If you're able to deliver quickly, we want to get feedback from our customers more often
We want to be able to understand and react to what they're doing
We want and at the same time we want to reduce risk in our ability to do that
Yeah, all the culture helps with those things and many more
But you're talking about those realize that's part of a quality culture and in order to function in the way we want to function and to
Keep and retain and engage more users. We need that high quality culture and the key thing
I think you talked about just a second ago is
Actually, I love how you phrase that I felt a bit surprised you started off at contributing it to me
Sure
Yeah, yeah, that's exactly where I was going Alan like the continuous deployment
We talked about it in some regards with respect to risk minimization, right?
This is this is one of the reasons why companies hire testers today
They're kind of like an insurance. Yes on the product, right? I will pay and
Thousands or millions of dollars to do an amount of testing to reduce an amount of risk, right?
But
Here we're shifting it towards
No, there's another reason why we want these small batches and that that is so that we can react
To knowledge gained. Yes
knowledge gained
with respect to
Hey, is this causing pain or?
Is this creating delight?
And I like to light delight your customers
It's sad that that meme ended here within Microsoft. No one talks about customer delighters really much anymore
No, but anyway, it is what it is
The other thing that I think is important around building the quality culture
It is all about knowledge share
Knowledge sharing in any system that
In a software world, I'll just I'll just say it this way if you have a system in the software world
that contains human beings and
You're not
working towards
Creating something that optimizes on
Utilizing the knowledge within those human beings
You're really
putting yourself
Not in harm but but you're slowing yourself down
Software is knowledge work. Yes, it is and the great thing about
Knowledge is that the more you give away
The more there is in the system a
Quality community given given an agile world and sort of an emergent goals
right
by by constructing a
Place where ideas can come together
What happens?
New ideas get formed
We may have mentioned this before
Thousand times yes, and I can't hit it enough we in the knowledge worker
business
you want to make a mechanism where
the these ideas are
coming together
new ideas form and tested and try out and
that is
One place particularly that if it's around the quality culture
That's one place where you're really going to accelerate the achievement of shipable quality
And when I think about a high quality culture, I'm thinking about a culture that is purely in optimizing mode
So they're in a they're just in a place where everything is about learning and adjusting so to recap the first 20 minutes here
The quality culture is a shared mindset about how we're gonna make quality software and we do it
It's important to do it because it enables us to
Accelerate the achievement of quality
Enables us to much better do that. I'm gonna tweak that because it's I don't think it's about how we're gonna make software
I think it's about how we're going to solve our customers problems. Yes
Right because customers don't want software. They want their damn problem solved, right? So I want to do
Some what like what is a quality culture and then a whole bunch of how is it cool that fit in your agenda?
well, so the second part the second part of the
The principal
specifies that one of our goals is to coach lead and nurture the team towards a more mature
That is the how so I want to talk about what a more mature quality culture is and then how we lead teams towards that it
The second yeah, and then what is a more mature because it
That's me that that invokes thoughts of any number of
Maturity models, so I have a thing against maturity models
So I and only because and I can get over it, but I've just seen them used wrong so many times
and with the biggest culprit being CMMI which a lot of our European listeners have had to deal with and
Two huge problems I have with models like that is CMMI
You go from lockstep to level 1 to level 2 across a whole bunch of different areas
Whereas it may even make business sense for you to grow your maturity model in
different rates in different areas or
attributes of quality
the other thing is is a lot of companies wore their CMMI level like a badge and it turned into much like tester certification a
a maturity model certification level where people would pay money and if you if you paid more you might get a higher
Rating so it's just I don't like that. I like the model as being a discussion point not a blueprint
It's a way to figure out where you want to improve so that disclaimer in in
Front of it. Yes, it's a maturity model, but please use the
Use the model all models are wrong some are useful
It's a model for learning and a model for assessing and figuring out what you want to do not a badge to wear. I
don't disagree
Maturity model the one thing
quite honestly that that
that I am
I'm not wired. So maturity models are great because they kind of I like them to help
describe
sort of a
known set of patterns
around
what typically people will
once they've mastered a particular amount of knowledge
Where they immediately realize oh if we mastered this amount of knowledge
We'd be able to do these other things, right?
If you remember the a Sierra
Stuff we talked about here a long time ago around data
Right a line collect inform recommend act
Right that that's kind of a journey, but you wouldn't pick much to convert it to a maturity model
Describing going from data oblivious to data centricity
Right, but I don't I don't prefer that I prefer sort of a guiding light. Yes and part of the main reason why is
I view them as
Well known sort of practice patterns sure, but I see them often being referred to as best
Practices and that concept offends me. Yeah, it's easy to use them incorrectly
I like the idea of there's another problem on the plus side for the model
Here's a problem they help solve and then we'll talk less abstractly and talk about a maturity model that I'm building for my team
Or my teams. I think often people see okay. We're here
Current state we want to be there the desired state. Let's just do that, but you can't there's a whole
100 baby steps in between so one thing a maturity model like construct does is lets you see some
progression towards infancy to adulthood lets you see what adolescents and and and
Teenage years are like in between as a metaphor for maturity or an actual
Not really a metaphor because that's actually actually is maturity
I've been working on trying to figure out trying to walk the talk and figure out what is a maturity model for going to figure
how to improve this
So I started thinking a lot about what attributes make up a quality maturity
And I came up eventually with what I think is a pretty good list
It's probably not perfect and because everything I do iterates all the time
It doesn't matter but I came up with eight or nine different areas
There's testing breadth which is like we just do functional testing to we test we actually
Contextually test all the things that you know, we know when the test reliability security, etc
We do the right right breadth of testing. There's the quality and test ownership. Are the testers doing all the testing?
Or are the testers merely coaching in some cases principle number seven
Maybe not needed because the teen just gets testing testing is part of what they do listening to a podcast this morning
I won't name it because it wasn't very good
But it even in talking about DevOps and the in the podcast I was talking about
They were still referring to testing as this unique phase that happened during the process
I just it just made my head shake a little bit
Bug lifecycle we've talked about bug backlogs and how those are a bottleneck I think
There can even be maturity of how you deal with those from the traditional bug backlog on one end all the way to
Working with a zero bug policy and bugs are dealt with very efficiently and quickly as they come in
I know you say this isn't part necessarily part of
Without the testers job, but we don't talk a lot about code correctness and code quality, but I think there is a maturity in
in
Code quality code correctness tools how you use coverage analysis tools
Etc in your life's up part of your CI. I think you have to do those in order to reach levels of quality elsewhere
Yeah that that
These are for me. They don't have to be for ya. That's fine
Customer the data analysis we've talked about a lot of times. This is basically can go
maybe not align exactly with your
Your model of oblivious aware driven centric, but there is a level of
Starting with oblivious and moving to data centric actually maybe maybe as those
Maybe that that maturity model fits really well within this quality culture
The development approach this is where the agile practices come into place you have you can have a total ad hoc
People work on whatever it's done whatever sort of thing or on the other end of the higher maturity you have super small batches and
and
the process the process is used to
Build the software or to think about how things are broken down are very mature and efficient and just a few more
learning an improvement where
Do you bother to learn from on one end? Maybe you don't even bother to learn mistakes or things where blame happens?
But on the other end every failure is an opportunity to learn and that opportunity is taken
Very good retrospectives happen on these teams, etc. And then finally you need some level of leadership support
And not I don't think is leadership mandating everyone follow all these other practices
I think for culture change one of the things doesn't have to be like the person at the top leadership support this can be
When you see good quality practice is happening. You need people who will
Point them out and celebrate them people that will you that reinforcement of
Excellent. This team is doing blah or this person is doing blah. This is great
You need a level of support if you have a shared vision or shared values around quality
reiterating those Pat Lincione in his book
the advantage talks about the power of
organizational health
which has a lot to do with mature quality organizational health with product quality and
his
Four steps which are really interesting and I love them for building a healthy organization are to
Create a cohesive leadership team
Create a great division clarify the vision communicate the vision and re communicate the vision that was five so two of those are actually
combined but it's about
if
You have beliefs or values and how you're approaching your engineering efforts or how you approach solving customer problems
you should
Live those how many times do you giving double from Microsoft? How many times in your?
Microsoft career which is over 20 years now, right? Yeah almost 25 have Wow. I didn't make it that far
have you
Seen some vision get blasted out whether it's like for your organization and then
No reinforcement of it. Nothing ever happened with it again. It kind of faded away people didn't know what it was
If you're really serious about this you need to make sure people it's part of how people function
Unity has these customer values around democratized game development solve hard problems and enable developer success
Which actually come up in conversations all the time
I hear stories from my Amazon friends about how their values come up meetings all the time
for better or for worse, I
think if you're going to have if you really want to reinforce and ingrain a shared mindset you need to
Reiterate and clarify and celebrate
Those values the one thing I didn't hear
In in a lot of that like I would actually
And maybe maybe that's the right thing in the maturity model. We're in right now
with respect to
To MT although it is interesting
so Alan asked me on
slack just the other day that
Or maybe you made a statement around
surprised not surprised at how
The the community at large is responding to MT
right
We're sort of
If I were to put it this way, it's sort of a polarizing
There's one set of folks that seem to be saying ah
That's what we do
Thanks for giving a name to the practice something to that effect and then there's
another set of folks that are kind of
Going oh that will never ever ever ever work
Right in yeah, there's there's there's there's folks in between but that's sort of where I see the polarization
going
Yeah, there's a lot of in between I do talk to a bunch of people go that's yeah, that's where I want to be
We're not there
which I think is actually a much better place to be in then that'll never never never work because
You're already proven wrong it does work. Yeah
Those the folks that that's claim it'll never work my them
I just sort of
Ignore them and I used to look at them and go all right
Do you not pay attention to what's happening in the space and
I basically found out that the answer to that is no
right and I
Neither have the time nor the patience to sit down with them and walk them through what they
Should have been paying attention to
On quality culture
So I think a lot of those techniques and a lot of those approaches are some a lot of places where where people can start with
today
I'd really like to see this shift towards more again
It is not focused on the process. It does not focus on any particular technology stack
This is primarily around
people people not only in terms of
I have said this on many times before
Any time you're trying to make a change there are three things that you need to change simultaneously
The people the technology and the processes
So we talked about the technology, but if you if you change the technology, but don't change the people's mindset
you're not going to be able to
Impact the the process which is the glue between technology and people
You can't change people without the why you can't it sure helps a lot
You can change people without the why you could use command and control aspects
But I recommend strongly against that because it has a top end on how you scale. Absolutely. Absolutely
One thing I want to bring up and then I want to dive into the how and they just if I do it
right old segue
the
Method I used to come up with those list of quality attributes I wanted to improve you should come up with your own
Don't copy mine you can but you shouldn't the method I use that of a book
I've referenced a lot on this podcast in my blog and etc. But called leadership on the line by Ron Heffetz and
this is where this
concept of adaptive challenges come from that I mentioned earlier on the episode and
one of the things you do to help solve an adaptive problem is to identify the current state and
The desired state and I what I did was a variation on that. I thought about what are I just
basically affinity exercised
By myself all the different things. I thought all the different engineering teams I work with and even indirectly
What would that minimum level look like and then?
for all those things I thought about what would the
Highest level look like and then I did some consolidation where I was like
Oh, these things are the same as these things. That's right eventually got down to those eight or nine categories
I have and then once I
vetted sort of that beginning stage and then the end stage I filled in a couple levels in between and ended up with a
For better for worse maturity model to be used as a discussion point figure out how teams can improve
Their quality culture you can do this exercise yourself for the things that you care about for your team in your context
So now that we have that
The next step and this is gonna be different for everyone as well. The next step is about
Making that change happen. That's for the leadership
That's for the leadership aspect and the community building aspect of this principle coming to play
Yeah, the I definitely view
The community building part of this is
Is
growing other leaders
There's another book
I can't remember the name of but another model of leadership where you have to be in a position of leadership and then have people's
permission to lead them which is about establishing trust and
There's a few levels in between and they one of the higher levels is you're able to
You're not able to more of your focus is on building other leaders and
I realized for better for worse
Brent just slipped off his computer a lot of my success and my my success is in
Helping move myself out not of a job out of a role is
I need to that is hinged on my ability to make the people that work for me now
Good leaders who can build other leaders
so they need to be in much as I'm worried about building community and
And leadership they need to be able to be leaders and build community as well. They need to build their own
Quality communities and quality cultures and the teams they work on so I've done a lot of
Over the years a lot of leadership training
one of the things
I'll absolutely share
Whenever a mentee comes to me and says hey, I want to be a lead
I
could tell you I
don't know but
80% chance that this speech is gonna load
You want to know what the single most important?
aspect of a leader is
Please tell me they have followers
True this seems like a tautology
It is not this ties right in that principle. It's one thing being a position of leadership
it's another level up to have followers or as
This Maxwell maybe as the author to have permission to lead
Yeah, there's a that it's it's a line with that permission to lead
The you cannot be re-orged into or out of
leadership
You can be re-orged into and out of management
leaders have followers and
a
Follower is someone who has made a conscious decision
To go in the same direction you are right? Um, so there's
To to be good at leadership. You have to be good at communication so that your goals are clear
And you have to be good at
Influencing and and inspiring others to decide to walk your path
right it this
And then there's another speech that
In this leadership training I've done years ago
Right. There's this definition. It's somewhat controversial, but I think it applies here. How would you define empowerment?
Empowerment is very simple
empowerment means
Others would make the same decision you would in your absence
That's an interesting definition. Yeah, it's some as I mentioned it's somewhat controversial
But if you empower someone to make the decision
What essentially are you doing? You're essentially saying
Do you think you're saying?
So let's say you empowered one of your employees to make a decision in that decision with the same data is
Diametrically opposed to the decision you would make
Right there's a strong chance
You're gonna stop their decision-making process
Right, unless you unless you can springboard it into a learning lesson or along these lines
This is important. I just read something as recently and I wish I could would have wrote it down
But what's the difference between delegation and empowerment? Oh
That's actually pretty
Delegation is I decide you do
Empowerment is
Is essentially you decide
And we do we do you do someone else does I think the do part is
Irrelevant there, right? Yep. All right. Where are we going?
We were trying to veer towards and in and dancing around the how
Yeah, so you should take points on that one in this conversation because you've done it a bajillion times
try stuff
fail learn the exact in an
organizational change and in improving quality in the how it's just like a
Just like good agile software development. You need to
Don't try and make sweeping changes at once. Don't sweep in with mandates and saying we're doing blah blah blah blah blah blah blah blah
Try little things
Stuff works do more of it or try more things when things don't work
Figure and don't just give up do that pivot or persevere the same as you do with experimentation and figure out
Well, why didn't this work? What should we do differently?
What areas do you want to focus on it all those areas I gave earlier?
Do you want to would you want to work on improving all those at once maybe probably not
Figure out which ones are the most bang for the buck but make small changes if you're if you have a huge bug backlog
Say, okay, we're not gonna have any bugs long any bugs
Stage one. Let's see if we can get down to no bugs older than a month three months
Whatever makes sense for your team figure out what the right baby steps are going back to heffits leadership is disappointing people at a level
they can absorb
So if you try and make a sweeping change people are going to be too disappointed. They're gonna shut down. They're gonna rebel
This falls into the boiled frogs parable, but all these things work
You need to make lots and lots of small changes and evaluate all the time that said
Do you think?
Ripping the band-aid never works. I think you need to look first
ripping the band-aid can work
I have been on teams where we said screw it. We're killing we're just gonna
Declain bug bankruptcy and close anything older than you know, two weeks fix all the rest and start from there
So you can rip the band-aid off if you but you kind of need a
Majority or large part of team buy-in or that culture or that shared values first
So you need you do need to take time to see whether it's to see if it really is a tourniquet
Yeah, I was I was actually just thinking about that right? I think I told the story last time
Where when I went to development and being I started off with doing scrum
But I described Kanban and I said we're gonna do scrum on the way there
Right and then when scrum failed they said how about this Kanban thing?
Right it so so in that particular case, it's a lot easier to rip rip the band-aid
When yeah, but the team was ready the team was ready for it. They asked you they were ready for that change
Well, they did they did they still didn't understand it. They were just like well this sucks. Let's not do this
Yeah, look just don't assume everything's a band-aid and don't assume everything's a tourniquet
Disappoint people at a level they can absorb or as I paraphrase at a level they can tolerate and
Yeah, there's there's this concept
You've heard of out of the box thinking sure love out of the box thinking it's fun
Have you ever tried to implement something that was out of the box?
Give me your example, then we'll get back on track
well, so some the example I'm thinking of right now is
When I was
Leading in in media center and they had
Gone six years and never passed BBTs
Okay, and it's not a great example, but it's it
They were
holistically entrenched and
This idea is the
Way we we need to move forward like they as I described back then they were heavily solidified in
No, what we need to do is have our end-to-end tests in our BV T suite, right?
And this is just a horrible idea
But their whole organization was bought in
But they couldn't get BV T's to pass
In that particular case and I met with a whole lot of resistance
But I basically said no we're gonna stop that. Yeah
Yeah, that's just a dumb definition of what a BV T is
For sure, but I mean the point the point is I was surrounded with people
That said we've tried everything
Last six years. We tried everything we can't make this change
Alright, and some of the times like one of my favorite things to do is
When I realized that a change has to be made but
People want to see something but they don't feel it can be done
Because of politics or or
You know interactions or people complaining
Right. That's a great place to just rip the band-aid, but it's sure but you're out of the box
And what turns out to be a very very small box
Yeah, if
So I think the point is you want to try
These little things they can be things that are incremental or things that can be
Incremental changes from where you are or maybe some out-of-the-box things that can leapfrog you
So what I was gonna say if it's too out of the box
Then what you want to do is around the box thinking so you earlier you're talking about where are you now?
Where do you want to be?
right and a third step is
Alright, what is the first action?
that you should take
towards where you want to be
And communicate that one action is actually the goal there are a zillion
Quilts you can go look up on the internet that basically say the hardest part of any change is starting. Yeah
So for anything you want to improve just start just try something then the other bit I wanted to get to is
They're gonna try a bunch of stuff you use different kinds of thinking you're going to
Reflect and try and find new things to do to you're trying to create a learning organization
I think it's a lot of parallels between the learning organization as Peter Senge talks about and a culture of quality
In Senge wrote the fifth discipline where the five disciplines
Well, the fifth most important one is systems thinking which I think is highly related to a quality culture
but
Once you start getting these changes to happen, you need that reinforcement. You need
Some celebration of hey, we're able to cut down our cycle time blah blah blah here. Hey, we were able to learn
This thing from data weren't able to do before. Oh, hey, it looks like we have not a bug older than seven days in
three months
Those little you don't need to have a huge party for all these things but celebrate the things
That are leading you in the direction you want to go and by celebrate. I mean, you know, call them out in a slack channel
call them out in a
Standup give some recognition for those things because those that recognition to some people
Often is worth more than giving them a monetary bonus, especially in front of people, but it also motivates others to
Try and model that behavior so those things as a leader are very very important you want to
inspire your followers
Use your language from earlier to
Model the behavior to the behavior you want to see so when you see what you when you see what you like
Make sure other people know that you like it
Or know that it's appreciated. You have to be careful with that
right, because
It does it can run the risk
They get misinterpreting. So you want to make sure that what whatever you're celebrating
you're celebrating it as a team goal achieved and that it's not being interpreted as oh
I'm gonna do this because this is what makes Alan happy and
Then I'll get a good review. Yeah as well right cuz that would then reinforce I see how that could happen at Microsoft so
So that is important depending on the culture where you are. I'm glad I was able to load you know load up another Microsoft thing well
It's a company obsessed with competition both against other companies and internally with teams against each other and people against each other
That is for better for worse the culture that drives Microsoft
Yeah, that aspect is is
The intra team
Competition
I'm not gonna lie to you and say it's not there anymore
but it is
vastly
It was there in full force a year and a half ago. It's vastly toned down. All right. I can't comment after that
Alright anything else you want to talk about as far as
principle number four
No, I think we're out of time anyway
Excellent well one last thing to say is viva la France
France just beat Uruguay Oh
France will go to the semi-final in the World Cup. I'm very excited
I predicted France would go to the final where they would lose to Germany
But Germany failed to make it out of the knockout stage so
that happened I
Picked a bracket before the before the tournament started and I get another long outro
The left side of my bracket was I was France perfect. I got everything right the right side nothing
It's all a big mess of everything's wrong
Okay. Well, I am Alan and I'm brain. We'll see you next time