test the modern testing podcast join your hosts Alan and Brent I am mindless
agile robot I must iterate as we talk about software engineering software
quality leadership and whatever else comes to mind now on with the show hey
Brent hey Alan how is it going super happy holidays to the three we are for
the first time ever recording a podcast at Unity's office in Bellevue Washington
if we sound like we're in a different place that's why and Brent is gonna take
a commemorative photo of this event and now it is done and now that part is
probably my fault you can fix that while I talk this is episode number 95 I guess
we should catch up a little bit kind of keep the the pattern to a minimum if we
can although we are incapable of that and then see if we can get into it sound
good Brent it does anything new and exciting I should know about I do
neither new nor exciting okay then yeah so let's get going so let's start with
some reflections on 2018 do you have any of those Brent Brent is frantically
staring at his phone I'm not sure if he is downloading inappropriate material or
if he is just look actually looking for something to do is that your best two
guesses yeah right trap and fire oh yeah favorite book you read in 2018 tensor
flow using Python excellent excellent choice Wow favorite movie the one I
watched the most often I would go with favorite and that would have to be
Guardians of the Galaxy volume two a good choice a good choice which I think
I actually liked better than Avengers infinity war I also loved I also loved
I went and I saw the new spider-man movie this weekend very good my son and
I are my middle son has been on me he is expecting to see that dad very soon is
it's worth it excellent favorite a B testing podcast episodes of 2018 I have two
on that one 77 what do we do in 77 we actually wrote down the principles oh is
that that we've we've vetted though so 20 in reflection 2018 was the year of
the modern testing principles because we came from sort of a outline of like how
about these dude they're not quite right to vetting and editing and also standing
our ground in a few places with the three until we came up with what we
thought would continue to evolve but they've been locked solid for almost a
year now yeah March there is a strong chance I was a strong chance that
episode 100 might be the anniversary of the development of maybe I thought I showed
the modern testing principles briefly at test bash in 2018 which is one of my
highlights of 2018 which was February March and the end of February beginning
in March they might have been done a little earlier than that we might have
the pod I don't know what we'll figure it out we're not too good on 77
remembering things yep my other favorite episode is 86 and that's the one where
we do the drill down and on the customer principle oh yeah which was when
we came up with these I was surprised that that one ended up being
controversial and we've talked about the controversy around that before drink
so yeah that was a good drill down and people that don't get it should listen
that listen to that episode and join the slack channel because the conversation
still continues one of the three dot slack comm you can go to modern testing
org and find a link there to sign yourself up
auto magically I can't think of a good podcast a good favorite podcast of mine
for the last year to answer my own question I already answered the movie
question favorite book I read not as cool as TensorFlow with Python but I read
what was the name of the book about the startup run by the really bad CEO in
Silicon Valley they're they're a blood testing company they're trying to make
hardware to test blood and they were cutting all kinds of corners doing all
kinds of cheating reminded me of when I used to work at midi soft back in the
early 90s bad blood it's called bad blood I thought it was pretty cool I felt
like hey as bad as I thought it was when my CFO told me to start changing time on
our network service so we get a few more sales into each quarter that was
nothing that was like eating cotton candy compared to the stuff going on at
the company whose name I can't remember who actually did go out of business
finally just this year CEO was fired years back but there is a movie being
made it was a great year for Marvel movies also a sad year in losing Stan Lee
I grew up with Marvel Comics so I I see I love that the Marvel Universe is
getting so much love in the cinema did you know there's a my kids are excited
my daughter especially who just turned 13 is excited to go see Deadpool Deadpool 2
because there's a PG version coming out I'm kind of interested to seeing how
much gets edited and what the heck happens why would you know it'd be that's
funny because I could see Deadpool and I could see Reynolds coming out as
Deadpool and then making some snarky jokes about bleeding the teenagers dry
first off we didn't actually talk about Deadpool I have to say that I was
disappointed with Deadpool really yeah I found it nowhere near as as funny although
Deadpool forming up X Factor and then slowly but surely slaughtering them off
accidentally that was amusing that was totally amazing and the invisible guy
did you the invisible guy that you never do was really there until he died did
you see who it was when he gets electrocuted you briefly see his face
no it's Brad Pitt oh anyway one thing as I mentioned we do predictions every year so
we should take some time and talk about our predictions from last year no one of
the things we had a long conversation last year around which episode number this
would be and it's funny because I in the conversation I was all about I think
it's gonna be I did some math I think we'll do it be productive do this many
last year probably around 95 and then so I said that in the conversation I
relistened to the podcast one of the few times I've listened to a podcast
other than editing and then in the then Brett says I think it'll be episode
90 and I said 92 so I'm closer but without going over I'm closer without
going over but we had a fairly productive year we did how many episodes
is that 23 23 episodes pretty good yeah that's almost ones are one every two
weeks almost yeah we we we did between between travel and life we did pretty
well all right well we'll get back to maybe a prediction around that later in
the episode I also threw out a prediction which is which is contrary to
you are wait so far Alan won Brent zero excellent excellent I'm gonna hit a home
run here in a minute you threw out a prediction that maybe episode 100 would
be on the anniversary of our modern testing principal principal reveal or
according to your notes here it said Alan not me predicted that a hundred
would be near the five-year anniversary yeah and we're on track for the brand but
let me finish cuz these are two different things I was getting there you
made a prediction a minute ago five minutes ago an hour a lifetime ago saying
that the episode 100 would possibly be on the anniversary of modern testing
principles and then I was gonna segue that in brilliantly until you screwed it
up to say last year I predicted that episode 100 would be on our five year
anniversary which is just after that in April I can make that both of those
predictions come true I'm still taking applications for people with the first
letter B in their name but another thing we said I think I said it we kind
of agreed on it that that in 2018 by the way Breckner Bach there's plenty of
people Oh God and and now you can figure out which one goes with which all
right predicted that empty modern testing would become a thing and damn it
if it didn't sort of no it's a thing still totally blown away that ministry
of test and actually the reason I know that the principles were at test bash
is shortly after they made that poster of the modern testing principles yeah
which is kind of cool and there were actually it's way way more than kind of
cool it's super cool there was lots of discussion around it we have seen meetups
people have made it central to yeah it's it became a thing I don't know how
because we it wasn't the first external talk I ever gave about modern testing was
in late Feb at test bash Brighton Joe has has made it a key part of his
lightning talks to OTCs in a row so cool thank you everyone out there who has
reviewed and given us feedback on modern testing so hopefully it continues to be a
thing until it doesn't need to be a thing anymore yeah I'm not certain when
that's gonna be yeah predicting things is hard especially about the future I
had a sub prediction with that which actually did not work out where I
predicted that modern testing org would turn into something and it remains to be
purely a redirect into the modern testing principles at some point we could
make a website around that with some more information and we could host the
podcast there versus being in a a sub domain of anger weasel calm which I did
change hosts on anger weasel calm this year and reset everyone's RSS feed as a
side effect of that I would probably would probably have it would have to
happen again if we change web hosting which is one of the big reasons I
haven't thought about that but I don't know if I will continue that prediction
I think I can just keep doing what it's doing I've realized more and more that
domain names don't matter because of search yeah that's true the thing is
even I mean back then when we did this prediction that we saw a lot of momentum
moving towards it in modern testing org being sort of a central place for people
to get information base has as we've gone through this last year I'm not
certain that that's really all that important right the Ministry of Testing
has has con people don't seem to have an inability to to find it right right
right and that's to me that's what's important yeah I like having the domain
and the redirect because a lot easier than telling people to go to angry with
the calm slash a be testing oh for sure in modern testing org and that gets you
everything you need to know podcasts are on that page you are good to go
Brent I want you to talk a little bit more about this prediction because I
will dive in here a little bit you had a little diatribe small soapbox around
how there would be a tipping point in the way test job titles are used do you
remember this yeah I vaguely remember it I don't remember so what I've seen is
it's a tough prediction to make because test job titles for testers are stupid
silly they're all over the map they don't titles are still stupid one year later
yeah this I'm gonna go ahead and and see in terms of your predictions like the
scoreboard I think is Brent zero Allen two will go and with this one I think
it's still Brent zero and but and by the way just jumping to the end it's
Brent zero this is something that I think still is is very important but I
no longer really have a sense that the momentum is in this direction right the
I'm seeing a lot of in in what I'm visible to in the in the test community
I'm seeing a lot of almost for lack of a better word a reinvigoration of
traditional stuff right and I'm thinking thinking through like a recent tweet
storm where yeah we were asked to sort of incorporate the defense of a test
specialist into the modern testing principles yeah and let me let me just
read that so it people who don't follow Twitter can have context someone found
the Ministry of Test list of the modern testing principles and they sent a tweet
to me saying can I suggest number eight we should articulate the value of having
dedicated testing experts whose role is focused on critical thinking achieved by
maintaining critical distance from the product yes that was that event occurred
and that's and that proposal was rejected yeah by both of us in Allen in in the
thread for those who don't want to read the thread Alan essentially said yeah we
think this is covered sufficiently and then I piggybacked off of that and said
you know what MT does not explicitly say one way or the other if a business
decides that they need this great if the business doesn't decide also great
right now that's empty my personal opinion which which may not necessarily
align with with well it aligns with what I just said about MT but I will go back
my rule of thumb is the term specialist is a bottleneck so yes I am
unlikely to ever proactively in a written form defend the role of a
specialist short-term sure I would defend it but it has to be it would be in
my mind all right if I'm helping to make this decision my job is that going to be
to alright I have a bigger problem to solve right now but I'm going to be
creating a new problem by incorporating a specialist into the system and so it's
going to be a cost-benefit analysis in my view I get it yeah more importantly is
I don't know if we maybe it wasn't it wasn't conscious from my part but we've
been talking about modern testing as the antidote or I've added that word is the
antidote to traditional test last bottleneck testing and the principles as
you know if you've if you've read them don't talk about testing they're about
how to make quality software yeah so having one specifically about testing
was weird but there always be people who want to and they see this a lot there is
a faction and rightfully so of testers worried about job preservation and by
pressing this idea that your special snowflake like I'm the only one that can
apply critical thinking and critical distance to the product that it helps
preserve that that role that specialization for a job I am about
getting rid of bottlenecks and we'll actually talk more about that a little
bit I'm about yeah getting rid of bottlenecks is certainly part of it the
the thing I would really like to see and it's really hard to defend against
but the the old story of the Emperor's new clothes right I think the test
discipline has wrapped themselves up in the the Emperor's clothes and for a long
time and I'm nodding my head trying to shine the light on this and in the way I
internalize it is is getting some of these folks to open their eyes and
re-look at the world they're in particularly the leaders like the the
leaders in the test community who are open-minded and have a defense against
the following phrase I have been in the industry for 20,000 years and I know
everything and I'm exaggerating of course no you're not there's not too many
people been here for 20,000 years but you get the point right that experience is
valuable particularly with those leaders and what I would love to see a
lot more of is those folks saying recognizing that what got us here may not
necessarily get us where we need to go for sure right all right back to the
list so on the tipping point the way test hot job titles are used I'm gonna
take that back and matter of fact it's Brent zero Brent zero and I don't see I
do think that the way this happens is we get enough in the leadership on this
front but I'm definitely wrong on this one and and I actually don't see it's
coming close it may not be a change is needed yeah what about the next one I
have some thoughts on this but I'm gonna let you answer it you said that
AI would become democratized that is still on track yeah it's happening at the
house we might come it's happening it's not there it's not there yet but it is it
is so that prediction I think is still very valid I'm just off by the timeline
yeah that's cool I'm even now telling people and I mentioned this on the slack
channel people going into college today I currently don't think data science is the
way to go if you want to go into software industry I do think targeting a t-shaped
role focused on CS but adding data science is the way to go I think the
devs of the future need to have this in their back in their back pocket yes I
agree so I had a prediction that and someone can I didn't go look at the
websites to see if these things happen that I didn't know about them maybe they
were going on and I was subconsciously do about them but we had a discussion a
year ago I said that machine learning would creep its way into automation and
that they'd apply ml to test automation to help solve some of the problems and
where's my bell sound ding with the rise of things like Mabel and test him and a
few others using ml to take care of the flaky test problem with web automation
that happened that's out there that's done I don't know if I in hindsight
these companies have had to have been around for more than a year so maybe I
just didn't know about them I heard about them I was influenced but if I
didn't I'm a genius yeah or very very lucky I'm realizing how how you nailed
your prediction here because I think two things that you really say that really
nailed this number one ml will creep its way right you know any sort of
movement into automation with the word creep makes that a winner oh don't
make fun of my weasel words the other one is tool vendors will apply ml
oh my god right all that really means is will tool vendors to pass this flag
tool vendors all they have to do is realize make fun all you want I'm not
making fun of you actually I'm making fun of tool vendors say hi I'm a tool
vendor for automation we have all the ml's and all the AI's yep yep okay ding
point for me yep for sure and did you finally graduate no that was your
prediction yeah Brent did you said you're gonna reboot blogging did you do
that no and Brent last but not least for sure wrong
Kylo Ren will be revealed as Darth Reven yeah matter of fact we didn't even
talk about that Star Wars movie Last Jedi with a name like that you expect
cool man we didn't talk about it but man was I disappointed about that whole
thing like I don't get where where they're going with this franchise like
the next Star Wars movie hopefully they'll be the last one because I will
probably be thankful it one last thing on the reflections I wanted to mention
before we go into prediction mode is I discovered many new blogs this year but
I discovered my favorite blog that was new to me at least in the last year and
I've tweeted a lot about it I don't know if we've ever talked about it on the air
Jeff Niman you know do Jeff is no stories from a software tester very good
writer much better than me he writes about a lot of topics that are I don't
even know if he knows much about modern testing if that's on his radar but I think
I do yeah it's a tester stories comm stories from a software tester he had a
post about should be higher specialist testers of course he takes six pages to
write about it well he probably needs to explain why yeah but he has he's he
makes some good cases he writes well so that's my I wanted to give him a shout
out just because that's it's one of the blogs of course I have a RSS feed of a
gazillion blogs I look at most I don't read through his posts are ones that I
stop and read so that's my new discovery any new discoveries on the web
for you this year blogs websites no actually this year so the stories of the
tester like the the thing that was interesting to me most of the the blog
stuff that's relevant to our audience was a random listing of people and how
they're using modern testing modern testing is is in a lot more discussions
and they're just popping up everywhere so that's where I've either that or
investigations into data science is where I've been spending my time okay I
have not other than our own this last year I don't think I've actually
listened to a single podcast oh I've been getting really into trivia
podcasts oh you've always been into it I didn't know I added a few more to my my
rep my list trivial warfare probably one of my favorites now gets a little
obnoxious sometimes but it's fun I like trivia I like watching jeopardy I played
jeopardy on my Amazon echo all the time I do pretty well I have to say yeah
all right let's look forward to 2019 but before you and I look forward to 2019
let's we had a few members of the three look forward 2019 want to share what
they had so we had one of our listeners Ryan Kuelhorst send in his thoughts about
2019 in an audio clip here it is hi Alan and Brent and the other two
listeners of the A B testing podcast my name is Ryan and here are my predictions
for 2019 I think first off teams will start to utilize JavaScript and node JS
more in their test automation strategy I've been diving into node JS and the
last year and I found a lot of really helpful libraries some of them include like
Cypress IO and test cafe for UI testing really nice HTTP client I use axios JS
and for machine learning I've been kind of diving into TensorFlow JS so I think
there's really powerful to use JavaScript as a language for your
automation strategy so I kind of see teams moving in that direction another
thing I see DevOps DevOps DevOps like everyone is talking about DevOps and I
know there I know you might be like come on Ryan DevOps that was like five
years ago it wasn't the Phoenix project released five years ago big
organizations are just now getting into looking into DevOps as kind of a way to
run their organization so one of the like big tip offs was for me for this was
a local QA conference conference just released their speaker talks and half of
them were focused around DevOps so I think DevOps is definitely starting to
build momentum and you'll just see like you'll just get hammered with DevOps
DevOps DevOps in the last in the next year the last thing is there's a new
Avengers movie Avengers Endgame the last movie Infinity Wars edit on such a
hopeless note and it's really it kind of akin back to the Empire Strikes Back
but I just hope Endgame doesn't have the same kind of lackluster conclusion
as Return of the Jedi like make it better make Thanos I don't know better
than than what like Vader turned into so kind of on that note I wish Alan and
Brent and the other two listeners a happy 2019 cheers so thoughts on that I
have my own but I'll let you start this time Wow no I'm actually thinking it's
too bad Ryan's name doesn't start with a B Brian yeah maybe maybe he's
comfortable changing it to Brian so I'm I'm gonna jump in because I use a lot of
Node.js I'm doing Advent of Code this year although I get kind of stuck a couple
days ago so I'm stopped because it's hard but I've done everything in
JavaScript using node and we have a lot of node apps here and I play with a lot
and he's right there is we're starting to see almost a tipping point of testing
and analysis and quality tools built on top of JavaScript built with JavaScript
built on top of the node package manager library you know NPM install all the
good stuff and I see more and more test type tools showing up there so that's
a good observation about yeah I think he could be right that we are ready for
that to become even more of a thing I think it's gonna continue right and
Brent got all squealy when he mentioned TensorFlow yeah that was that was
fantastic good good job Ryan the first so the one thing that was interesting to
me is that the his first prediction he might as well have been speaking Greek
right these are I'm like what what are these things right it's like I listen to a
foreign language you hear like one word you know it's like what what a lot
TensorFlow yeah yeah no it's it's I've realized that I personally my investments
in in sort of the the test space in a deep dive rather small a lot of these
things I don't understand what they are anymore right I would I would not be able
to go back to test if I wanted well think it from this perspective when you move
to modern testing if you if say you get to principle number seven and you get to
the point where you no longer need actually have to go that far as far as
not needing a dedicated testing specialist one way to get developers to do better
testing and write better quality code is make it easy for them to insert quality
and testing tools into the workflows they already know node does that yeah and
there's there is here's one one thing that I have observed and and I don't
know about the specifics of Ryan's first prediction but one thing I observe is
technical communities so here I'm talking about people's code getting
together and sharing knowledge not necessarily people those are thriving the
matter of fact actually just this last weekend I've been doing a lot of ML I'm
on my holiday vacation starting last Friday I do a lot of one of the things
that's generally been true first thing I do when I go on vacation is I work on the
the AI stuff that I haven't been able to do at work because I'm a manager and
people like are you my wife's like are you doing work I'm like well literally
yes but no but for example your Taylor Swift ML thing that you sent out a while
ago I read that and the approach that they do is very similar to a problem that
I have so I've been working on sort of re-implementing that approach against my
data set and it's it's that sort of humidity around code around even
solutions and then blogs and stuff that's thriving DevOps DevOps DevOps oh
yeah that so that was one of my predictions so Ryan's predictions right
so I think as we get through playing through the three I'll have nothing so
that way oh okay yeah so the DevOps thing I definitely think that that's I
obviously I completely agree with with with Ryan on I think and we've talked
about the three ways of DevOps all line a lot with modern testing principles so I
think if our if as much as modern testing is becoming a thing DevOps people
actually getting what it is not using it as a buzzword which thankfully they
haven't done with modern testing yet is something yes I agree yeah I have a I have
a relevant segue to that it's the last thing on our segue flash tangent yeah I
don't want to take it yet but but I do think DevOps is DevOps is going to be a
thriving thing and I also think it is part positive and part negative I think
one of the big one of the major reasons for this is that it is to business
leaders who do not understand the test role it is an obvious thing to take these
trained experienced people and move them into yeah I'm kind of glad we
didn't have a lot of these or more than one of these audio submissions because
you're kind of turning them into full-on mailbag answers but they're
just prediction fan so Avengers Endgame my notes here say there should be no
ewoks in Avengers Endgame yeah we'll see I'm really looking forward to that
movie I like a dark movie once in a while I liked Infinity War thought it
was very well done yeah they've done a good job hyping up Chris Evans hopefully
whatever the hell happens to Captain America meets up to the hype but of
course it won't we will get there a couple other notes from the three to
show you on Avengers one of the things so you've seen the trailer yes okay one
of the things that I am extremely curious to find out is how the hell at
man got out of the quantum room because the end of the the ended number two and
he's stuck there and then suddenly he shows up and the remaining Avengers
don't know how he did it so all right well we'll get there sure a few other
notes from the three Patrick Peryll test Pappy has no predictions but does
want to say thanks for the awesome episodes 2018 and looking forward to more
interesting discussions in 2019 thank you Patrick we will try and do that
Percy is jet-legged but he says his prediction is a growth on practical
illustrative examples on how to employ MT well sure I hope that happens too and
it is and and an increase in attacks against MT which I think I think that's a
valid and probably going to come true prediction as well I think I'm okay
with that I think both of those will come true I mean the first one's easy
we just had to have one and then it you know we have an increase growth so are
you ready for our own predictions that you haven't already shared you ready
yeah you have any so what do you think what what's gonna be new in 2019 one or
two things it has to be a lot of things but fire something out that as we know
from last year it's probably not gonna happen so one thing I will say is that
I will finally decide this year whether or not I will actually graduate matter
of fact I got to do that within days all right yeah that one's still a
tortured decision for me I kind of wish my personality type was a little bit if
I were closer to Alan's personality type I'm pretty sure this would be easy
what what personality type is that fabulous in this particular case it's an I
think actually you if you were in my shoes right you have one class left to
take on the degree I think that would be all you would need for a decision
yeah yeah I'm a I'm a I'm a deep analyzer and so yes it's still a struggle
so well I'll discover what what I'll decide I don't know if I mentioned this
on the air but there's two things I want to mention on the air before we go on
one is one more reflection my favorite author Steven Johnson came out with a
new book this year it's called Far Sight it's about how to make how people
make decisions and not in the blink or the decisive blink with Malcolm Webwell
decisive the Heath brothers he looking at decisions to take a bunch of factors
that have that have outcomes that last years or decades or more so more of the
big decision-making kind of things very fat as usual fascinating read but your
thing on decisions reminded me of that the other thing I want to mention is we
haven't done a sponsor in a long time and we don't have this isn't a sponsor
but I do want to give a big shout out to the folks at hey taco we use this this
bot called hey taco in our in our slack group to it's a free currency to give
other people when they do things you like they pass out a taco you can give
away five tacos a day I love gamification of of promoting like
helping each other and sharing I think it's a great idea their cost after the
free trial was a little more than we could afford on our non our what's what's
not only nonprofit but operate at a loss podcast effort so they gave us a sweet
deal on continuing to use hey taco and so huge thanks to them it's really cool
if you got if you use slack in a professional setting that makes money you
I can't recommend it enough it's very cool stuff okay all that all that said I
wanted to give him a shout out I should have done earlier but I'll
probably mention them a lot throughout the year because they're awesome and
just really great experience talking to them and and using the product so very
excited I was quite saddened when I read your statement around hey they want
us to want us to pay for it because uh yeah once you once you get the taco
yeah tacos are great so tacos are around for a long time that's good okay
so and I even spent some amount of time looking through right how we could set
up the rewards on the tacos all right we'll get back to the world then what
are your predictions is we'll figure out something interesting to do with tacos
in 2019 sure that is marked all right what other predictions do you have as it
stands right now for me on the on the test front you know it's really hard for
for me to make a prediction on that one what I'm seeing in terms of momentum is
is sort of a polarization happening which I guess is standard I'll call it
the well we already have it the traditionalist and the modern testing is
right um will that conclude next year probably not but yeah so in terms of
Percy's prediction on more attacks yeah I agree on that one okay do you have any
predictions of your own yeah okay those would be good to get to so well I guess
there are more predictions I want to read but I'm afraid you'll comment at
length about them no let me just say in terms of in terms of data science stuff I
do think the democratization will absolutely continue and I do think we're
gonna see in the next year I think we're gonna see comments from the three around
actually using it to achieve test goals here what we see a listener basis you I
see a lot of people commenting on it and a lot of it's very theoretical I'll see I
think we'll see them actively using it and actively being successful okay anything
else no all right I want to throw out two quick predictions from Patrick Prel
that just came in moments ago and then I'll go on with mine the first one is
probably they're both very unlikely number one Trump will not do something
extraneous extraordinarily stupid for two days in a row I can't see that happening
but you know you never know and number two is you'll love this one
ISTQB will come up with a certificate for the modern testing practitioner
imprints making a face so don't comment I don't I think probably that one is more
likely to happen than the first one can they do that with our license we don't
have yeah I guess I really know it's license we the principles are creative
common pay it forward that you have to attribute but yeah they could if they
want to they won't I think principle number seven is in would they'd have a
hard time with that one because they're a for-profit business on creating testing
specialists so yeah yeah be interesting if they did it
okay so my predictions I know I would work hard to make sure that doesn't
happen so I got got got I have talked a lot about moving my org towards modern
testing and how I am slowly but surely working myself out of a role but
hopefully not a job I think I'm on track in 2019 to actually work myself out of a
role so I will have a new role same job new role I don't know what that is yet
DevOps DevOps DevOps DevOps one thing to mention about DevOps is one of my
former test leads is now a DevOps lead and there are it was a no-brainer
striking similarities it is in this DevOps is of course a culture not a role
but you may be in a DevOps role to help move the team towards a DevOps culture
which is what he's doing and I think we've said a very very very similar
thing about QA or test roles yeah unless you finish your predictions but
there's a lot of similarity there yeah so that will happen the other one was
test pappies number one prediction is not coming true that won't happen I vowed
took a I made a statement that I would not speak at conferences in 2019 and I
will say that will not be true but will be true is I will not speak at any
testing conferences in 2019 any even OTC test bash I'm not gonna speak at test
conferences in 2019 that's my prediction we'll see how what will
we'll come back and watch me do like 10 I'm kind of burned out on test
conferences I love test bash I'm burned out on many of the other ones and some
I will just there's some I just will not go back to it's too much of a
world I don't want to live in I am I could see you not going but especially
when we do test bash Seattle I'll have to go to that but that probably won't be
in 2019 I may given the right opportunity speak at a non testing conference but
we'll see I may it may just be there I speak at no conferences but if I do
speak at a conference it will not be a testing conference I guess is the actual
prediction yeah it's interesting that Lisa Crisp and I don't know if you've
been following this she's trying to speak at DevOps conferences no oh good
she's wondering how to how to break in because it's it's uh she's been rejected
apparently interesting but right I I do think that's gonna be a big mover I
think it's actually rather brilliant of Lisa to realize that that's where she
needs to go yeah for sure I don't know I haven't heard any statement around her
saying she's gonna stop doing test conferences but it does seem like it's a
thought process it's in her mind cool I also predict that Avengers Endgame will
be my favorite movie of 2019 I predict that the Seattle Sounders not Royal
Salt Lake salty gunner is a real Salt Lake fan
Seattle Saddles will return to the MLS Cup and win it in 20 between 19 yep and
what else what are the random predictions can I give to kind of screw
things up I'll do one last one last prediction for bread we will create a
principle number eight holy crap okay I may reject one out of spite okay that's
it that's a bold prediction because I could see I will be as much as I like you
to get zero points in your predictions if there's a valid number eight of course
no I I'm interesting I will not bring it up I'll leave it as a cliffhanger yes
but I believe I have found a key flaw that I think MT needs to address that
is cool all right I'm not even gonna ask you what that is on the air to find that
out you're going to have to listen to episode number 96 which will come out
sometime in January of 2019 all right I am Alan and he is Brent I took it from
you huh happy holidays everyone we'll see you next year bye guys