A.B.
Test
New Year!
Welcome, welcome.
Good to have you here on the A.B.
Testing Podcast.
I'm...
All three of you.
Yes, thank you all three of you for listening yet again and joining us in 2019.
And I made this rant one year ago, almost exactly, in 2018.
The proper way to pronounce the year we're in is 2019, not 2019.
If you disagree, you can just stop talking to me.
If you feel like it's something you're going to repeat every year...
I wasn't born in 1965.
I was born in 1965.
Just saying.
Yeah, if you're going to do this every year, perhaps you need to be a bit more assertive
or tell them what, you know, something a bit stronger.
Like it's 2019, right?
Yeah, I don't know why I would need to be assertive.
I was like, do I need to be assertive saying that two plus two is four?
No, people should just know that.
Well, you know, the other thing too, I don't think our listeners would pronounce it incorrectly.
I don't think they really care about this conversation.
So let's move on.
Okay.
Anyway, happy new year, Alan.
Yeah, you too, Brad.
Did you enjoy your break?
I did.
I did nothing but play Xbox and watch Netflix pretty much.
I did some house cleaning.
It was fun.
I did not get away from the screen, but I watched a lot of Binging.
I watched Bandersnatch.
I watched Birdcage.
Birdbox.
Birdcage.
Awesome movie.
Totally different plot.
I watched the Birdbox.
It was good.
It caught up on my Luke Cage, got into my Daredevil.
I'm kind of behind on the whole Marvel, Netflix thing because so many come out.
And I don't have that much time.
Yeah, you get a lot of time.
Yeah.
And so I didn't get as far as I wanted.
Excellent.
I can get caught up without worrying about when is the next Jessica Jones coming out,
which is my favorite.
Is it?
Yeah.
I liked Iron Fist, but I have a martial arts background.
And that's probably the most.
The Iron Fist ended it so freaking weird.
I haven't watched that one yet.
I was a big fan of the comic book.
Yeah.
Both.
I have many issues at home of Luke Cage, the comic, which turned into Power Man, the
comic.
I also have the whole Iron Fist series, only 15 comics.
And then I think John Byrne, who did X-Men, drew all those and tell the stories.
But I also have the Power Man and Iron Fist series.
I have a comic book collection at home that is probably worth today around $30,000.
And so let's excuse us for the tangent.
So Marvel's DC?
Mostly Marvel.
I was a big Marvel thing.
I should give you my stash link.
Okay.
I don't know what that is.
It's a website where I have all my comic books cataloged.
Yeah, you should.
I would love to.
So I was almost all Marvel.
I haven't cataloged.
So I used to catalog them in Excel.
And then I would download the, what is that, one catalog book.
It's a huge, the Over...
Overstreet comic book guide.
I used to keep little index cards of all my comics.
So I had condition and writer and artist, et cetera.
So what was your jam?
What was your go-to comic, your favorite?
Oh, Thor.
Oh, really?
Yeah.
Thor.
That's interesting.
I was total X-Men.
I had pretty much everything from, for a while, I sold some of the more expensive ones in
college to make some money, but from the, what do they call them?
The new X-Men.
But from 1994 on?
The new ones.
No, no, no.
Those came much, much later.
So that was more mid-70s to early 80s collecting.
I didn't stop collecting.
Actually, you know when I stopped?
When I moved to Microsoft.
I stopped in college.
I was out of money and actually sold some comics in college to make money.
So I did, I didn't stop comics, but what I ended up doing, I made a lot of money off
of magic cards during that same time period.
Oh, interesting.
Interesting.
I never got into that.
I think the writing on some of those X-Men series was so good.
I had a girlfriend in high school who was way into soap operas.
Oh.
And which, like, whatever.
Oh, soap operas.
It was high school.
But I remember giving her my X-Men, like, check these out, and she got totally hooked
reading through those stories because they're so well written and so well, you know, cliffhangers,
every issue.
Do you know, do you remember the name Walt Simonson?
No.
So he was the writer of the Thor books back in the day.
And the stories he wrote are a big part of what's in the MCU right now.
Oh, interesting.
Very, very interesting.
Yeah.
And of course, X-Men, those who don't pay close attention to the Marvel universe, X-Men
actually live in a different universe than the more mainstream.
In the MCU.
And do you know why?
Actually, I don't know why.
Because Sony owns the rights to X-Men and they can't.
That is why Scarlet Witch got her powers from the Infinity Stone and not actually being
a mutant.
Yeah.
Okay.
Well, you got to do what you got to do.
Indeed.
Speaking of cliffhangers, do you want to...
Oh.
It's episode 96.
Yeah, this is episode 96.
So you just hung out for the break.
Yeah.
I ended up spending a week in Carlsbad, California.
I saw it with the Disneyland, which is not in Carlsbad.
No, it's in LA, Anaheim.
Right.
So I grew up in LA and man, is Disneyland different.
No.
Disneyland itself isn't, but the parking structure wasn't there.
I've never parked there.
I've always just gone for a conference or flown down a stain at the hotel and then
walked over to the park.
The Downtown Disney thing seems to have changed quite a bit from...
That didn't exist when I was there.
Yeah.
And the California thing didn't exist.
The crowd was crazy.
Yeah.
I definitely, now, I've been to both, but at this point in time, I definitely prefer
Walt Disney World.
If nothing else, because it spreads the crowd out through like 18 different parks.
Yeah.
I went to Disneyland Japan once and that was...
You think the lines in California were long.
It was every single, every attraction was two hours.
Yeah.
We didn't have that problem.
There's a great app that we took advantage of.
We very quickly, me and my son, who were more efficiency minded, worked together and
worked out like timing and minimizing wait times.
Very lovely.
My agile training got involved in...
Very well done.
Walking through.
And then there's an update that I have.
So as the three know, I've only had one class left and just before New Year, I finally
went and tried to go sign up for the class.
And I couldn't.
The website said, not a student.
The web, a bunch of other signs on that.
And I'm like, holy crap.
And then I went and looked up requirements on the degree.
It's in the University catalog.
And it said, you have to pass these things and you have six years to do it.
It's one thing that's nice about my school.
For a master's degree, you have six years.
It's online.
You can really take it easy.
And then if you work at something like Microsoft, with six years, you can really spread out
the classes and take advantage of the education benefit here, where they'll pay for school,
but they'll only do a max of 10K a year.
Anyway, I, as several people know, I was iffy.
I'm like, God, I don't want to do this.
But it's one thing.
And going back and forth.
Well, once I discovered that the choice had been taken from me, I was actually surprisingly
depressed.
I'm like, oh, okay.
What do I do on my resume?
What do I do if people want to...
Just lie like everyone else.
Yeah.
Well, you weren't there at the time.
So the couple of days later, I sent mail to the registrar playing dumb saying, hey,
I can't register.
What's going on?
And they came back and they said, oh, yeah.
I just put a block on you because you took the last year off.
I'll re-enable it and you'll be able to go and register.
And then I realized even though 2019 minus 2013 is six, I still have all of 2019 to complete
my sixth year.
And I'm like, so a little bit of relief.
Signed up.
Class already started.
I still am not happy that I have to do this.
But you don't have to.
I don't have to.
You don't have to do anything.
No.
So now I realize that if I don't...
I will regret it if I don't complete it.
So that little thing actually closed the decision making process for me.
Cool.
Anyway.
You can join me in having a master's degree.
That'd be nice.
Of course, my master's is useless, but well, I learned how to learn.
I don't think your master's is useless.
All the research part, I still apply every day.
And the other thing I'm excited about, because I've known this for two years now, is that
is once I am done, I already know what I'm going to go do next.
And it's relevant because I'm going to start taking guitar lessons.
All right.
Cool.
Do you want to do a podcast?
Sure.
Let's do a podcast.
All right.
If you haven't listened to episode 95, our year in review, which by the way...
You didn't do it like Voiceover guy.
Last time on...
Last time on AUB testing.
One, our episode was mentioned in the latest weekly update from Ministry of Test.
That episode was?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Why?
Because it's cool to listen to.
Oh, the podcast, sure.
But why that episode?
Because people like reflections predictions.
So then they can come make fun of us when we're wrong.
But as we were leaving the room, as I was heading on my vacation, you were returning to yours.
You said something interesting.
I did.
I believe I have discovered a missing principle from MT.
You have, have you?
I believe I do.
Is it the Peter Principle?
No.
Since that one is well established, doesn't need to be part of MT.
Although actually, in a twisted way, yes, it is the Peter Principle.
Tell me your hypothesis.
And for those of you following, we don't add principles willy nilly.
We don't even edit them willy nilly.
We vet them significantly among our three listeners who all hang out with us on one
of the three.slack.com.
Of course, you can go to moderntesting.org and click the link to join that Slack group.
Free to join.
But.
And it's the only place to get the cool sticker.
I don't know what you're going to say, but let's talk about this proposed principle
number eight, which I already feel strongly against.
And we will discuss it.
And you feel strongly against just because seven's a cooler number than eight?
Because I feel like the principle.
More and more, I feel like the principles are complete.
Okay.
Let me sum the current principles.
Number one, I'm not going to read this whole thing.
It's around guiding people towards the key focus, which is the business.
Number two, it's about being in a team accelerant and it speaks to sort of an execution model
and the types of differences we use to execute.
Number three, a force of continuous improvement.
If you were to sum up, this is about adaptability, not prescriptability.
We're helping the team learn.
Sure.
Well, then I would say number four is about the quality culture.
And I think that's a big part of helping the team learn, but it's a team focus.
You help the team grow.
Number five, it's about the customer.
And in my view, it is about the true definition of the word quality.
Number six, data.
Data is great, but in another aspect, it's about an execution model.
It's about a how.
And then finally, we expand the testability and know how.
This is about testing scale and in my view, removing testing specialists from being a linchpin
in the system.
Sure.
Okay.
One of the things that we've talked about over and over again is followers of MT need
to be accustomed to taking a leadership role.
I think the fatal flaw right now is in the MT principles.
If you go through and you do this and you do this too soon, what happens to you?
And I think one of the aspects that is missing from MT is that, and I wanted to talk about
it today.
I wanted to propose it and see if you agreed and then maybe brainstorm around the language.
But I think the issue that we are missing is, you know this whole phrase, you can't love
anybody else if you don't love yourself?
No.
Okay.
It's a phrase it's old.
I think it's similar to leadership.
One of the first things around learning leadership is leading by example.
I do think one of the things that you have that is missing from MT is some sort of principle
that specifies you need to guide yourself, you need to control your own destiny as a result
or as part of this as you go through and migrate people to an MT philosophy.
Thoughts?
I will say it is on the slide channel, why you're thinking.
One of the most common questions that we have is, well, what happens to me or where do we
go or how do we do it?
They're very tactical things.
So that point is true.
A lot of questions we get are what happens after I transition my team to modern testing?
If I'm going through that myself, continually shrinking my team, what do I do next?
So that part I fully agree with.
That part we need to discuss because the answer to that is a bunch of different things.
And then getting into your point, yes, it's important that we think about how do we,
what does our transition role look like?
But the difficult part is for that question is that it is unique for, it's going to
be unique for every single person.
There isn't a blueprint like the person that transitions teams to modern testing.
This is the role they typically do, that it looks like X.
That's stuck in a habit.
I actually like that modern testing principles are about how they're really an extension,
as I called it before, of Agile testing.
But they're about the team, how the team becomes a top class software engineering team.
What things do they have to do to make quality software that combat all the things that
are wrong with traditional test blast, test as the bottleneck, test as the scapegoat, testing
approaches?
I completely agree.
I like that.
So it's tough for me.
But let me add one counterpoint.
Okay, then I'll go on.
If we have software teams today, it's going to be about leadership.
We talk about transitioning of activities, as well as supporting or investing in several
execution activities.
The one thing that has occurred in both your and my careers in the past is as we work towards
elimination of things that are stupid, we've both discovered that we get acknowledged and
moved into a different role.
However, I don't know that it's entirely accidental or luck driven.
Both you and I, for example, as I moved out of test, I went to dev.
How did I get to dev?
Well I invested myself because at minimum I needed to pass the stupid interview.
The leader in the empty space that we're targeting here needs to have a sense of where they're
going and needs to invest in themselves as well.
I think while you were talking, I got why it doesn't click with me.
And maybe this is where some feedback would help.
The modern testing principles, again, I call the antidote to traditional software testing.
That's how we make software in a much better, more efficient way that's going to be better
for our customers and better for our business and more efficient overall.
They're team based.
I think where the glitch comes in is we've talked about this before, but very early
on in our discussions about modern testing, we said there's no such thing as a modern
tester.
But we've also acknowledged that someone who's leading the team towards modern testing principles
could be referred to as a modern tester.
But I still, and that's I guess sort of the role I'm in, I'm not a new name for that.
If the person that led the team towards modern testing principles was called the Poobah,
I'm in the role of a Poobah.
We have language for it.
We call it the coach.
Okay, so I'm the coach.
These aren't coaching principles.
They're about the team.
So it just so happens that I'm in individual role, but the principles, having a principle
around an individual role takes away from the modern testing principles which are about
team achievements and team capabilities.
I hear what you're saying.
So I'm still not thinking it's a principle, but given the amount of questions that
given what I'm going through myself, given the discussion we've had on the Slack channel
about this, given how open ended is, oh my God, what happens?
And also adding into that the fact that just like when Microsoft or Yahoo or whoever just
got rid of their testers thinking getting rid of the safety net entirely was all you
needed to do, there is a probably legitimate worry as more and more teams become aware
of what modern testing is going.
Okay, let's do that.
Let's skip to the last half of principle number seven that'll accelerate it.
It accelerates in the mission statement.
We'll make all that happen.
I think there is some sort of a den.
I'm not sure what the proper name for this is.
Let's not get semantic yet, but there's a lot of principle.
There is a supporting paragraph or a supporting manifest, a supporting something.
I don't know if it's a principle or not.
That supports the leadership and the individual role and what happens when someone
gets caught.
But I have just realized, so this is fantastic.
This is kind of what I was hoping it would happen.
So principles, let's ignore the semantics.
If it's important enough, you and I will agree it's a principle.
I'm not going to try to fight that.
I think there's agreement that it's an important topic.
Principle number five.
We can have this discussion to vet it out, but only the customer, our listeners, people
who only our listeners can help us figure out what is right here.
We'll just have the debate to get the ideas out there.
Okay, go on.
One of the things, and what you just said triggered a thought, and it's a thought that
I've seen over and over again in the teams who I trained through Agile.
I now have gotten very good at de-specializing teams.
But once there's momentum in that direction, you need to stop them before they overgeneralize.
So you can think of it as a pendulum between specialists and generalists, and you de-specialize
and they are becoming nice, TC people, but then they don't stop.
Until they're flat as a pancake.
And the risk with overgeneralized people is that they're all the same.
So the problem with having a team is teams are made up of individuals.
You can't treat them.
There is an investment that needs to be done within a team at an individual level because
they are part of the team.
In a soccer team, you don't train everyone to be a keeper.
You don't train everyone to be a forward.
You do want some versatility, but the people who are talented at keeping and forwarding
– yeah, I know all the soccer's – you want to invest in that specialization while
still maintaining that generalization.
And I think language that is highlighted around that is important and missing.
Your turn.
Now I've got to think about that because now it's clicking a little bit better.
I don't know.
I've got to think about that for a minute because it doesn't have the same sort of trigger
as the – let's have a principle about the individual.
Agile's different than MT.
MT fits within agile very well, like a foot in a sock.
There's probably a better metaphor there.
Is there anything in modern – anything in the principles now that would lead a team towards
overgeneralization?
I think.
I don't think so.
Convince me I'm wrong.
Boy, we could –
So here's the thing I'm saying is that there's nothing that prevents it.
I don't think it's anything that encourages it either.
No, it's – so what I will tell you is, at least from my experience, like a lot
of the principles we have here, as you well know, come from Lean and –
And DevOps.
And DevOps and other things like that.
But this is – much of what is discussed here is we're telling people to battle against
external forces.
And I think it's entirely possible.
Let's take your situation as an example.
I think you're leading all of this just fine.
But once you have created a stable quality culture, once you have converted people into
understanding the customer and not the PM is the only one that matters, once you've
convinced people that the team is stronger by spreading out the testing abilities – right?
Let's take that aspect.
So for a lot of teams – and I'm certain this happens within Unity, but I don't know.
I don't work there.
Several people are going to view you as, in fact, the test guy, regardless of what decoration,
what title, and how you frame it.
You're going to be the test guy to at least one person –
Probably more true for the people on my team than for me.
Right.
When you succeed in publicly spreading out your secret ingredient, your special ingredient,
the reason why they hired you, and you've convinced them that, yeah, in fact, we don't
need Alan's team, if you haven't invested in some fashion of where you're going to
go next, that puts you at risk.
I think that lives outside the – I don't feel at risk.
The absolute worst thing that happens –
Well, yeah, but is that just because you're chock full of self-confidence?
No, I don't have nearly enough self-confidence, but I do have enough – I mean, the absolute
worst case thing that could happen is they say, thanks for fixing all this stuff, Alan.
We don't need you anymore.
Then I go find another job.
That's the worst case, but that's not going to happen.
So yes, you need to think about probably earlier than you think about what you do
next and how your role evolves.
It's really not a next.
It's not a step.
It's an evolution.
Yes.
As you are helping the team adapt, you yourself need to adapt.
Yeah, absolutely.
That's –
And I get that, but I think –
And you can't ignore it.
That's the message I'm trying to say.
This is something we'll continue to discuss.
I'm not bought in yet.
I think the individual growth comes outside of modern testing.
But while you were talking about overgeneralization, I wanted to walk through the principles real
quick and ask you this.
I'm curious what would happen.
It's like, can you overdo any of these principles?
For example, walk through with me.
Listen, don't read.
Could we improve the business?
Could we over-prioritize improving the business?
I guess, yeah, if you put it that way, maybe.
Yeah, for sure.
You couldn't improve it too much, but you could over-prioritize it.
Could you accelerate the team too much?
I guess you could focus too much on it.
Now that I'm reading through it, you could overemphasize it.
The way you're going to go is very much my complaint about the Agile Manifesto, right?
People, the part of the thing about the principles is they're intended to balance each other
out to make sure that you don't overemphasize one thing in contrast to another.
So I'm going to say if there were to be –
It's a system.
I was going to say if there were to be an eighth principle, that it would be that these
principles are a system.
They work together.
Actually, this is maybe going somewhere.
I'll get the right phrasing here, but leaving one out or overemphasizing on one is not
modern testing.
It's a balance.
It's a balanced system.
You can't just go, yeah, these are great, but we're not going to do the data thing
because we think they're stupid.
It's not empty.
Or these are great, but it's somebody else's problem to improve the business.
We're not going to focus on that.
That's not our thing.
This is a challenging topic.
When I coach people through, particularly if I'm going to coach people through Kanban,
if they're in waterfall and I skip straight to Kanban, it's foreign to them.
Oh, no shit.
I mean, yes.
And the biggest problem – and here I will say a problem in this context – with a shift
to Agile, let's say, again, like Kanban here, is it's principle driven.
It doesn't tell you what to do, per se.
It tells you how to decide.
I like Mary Poppendyke's principles that she uses.
For example, the one I'm thinking of right now is optimize the whole, which says you're
going to have some business KPI, optimize the business KPI, don't decompose it into
its component parts and try to sub-optimize those.
From a data science point of view, I know that to be true because you end up having
one KPI, one of these component KPIs cannibalizing the other and having no effect on the whole.
But I did the analysis and I said, okay, I think she has seven principles in her list.
And I said, what happens if I do – I did this for each of them.
What happens if I do all the others but not that one?
And every single time, I was able to go, oh, this dysfunction would creep out.
I see the same thing with ours.
Not to break my arm, patting ourselves on the back, but I think they're a system.
So I'd be curious to look at hers.
Did she talk about them being a system and working together?
Or does that just come out of the fact?
I don't recall.
Because maybe I've taken that for granted.
But no, I think it's – or maybe it's in some text that goes around them.
I don't know.
But when I guide people through it, I said – so my process is I guide them through.
I spend three months being their scrum master of sorts.
I run their standup and – to help reinforce what I taught them, because it's too much
all at once until they can sort of get it and they can hand off to an internal coach.
But one of the things that I tell them is when you start this, you – I will tell
you a set of rules and you will follow those rules.
It is an advanced topic to – and as you know from your cities with Kanban, you are
permitted and encouraged to modify the rules as long as you have a rationale.
But what I've discovered is when people start doing that and they don't understand why
the rule was there in the first place, they always, literally 100% of the time, hurt themselves.
All right.
So I haven't sold you on –
No, you haven't.
But I do think – you sold me on the idea.
Even with all the questions about what happens when I get my team towards modern testing.
I mentioned earlier, the worst thing is they – is Unity says, well, thanks.
You did everything.
Nothing left for you to do.
Get out of here.
But that's not the case, because although we're moving towards modern testing, we have
a ways to go.
More on some teams, much less on others.
It's certainly not self-sustaining in many places.
So there's a lot more to do.
But I think optimizing the whole is a good way to put that.
I think making sure that we are accelerating the achievement of shipable quality across
all teams is still a goal, still a mission, and there's still work to do there.
Let me tell you my motivation.
And you know this already.
MT in my mind is an amalgam of our experience towards something that you and I had a lot
of passion around when Microsoft went through this.
And that is helping to remove the FUD from the test organization when this was announced
and helping them guide – or helping to guide them towards a place where they would
add value.
And I will say first, certainly in the orgs that I was in, I was in the minority of seeing
the clear path here.
I was talking with tests and they were like, oh my God, I'm going to lose my job.
I'm like, yeah, with that attitude, you will.
Whether you're right or wrong, what you believe will happen will happen.
But open them their eyes that, no, they are not – they are at a fork in a road, not
on a path that guarantees a leap off the edge of the cliff.
When you're scared, when you're frightened, you don't see that other path.
What I worry that in this particular case, right, we have the three listeners.
Oh, by the way, for the three, FUD is fear, uncertainty, and doubt.
Yeah, the scary future.
I don't think you and I scaled to be able to be there and intercept each individual
as when they're not able to see that positive path forward.
And maybe that's it.
Maybe it's – maybe what I'm seeing is perhaps just a slight language change to Principle
7.
Let's – if you don't want to join the Slack group, that's cool.
You can email us, allanatangryweasel.com.
And if you have feedback on that or thoughts, you can just let us know.
But I have a feeling some more discussion after feedback will come up on this in Episode
97.
I have a hunch.
Yeah.
And one of the things I'm actually excited about as well, and it's on the Slack channel,
if you have an interest in it, you'll need to join the Slack channel, mostly because I'm
lazy and I don't want to look it up.
Danny Fought is about to do a presentation on his experience leaving test.
And I think those type of things are going to be helpful towards the MT believer follower,
whatever we call them, to make sure that as they're doing the right thing for the quality
culture, they're also doing the right thing for themselves.
Because I didn't get into this to create a new way for these folks who I believe add
great value.
I didn't get into this to find a new way for them to lose their jobs.
I got into this to find a new way for them to still add value.
I'm not, as I mentioned last time, I'm not planning on doing any conferences, especially
not test conferences in 2019.
But while you were talking, I had an idea for a talk I want to do, but it'll have to
I'll just plant the seed someone else can give it.
I'll help you with it.
But it's a life after test talk, which is, which is good.
Danny's stories is his individual story.
I think sharing four or five or six different paths, because I know at least that many
off the top of my head.
I don't think it should be a talk.
I think we should do it on the podcast.
I think we should invite people in and interview them and do that.
You know, one of my predictions for I don't know if I talked about it last time, one of
our predictions for 2019 was that we would have an external guest, a dial in guest.
And we could still do that.
I have the hardware to do that to get a good recording, which I haven't tested yet.
And I'd also have to the only way I know how to do is Skype.
But I have to install Skype, which is a little bit which I hate, but I guess it could
happen.
Something we could do, we should have.
We really need to have some guests to talk about the transitions this year off to
figure out how to do that.
I had a as an aside, usually we keep the recording equipment here in.
I'm sorry, I forgot what's the name of your company?
Microsoft.
Microsoft usually keep it here at Brent's office at Microsoft.
But I had it with me over the break.
And I should have taken some time when I had it to try out the adding a remote
color hardware to my setup here.
But I didn't.
It's not that much harder to take the gear and instead of walking it to my office,
walk it to your car.
I know, I know.
I could just take it with me.
Right.
You're right.
I could just take it with me today and then go check that out.
Maybe I'll do that.
I don't know if I have time in the next two weeks.
I'm taking off.
We didn't get this in the pre-patter, pre-chatter, pre-chatter-patter.
I am leaving to Europe for 10 days in, when do I leave?
Two weeks?
Work or?
Work.
Two days in manager meetings and then travel day to go, a whopping two hour train ride.
Travel day and spending a five day internal conference in Sweden.
Nothing like going to the beach in Sweden in January.
Five day internal conference?
Yeah.
How many people, how many employees does Unity have?
Total?
About 2,000, but there'll be about 100 of us there.
So is that more like a ginormous offsite then?
Kind of.
It's kind of a ginormous offsite, but it's all, it's, remember what we used to do at
Microsoft?
Sounds like a Windows all hands.
The engineering days, the, what was that called?
Hackathon?
No, it was a call when we had over in the conference center the week of talks and
workshops.
EE, the org I was in ran the thing.
Yeah.
So the one I pay attention to is called the MLDC.
No, it was way before then.
There was like for three or four or five years straight.
Machine learning and data conference.
Yeah.
So yeah, we call it a conference.
Anyway, it's that sort of thing.
So about a hundred of the people in quality roles across and some other roles across
Unity doing talks, workshops, lightning talks, hanging out, getting learning from each
other.
You know, I'm a big believer in community.
So this is something I'm really excited about.
So it's a Barney event.
What's a Barney event?
It's sharing is caring.
Oh my God.
Yeah, that's right.
We would love to hear what you think about the discussion today.
I definitely am leaving with a lot to think about.
I'll post the question up on the Slack channel.
It's technically a Slack team, right?
I don't know.
There's channels within the team.
Yeah, the Slack thing.
I don't.
Yeah, that thing.
I was on LinkedIn the other day and saw a posting for someone from my old team at
Microsoft Teams posted.
And it was interesting because it was largely like, oh, I was like taken from a job
break that I wrote.
I recognize this job break.
I recognize these words.
Yeah.
Teams.
Teams is the thing now.
Teams has almost successfully gotten rid of everything in Skype within Microsoft.
And as I get more and more accustomed to it, I'm hating it less and less.
And to be fair, it's a good product, but you would never, it's.
There are things that I, that I, there's little bells and whistles that I think the
wrong decision was made.
But I also, so I want to invite any new listeners to join the Slack team.
There you go.
I think that is right.
Yep.
I think we have enough queued up in the mailbag to do a mailbag next episode.
All right.
Let's schedule that in a moment here and we'll figure that out.
Or we can, if there's enough interest in the three, we can keep going on principally.
Yeah.
We'll just wing it.
But for now we've babbled long enough and probably nobody is left listening.
They've all hit end.
We'll see you next time.
I'm Alan.
I'm Brent.
Bye.
I discovered a way.
Yes.
And it will be.
I am so going to keep this part on the podcast.
What the.
I started recording already.
It's still going to fall down.
I think I have to do righty tighty lefty loosey.
Ha!
Inanimate object.
At least for this podcast, I've defeated you.
And one of these is shut the fuck up.
I wonder, I'll make that the inner groove.
What?
Where the inner groove is?
No.
The inner groove is like sometimes you buy an album back when you buy a record album.
A vinyl disc.
Oh god.
And sometimes they put a little bit of like audio in the inner groove, which is that groove
that when you get to the end of the record, whether it's a 45 or an LP, you get to the
end that little space in there.
Sometimes they put a little, and the needle would go, it would just kind of go round
and round there until you lifted it off.
Sometimes they put a little bit of fun audio or music or a spoken voice in there.
It's called the inner groove.
Okay.
Wow.
You're old.
I am fucking old.
You know, growing up, I never did a lot of vinyl.
Alright.
Because you can't play records in your car.
That was a cassette tape.