Welcome to AV testing podcast your modern testing podcast your hosts Alan and
Brent will be here to guide you through topics on testing leadership agile and
anything else that comes to mind now on with the show hello again everybody
howdy Wow that's gonna spike the levels out loud hey a lot of things going on
it's the holiday time of the year it's episode 113 we're recording on Friday
the 13th and it's our last show of 2019 that's a different different song for
Friday the 13th so where was I before you derailed me I said you said it was
Friday the 13th and I said oh is it yes yes and I'm happy because if you've
heard me bitch in the past we talked about these year-end episodes I don't
like this 2010 2011 was 2010 2011 2012 and I finally with 2020 people will begin
pronouncing the year correctly I think in 1910 people didn't say what or 1917
1919 then say oh the year is 1919 and you won't have to deal with it again
until year 3000 now yes I know and I'm probably gonna live forever and no I'm
actually as we all know getting closer and closer to dying but that's what
happens I aren't we all yes and I'm closer to death now because I lost a
couple years of my life in blood pressure wrecking my heart last night
screaming at my computer while watching the impeachment hearings that was a
mistake I sure wish I could get that time back someday sigh so as we do every
actually you know what's gonna happen here in a minute I'll explain it for the
new listeners the new listener man there was a bunch of stuff I was gonna
mention I thought of on the way in here that I forgotten so I'll just say hey
Brent what's new with you uh we'll probably get into it when we get
further into the episode alrighty needless to say this is shaping up to be
one of the best I'll call it fiscal years I've ever had we have we've done well my
org new one nice done well well throwing numbers out there because that would get
me fired and I like the job not gonna not ready to get fired yet hey speaking
of which you recently sent out a text about your new manager blaming you for
he's not my new manager I've had him for eight months and he took a while for me
to get to know and he's still a little hard to read but I'm slowly getting the
like I just do what I want it's autonomous Alan a yeah and I which is
funny cuz another in response to this I'll go backward into this one of our
one of our listeners said which we're thinking of Alan having a boss but sure
I guess so but yeah I have it's funny you mentioned that because you're in my head
because I what are you laughing at I'm just wondering if I'm wearing clothes oh
my god please save me it's not a good place if you're in Alan's head anything
could happen yeah no you're straightjacket I need to wash my my brain
out with the soap gross okay so anyway I for the last as long as I can remember
my career I kind of do what I want and I'm very good at that not meaning I'm
good at doing what I want because everyone's good at doing what they want
I am good and lucky at choosing things that make a difference and he's also
very good at showing that allowing him the autonomy will create business value
and that's just not for me that's a culture thing and also when you're an
exec leader you don't want to spend a lot of time in fact I'll put it this way
if you're an exec leader you shouldn't have to spend any of your time telling
people what to do you can nudge him in a direction which he has done from time
to time but which he did with this complaint he gave me which which will
now back into I put this on our rants channel on one of the three dot slack
calm if you want to invite you can go to modern testing org there is a link
there you can come join the fun and I am trying hard not to go into tangent
inception anyway I did a rant it was more of a humble brag rant and I'll admit
that I said my boss is blaming me for all of our quality improvements yeah
that that and hard to part I don't think so I don't think so what it means
is we've massively increased our velocity decreased our number of
incidents and decreased the revenue lost from those interest in incidents all
while greatly a big number increasing our revenue over the year okay and I
tried to tell you should feel bad for you he'd been blamed is not necessarily
mean bad I don't understand why is it so difficult to parse for you it's
blame so I it was it was it was a written format I can't tell if you're
being sarcastic I do you read things very often is this I think you can do it's a
skill I'm developing the idea is are all these things are happening and I
say and and because it's me and I do everything I do is small micro coaching
adjustments and nudges here and there and a little bit of organizing and
asking lots of good questions here and there so I said I'm not sure how much of
this blame I can take and he convinced me how much of how much of this is due to
things I've done and he convinced me whether I believe him or not this is
where the blame comes in he says no Alan you did this okay great so that's part
one that's part one of my rant the second part is and okay so I get it
for Brent who is dance really really you know what I've been bored for a hundred
thirty episodes give me a break actually no a DD trigger I'm moving on actually a
hundred and eleven episodes because thank God you weren't on one that yeah
113 minus yeah this is the 113th yeah I fixed the math that the the I fixed the
error in my head anyway everyone every six billion people in the world oh yeah
I know what he means it's a for Brent going it was a good thing he likes
what's happening in quality wants me to put together a presentation explain
sort of what we did so you got to do a brag deck for your CEO yes it's more
than a brag deck it's also explaining because we're gonna expand a lot and
this is a good concern and what I'm willing and happy to take on which is
if we're going to grow the number of people in the org we've all seen this
before you add a bunch especially Microsoft when you buy a company and say
oh that's not enough people you need to double those then the company ends up
dying rant okay so what I need to do is try and put that in a way that shows not
only what we've done but what we've learned and what we're doing so that we
know that when we expand it's all pure acceleration and not create scale to the
CEO I was gonna say how do you make it scale that's so damn cliche that I
didn't want to everybody says and then how do you make that scale I don't
like saying I'm I'm a I'm a loner I don't like saying the things everyone else is
saying so anyway you brought it up so now we're gonna move on this is episode
113 that part doesn't matter what matters is it's the last episode are you
bored again no the last episode of 2019 and we're gonna talk about we're gonna
take some time to reflect on 2019 including the predictions we made almost
exactly one year ago and then we'll talk about what we think is gonna happen
in 2020 and then I'm going to strangle Brent tear off his neck
Travis head reattach it to his neck backward using his hair as thread and
then I'll go home and celebrate my happy holidays all right so Brett tellin do
you want to start with a little bit of reflection on 2019 or do predictions on
2019 or or interweave them together we could talk about you know the the last
year the last year's predictions I did not write those down did you I did heck
yeah awesome yeah and we were talking in the hallway on the way to this room
earlier and our predictions were more more of the self-fulfilling variety like
they're more of like goals like I'm gonna do this right but most were I am
not gonna do this but but some weren't and we were still remarkably accurate
for two old dumb guys I had them so Brent we started with yours last year and the
first one is worth worth some mentioning today which is Brent will finally decide
whether or not he'll graduate and not only did he make a decision as of maybe
a week and a half ago no Monday as of Monday I'm again old Brent has graduated
round of applause from the three I have completed it I don't have my piece of
paper yet that should take two weeks for someone to tell me that they're
gonna that I get the piece of paper and then another month before doing it
that semester was hell as I knew it would be it was interesting going back to
listening to the first episode of this year because then I was still knee deep
in sort of the the torturous decision-making process and what finally
pushed me over I am done I do not foresee me ever pursuing a PhD oh then
you can make everyone call you doctor oh for sure right I was considering making
you have to refer to mr. Brent Jensen MS this whole episode but then I thought
that was stupid you've never called me mr. Alan Page mm that's true mmm
I got I have a degree in mmm bop the song by Hansen from the 90s you know go
on so I'm still kind of reeling it in it this this weekend will be the first
weekend in a very long time where I don't have to come into work to do
schoolwork so there's that there's that aspect of feeling that there's a big
gaping hole that you should be doing something now that I'm gonna have to fill
yeah I think you'll find something oh I know one of them obviously yeah be way
behind on holiday shopping so I got a I got that one to use you see a couple
hours on Amazon and I have not even launched Xbox even to watch Netflix in
at least six months expanse came out last night it's all I could do to not
stay up and watch I don't even know what that is you may have to start from the
beginning it's one of my favorite shows of all time now oh on Netflix Amazon
and actually Amazon they they were on sci-fi originally and Amazon bought that
they were gonna be cancer after three seasons and Amazon bought them and are
producing more on Amazon I haven't started yet but I'm excited to get into
the boys have you watched that no the boys is a
episode around it's a superhero show what but the superheroes there's sort of
like a Justice League type of thing but then they realize that the best
way to keep it's it's kind of like if you combine Justice League and I robot
where the the all-powerful beings realize that the way to keep peace is to
control it and the boys there's our set of regular people trying to revolt
against these super-powered individuals I will check it out all right so then
you predicted so so more on the ground for one prediction correct one prediction
correct you can keep tally over there a little notepad all right you also said
this one's not self-fulfilling and it's interesting and probably worth talking
about for a moment you predicted there will be more controversy and attacks on
modern testing yeah and I'm happy to say and like we've said before and all
repeated again is we've had various attacks on modern testing mainly people
not agreeing with some of the principles or whatever there was a conference
recently where someone made a passive mark about modern testing they tried to
attack it but they didn't understand it so didn't count I guess but we had
someone else write a series of articles on LinkedIn sort of passively
aggressively attacking modern testing principles and what I say to them is
welcome to the conversation oh yeah no so I think the attacks have gone up the the
one individual that you're referring to is actually one of the thought leaders
on the traditionalist side of testing with confirmed but a confirmed quote where
they're referring to modern testing right it's it it's definitely on the
mind of the traditionalist and I do think that that's going to become more
more and more open yeah and to be clear the people that look funny at us are
much more in that traditional test camp and we don't mean traditional someone
brought up software testing techniques which is I said well this is
traditional they never brought it was Rex block to brought that up and
Beiser if I recall correctly Beiser wrote software testing techniques for
developers but anyway I digress I'm not going to find the quote here because of
my tweets or all my complaints about the impeachment hearings last night but I'll
paraphrase the people attacking this partisan paraphrase people who are
concerned with modern testing are these traditional type testers and they think
it's attacking testing but as Brent and I have said we care very little about
testing we care a lot about quality and what the principles are about is
about building quality software we call it modern testing because it's an antidote
or a alternate way of looking at the traditional way of testing last or
testing as the way as the primary way to improve or to decrease risk and
improve quality so as many people from the test community who think oh the
customer can't evaluate quality or you can never not have testers I'm reading
and I put a couple quotes and this is where the paraphrase is gonna come in
I'm reading the unicorn project which is about it's a horror story about a dev
ops transformation meaning they describe this company in the worst possible
state is what my all my only complaints about the book is that the
scenario they describe is so contrivedly bad and maybe their companies like this
and somebody will tell me there are that it's a little hard to go yeah okay
surely someone must have done something but anyway one of the quotes in there
is the the main character of the story Maxine is working with QA and she
makes some comment says they'll pair and help on testing here knowing
eventually the QA group will move into an advisory or consulting role yeah well
and it's not surprising it's like oh and this goes back to as much as you're
mad at Brent and I for the modern testing principles we're just taking
what's already there and looking at it going this is what works and writing it
down and and putting a label on it we didn't invent modern testing principles
much as we corralled them from our influences and how to make quality
software and experiences and I think you know moving to coaching as consultant
that was largely driven from my experiences and my coaching to test
teams and then moving to unity doing the same thing this is how it's
supposed to work it's not a new concept but what what I think we're doing is
we're pointing it out as key right agile testing right the Lee Sin Lee Sin Lee Sin
binder first and last name sorry Lisa Crispin and Janet Gregory for those that
don't speak Brent right they've been talking about whole team testing for a
very long time yes right and now we're and we're just putting a big the whole
team testing without your specialist taking on a coaching role really all
we're doing is putting a big fat exclamation point on it's contagious yeah
yeah let's do another one okay so I think like lots of head nods people are
bored as bored as Brent I'm saying I met you don't so far you also and you're
gonna be at three in a second here because you also said we'll begin to see
more practical applications of modern testing yes and not only are we hearing
more like I use these principles we had David from three pull out the
principles during his interview at a job which he got we have people giving
talks about modern testing we had one at the online test conference literally
I read the abstracts said wow this is cool I went to post about it to see if
that person was in our slack group and they joined as I was opening up the
slack group said hey welcome I was just don't this is not creepy I was just
thinking of you so yeah we are seeing not just people that have listened to the
podcast we're seeing it the other way maybe at first we had people listen to
the podcast going or see talks that I gave and go yeah I'm gonna there's some
of this I can go try we're seeing people discover modern testing on their
own without knowing what it is and then coming and finding us going yeah there's
a home to describe what I've already been doing right it's sort of the like
the the seven degrees of Kevin Bacon right now it's we are seeing signs of
modern testing being a thing with people not knowing the source we've had a large
number of people this year have presentations with on the theme or even
explicitly referred to modern testing it is in as part of that virality we're
seeing new people come into it and not knowing the source which is fine it
doesn't offend me at all what so what I mean is when people are introduced Alan's
looking at me for those not watching no no no I was thinking I was bored and
trying to remember who said something I wanted to bring up later I was actually
planning I was I was playing 3d chess with our podcast oh I appreciate the
strategy okay go on yeah so there are signs that MT starting to take on its
own life right it in oh and potentially in a way that that you and I will no
longer be able to control yeah that's fine I'm not worried about it and it's
not like I'd ever see someone or you either we wouldn't see someone coaching
their team and trying to make them faster go hey that's modern testing you
have to call it that that's absolutely the opposite of our intent once it once
it achieves that tipping point and it's got its own momentum to me it's gonna be
the sign that you and I need to start thinking about okay what's the no and I
think we're already there we started off talking about like here here's why
these things are important and why you think they're important too we don't
have to sell that as much anymore it's more on the practicality how do
you how do you mature on these how do you what's that transition like from
moving into a coaching role and how do you how do you keep the team sharp and
understand new things it's more of the practical and advanced application of the
principles more than the convincing people they're valid part we did in the
beginning yeah and then because no one's a winner all the time Brent's
final prediction was we will create principle number eight did not happen
did not need to happen not to say it will never happen yeah and you can go back to
episode 97 ish 96 I did I was yeah the idea there were not won't dive into
deeply was that what about the individual how do we make sure the
person doing this is taken care of and maybe that came up in context because as
we recorded last year's I was still on job limbo I wasn't moved into my new
cool monetization Alan does what he wants role yeah we we we had a good
discussion on that one the way I would interpret number six is our 96 brother
when we talked about my proposed principle eight we had a good
discussion I concluded that we we at minimum both needed to be anonymous or
not anonymous on it being a good principle before proposing it to the
three as at this point in time I don't think empty we curated I don't think we
own it meaning it's the principle number five it's a customer's that define
it so I don't think we fully closed or locked it down but because we're very
ADD ridden we never brought it up again and one of the things Alan pointed out
in that episode is that I don't think there he he didn't think it was
important enough to put on there and I think time has it's I think time has
proven that out yeah right so yeah excellent I'm three for four all right and
that was the end of your predictions before we get to mine we had a couple
other predictions throughout the year or for that episode one was from Ryan
quell horse he had a couple but the one I want to call out is the rise of say
continued rise of DevOps DevOps DevOps DevOps and I think the unicorn project
and watching what they're doing with the DevOps transformation is a lot
about modern testing so I'm gonna slightly skew his prediction and show
that yes and I've said a few episodes ago and it could just be biased because
I'm taking over the DevOps team at in our org at Unity but it is a fantastic
way to draw to accelerate the achievement of equality
I think that is all about 2019 absolutely in the context of the AB
testing podcast anyway if not the world I think 2019 was the year of DevOps I
can't disagree and did accelerate came out in 2018 if I remember correctly
wasn't a 2019 book definitely not could even in 2017 we weren't aware of
it until no I definitely read it in 2018 because it was an inspiration for me in
the quality culture acceleration quality culture transition guide I wrote it was
some of the inspiration for how I put that together okay so that's how I know
is out of year and then Tess Pappy had a couple predictions hey Patrick he said
Trump will manage to go two days in two straight days without being a total
D bag and he's wrong he failed couldn't make it two days and he also
predicted these his other prediction which also thankfully didn't happen other
than a well photoshopped or or CSS edited is he predicted there would be an
IST QB modern testing certification yeah yeah a little tongue-in-cheek okay many of
my predictions were also self-fulfilling I'll go through my five
predictions you can comment I said I was well on track to move myself out of
a role done check it's sort of what I do for better for worse and and luckily I
tend to land well despite everything around me I think you thrive better in
ambiguous environments I do I do I I do that's where I like to live I predicted
that I would not speak at any testing conferences 2019 I did not I spoke at
one conference or it of in as we talked about a few episodes ago so also true
again very easy to make that self-fulfilling come we'll come back and
figure out what I'm doing in 2020 I predicted that Avengers would be my
favorite movie of 2019 ooh struggle if he says it wasn't then he's wrong on
the prediction but if he says it was and it wasn't then he's a liar on air
what's your choice I don't know I don't think I can add I think it was like a bad
prediction that I shouldn't answer because of exact same things you just
said and honestly it's probably between that and Captain Marvel which a lot of
people didn't like I really liked it I wrote it down I I did not do a lot of
movies this year but of the ones that I did see and here I'm limiting it to the
ones that I saw in the theaters Captain Marvel was the best one I saw in theater
and I saw in game I did not like in game I did not I like it I actually I like
all the Marvel movies but I liked I think I liked Captain Marvel more to
interesting about that up yeah I definitely like that okay let's move on
my last one was not there was no way for me to make this self-fulfilling and it
was really made off the cuff but more on gut and maybe more on want and more of
me wanting to we have one of our listeners Michael Richard who is a big
royale Salt Lake fan that's major league soccer for those not in the US
it's it's like it's like real soccer they play in Europe just a little slower
with a little clumsier but I predicted that our local team Seattle Sounders
football club would make it to the MLS Cup which is a end of year tournament
and that they would win and I'm happy to say that not only did they win is that I
was at the game and had a fantastic time watching my home team win the
championship so super happy that one came true and I got to be a little bit of
a part of it exciting stuff congrats well yeah so I look mostly I kicked butt on
my predictions they were kind in hindsight they were kind of safe
predictions yeah you know it's better to make predictions particularly if you're
gonna get judged at the end of it it's better reading predictions that you're in
control of right so I recently learned I'm not a master of the soccer's but I
recently learned and hopefully it's a true fact that Drew Carey is either
owner or part owner yes he's part owner yeah I didn't I'm like oh neat he is I'm
a fan of Drew Carey a fan of Macklemore I could listen to thrift shop Don
repeat all day long I love that I don't know that I would say I'm a fan of
Macklemore I went to college with Michael ones Lee he sings the he's the
singer on the song and he's another part owner and Russell Wilson from the
Seahawks is another part owner okay nifty nifty
Nift Shop so that's it for predictions a couple other reflections which I'm gonna
I wanted to put in here but I haven't thought through for 2019 do want to
mention I'm thankful for our listeners and not just people who download the
show but the slack community we have is it's fantastic there is it's just people
helping each other out people willing to try things people willing to we had
people put together a github account for modern testing to try and capture all
our resources just all kinds of help and involvement in trying to spread the
word on what we do so a big shout out and thanks for everyone who helps out
we're 2019 you had a 2017 prediction I think it was Brent's having your math
problems right you definitely had a prediction and it's not this time
around modern testing that or would become a thing well we want a modern
testing to be a thing and modern note you specifically called out the website
modern testing that which is just a link to the principles on anger weasel
calm right but because here I'm just gonna credit David directly he had the
idea hey this let's start putting this on github let's start organizing this
this get have the three do self-service stuff I actually think him being
motivated to do that is going to help your prediction be true albeit quite late
but true we are really a show about of and for the people and it's great to see
the community take charge and starting to add content I can't wait to see what
comes next yeah that's the fun part I can't wait to see what comes next
other let me join into predictions you probably have some I have it I have
several so it's funny so last year let's do some typical things so the
best of right do you have that list I know no but I in my head I do because
they didn't go over I did read through the podcast list so what was the best
episode I think I think some of these things you really easy you don't even
need to ask you don't even need to ask our hands-down best episode of all time
was the one that you weren't on no just kidding it was episode 100 that had
everyone on it yeah it was fantastic completely agree that was fun
again predictions but that was that was great I think we covered a lot of
ground I when I look back on the earth it will Britain I'll just talk about the
same stuff every time but we don't somehow we don't I looked back and it's
fun to see our thought process and of what we talk about and the things change
which is great and we're rolling with it we're not stuck in the past the themes
are I think I mean you can always you can go back to episode one and see
themes that we're still keeping alive today so I mean we're consistent we
changed the scale of the content best book oh gosh I don't keep track of what
what year my books come out I'm enjoying except for the contrived the
contrivity example I gave earlier I'm enjoying the unicorn project very much
hmm that's probably its proximity because all the books are great when I
read them but I don't know what else to throw out there I'm going to say given
our official a B testing declaration that 2019 was the year of DevOps the
absolute most important and best book for this last year and if you haven't
read it you still need to is accelerate okay but didn't come out in 2019 I
don't care okay fine it is one of my favorites is one of the books I keep
there are a handful of books I keep with an arm distance of my desk I think
accelerate it is if there was an MVP of books I think accelerate is an important
enough book to be up there next to product development flow yes and
actually it's another book with lean startup those are those are three three
books that I keep within arms distance of my desk at home all right we talked
about movies already I did not do much podcast listening do you have a
favorite Oh other podcasts yeah let me think what new podcasts I've added I've
been toying with podcast like thinking about getting a new podcast player
recently but I haven't found what I liked other than the the old-fashioned
what I'm using but that's a total big tangent I found what's it called
give me a moment let me bring up two podcasts that I discovered over the last
year that I really like one is speaking a DevOps DevOps DevOps it's arrested
DevOps if you get it it's a play on arrested development but arrested DevOps
is pretty good good interviewers I like what they do they had I found the show
when Nicole Forsger was on it and she was fantastic on her episode and I've
listened every episode since the other one I listen to is nothing to do with
software but you know I I like trivia I'm always adding trivia podcast sometimes
I drop them because they they're sucky but I like puzzles too and the one I
probably added most recently that I like is a podcast called escape escape
this podcast and what it is it's a verbal it's an escape room done via
conversation okay so it says you're in a room here's what you see and then the
host has to say you know here's what you find as you as you discover things and
it's it's fun I just like the lateral thinking of those things it's it the
problem is they're about an hour long and most podcasts I can pause in the
middle and come back I need to kind of do these on road trips where I can
listen to the whole thing okay because I kind of want to listen to 60 minutes all
at once but yeah I've enjoyed that my favorite new podcast is that one
favorite one to write that the listeners would like is arrested DevOps
that's an interesting concept how about you man oh I'm only like five or episodes
in and I'm way behind I've been around for a couple years so I have plenty
more information to go through no so because of the degree as I mentioned if
I don't spend time on on on Xbox right you can pretty much guarantee I'm not
gonna do much on podcasts got a drive to work man you got a drive to work yeah
lately I've been listening to my radio station down in California I had noticed
that they stream and those who are familiar with the station in LA called
Caro Q this year the famous morning show Kevin and Bean being left the
episode or left the show moved to England and that show has been sort of a
big part of my daily ritual for decades gotcha I do have a best TV show oh
interesting cuz I don't watch much TV yeah oh well and you I know you cut
the cable I yeah well you do but you get all the same channels have you heard of
the show the masked singer I have seen a commercial for it this is actually good
oh it's awesome love that show I can't say enough about it but we're at a time
when we got to predict things okay I will put it on my list I have YouTube
TV so I'm sure they have recordings of I can go find you can just make sure so
it's very much about you're gonna go into it I'll let you know so just
giving you it it's a guessing game you're trying to figure out who's in this mask
right when I have to know there's ruin the fun really quick and if you go up
on YouTube there's a good chance because of the search engine you're you'll
be watching something and then in the search box down below it'll be oh the
peacock revealed as an example so it's a lot more fun if you if you don't know
the result shall we get into it I have what a whole bunch of predictions to be
wrong on next year okay and I don't have any prepared but I'll see if I can
come up with some okay go for it all right let me start with the one that
will drive you the most insane politics I predict Trump will get reelected but I
also predict Pelosi will keep the house listeners of the show may or may not
realize I am a libertarian so that puts me in a position where I continuously
either agree or disagree with you I think both of the the two parties are
wrong quite often but none of my candidates will ever ever ever ever show
up I don't disagree and and just to be clear I have survived through
presidents I have not agreed with for many years and I'm okay with that
that's the way politics works it's the way the country works were yes what I
don't agree with is a president committing crimes and having his party
back him up because for party lines that shouldn't happen as an independent I
will say and you'll see this in the reports the majority of the independence
and I will lie with I will stand with this don't think the impeachment trials
are concluding the way the Democrats are espousing I do think if they continue
focus on this it will actually harm the Democratic Party and that will be why
Trump wins yeah I think there's a good unfortunately there's a good chance of
that yeah I'm still glad it's happening yeah all right move on to something else
okay if any other day besides after me watching six hours of impeachment
last night driving you crazy I would like to move on I'll just start at the top so
we spent a lot of time talking about DevOps I am going to introduce a term I
don't think we've ever talked about on the show oh god and I think this term
will mainstream next year the term is AI ops interesting well tell me about
because we have an ML ops we talk about ML ops a lot at Unity so I don't know ML
and AI are different so talk to me about AI ops AI ops there's another term you
may not have heard of which is RPA and I forget the P but it's robotic process
automation okay and by the way Jason Huggins on the show that was one of my
other highlights of the year oh yeah that was fantastic I completely agree
the croissants are Selenium go on yeah so DevOps is is essentially the dev team in
a nutshell the way where the the name comes from is the dev team owns
operations it's not a separate team you have to create in you have to create
monitors you have to continuously monitor the situation yet to respond
quickly okay that decision-making will begin to move to artificial intelligence
ML ops is kind of a in my humble opinion sort of a nonsensical concept because
machine learned is it's not decision-making but it's around gathering
the data to make it easier to make those decisions so I view ML as sort of a
way to scale DevOps but AI ops where the decision is made if by a robotic system
will begin to mainstream next year that's a prediction cool that's a good
prediction go on MT will mainstream next year what does that mean talk me oh and
I knew you would ask because I told you I'm good at asking questions yes yes
yes here's what I lay down I will say up front that literally it will be wrong but
I think it from a probabilistic point of view I will end up being more right than
wrong I believe that there will be one talk per major test conference specifically
containing or about modern testing this next year I think that could happen I
like that and and I want to be because when I say about I don't know that
qualifies as mainstream but it definitely gives it closer to the tipping
point yes I think on the tipping point discussion I do with some of the
convergence of modern testing and AI ops and software by Alan Page I do think
one of the things that's a potential because I people following me know I've
been constantly looking for wins the tipping point wins the tipping point
wins the tipping point I'm actually beginning to worry that that the
tipping point will not occur because the tipping point of the next of
post-modern testing will actually occur first huh right because if for example if
AI ops does mainstream that that leapfrogs that that leapfrogs a lot of
this stuff sure and I'm gonna comment on that one and get a prediction to hear
myself because we could make that self-fulfilling I could go give a talk
on modern testing in every major testing conference that I predict that's not
going to happen I predict once again I will I will speak at exactly one
conference in 2020 and to be clear and I'll totally honest I have no
conferences lined up I haven't I've said no to everybody so far people are not
asking me anymore because I say no all the time which is great but I will
predict I will speak at one conference in 2020 it won't be a testing conference
it won't be no I'm it may be a DevOps conference maybe a dev conference maybe
something else I don't know but I'm not speaking at any testing conferences but
I will I do think I'll speak at one conference I don't know which one yet I
should probably figure that out just pointing out that I'm not gonna make
this happen by showing up and giving talks at test no the thing is is I'm
like hmm I have a big gaping hole now in my life since I don't it says I
don't have school maybe it's time for test bash Seattle oh and if I do test
bash Seattle I can guarantee that Alan's prediction will be wrong so much
time plotting for my demise the the other thing on MTV I wrote down two
criteria one I think a one talk per every major conference and I'll even
say not by us and even potentially by people we don't know yet currently not a
member not of the three I think MT attackers will grow yeah I think we're
going to start seeing right now 2018 we see a lot of passive aggression that
right I think it'll start being direct I think that I think name calling will
begin I think that's inevitable and that's yeah I mean name calling should
continue I've been called things no name calling on MT yeah yeah I mean
you're a dick I had that when we call that I can recall one conversation about
principle number five or I was told I was ignorant and wrong and and harming
the craft yeah but I think we're modern animals got deeply sucked into that one
modern testing is a threat to those that make a living relying on testing as the
primary way to reduce risk in the project testing is not the threat the
threat is the world's changing we put a name on it like yes that us we're those
people taking down modern testing does not save their careers I know I deny
change is what they're saying when they call me an asshole right that's fine
whatever and into those who like we see the change going in and if they say hey
we're harming the craft no we're naturally not because the craft is on
its way to death and I don't care about the craft I care about the people who
are in their skill sets and I care about quality and I care about helping
those people transition into the new world yeah and I will not be silenced
blah blah blah okay observability the term observability will kill the term
testability um I have no idea how I'm going to measure success or failure on
that I don't know so I look at that differently I would tell you why that
one's gonna be wrong now I look at my biggest two levers to improve quality
our testability which which includes the testing we do like how quickly can we
do the testing we need to do before we deploy and operability which includes
observability among how we do to safe deployments etc but I look at those as
done done equal and what I got now I can't paraphrase the quote of the damn
show but I look at those as equal levers I have to help improve the
quality of what I think is gonna happen so tell me tell me the difference
what's gonna what's gonna rock my world here's what's gonna happen all right as
empty progresses the term testability is brought up because of separation of
disciplines as empty continues and dev takes over this testability isn't a word
that's in that language we don't have it I still think of it as testability
it's all the work we do to make all the code correctness and code simplicity
stuff and being able to easily write enough tests that will all disappear
that will all just so be wrapped into what does it mean to be a developer yes
and that's really what it's about that and on that front testability will
become accountability look sure right yeah I get that observability is very
similar to testability except what we're now trying to look at is customer we're
gonna have a whole podcast about this because I agree with you but my my
definitions and how it happens are different okay so we're gonna talk about
testability and operability at an upcoming podcast go on let me go
through we have people looking in the window I only have a few things and I
can go very quickly I do think in 2020 we're gonna start seeing everyone
becoming sort of a compliance expert gross I hate it too but necessary I think
it'll be necessary the personal note I think I will start guitar lessons this
next year all right I have a huge hole mentioned over and over again and then
on the sports front I think the Niners will play but lose to the Ravens in the
NFC championships and not make the Super Bowl and this saddens me greatly and I
hope I am wrong on that prediction on the the quick my sports front thank you
for those I don't really care about the Niners and really really who does
that's American football the one where you don't use your feet for our foreign
listeners I predict on the Sounders front the Sounders will make the playoffs
the 12 straight straight year but they will not win the MLS Cup they'll
probably lose in the the conference championship the semi-final
conference championship but I do predict they will make it to the final of the
CCL the CONCACAF Champions League where they will lose to one of the Mexican
teams not the galaxy they're not in they didn't they didn't make the CCL yeah I
only know two football clubs and that's probably all I didn't prepare any
predictions I gave lots of feedback on Brent's anything else really quickly
here before we close up I predict I already gave you my conference
prediction I gave you that yeah I'm gonna oh here's one I have as long as
Brent's know me I've changed jobs every two years the end of year next year will
be almost two years of mine in my current job I will predict that one year
from now I'll still be in this job and we'll have at least another year after
that I think it's gonna take me longer to work myself out of this role that's
good for you it is I suppose all right happy holidays happy 2019 thank you
everyone for listening once again I'm still Alan I'm Brent and we'll see you
later see you in the new year