Welcome to AV testing podcast your modern testing podcast your hosts Alan and
Brent will be here to guide you through topics on testing leadership agile and
anything else that comes to mind now on with the show bonsoir aloha Brent
hola we can talk welcome listeners to AV testing this is not AVT 343 but you
should be checking those out because they're awesome they are despite me
despite me I love talking to people and I could I realized how unsmart I am
sometimes I hang around Brandt my ego gets all like oh yeah I'm really smart
and then I talked to other people I realized not so much how you doing I'm
having a good week good happy December 12th no happy episode 112 today is
December 5th 6 somewhere in there happy three days after one step closer to
your death yep I turned you know hold I am do you know how old I am you are
53 I believe I just turned 50 quattro oh that's fantastic that is so three
years older than me knowing that you're four years older than me just makes
things so much better it is I am pretty much older than anything yeah so so next
next March you would apply for it so tell me what is the pros and cons of AARP
it's only pros only only pros you get it is the most widely the AARP magazine
most widely distributed magazine in the country because there are so many of us
old farts now luckily the I am just just barely young enough that you cannot
ok boomer me boomers I'm Gen X generation ahead of me so screw you and
you're ok boomer no matter how crotchy I get you can't call me a boomer you can
just call me a dick so now shut up and pay your mortgage I have a soon to
be 18 year old son and he has informed me that it does not matter if you are a
boomer you can be okay boomer so I think you need I do a quality check on on your
principle here or it could be that as far as intelligence goes leaf doesn't
fall that far from the tree yes he is in the extreme not very smart I get I
get that you know some details about this one this is my this is my personal
challenge child and a lot of the times I would say he is too smart for his own
good yeah I remember being 18 when I thought I was much smarter than I like
if I was anywhere close to as smart as I thought I was at 18 to 20 I would I
would be a genius I would be running the world but here I am sitting in a
room with you yeah alright 112 this is our next our penultimate episode of 2019
let's just pause there yes Alan said penultimate he did right usually this is
mono syllable or monosyllabic word I normally I try normally I try and speak
in a language that you can understand right but I chose I chose a long word
because I didn't feel like saying next to last wait next to last panel it
felt it was longer I was stupid yeah I shouldn't have done that you know if I
hear one more person use use the word utilized when use is perfectly
applicable they're not synonyms I'm going to just stop and tear their head
off pee into their neck and go on my day the arson and mish ish utilize means
to use something in a manner which it normally isn't used for I'm gonna
utilize your finger to shoot I didn't have a good place to go there well I'm
gonna use utilize my finger you're going to use your finger to look up the
definition of utilize in to make practical and effective use of use is one
syllable utilize is three stop using the word utilize just stop it you don't
need it you don't sound smarter in fact even you when you say the word utilize
for use with you would work you sound dumb dumb dumb dumb if this is it
right so utilize does appear to be a synonym for the phrase use of my body I
get actively I made you lies I made use of a screwdriver to hammer in this nail
I utilize the screwdriver to hammer in this nail that works you don't utilize a
pencil to write on paper where do you stand on the then and then controversy
that's just grammar look if you we have all these idiotic Americans complaining
about oh immigrants blah blah blah but they can't even use our own language
very well drives me nuts by the way I tweeted this and this is the the
political portion of the of the podcast and we'll go on but I didn't I was
busy last week I was doing advent of code I'm still caught up I'm caught up
in advent of code yesterday's was super easy the day before I wanted to punch a
hole in my computer that's all I'm gonna say day five it's like I couldn't it
took me at least twice as long to understand the problem I was trying to
solve them to write the code at least and some people got it right away but
and when I go back and read it I go how did I miss that's right there but it
was really really hard for me to grok yeah you should give our listeners a
heads up because you announced it every year that you've been doing it for
several years I never finish I get about 10 to 12 days done then I then it gets
hard and I find things I'd rather do and every time you bring it up I go oh
yeah that sounds fun oh he just said he's on day three so I'm late something
interesting I went to see the as I mentioned before the the owner the
creator of advent of code he gave a talk when I was at or dev and he talks a lot
of people like make visualizations of the visualizations of the program which
is kind of cool this year someone did is doing all of the questions in Google
Sheets and Excel all in formulas there's always someone who can solve
the whole problem in one line of Mathematica a very very long line there
is a language you heard the language called rockstar no you should look up
rockstar someone did a solution in rockstar what was really fantastically
interesting is the the passion of this community in advent of code is days two
and three I think or maybe three and four two and three where this you're
programming this int code this you get a string of numbers that end up being
byte codes and instructions basically a string of custom assembly that you're
trying to send to the robot right to write an interpreter for him and then
someone after learning being taught this this byte code instruction in language
someone went back and solved the first day's problem using these this fake
int code language from day four and five like people are just crazy just
crazy I wonder if anyone's ever attempted to go a whole advent of code
doing nothing but turning machines I don't know there are people trying to
a different language every day which I so I have tried to use a different
language each year so when I first did I did it in C sharp which was fun because
I didn't I've written very procedural C sharp not very good at it but it gave
me a chance to learn a lot of the more object oriented aspects of C sharp
and actually use it like a real programmer that was fun the next year I
did it in Python which was fun for me to learn Python I think I've
forgotten all of my Python and then last year I did it in JavaScript which
was interesting I don't like JavaScript I think it's a millennial language because
you can write really bad JavaScript and it still works kind of but you don't
really know no no no no no you're missing the point I think it's no matter
what you do no matter how good or bad you write it because I grew up of
course writing C programming where if you made one tiny mistake code wouldn't
compile and most time you wouldn't know why so JavaScript like you get it kind of
close in the compiles kind of like the everyone gets a trophy language yeah and
then this year I said screw it I'm just gonna write it in C++ C++ is your your
go-to C and C++ yes I am making massive use of vectors I find myself
entirely disinterested in C C++ as well as any time I have to be on a team that
makes that a requirement because the it's an extremely powerful language I
remember I remember I remember like yesterday when I first got the concept
of a function pointer and oh oh right and I was like oh my god this thing is so
sweet but now it just I find it slow I think it slows me down and I'm trying to
go from A to B and spending the extra few days go making sure I'm not doing a
mem leak it's just friggin annoying when particularly when there's languages out
there I know I know it's just it's what I cut my teeth on and I and I read them
one thing and we're never gonna get to I have a full board I actually wrote the
the agenda today and but we have so much to talk about I feel like it's been
more than two weeks since we chatted do we skip a week I don't know oh do we
have a holiday in there something so anyway yeah I was talking on the slack
channel about they had a developer on the heart a developer who was rock star
and shouldn't even use the word rock star and actually you should look up
this is tangent exception the coffee's kicking in one of the reasons the people
that developed the rock star language wrote it was that I could become popular
and recruiters couldn't look for rock star programmers anymore but let's say
you have a very awesome but who so a variable does that mean people will go
in and in their resume put I'm a rock star developer prior to the language
being developed or or we're looking for a rock star developer sorry I only know
Ruby so don't you can look it up if you want I have so much stuff to cover
we're gonna have to cover some of this stuff next time that's just gonna happen
yeah oh next time penultimate episode oh my god this is awful next time we'll
do our look back on 2019 some recommendations of cool things we like
and our predictions for 2020 yeah so rock star real quick one of the variable
naming conventions is variables or variables have a proper name like Brent
and if I put stuff into Brent and I want to print what's in Brent to the screen I
shout it so shout it Brent shout at Brent print it twice oh this is yeah so
the idea is that the language ends up looking like 80s heavy metal rock ballad
lyrics awesome yeah it is it is good anyway a quick story about we saw on the
channel this week someone hired someone who was really good in one language and
and really only wanted to go in that language but their company didn't use
that language and all they did was complain that they didn't get to use
their language that they like and have been easier and and then I face
palmed and then when I really hard I was unconscious for a couple hours and
then when I got up I I made a point that today in programming you have to
learn new languages like when we interview I used to be you could
interview for a language maybe but even though that was probably always
stupid if you get the concepts of program you can learn new languages I
was actually like I was doing an informational just yesterday and the
woman I was talking to kept on doing self-deprecation she had a massive amount
of confidence around Python but did not feel super confident with C sharp and
I'm like so well to me that almost is a sign of a beginner programmer right it's
maybe even intermediate because I'm at a phase where I go no I am so strong in the
the basic concepts right I understand I understand design patterns I understand
functional languages or a procedural languages or cake right once you'll
understand the constructs in my humble opinion you will understand every
language as long as you have the the book that tells you what the stupid
keyword is for the thing in this language yeah I I am confident through
other questions we asked I look for people who like to learn and usually I
hire people who tend to are really good at looking things up on Stack Overflow
yeah I had so it was a point way back in my Microsoft career when we were
doing scene C++ and we have a lot of people coming in and Microsoft more
than Unity for sure but they really milk that college pipeline so we get a lot
of candidates out of college we still do yeah I know I know I know I know I had to
actually had to go to recruiting and say hey at one point is this two years
ago now I said I would like to hire some students out of college they go oh
teams don't usually do that that's a great idea which coming it's like what
we end up looking maybe it's a smaller company thing in looking for a lot more
unicorn type people anyway I remember way back when they would program in Java
it's okay I can read Java and then for then for a long time even up to today
it's like Python yeah pythons a good language that's cool you can do that
it may be something different later I would love if I could interview candidate
to do a question in rockstar that'd be awesome I'd interview this week I just
did a little phone phone screen that is super just had someone walk me through
something pretty easy find a find a missing number in an array kind of
question and they did it in bash okay I get an idea how you think it's cool
no it's cool like you do all you've changed your OS you do a lot of stuff
in in unique syntax bash would be hard for me now I haven't so an interview
question in bash would be hard for me because I think but I would never ask
unless I was hiring you for a Linux sysadmin I would never ask you a
bass bash question no no I don't so certainly I would turn down writing it
I'm like yeah probably uses keywords but reading it because so a lot of times
when I'm asking coding questions I'm trying to think ahead of the candidate
so I can figure out where they're heading what wall they're likely to to to
hit and then do the probing yeah yeah right bash I wouldn't be able to do that
because yeah oh yeah I can't even read it any like I could follow along yeah
anyway I'm gonna cross something out there I'm not sure which one yet but
it's obvious we're not gonna get everything up there sure what would you
like to do let's do number two because you promised me shock surprise and
amazement well I don't know about that so telephone game mailbag I heard this
through the grapevine but want to call it up as a mailbag and just to get your
thoughts so there's two questions here and I'll give them to you one at a time
okay one is we have talked and I thought we covered this so we'll cover
this quickly I think but I haven't heard much or any concrete examples of what we
should be doing instead of Selenium testing right now and talk a lot about the
downsides of choosing Selenium testing sorry sorry Jason Huggins we do not yeah
not not exactly no we talk about the downsides of doing UI test you can
exactly and things that you shouldn't do and why you shouldn't do that but I
feel like there's a missing episode what to do instead I feel like we've
covered that but I'm gonna go ahead and cover it quickly so actually I'll let you
cover it because I've ranted enough about UI automation so can you clarify
our stance on Selenium testing and what we suggest people do instead of Selenium
testing Selenium testing is fine Selenium is a great framework again
don't do UI testing our UI automation yeah the point is don't try and verify
your program logic through the UI you use the you you want to write Selenium
tests for tests that can only be caught via Selenium tests I'm a little bit more
flexible than that I'm not if it can be caught at a lower level let's catch it
there right but you can if you can use Selenium ultimately has now become a
super flexible framework so if you can catch the lower level things via
Selenium knock yourself out I don't care and the advantage of Selenium I
just want to call out Selenium and UI testing are not synonyms correct although
then I believe the majority of people writing tests with Selenium are writing
them as your canonical 30 year old UI test I do too but if we're gonna if
we're going if we're going to be bashing something on the episode let's
bash the right thing Selenium is great UI testing is not our UI automation
so instead if we're asking you to write less or fewer Selenium tests or sorry
if we're saying don't do UI automation which I've been saying for going on 20
years now maybe just 15 and we want you either to use Selenium the right way or
to focus your testing efforts elsewhere what is that well it's gonna depend on
your architecture I have always chosen to turn it into an API test so most
well-designed architectures have a business logic layer that sits in
between the the presentation stack and and the for lack of a better word the
database so that's where I would go and automate I would turn it into an
API test and then validate that when you call the as an example the button click
event the UI update event handler gets called yes typical model of your
controller right so I did a and we'll close on this I did an informal Twitter
survey as you know as a data scientist that people that follow me on Twitter
probably aren't the most representative sample of testers in the world because
I've pissed off the ones that maybe are doing more UI testing but I did have a
hundred and fifty answers to my survey when I asked do you mostly write code
to automate the UI non UI animation tools that aid in automation that aid
in testing and other and 24% code to automate the UI I believe in the
industry that number is higher but in my survey 24% with 35% apiece on non UI
automation and tools that aid in testing which I think isn't bad I think
that 24% I mean you're talking to a guy who as we've talked before I've been
in the I've been a traditional test manager I've had to make these these
concrete decisions and several occasions you you just discover your UI
automation is harming you UI automation is we've said this a thousand times
before there's probably not enough tequila in the world to drink UI
automation is some of the hardest thing to do and get right it is a money pit
uh-huh the more UI automation you write if you do not apply your more senior
talent to developing the architecture and working with development to make sure
UI changes are are well handled you always need one more automator yes because
as you write more the maintenance cost goes through the roof and you you just
can't get to the next set of tests whereas the business layer underneath the
UI because dev needs that to be stable it's so that the UI doesn't constantly
have to be rewritten that just makes a lot more sense and another question and
this is interesting I saw this on I did a search a year ago maybe on modern
testing and saw this I'd ignored it and then I saw it somewhere else and I'm
gonna have you address it and then I'll address it and then we'll laugh
about it you're gonna want to hear it first I'll ask it this way Brent it's
one of the reasons we don't talk about like what to do instead of Selenium or
enough is that because are we building ideas or trainings or do we have a
startup or consulting business we're trying to kick off so we're limited in
what we can say are we trying to hide something do we have an ulterior motive
I've heard this like I was I think Alan has an ulterior motive in talking about
modern testing so I'm gonna I told you you'd laugh yes we do we do have an
ulterior motive and what is it the ulterior motive is we wish to save as
many people we can from going down the wrong path in their career we do not
make money on this show we do we've had we've had sponsors now and again that
has always gone back directly into the show when you join the one of the
three slack right the stickers that you can ask for that we pay postage on and
we pay the stickers on that all came from the ten dollars we got from
sponsors the new year we have I did develop a modern testing course for
ministry of testing plug but if if money comes in from that that also goes back
into the podcast we have no consultancy plans I think my retirement
job may be consulting but I don't even know when that is it's not it's
not related to this I may have to I may have to get a test automation
consultancy because it seems to be a lot more of those jobs around the modern
testers yeah so the important thing here is no we're doing this because we
we want to try and help people we we have some strong opinions we want to
share and we think that they're helpful to some group of people and that's it
I may even say it a little stronger like you and I have had conversations before
around traditionalists and here I mean that more generic than just test
traditionalism we're trying to reduce just a little bit of the ignorance in
the world right or to spread our ignorance whatever however comes across
well the you know I think back to exploratory testing and the
conversations that we had when Visual Studio came out with their version of
it and they renamed it to XT oh god right and that that's spreading
ignorance it's it's it's just a little bit of look up and you realize that
just a bad name for me it's all about how do we continue the conversation my
motive is is I want to get rid of test zombies people who just continuously
they've they've they went through a phase they thought about it and then
they stopped I want I want people to help advance their own careers and the
more we're able to say hey there's an alternative and there is and for a lot
of really good reasons it is better than what you know and in a lot of places
again there was a conversation on the slack channel tipping point may even
be nearing the the nice thing is is that looks like the tipping point the
way the way the tipping point towards an empty or something like it looks like
it's going to be more of a boil the frog action and again going with ulterior
motive we're not looking to make any money or fame off of modern testing and
what we what I'm seeing a lot of people doing you don't have to call it modern
testing and remember it's not that modern and nothing to do really to do
with testing it's about how it's really about lean and agile and how to
accelerate the achievement of a quality I think it's also about measuring what's
important I think and the data and that's what I was getting to is like
there's many many more well apparently a shark has been jumped but there I see a
lot of talks about data and using data at test conferences there was one at
online test conference recently I feel like there's an overabundance of talks
at test conferences about how machine learning is changing the world and
whether it is or not that's great I wish they talk more about using data to
get insights instead but there's a reason I'm on a podcast and not a
conference coordinator so I'm seeing more of these things that are modern
testin ish happen which is great and I think they would have happened whether
we were talking about it or not we try and give is a framework that wraps a
lot of the things that are all of the things that we think go into making
software high quality software that customers love and made by high by
high-performing engineering teams I mean it's it's a bit too altruistic
sounding to fit into my personality but I think we're just trying to make a
better world here that's way too out that's too altruistic for both of us it's
in terms of the end you lean agile right I think what we're doing here is helping
to accelerate that tipping point yeah I hope so I hope so it keeps the
conversation going like we said when people people whether people agree or
don't agree with the principles we're happy to have you in the
conversation so you can think about it I hope that through debate people at least
challenge what they're thinking and I challenge what I'm thinking all the time
I do this in politics I never I'll skip on my political tweet a quote but I do try
and look at what the other side and try and understand how they're thinking
and I think we should do that in testing as well I did tweet last week I
saw a lot of people I had a conversation on a different slack channel
where all someone did to make their point was to point to links blog links
from a single test blog author and I don't think that makes a good argument or
good stance I think you begin to form your own opinions when you can take in
input from 10 20 30 40 different sources and figure out what you really
think I don't think it it makes a stance for yourself when all you do is
quote one person anyway tangents tangent so yeah that was all about no we don't
have a business we have a podcast where we it's all about trying to be a service
to people who listen yeah yeah one other thing to hit here a couple questions
came up in not really mailbag in the slack channel worth talking about let's
take them separately they're kind of related but separately one we've talked
a little bit about before but probably worth hitting on again is how does
someone so if we get to a world where there's modern testing and maybe it
seems don't have a dedicated testing specialist which again is if you if that
happens it'll be obvious that it's the right thing to do we're not trying to
tear away testers directly what's a junior modern testing how does someone
get started in modern testing and I think you and I are aligned on this
but I'm gonna ask you I think a junior modern tester is the same as a junior
developer in today's world when when I'm asked this question I go to okay let's
say I am gonna start up a new startup redundant and it's gonna be me and five
other people and we grow to a point where hey let's start bringing in
college hires right what am I gonna bring it I'm gonna bring in someone who who can
contribute but it's gonna be a sponge made modern testing is a quite honestly
it's a senior concept it is it is right I'm not going to bring in a monkey
tester now if they show the systemic thinking right that's something that
tests off and prides itself on is oh but testing is all about how to think and how
to ask questions yeah you need that talent in yes so development as well you
needed it in all knowledge work that's the part that drives me crazy Oh
testers do a B and C yeah that's important in all knowledge work it's
not special no so what I what I'm gonna look for is someone who I can train
MT on well I'm still delivered and in your startup you don't need to
necessarily train them it's the culture of the way your company works it is and
I have so right now I have although we talked about modern testing isn't a role
and I have a couple quality coaches they help their teeth they they do some
testing but not actually not really that much depending on on the time of
day in the season but they're helping the team do better testing if they left
at this stage I will probably try and replace them but I also have senior
devs in the org who do a lot of quality coaching whether they know it or not I
guess the point I'm making is some of the best testers I've known people that
that testing mine people that know how to people who have that system thinking
and know how to figure out what's gonna go wrong and mitigate it they're
just to seeing your devs on the team let's take it a different way okay
that's right principle seven says blah blah blah blah blah blah knowing that it
may reduce or remove the testing specialist I go the other way around and
I go okay when would I in that startup scenario when would I bring in that
testing specialist you have an answer to that one because I'm gonna start off
the other way I'm gonna start off with nope the the ground you and I are in
the same page so I think can be taught I would I would so what I tell my manager
I know I've mentioned on the podcast is our development team do all the testing
they know how to do they're not they're not skipping out on any testing they know
of however there's some testing ideas some expansive knowledge that they can
do more testing this on order to get that's what we coach them on we teach
them more things to think about so they can do more testing and figure out
I figure out a strategy conferences you can send I could so yeah and I'm
getting there so I would bring in a testing specialist when I felt I
couldn't scale it's like say I didn't have one and I guess for the same
reason you bring in a consultant I want to bring a coach in because they can't
learn the testing they need to learn quickly enough for the scale that our
business is growing so I'm gonna bring in some help to help them expand that
knowledge absolutely so that's that's my answer and there's things where I like
to bring up perf testing perf testing is hard that's a specialization of my
humble opinion you can get through a good 60% of it you know by looking books or
doing other such things but if you really want to nail it into in someone
dedicated to my experience is required security testing I agree on security
maybe not as much on performance relative security is much more needs a
specialization right because even it's a full-time job even just staying on top of
threats yes architectures I don't know that I would even bring in one a test
architect in any more because there's so much open source no no no no no no no
I although I've been a test architect as we all know I do not like that title
anymore it reeks of 1990s yeah I have as well get rid of the word tests and I'm
fine with it right to me it's a good architecture is a good architecture yeah
yeah it's a remnant and the only reason we had him at Microsoft was we didn't
have a career path for senior testers so I said I know we'll make test
architects and that'll keep them around it was fine it was fun but that was yeah
it created its own new problem it did and it was it's a it's a solution for a
problem that's wrong long past all right one last thing and I forget the context
I brought this up in but it's worth talking about David asked in the also
in the slack channel lots of activity there I mentioned as an aside oh I
remember I was a talk or where I heard it but I heard someone say something to
this effect Oh CI CD that's the dream and again I face-palmed and when I
regain consciousness a day or two later I asked I said CI CD I think is the bare
minimum at least CI and so then David asked so if that's the bare minimum and
I don't know if I said it's the bare minimum for MT but it's my bare minimum
expectation I expect teams to have CI check in crap happened to get tested
gets failure gets pushback what other sort of assumptions what's the baseline
for a team ready to adopt modern testing principles this is probably a
lot more than we can cover in six minutes but we'll do our best first off
and CI CD I just want to address I I see I see where where David's coming
from I I have models that I shipped her production now on a weekly basis and it
took one of my developers nearly the last six months to build a CI CD pipeline
then it it for for the because building the model isn't actually a failed the
way for those of you not watching the livestream I'm making I'm making a face
you're like there's two words after what but yeah the and then there's the other
aspect so you go what I want you to do is outside of teams think through the
other teams that you had been on mm-hmm right Xbox I've spent time in Xbox
bangs the best I've ever been on on CI CD but if you're accustomed if the
current practice is miles away from CI CD it feels untenable to even bring that
up right it just just think of dysfunctional forking such it's but
yeah so maybe the minimum is a just a minimum quality culture and I want to
fight us it's not just text we talked about it before we know it is a people
the process and the time right it's right and when you start going into
long-standing process changes those can be brutal and hard fought when I was way
back when I worked on Windows CE didn't you work on Windows CE also at
some point when I worked with okay so we had before we there was even a name
because the CI CD book from Jez Humble and crew is just 10 years old now so this
is way before then so we didn't call it that and I won't it wasn't certainly was
his continuous deployment but we when people checked into we were to check in
system a check-in gate what we wanted to do is run some static analysis checks
run a small set of tests and then then then merge the code on their behalf
pretty common pretty common that's that's kind of the way CI works today we
deployed it so this guy Marty and I wrote this tool at first for the first
two weeks we got more than a few dozen emails a day with titles like slate rhymes
with hate slate was the name of our tool because people didn't like great I
check in my code and then my then I want to sync it to my other dev machine
and I can't because it's going through slate and slate took embarrassingly like
an hour which wasn't that bad an hour to finish we had a lot of running on some
beefy machines and somebody else broke something and it blocked my change from
getting in and we're blocked we're blocked me so we the same things you
hear about early stage CI today and we dealt with it we made some tweaks we
fixed the process a little bit we kept on going we didn't turn it off we just
dealt with it and what was great was like with that was like within the
first two weeks within a month we started getting mails like I don't know
how we ever survived without this before and all kinds it just you have to
people talk about the people part introducing a process using the tech to
introduce a process can cause the people to freak out I hit all three of
your piece there and it takes some leadership to get through that so I would
say another min bar another minimum thing is you have to have people willing
to disappoint people at a level they can absorb which is one of my definitions
of leadership and be able to take the heat for that and hold their ground and
and make good decisions which is another thing every leader I've ever
respected is excellent at making decisions they're not like looking for
consensus on everything they can take the data they have make a decision so if
you have a good leader who's not afraid to disappoint people and can make
decisions based on what's coming in and tweak the process is needed to make it
work and and persevere that it's kind of like a high bar but you have to have
some leadership in place that knows how to facilitate change in order to move
to modern testing it can't happen if your team is a bunch of zombies no no
and that would probably be another min bar we should probably go into this
more in depth in 2020 in we have a full agenda for next time which which
involves me doing the one time a year I do prep when I go back and listen to the
end of show end of your show last year at one and a half speed you know what I
watched one of my I can't watch my own talks but I watched one at one and a
half speed and at one and a half speed I'm pretty good
nice all right anything else no okay we're gonna go with that keep your
questions coming thank you three the community and we'll see in there
brand-new say yeah if you are not on the slack channel get on the slack channel
yeah lots of good discussions it's it's you can go to modern testing org and
there's a link there I just adore the three right there's a book club going
people are helping review other people's blog posts people are posting decks and
and we have tacos oh the tacos are great yeah all right I got promoted I think I
don't know I got a taco promotion I got to check my taco stats all right
Aloha au revoir see ya