A B Testing, the modern testing podcast. Join your hosts, Alan and Brent.
I am mindless agile robot. I must iterate.
As we talk about software engineering, software quality,
leadership and whatever else comes to mind. Now on with the show.
I don't know how to start. Hey guys, welcome to AB testing.
It's episode one or two. How about that? That's pretty good. Uh,
there's something significant about one Oh two. Where, where is one Oh,
does one Oh two exist in pop culture anywhere? That number.
Um, I am absolutely the wrong person.
That's right. You are pop culture ignorant.
You want me to look it up? No, no, I do not want you to do.
Cause just before, just before, at least you're not asking Cortana.
So let me, okay. Or big speed. Oh my God. Whatever.
My echo understands me pretty well. My phone. Okay.
Google understands me pretty well. Cortana on my damn Xbox.
I don't know what the hell Microsoft because all that ever happens is
I never asked her to do anything, but every once in a while,
she'll just chime in while I'm watching TV and say, I'm sorry.
I didn't understand you. I didn't say anything.
And then I try and tell her to do stuff. And it's like,
I'm ignoring you. This is like me in high school trying to date.
I wasn't talking to you. I said, I wasn't talking to you either.
Alone. You're harassing me. It's like, I, bye.
I'm going to go back to my room and play video games,
which consisted of at that point in the,
in the early 18th century was the football game.
Now people were thinking now Madden football, the kids today. No,
it was the little little LEDs you went that you moved up and down to avoid hitting
the other. My best friend in high school had that game and I spent hours on it.
Oh, the kids today. So just before we started recording,
we were talking about Brent was, and we're going to spare you from this.
Brent was singing radio Gaga and he says, have you seen that movie?
And yes, I saw it opening weekend. I bought the Blu-ray the day it came out.
Not only am I and was I as a kid, a huge, huge queen fan,
the movie while it took, cause I knew so much of the history of the band,
it took way too much artistic license and how the story was told.
But the acting that Rami Malek was just amazing as Freddie Mercury.
And then the point I wanted to bring up is on YouTube,
there is a split screen side by side showing the Rami Malek and band.
A live aid concert alongside the original live aid concert.
Oh my God. Not just everything, everybody,
everybody in the band.
They made John Deacon look so eighties Deacon throughout the movie.
But yeah, that side by side,
the whole band and credit to directors, producers, everyone involved, coaches,
everyone that got them to do that. That is just amazing.
That story, I too adored Queen growing up.
And then there is another angle where the Freddie Mercury story resonates with me.
So my eldest is gay.
And so I think about these sort of things all the time.
All the time, like as a father, you go, wow,
I wish society was not quite the way it is because he's going to have a tougher life.
It does make your life harder as a result.
And there's nothing I can do to help him. Right? It's rough.
Yeah. Well, on that note. Yeah.
But no, that's the,
but I hear that a lot from friends who have gay children or just, it's just,
it's tough. Anyway, on a more serious note,
let's talk about things that are pissing me off. Oh, we already,
oh, we actually,
we should probably check in and see how things are going.
I'm busy in my new job. It is awesome. I'm liking it a lot.
How you doing, Brett? Oh, I'm, I'm, it's review season.
That's all it is. Oh God. Yeah. No, it, I'm so sorry.
It doesn't end for another month. Yeah. Okay. So good luck with that.
That goes back again. And then. All right. Um, I recommend alcohol.
Uh, yeah, there will be lots of that this weekend. Yeah.
And before we forget and get onto the meat of the show,
I would like to mention that Brent and I will both be,
we'll be co-presenting a session at the online testing conference,
online testconf.com on June 6th at,
well it's June 5th and 6th. That's the OTC. That's the OTC.
Our talk is the 6th. Our talk is the 6th at 11 AM Pacific,
but you should go to all the talks because it's free. It's online.
Pants optional. It is really cool. Yeah.
I think Lisa's in this one too. There's a lot of good ones. And in fact,
I have a call today, uh,
with someone else that I'll remind me to talk to you about this.
Cause I have it yet.
I have a call later today with someone else who was presenting an OTC about
potentially being a guest on this show. Nice. All right.
Nice. I want to.
That's better than the answer. You go, no, no more guests. We've tried this.
No, well, we all know, we all know.
We stop when we've,
when we do multiple guests and we're realizing that we're not actually
learning how to do guests. Thus far we are, we've learned a great deal.
So now I know how to have a guest. I think.
So much easier. It's only one person,
but the a podcast just doesn't have a good ring to it.
A testing. Yeah.
Testing. Yeah. A testing. A testing podcast.
It kind of gets rid of the theme. So yep.
We're stuck with each other.
Despite the fact that I managed to anger most to
all of my Twitter followers this week. Did you catch that?
I did. Yeah, that was fun.
Oh, they were coming at you in so many different angles. So,
and this has happened to me before.
And if you don't run the Twitter, I will catch you up.
I don't even know where to start because I have so many rants related to this.
So this is going to be very disconjointed.
I should have come in with an outline of making my points in the proper order,
but we're going to kind of ramble through it. You know what?
I don't think that should have been the case. Right.
That even an outline or that I shouldn't.
Like there's one comment I'm thinking of was like, Oh,
that was irresponsible. Yeah. Let me, let me get to that.
And you know what you were ranting. Screw that. No, no, no.
And I don't think I was. And, and, but the whole thing.
You don't think you're irresponsible or ranting?
I don't think I was irresponsible. Okay.
And I think this stems from a much deeper seated
problem in the testing community.
So let me start with how I angered the masses.
I was talking to a colleague about some UI automation he was working on and he
wasn't really working on it.
What he was working on was I wrote some proof of concept,
you animation tests.
I'll get back to those later and a year ago and he was going to dust them off
and get them running as part of CI very basic. And then tests.
It's something I did a proof of concept to see if a particular tool would work.
It did a year later. My tests all ran, except for ran with no errors.
A year later, active development. Yay. Alan with one,
one error due to a, uh,
a redesign that changed the name of the selector. Okay.
And the redesign, that part of the,
that part that those elements on the webpage removed from angular to react and
he was telling me that react, uh, does some weird things with selectors. I said,
yeah, I'm sure, I'm sure they do because they're stupid.
We talked about data IDs, et cetera. I went to look up some things, uh,
just to see if I could find some quick tips.
And I came across this blog post,
one of the many gazillion blog posts talking about how they've used selenium
to solve their quality problems.
And someone was wrote this code and was very proud of it.
And I just did this and this, and this was great.
And this is how you should do it too.
And it was some selenium thing where you'd find the element by CSS selector.
And the selector was this ugly string of HTML because that's the best they could
do. And I said something to the effect of reason
34,986 why I hate selenium.
People write code like people write code like this and are proud of it.
And in many ways I do hate selenium,
but I learned from the internet that I am not freaking allowed to hate selenium.
I had no, why not? Well,
well, unless you want people and actually I gained like 10 followers from that
tweet. So I'm not sure what happened. Apparently,
you know how people follow Donald Trump?
Because they just want to be a firsthand witness to the train wreck.
I'm assuming that's where my new followers came from.
That one other stupid things I say.
So I got a whole bunch of your,
well I got a whole bunch of twitsplaining.
Is that what it's called? When they explained to me that, oh, well you,
this is just a bad selector. This is bad code. Please don't blame the tool.
That's the nice version.
Angie Jones who I love and respect told me I was irresponsible,
but she did say for someone of your stature.
So I think there's some respect in there too.
I don't think I was irresponsible. Jim Evans,
who's a fricking hero in the selenium community,
he has put so much work into trying to make web driver work for,
especially for IE. I believe he's done some selenium work as well.
He and to give him credit,
he apologized and backed off on this tweet.
He tweets like this are why I consider quitting contributing to open source.
So, well, that's a little bit of an overreaction.
Be backed up. I guess he's taken some heat on other things as well.
People told me that I got a lot of twits.
I never got much what's blending,
twitsplaining on using better selectors.
Like here's how you do it.
Well, you need to go to the developer and tell them to give you a data ID.
So you can write a proper selector.
And then I thought, well, all this happened.
And then I thought,
if I'm going to go to the developer and ask them to write a better selector so I can
write my silly UI automation test and then somebody else,
and I'm all over the place here, somebody else, like you will,
that's not testable that way.
You need to get the devs to write testable code,
which brings me to my point of if you have to test at the UI,
if the only way for you,
you to test this application is through the UI,
it's not fricking testable.
Yes.
And nobody gets there is, and this is where the rant goes.
So my problem isn't directly Selenium,
but I'm going to come back to that.
My problem is Selenium.
You know why?
Because Selenium is good.
Selenium is easy, fairly easy to use.
Selenium is used widely to automate UI,
which means you have a bunch of people and I've written UA automation and it is
very, very difficult.
I'd rather go write a Blu-ray decoder.
Me too, especially.
You don't know how to code yet,
but here take this Selenium and automate a bunch of UI.
So much wrong with that one.
It's hard.
And there is a whole community of people out there making money,
consulting, writing Selenium tests.
There's this idea of an automation engineer, which is, and I don't,
I'm sorry, I've made some of you mad, some of the three,
but if your whole job, and actually this probably isn't true for the three,
but if your whole job is to write UI automation,
I am so, so sad for you.
You're telling me, I love it.
I love it.
It doesn't, I can't even think of the right analogy that won't make you hate me anymore.
I'm working it.
We are, and I'm going to get over my rant here.
You can jump in.
I'm not sure how to not repeat myself over and over and over and over.
But the problem stems from the industries over infatuation with UI automation.
It is, and I'm going to go off for a minute and then I'll let you speak.
I'm going to hold on one second.
Hold on one second.
I'm holding, I'm holding, I'm turning red.
Steam's coming out of my ears.
There is a phrase that you use.
I forget it.
You say MT is the cure.
Modern testing is the antidote for traditional software testing approaches.
Okay.
Now, primed with that, continue your rant.
Because I'm already going to, I'm already going to tell you,
we have been working the solution for this for a long time.
I know we have, but when I get responses like this, it reminds me how far behind a
chunk of the industry is we, and I'm not saying don't write UI automation.
All I'm saying is it's a last fricking resort.
You write UI automation when that's the only way you have to verify that
something's working is through the UI.
It should be rare.
You have to write UI automation.
Yeah.
You know what?
I'm going to actually say it stronger.
I'm going to say, don't write UI automation.
I've, I said this 10 years ago now in a blog post, it stopped writing.
Every time you, you give it, people don't get, it should be the exception.
Exactly.
That's why I'm so pissed about.
So Brent, I don't know where you are on second amendment rights.
I'm which one's that one?
Is that the gun one?
No, that's the gun one.
Brent, do guns kill people?
No, people do.
People with guns kill people.
So you hear all the time is selenium shitty.
No, the opposite is good, but people with selenium are often shitty.
And by I don't mean, and I'm attacking the person in that case.
That's not what I mean.
What I mean is 99.9% of the people using selenium are doing it in an asinine
method, whether it's their crappy coding, whether it's their approach to
automating everything to the UI.
I don't care what I automating the UI is the exception.
You do it when you screwed yourself.
That's the only way you have to test it.
And people will argue, give me all their snowflake edge cases on why they
have to automate the UI and how Alan, you just don't get it.
You don't understand where the industry is.
And if that's where the industry is, I don't care.
Cause that's, I don't want to live there.
I want to live in the modern testing world moving forward where we do things
in a way that accelerates the team and delivers customer value more quickly.
Yes.
Damn it.
No, no.
Um, you and I have seen it over and over again.
The thing there, there, I was actually thinking this morning on the drive in.
And I wonder, I'm just thinking through, do we actually have this in the
principles because there is sort of a principle zero, which is something,
something, something, right?
I don't know what that is.
It's important.
And it's the single most important thing.
Right.
It's we talk about thinking Brent was going to calm everything down.
No, no, actually.
I mean, I had prepped coming.
I think my warning to you yesterday was enough cause I had prepped coming in
expecting to poke you all this, this podcast, but no, I'm a board.
Um, here's one thing about tools, tools and automation when used correctly
are fantastic.
Oh, and let me interrupt for a second.
I got a lot of that.
Any tool can, I heard this over Twitter.
Any tool can be used incorrectly.
Yes, I know that.
Thank you.
Actually, I'm going to disagree with that because I think when it comes to tools,
one of the most important things to close the loop, people will do things
like produce selenium and then go, Oh, look what we've done.
And sure, they've unlocked a great deal of value.
But tools, one of the things tools do is it enables lesser trained people to
succeed at the same level of highly trained people previous to the tool.
Okay.
Are you able to follow that?
I actually was able to follow that.
Fantastic.
Which is weird.
Now, I can't guarantee you listening.
If it reduces the friction around enabling positive outcomes, if the tool has not
been designed as such, it also reduces the friction around negative outcomes.
So it allows you to very quickly produce gold and crap.
And if you're not trained or the tool doesn't prevent you, you're going
to go down that path.
There's a big rich topic, GDPR.
I'm sure you've heard these.
Oh, terms.
Yes, I have.
Okay.
It is chock full of lawyers speak.
Yes, I've read it.
Okay.
You put 10 experts in a room, you will walk out with 11 interpretations.
And then you try to roll it out to engineers and they are given choices.
If you store the user ID, you have to build up this infrastructure to enable a user to
come in and delete things.
Just as a simple example, like any user that says, delete my data, we have to be
able to delete the data and well aware, well aware.
Now, so what people do is they say, well, screw it.
We're not going to collect any user information.
Okay.
Because that is the easiest way to implement GDPR.
If you don't have user information, then you don't have to do anything.
Of course, that harms the business.
Yes.
And maybe, and this is zero principle.
There is, uh, I was going to say critical thinking earlier, but there's
some systems thinking as well.
You have to realize, Oh, actually it's, there's some, I don't know how we fit this
in here.
Uh, there's, there's a systems thinking aspect to empty or our job and
accelerating the business is looking at the making decisions based on the big
picture, not the short term, right?
And maybe that's covered elsewhere, maybe not, but that's what's missing when I
see people infatuated with UI automation as they're solving a short term problem.
And again, we have to, because our, because whatever reason.
No.
And, and, and the thing is, is I will just tell you in my head right now, it's
loosely connected, or I don't want to spend the podcast trying to prove it to
myself, but I actually think UI automation is another manifestation of the
dysfunction loop that we talk about all the time.
We have consultants coming out and, and how can UI automation and we know from
experience that UI automation actually is an entrapment.
If you do not spend, I mean, you come in and you go, Oh, look, you, I don't
know, I'm Asian.
It makes your life so much easier.
Look recorded script.
Oh my God.
Consult comes in recorded script.
That's yeah.
You can create a great demo that plays well for the executive.
And then six months later, the executive wonders why 50% of their resources
are constantly updating automation.
Yes.
And we've been through that loop.
Let me just, uh, I have multiple peeves to get to, but along those same lines,
every day I get at least one of these and it's, I don't know where they
got my email address, but I get one of these good morning, Alan.
I tried reaching you many times, but could not get your attention.
I would like to set up some time to discuss software testing services, test
automation, implementing agile and DevOps seamlessly with you.
And I just never reply because I don't care.
Yeah.
I, I, I get those actually, I get those for data science and
I still get them for tests.
I do not know why I get it for tests.
I have been out of tests for almost a decade.
Yes, it is not.
Yeah.
Anyway, I test hasn't been in my LinkedIn profile, my Twitter
profile for year, at least a year.
And it's no longer at my job title.
So let me talk about, cause I want to bounce back to this.
The last time it weaves some stories together.
The last time I angered the Selenium community, cause this isn't,
isn't the first time, believe it or not.
When I was as a year ago, when I was prototyping these tests, just, uh,
we had a, what I wanted to do as a leader.
So often I'll just, I'll just bootstrap something here.
The proof of concept.
I don't have time to write a lot of code.
Uh, when I get my hands dirty, I want to do things that are important,
but not critical.
I mean, I don't want to be known to be blocked on me.
So doing these little projects of whether it's analysis tools or I'll
write some new animation, whatever.
Uh, we had a website I wanted to write some new animation for, and it was
angular and the de facto test framework for angular is protractor, which is
a wrapper around Selenium that uses some, it's just, there are a gazillion
wrappers around Selenium.
I started writing a test in protractor.
I got halfway through it.
I thought, I can't do this anymore.
I can't, this, this code's the way it's ugly.
The way I have to do weights, I think is ugly to synchronize rather than
sleep, so you just wait for things to appear and you have to verify
everyone as it surely is a better way.
So we would, so it's an event driven sleep.
Is that what you're saying?
No, no, rather than do a sleep, it's an event driven sleep.
It's wait for object.
Okay.
Every UI animation tool has these things, but you end up wrapping
everything in this wait for object things and it's, I get it, but.
And I understand cause I've written a lot of you animation.
I've written enough UI animation to know why I hate it.
So, so there, so anyway, I got halfway through.
I said, I can't do this.
I can't write code like this.
I can't say somebody here, this works and give it to them.
So I wanted to check out some of the other things that were out there.
So I looked at cypress, which I like, uh, didn't love, but then I checked
out this thing called test cafe, which, uh, I thought was much, much easier to use.
Uh, the, the code, I could be more compact.
I'll let you look at it yourself.
I will not.
And okay, that was for the readers, not for you.
So anyway, I wrote these proof of concept tests and test cafe.
And I posted something to the effect of, uh, just spent some time with test cafe today.
Uh, so far I'm liking it a lot more than selenium.
And I might've said for some, you know, and oh my God, sparking wars.
I cannot believe the people who told me everything that was wrong with test cafe,
which boils down to this.
Basically they called it.
I don't know if you remember when selenium ID was out.
One of the reasons people didn't like it is it does what test cafe does is that
rather than interact with the, with the, uh, the object model, it injects JavaScript.
So they go, Oh, once you, once you inject JavaScript in your page, it's not the
same page that customers see.
So it's different.
And I thought, really, that's your worry.
But what happened was I did my development.
Well, so it is different.
Yes.
And I don't care.
I mean, again, I'm right.
But I'm what degree, right?
Sure.
Page loading times don't use this technique.
No, no, no, no.
Right.
So, so anyway, what happened was I did my development and again,
the tests are running a year later.
So there's that, uh, also I developed the test using Chrome.
I thought, well, one of us runs under Firefox.
I just changed the command line.
Oh yeah.
It runs perfectly under Firefox.
Wow.
That's cool.
How about Safari?
Damn, it runs there too.
Let me tell you my experience in a previous job, I'm sure as it's all been fixed
since then, except for every time I ask anybody about it, Selenium works
wonderfully as long as you're using Chrome, my cross browser compatibility,
my experience using complex websites was that we eventually got our
automation to work on Firefox.
We never got it to work properly on IE or, uh, and, and again, credit to Jim
Evans, I think probably IE is much better.
This was three years ago last time I tried this.
So I'm sure it's much better, but I'm fine with injecting JavaScript into my
page, if it gives me cross browser compatibility.
And then as I'm looking more into this, I see a school of people saying, well,
you don't really need to test cross browser.
They're close enough.
You can just test on Chrome.
It's fine.
And it's like you're justifying away limitations in the tool.
So I don't, you know what?
You know what?
If that's true, then, then I'm going to go back to, you know what?
No UI automation at all, which is where I'm going back to.
For me, cross browser testing is one of the places where Selenium is a fit.
Right.
Oh, yes.
But you have to be, it takes effort again.
I have it.
And to be fair for the people who are sending in hate mail, uh, to the show,
uh, that goes to Alan at angry weasel.com.
Please write an all caps so I can filter appropriately.
Wait, wait.
You have an email filter for all caps messages.
That's pretty cool.
Not yet.
But I'll, I'll read, I'll read them all and, um, probably reply to none, but I'm,
I'm, I'm glad to take your hate or on Twitter.
Uh, cause apparently that's where I receive a lot of my hate messages.
Uh, DMS, cause my DMS are open.
Oh my God.
You should see the DMS.
Hating Alan only makes them stronger.
And, and the hate is the explaining on like, they're telling me how to write
better code because I highlighted this shitty code on the internet.
Anyway, where was I before the hate mail?
What were we going to hate me about?
Oh, I just realized I just came up with an acronym that you're a sith
software integration testing hater.
And the more you send him hate, the stronger he becomes.
Yes.
Yeah.
The hate mail is, uh, I'm sure that writing cross browser automation is much
easier than my experience again.
It was three years ago.
The last time I worked on this, that's great.
And I was, and you will tell me how awesome it is.
And I heard about being in a second and that's great too.
But the, honestly, I still really don't give a crap about UI automation.
When I was in Bing, I just did like, I, um, so I used,
it and it just worked.
But I really don't know anything about it, but we did use Selenium quite
effectively to do cross browser.
And when I was in Bing, which is now got close to 10 years ago.
Yeah.
I wonder if the challenge for us was, uh, angular and, or the protractor
wrapped her around it, but maybe, but, but anecdotally, when I've talked
to people who use Selenium and brought this up, they say, Oh yeah, yeah.
Definitely works best on Chrome.
When an angular come, cause I actually, I don't remember having
angular conversations when I was in Bing.
Wasn't around back then.
Okay.
Diving in here and say, well, Alan, you talked about test cafe.
You can't totally hate it.
Uh, again, I'm talking about two or three UI tests or two or three scenarios
covered by UI tests for a very large website that's largely tested elsewhere.
I'm not saying don't write you animation.
I'm saying I kind of saying that, but well, while, while Brent says don't do it,
I'm going to say it's, it's, it's the last resort.
It's when you can only test things.
And I, I did it reluctantly.
I'm just going to say, don't do it because the people who know why I'm saying
that we'll know how to execute the exceptions.
Right.
And that, and that's the difference.
That's the complete, that's the opposite approach of these people who are hating
me on Twitter is that one and I'm picking on selenium because selenium is the
de facto standard for web automation, hands down and I'll, I'll, I've used test
cafe and had success.
I'm sure it has other limitations because I haven't used it extensively and I
never will because I never want to see it used extensively.
It's a last resort when you, when you want to do a tiniest little bit of UI
automation, cause you know, the exception.
I can't even keep my thoughts straight.
Cause I'm so angry about this whole thing, but there's a,
there's a lot of people that make their living writing UI automation every day.
And that's great.
I'm glad you can get paid for that, but
are you, I'm not,
I'm always happy when people can pay their bills.
So that's great.
I'm just like, you know what?
No, that's, that's too, I have a metaphor, but that's too harsh.
I actually think it's, I might even be able to weave an argument that UI
automation, given how testing is in the culture, given the empty stuff that we're
talking about, I think I could make the argument that UI automation is immoral.
So I'm, I got a lot of feedback from various consultants writing, you know,
who, who as part of their consultancy, right?
You animation for their clients and they say, well, and they give me like,
oh yeah, we, we're very smart about this.
And I work with my clients on testability and yes, you want to test at a lower level.
And then blah, blah, blah.
And I can picture me someday as I figure when my kids are done with college, I can
quit my regular jobs and do some part-time consulting.
That's part of my, that that's, I think my life plan at this point.
And I can imagine me going to a company and I'll probably get called in for some
quality consulting because that's in my past.
And I'm just imagining this life in me, but I'm, I'm picturing this scenario.
We didn't need all that set up.
They say, Hey, what we want to, can you help us with this, with this web
automation we want to do?
And I say, no, and never call me again.
You're dead to me.
I don't want to work for people like you.
I would suggest perhaps you instead of a strike one, you're out, maybe go to
strike two.
Yeah.
Luckily it's a few years away.
I could work on my negotiation skills, but I just, I just thinking that is not
something I ever want to do.
Could I do it?
Yes.
Would I hate myself for doing it?
Definitely.
Yes.
And that should be, that's what you should respond with instead of the other
message.
Well, again, I have years to work on this.
My job here is to help your business and what you just asked me to do.
I know we'll harm your business.
So no, I won't.
Here's an alternative.
I would suggest that's, that's what Alan, the consultant should work.
Yeah.
I, again, I got years, but I go back to principle water and our priority
is to improve the business that brings in that systems thinking, because
we have to look at that and go, this is, I get why you want this.
It's buried in lean in the, in number two with lean thinking as well.
Cause if you follow, if you follow lean.
No, lean is like one of the principles of lean is measure the whole.
Not H-O-L-E.
Yeah.
I know it.
I know what you mean.
And I think again, going back to root cause is one is the, the massive
infatuation with UI testing.
And I think unfortunately it's still a big chunk of the industry where the
dev team air quotes and the test team, more air quotes are siloed separate
organizations and with stuff thrown over the wall.
And that's not modern testing.
It's not the world we want to live in.
No, actually.
Yeah.
Did you just say no, actually?
Maybe.
Cause that was cool.
I'm going to highlight that.
I'll put a little bit, put a little reverb on that.
No, actually.
Yeah.
Nope.
No, I'm, I mean, probably that's okay.
That's what party already been doing that.
That's what editing's for.
We're good, man.
Um, damn it.
I got, I got to leave some of that in.
Uh, uh, so anyway, I hope that I don't know if I've explained myself
around my comments or if I've just put more fuel on the fire, but I
stand by all of that and again, I, I have to hate Selenium a little bit
because it has enabled these things to happen.
So I know it's not Selenium.
And I know people have worked very, very hard on it.
And I know people work really, really hard.
And it's not like they're incompetent people.
Good people are doing good work with these tools, but the problem is they're,
they're solving a problem.
They're solving the wrong problem.
The problem is the problem.
Definitely isn't that we need more UI animation.
Right.
It's, it's what they're doing is you said it actually, there's
no way to make it better.
They're solving the wrong problem.
And they're solving the wrong problem very well.
Right.
Um, and that's a really good way of putting it.
You're really, I'll use that somewhere.
So as you know, I played a part in creating an automation infrastructure.
Uh, I almost remember the name, some Greeky stunning name.
That's Perseus.
Yeah.
Look at me.
It's patented.
It is still in operation today.
Sorry.
And I invented it in 1998.
Okay.
Now I wrote a blog about this and I realize, so at the time I was like,
Oh, this is a problem.
And I solved that problem and I did it very well, but I realize
that's the wrong problem.
What I did was.
Reduce the friction around the organization going in the direction that
they wanted to go, but they shouldn't have wanted to go.
It encouraged it.
It encouraged.
Dev pushing quality downstream because we now in, in exchange had such a
rich automation system.
I've heard multiple stories where dev just wrote code, didn't think about it.
We'd submit it to the test system, come back a half hour later and
then fix the test cases.
Yeah.
It's like, they're, it's like, I automated the safety net.
It's like an extra warning level on their compiler.
I don't have to, I don't have to think about quality because the test
told me if I screwed up and I made it really easy for, for them to.
I enabled thoughtless behavior.
So I'm wondering, I'm an interrupt before I forget my thought.
Cause I'm old.
I'm wondering if there's a term in lean or elsewhere for when this concept of
solving the wrong problem really well.
And someone can help me out on what that is, but that's, I'm scared to ask Twitter.
They'll, they'll, they'll, they'll twitsplain it to me.
I'm thinking in, in, uh, in medical terms, right.
It's, it's solving the symptom, not the problem.
And there's some clever, witty things.
Yeah.
And I, and I guess it is that maybe it is.
Just that, but I like this idea of solving the wrong problem really well, which is what
the people who are experts in selenium I think are doing.
And they're going to be mad at me for saying that, but I fully believe that.
Now we'll tell you that.
We're actually taking it.
I mean, it does occur to me that with MT, this is the first time it really has
occurred to me with MT, we, we are potentially, um, that's another aspect
of traditional that accidentally we're taking head on.
Cause it's dumb.
Right.
It's inefficient.
Why does selenium, why does UI tests and exists because test or dev
doesn't create testable code.
And we have to go through the top layer in order to cover the whole thing in the
end.
Right.
And because of that, now why is that?
Because that's not what they're paid for because there's a separation
between testers and developers.
Yep.
Right.
And then given, given those worlds, yeah, selenium makes sense.
But I'm like, no, get rid of those worlds.
That's not the world we think the industry should be in.
No, I, I, you know what?
And I get it that it exists.
The developer is responsible for their own integration testing.
I can guarantee you any developer worth their salt will not test this at the UI level.
They will not.
And if, if you want to push quality up the stream, like the single most
effective technique I have done is I've stopped the enablement.
So when I was last in the test role, I'm like, you know what?
My team is no longer providing the service.
And my team is also no longer holding accountability over code correctness.
Yeah.
Even those two changes do whatever you want.
One of the thought experiments I threw out in our Slack group, one of the three.slack.com
you can go to modern testing.org to find the link to join.
One of the things I threw out there as a thought experiment was imagine, let's say
that UI testing was an unsolved problem and deemed impossible to solve by the
industry. So in other words, imagine UI testing is impossible and doesn't exist.
Now what do you do?
Well, that's clearly you, you hire.
Uh, an army of offshore vendors or, you know, crowdsource you test.com baby.
I guess that's an option.
That is probably an option a lot of companies would take, but I think you
would figure out how to test it another way.
And, and, and in actually today's world, you wouldn't do that because that so much
slows down your cycle time.
That approach honestly, just a ticking.
I, I, I, I think you don't test at all.
You ship straight to the customer.
I think teams that invest heavily in UI automation don't really care about cycle
time again, someone will tell me you're wrong about that.
We have these automation.
We run all the time and we ship seven times a day.
That's great.
Well now, but I want to be super clear.
We may even need to break down the taxonomy of UI automation,
UI automation to do integration testing, abjectly dumb,
do not do it ever. Please dear God, stop.
Cross browser integration. I think that's the place where it makes sense.
If you're trying to automate particular UI interactions,
like, Hey, what happens when you click this button?
Hey, it depresses. Sure.
If what you're trying to test is that the, the UI elements do UI element things.
Sure. That makes sense.
But in terms of trying to test the product end to end, it is terribly
in productive, terribly inefficient.
And, and now on this, like I'm firmly convinced it's, it is encouraging.
The dysfunction loop.
I would like to point out that also on the Slack group yesterday,
Brent said he was going to come in and poke me and,
and challenge me on some of my statements about this,
but instead he's doubled down even harder than me.
Oh yeah. No, no, no.
And it's actually because by me making that statement, I primed you,
the, which I'm going to argue softened you a little bit for the podcast.
And I also primed myself.
That was soft. What's that?
I was soft. Softened. Okay. All right.
But I think my metaphor I should with you, you realize that if,
if you went down that anything down that direction,
you were not going to win because you don't agree with it anyway.
Right. It's in the metaphor I said is, is essentially,
Hey, Alan, are you expecting the slim? Are you,
are you complaining that a hammer doesn't work as a wrench?
Right. Or a screwdriver, whatever.
Well, again, that, that, and that's funny.
You say that because that's what you came up with earlier.
And so we're solving the wrong problem really well. Right.
It's the same thing. Right. It's, um, you, you, you have your house.
Let's say you have black mold, right? Throughout your walls.
So you paint over it or wallpaper. Yeah. Right.
Looks nice. Now you didn't solve the problem. Nope.
Just a matter of time before it comes back and hit you.
Actually, maybe we should build a counter selenium tool and call it black mold.
Well, you know where they came up with the name selenium?
I'm guessing they looked at the element chart.
Not quite periodic chart. Remember when mercury was really popular? No.
I forget the name of their automation tool. Anyway, uh,
this called selenium cause selenium is the antidote for mercury poisoning.
Oh, interesting. You ever tell you why I called my tool Perseus?
Why? Because the competing automation was called Medusa.
Yeah. Please don't,
Brent and I have lived these mistakes for you.
It's a different world now. I feel like we know what we're talking about.
So yeah, don't, don't make the same mistakes we made. No, actually,
it's go to principle. So I agree with what you're saying,
but I'm going to say it even further. When you think about UI automation,
think deeply about principle number one,
and don't just go, well, we have to know stop it because you don't,
I can tell you on multiple different teams I've been on it.
Once you go down this route,
it is a matter of time before all your test resources,
all they are doing is maintaining UI automation.
Been there, been there, been there. Oh my God.
And you can not,
even if it is still your job to validate co correctness,
you will not be able to do that.
And it's just a matter of time.
Once you go down the route of choosing to use UI
automation to solve this problem.
Yeah. I wonder if, and we got it closed here in a second,
but I wonder if one of the suggestions I got was in my
Twitch splitting day was need to go to the developer and ask him to make that
code more testable and do it this way. That's great. I knew that.
I'm making a point here,
but I wonder if another conversation is to have,
if your job is to write a bunch of UI automation is to have a
conversation of ask if that testing needs to be done.
I wonder how much I'm wondering now how much you animation is not
not last resort only we can test it,
but it's because their job is to write you animation and they're testing
something that's actually completely tested by other tests.
And they're not actually getting any new information from that UI testing
investment.
I think there's also potential of a lot of self justification as well.
I believe that as well. There was.
And it's a set. This is why I said it's sort of the automation version of MT,
right? It's because we see that when we go and say we talk about principle seven,
we see like, well, who's going to test it? Devs can't.
There's two subjective, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
No, it's self justification. Yeah, it is. Absolutely. Absolutely.
I need to exist because I need to exist. Yes.
I I've heard that one too. I've heard it. I've heard it. I've heard it.
There was other Twitter drama that we are not going to get to today.
So I'll leave it to the listeners to discover and learn,
but all these cool stuff going on. I have work to do.
We'll ignore Twitter today. Good luck.
I'll edit the podcast tomorrow and we'll get it out there. All right.
That was fun. Thanks, Brett. You bet. All right. See you next time.