This is the AB Testing 343 podcast, a podcast where we ask one of the three listeners of
the AB Testing podcast, three questions about almost anything. ABT 343 is a fun slice of
what's going on in the world of modern testing. Let's get started.
Welcome everybody to the ABT 343 podcast. I'm joined once again by one of the three listeners,
Ariti Pannu. Did I say that well? Yes. As you can tell, I've been practicing. Very active
member of our community. Someone who is, I would maybe even call a fan of modern testing,
but someone, not just a fan, but someone who's pragmatic and practices some of the principles.
So looking forward to hearing some stories from her today. So welcome, Ariti.
Thank you for the invitation. Thank you for having me.
These are fun. I'm slowly getting better at these. I'm hoping that over time, these end
up being maybe even more exciting than Brent and I yelling at each other.
Oh, we wouldn't be listening if you were not yelling at each other. If it was a polite formal
conversation, I think we would just skip it.
Good call. Good call. So as you know, the format for today is I'll ask you three questions
and you'll give me three answers and then three minutes later we're done. No pressure,
say whatever you want. I might ask some clarifying questions and we'll see what happens.
Are you ready for your questions?
I am ready to rumble.
Okay, let's first we'll turn to politics. No, just kidding. So I already mentioned you
have some good interest in modern testing and some examples. So what are some ways you
have seen or experienced modern testing in your work?
I would say that I experienced this the other way around. I started listening to the podcast
about a year ago or 18 months ago and the principles were already there. So I read
them. I thought, these things make sense. They seem to be reasonable things. But I really
didn't know if they apply to me or whatever I did. And then as I kept listening to the
podcast, I realized that I went from a traditional tester into modern tester. That was about
five years ago.
Can you talk more about that transition because it just hasn't happened overnight?
No, no. And I really, really struggled with that. So a bit of history. I'm working at
SAP. It's a bit software company here in Germany and worldwide. And I started working, I got
hired to work as a tester in a very small product that was doing cloud things, which
were not very common at the time. And I really liked doing the testing. I really
liked finding bugs. I really liked blocking bugs. I really liked having this deep
knowledge of the product. But as I kept on working there and my role was evolving and
changing, I realized that I didn't have so much time for testing. I was doing other
things. And although my manager appreciated that, my colleagues appreciated that, I hated
that because I wanted to do testing. And it took me a long time to come to terms with
the fact that it's not only testing. And after listening to the podcast and reading
the principle, I said, this is what happened to me. Because to come to terms with the
fact that I'm not only testing, but I'm doing all the other things as well, it took
time. It was not from one day to the other. So what are some of those other things you
ended up doing? I think one of the major things is how to have our deployment
pipeline running in a meaningful way. I think that was the first thing that got my
attention. They were running all sorts of checks. There were huge jobs running things.
They would break. Nobody would know what it meant that it broke. My first job was to
clean this up. The other thing that I was doing had to do with compliance. And back
then to be compliant as an SAP product, really entitled lots of paperwork,
screenshots, what have you, and to find a way to make that meaningful for our small
product that also took time. And also the developers had objections to something, some
quality things imposed, and how to bring them to the company that also took effort.
So the role evolved from testing a feature to looking into the overall quality of
what we're doing and why. There were many things that we did wrong, but I
think overall, it was a pretty good experience.
That's cool to hear. And it just brought up so many thoughts in my mind. Recently, I've
been talking to Brent more and more about how I see DevOps, the DevOps, whether it's a
role or a concept or a culture. I think that influences accelerating the achievement of
typical quality a lot. It sounds like you were doing some things that would help
you to accelerate the team. And then also that testing is, and I also have a long
career doing testing, and it is one way to reduce risk and help the team move
faster. But it's not the only way.
No, but as I said, that took me a lot of time to realize that I was resistant to the
idea of now I have to do all these other things that annoy me. I didn't want to
handle, you know, compliance things. But some of them were useful, not all of
them, maybe not to the degree that we want them to be. But there were some useful
ideas there. And we had to take the best of what we had and do the best for the
quality of our product and then just complain about it or ignore it. These were
hard realizations. But this is also what the team and the product needed.
And I'm just kind of curious, how did you get over that hump? What was the like,
you didn't like it? And do you like it now? Or you still prefer to do
mostly testing?
And now I understand it. But I think I didn't fully I liked some of the things.
But I think that it helped me that I went on parental leave. And then I
stepped back. And when I looked at it from afar, I saw the value of it. While
I was in it, I cannot really say that they appreciated it that much. But when
I stepped back and I saw what was happening, and then it hit me that it's
the rest of the things. It's not only testing, it's all of the things
together that bring value. But while I was in it, I cannot say that I had
this revelation or but stepping back helped me a lot.
This is actually a really good story to hear because I think when we talk
about modern testing, a lot of people have already been on the journey or
they can't imagine the journey or they're in the middle of it. And there
are a lot of, you know, a lot of our listeners are career testers, and
there may be quite a few who are in that same boat, they're seeing the
role change, and they're not sure if they like it or not. And it just
realizing that's okay. And I think the directions you can go from being a
someone who's mostly dedicated or entirely dedicated to testing into a
more broader role. There's quite a few different directions you can go, of
course, I talked about DevOps. But there's also something we talked about
quite a bit with, I believe, principle number seven, and maybe five
to some extent is the role of the quality coach. I know you've done
some quality coaching at SAP. Yeah, tell me about tell all of us
about that role and what you liked and didn't like about that and
how that went, what your activities are, those kinds of things.
Yeah, so coming back from Pteranthaleev, I had this time to reflect
of what happened in the last five years. So then there was a newly
built department at the time, called Cloud Quality Coaching. And
the purpose of the department was to go to development teams, the
coaches, we go to development teams for one or two months, and
work with them not only with the quality people, but the whole
team how to improve their quality. Some teams called us
that we have a quality problem, and then we would have to go
in and analyze what the problem was. Sometimes there were people
that were doing excellent job and they just wanted some, some
conversation to see if they can do anything better. And my role
in that was mainly to coach people in a quality role, which
they had huge experience in releasing products on premise
or with big cycles. But to come to this fast paced world was
something new to them. And my role was to calm them down to
help them a bit, be helpful for their teams.
The quality therapist role.
The quality therapy, it was kind of a therapist mentoring
sessions, because these were people really experienced with
testing and setting things up and they were good when it came
to testing. But it was this transition to the cloud world
that needed a bit of work, let's say, and most of them
were really embracing the change. I can't say that I
found somebody that said, no, this is my turf. Testing is my
thing. And I don't want anybody near it or quality is
my thing. I think they were all or most of them were very
open to the change.
That's good to hear. Because when I think about, I have
stories about people who had expertise, but they had no,
they wanted to keep that expertise close to themselves
because it was job security. And I'm glad that isn't the
case there. So what were some of the, believe it or not,
this is just the second question, I just have sub
questions because it's tangents are part of A B testing. Do
you have a couple of examples of things you helped teams
do? I'm just kind of, I want a little bit more, trying to
understand a little bit more about what this role was. So
what would you, what was an example of something you would
help a team do?
Example that I helped the team to, I said, I was mainly
working with people in the quality role. So one was to
set some kind of boundaries. There were many things that
were requested of them, because in the old world, the
quality person was responsible for everything. To help them
distribute some of the work was one thing I worked with
them with. Because until now, it was all their domain, they
were the quality assurance people. But they needed to
delegate some things they needed to help others take the
responsibility for some things.
This is perfect timing to talk to you. I don't know if you
listened to the last A B testing podcast yet. But I
talked, I talked in there about how I'm discovering that
one of the things I want to get better at is coaching
coaches. And really, if you're coaching people who are then
working on delegating other work, you're, you're coaching
coaches too, in that role.
Yes, that was the point that we, as we were a central team,
our quality coaching team was a central team. So we would go
in and leave. But the main idea was when we leave, that
the team was more enabled to take care of quality on their
own. And people in the quality role were still needed in
those teams. But they needed to adapt their role.
I like it. I like it. Did you have I have way back like 15
years ago, maybe 20 years ago at Microsoft, I'm feeling old.
I was doing a lot of talking around the company and
organizing meetings of the senior testers. In fact, that's
where Brent and I first started hanging out. And one
of the things I toyed with for a while was if the same idea,
should we have this quality consultant quality coach role?
And would that be a better way to scale the relatively few
number of senior testers we had at Microsoft? It never
happened. But I think maybe the world wasn't ready for it. I
think in today's world, in a more cloud based org, I can
see, I can see good reason, see good reasons why this would
work. And probably some reasons why it wouldn't work.
Some reasons I wouldn't work because you go for for a fixed
amount of time. So what we struggled a bit about is how do
we keep up the work? So we would go in, come out. And then
what happened next? And to keep track of that, we we struggled
a bit there. And as I said, my, my part was to coach this
quality transition. But there were other coaches in our team
that focus, let's say on automation, they help the
teams decide a bit better on their strategy, what to
test where, instead of doing Selenium from end to end test,
not only about Selenium, just trying to automate something
from end to end with all kinds of scenarios, basically
scripting what they had as manual regression tests. So
there were colleagues that we were helping cut down the
tests and do a more meaningful automated test strategy.
I'm imagining me as a as a quality coach there and I go
in and tell teams to get rid of all their Selenium. Maybe
not. Yeah, that does. Yeah, that would be problematic. But
there would be maybe some interesting discussion of how
we define integration tests and who is doing tests. And
that's a whole new.
Yeah, I tweet
of worms.
As you know, I know you've listened long enough to know I
have my beefs with not with Selenium the language but
with the overuse of Selenium. Lately, I mentioned this in a
few tweets and I'll probably mention the podcast sometime,
but I'm slowly changing my tune on not writing any, I
think teams still write too much automation at the UI
level for web stuff. But I'm thinking with tools like
Mabel or Autify or Testem, I think the ability to write
reliable cross browser tests is getting easier. Those
are tools that use a little bit of ML to try and track
when things are changing versus having to go
up the other selectors.
They reply different question than the ones that let's
say traditionally this end to end test we're replying.
Right, right. And I just I still want as few of those
as possible. Just like, you know, when the cone
wrote that pyramid, and we're way off in the tangent,
he said it and everybody ignores this part and I
underline it eight times every time I see it, which
is at the top part of those end to end tests,
write as few of these as possible.
Yeah.
So we've we've hit it. We've hit a sore spot.
When I started this testing job, my first task was to
automate end to end tests from with QTP.
Oh, I'm so sorry.
Wait, was this in 1997? When did you do this job?
2010.
QTP is still around?
In 2010 it was.
Oh my gosh.
Oh yes. And it was a FlexUI for the fun of it.
And I am not skilled at coding for my life.
Yeah. So after playing with it for a while, I said,
do you have anything else for me to do? Because
this is not going to work. And I was lucky because
the developer in the team wrote a DSL so I could
test on API level.
Oh my gosh.
Yeah, the sound you're about to hear is the sound
of me hitting my head on my desk.
Yeah. But as I said, I was lucky. I started
working in a team with very good developers that
they realized soon enough that this is not going
to work because I had no experience in software
development.
Yeah. And I think I think that's a big part of
which means you're coaching the developers in a
way.
The developers not so much. No, I will. I think if
you have a team where the developers understand
that testing isn't this black hole, they go throw
this up over the wall to immediately being begin
to understand quality a little bit better.
Oh yeah. Okay. When I was working in the
development team, I went back to being a coach
in a central team. No, but yeah, as a tester
quality QA in a development team, you definitely
have to work very close to the developers and
operations and sales and business and you need
to coach them all a bit in certain ways and
they coach you.
Yes. One of the things I noticed as I begin
spreading the quality culture, quality culture
transition guide that that I wrote and
spreading that around unity was it wasn't just
enough to talk about it with development teams.
I think a quality culture spans teams that
aren't developers of software. I think it does.
Quality culture is part of the way sales
approaches things. It is part of marketing.
Good on you.
Documentation. Yes. Especially document.
Translation. You name it. If you don't align
more or less the teams together, you don't
get very far because you have them different
priorities and different goals, different
timelines.
Yes. Interesting. So you did quality coaching
for a while, but you have a new upcoming role.
Then I went on parental leave.
Congratulations again.
And I went back and I said, I revised what I'm
doing. And I think it was also a lot having
to do with listening to the podcast. But I
thought, Hmm, how can I really affect quality?
And there was a product owner job being
available in the company. I thought, Hmm, why
don't I try this side now? So starting January,
I'm going to be a product owner in some of
our internal tools. And interesting. So go on
a little bit. I have many questions. Yeah,
the main tool that I will start with what it
wants to do is we have all these pipelines.
All the company has everybody sets their
pipeline. So the tools team is trying to
make some kind of unification of the
pipelines. You have to be compliant. And
there are some checks that you need to have
in place. So instead of everything trying to
figure out what checks I do, I need to do
what are the thresholds on all of this. We
try to make this standard. So when you start
a new product or any project, so you get
the pipeline for free and what the product
that we're working on will do is store the
data that comes out of these pipelines. One
for compliance. This is the original, the
first goal. And the second one is then to
come up with some questions of what does
this data tell us? So this will start in
January.
My first question is, and this is just,
there's a name for this bias. It's a
it's a recency bias, where because I'm
thinking about something thinking we think
about is there a pattern here when there may
not be, but an internal tool sounds a
little bit, do you think of some overlap
there with an infrastructure team or a
DevOps team? Or am I making that up?
I don't know. I don't understand the
question.
That's probably because I asked it very
poorly. So I recently took over a team
we call our DevOps team, which builds all
of our internal tools, including compliance
tools, things we use in our organization
to help us ship software safely. And
with all the appropriate security tools
and compliance tools running in those
development pipelines could be a different
pipeline, different definition of
pipeline you're talking about. Is there
some similarity there? Or am I reading
too much into that?
I think so. We have a central tool
where if you if you go through all that
this is where you display what you
have done. This is one of the internal
tools. Yes. And the idea is to bring
whatever comes out of this pipelines
directly to that tool, instead of
somebody going and uploading log files
or what have you, that comes out of the
pipeline, the idea is to automate the
whole process. So I guess there is some
kind of overlap is taking care of your
household tools. You need developers to
come up with them, develop them.
As someone with a lot of quality and
testing experience, what are some things
that you think some unique ideas you'll
bring as a product owner to something
like this?
That's a very good question. That's
also what I said in my job interview
said, what will you do as product
owner? I don't know. I've never been a
product owner. I think it was
appreciated, honestly. I think the
quality perspective is, I think it
comes to the principles again, that
the customer is the only one who
knows what is good. And now as a
product owner, I have the chance to go
and speak to these customers and
bring their perspective as much as I
can to the team.
I would say that you will ask, and
not just when you meet with them,
that any product owner is going to
do that. One of the things I see
from testers is they ask better
questions.
Yes. You ask, first of all, why we
should do it?
Yes, yes, yes.
Why? Now all these why's that it
has a test or why should we do it?
Does it make sense to do this?
What problem does it solve? Or what
what problem do we need to solve?
Exactly. And then you also have
the input directly from your
customers. And then you can bring
that to your team. You can bring
them, I think you can bring them
better data, because you try to
work more on the questions that
you ask the customers. You try to
go a bit deeper than the surface.
Oh, I want this. And I find this
interesting. I don't know if it
would work out, but I really
find the topic interesting.
And it's a development team
without a quality person inside.
Yeah, you'll help. I think what
you'll end up doing is you'll be
the product owner and the
quality coach.
I don't think so. I think they
have already the quality culture
in the team. I think the
Scrammaster is doing lots of
quality work. Okay. They're an
established team.
One of the things I tell my
boss, he asked, how is our team
doing a quality and testing? And
the thing I always say is they
do, they're great. They do all
of the testing they know how to
do. And then my role is to is
to broaden that amount of
knowledge they have about
testing. So they do more.
They're happy to do testing, but
some teams don't know very much
beyond unit or functional level
testing. So what I try and do
and people on my team, the
coaches on my team, try and
help them figure out what some
other things. How else would you
test your APIs, for example,
and come up with some ideas for
increasing the breadth of their
testing coverage?
Yeah, I think it's something
that you said either in the
Slack channel or in one of the
podcasts is what is the worst
thing? It really think it's
what is the worst thing that
can happen and what is the best
thing that can happen. I
really like that. And to
bring that to the team, I
think it's something you can
do either from a quality
perspective or a product
perspective. So I'm looking
forward to it.
I am I'm confident you'll have
fun and you'll do very well.
Particularly excited because I
have I have a particular fondness
for a lot of people like to
work on those customer facing
features. And I've written some
of those for customers. I've
written a lot of shipping code.
I enjoy for some reason writing
and working on internal tools a
lot more. And and one of my
favorite questions to always
ask someone would come and
ask me for some very specific
thing. And time and time again,
I would ask them, great, what
would you do when you had
that, which was my way of
asking them what the problem
they're trying to solve is.
And often there was already
a way to solve it. And I
think that comes from my
testing background, being able
to ask those questions. So I'm
excited for you. I want to live
a little vicariously through
you. I think it should be very
interesting. I think you're
going to have a good time and
do very well.
Let's see. I'm really excited
now. I wish I could start
right now.
I think you'll enjoy some time
off first.
I will. I'm going on holidays
tomorrow.
Yes. Yes. I know you told me
so. And where are you heading
on holiday?
Greece going to visit my
family. Enjoy. Enjoy. Enjoy.
Thank you.
It has been a pleasure talking
with you and hearing a little
bit more about what you do and
a little bit more about modern
testing. Is there anything else
before I forget like Twitter
handles or blogs or anything
else our listeners should know
about you?
Um, yes, I do have a blog,
which is called unremarkable
tester dot com. And then my
Twitter handle is unremarkable
QA. And I guess I will change
my LinkedIn now profile to
unremarkable. P.O.
I really need to somehow
consolidate all of this, but
anything with unremarkable tester
QA, you will find me.
Perfect. Wonderful. Well,
thank you again for spending
some time with me today.
Really enlightening. Really
great talking with you. And
thanks again for all of your
support of the podcast and the
Slack channel. Safe travels
and best of luck in your new
role.
Thank you very much. It's been
a pleasure. All right. We'll
see you later. Bye bye.
Took about a year to the
Japanese and I could I can
get around the basics and the
same I spent a bunch of time
in France and I can get
around in France. I tried to
learn German and I just
couldn't get it. I couldn't
do it. I had a really hard
time with it. It's the
syntax. It's the way they
structure the language is
and also the pop music is
not so good.
Because I learned English
through songs, recording,
you know, with a cassette
next to the TV and Spanish
the same way. And then I
said, okay, where's the
German pop music? And then
you go like, no, no, no,
no, no, this will not work.
So I've been here for 10
years and and because I'm at
SAP where everybody speaks
English, I'm comfortable
not learning more German.
And now I have to do it in
German. It's really so a
new job in a new
language. Yeah, it's
interesting. I go to our
Montreal office a lot and
everyone there speaks
English. But if you work
there full time, they
expect you to learn
French. Yeah. They're not
expecting it here. They're
they're quite nice. Well,
they say, come on, you've
been here for 10 years.
Everybody in the team is
German. You have to be
able to participate at least
in the meetings in German,
which I can do. But when
it comes to details. Yes.
And even when I was at my
very best in French, it's
very much faded for me. I
I could understand a lot of
conversations, but if there
were too many details or
if they're telling a joke
that had, you know, just a
lot of idiomatic
expressions, I had no
idea what was going on.
And also context. If it's
about some commercial in
the 80s, it's like, okay,
I don't get the reference.
Yes. Yes. Yeah. So yeah.
Now it's in German. I'm
gonna let you get going.
It's okay. It's lady.
Have a have a great
holiday.
Thank you. I hope I survive.
I'm sick. The kids are sick.
We're traveling tomorrow.
That's the three of us.
They all they all get.
Yeah. Yeah. Good luck.
Yeah. Thank you.
I'll have my mom pick us up
from the airport and then
I have to do nothing.
My mom will do everything.
I'm a grown up.
You only have to survive
that long. Yeah.
All right.
It's it's only a two hour
flight. Okay.
Okay. Thank you very much
again. And thank you.
We'll cross paths again
soon.
I hope so. All right.
Bye bye.