This is the AB Testing 343 podcast, a podcast where we ask one of the three listeners of
the AB Testing podcast, three questions about almost anything. ABT 343 is a fun slice of
what's going on in the world of modern testing. Let's get started. We're back again for another
episode of ABT 343 and we have one of our three listeners with us today. Today we have
Percy Ababa. Say hi, Percy. Hi everyone. I hope the other two is out and about and we'll be
listening to this. Yeah, we'll get this out sometime during the holiday season. Happy to
have you here, getting a lot of great feedback on this series. So glad to have someone who's
practically a show regular here today. Percy was on the show we did without Brent in Philadelphia
three years ago, four years ago now, maybe four years. Yeah. Wow. A while back. Yeah, three,
four. Yeah. And then also took part in our 100th episode and is the creator of,
in a way, the creator of one of the three.slack.com. He put our Slack group together first.
Yeah, I was just the guy who signed up. Yeah, there's a lot of credit to be the
guy who signs up for stuff. Yeah, I do think that it's something that's inevitable. I'm not
going to pull a Thanos here, but it's something that would have happened. I mean, there is
definitely an acceleration among the listeners and the feedback, especially with how you and Brent
are talking about the mailbag questions that you guys get. It's like, man, how come nobody's ever
tried to bring everybody together to something that's kind of like 10,000 conversations permanent?
Yeah. One of the things we talk about, I was in a conversation on Reddit over the weekend with
someone who was very confused about modern testing. And in this conversation, I didn't
plan to bring this up. A nice tangent to start off with. He said, and I don't know the quote in
front of me, but he said, an agile is getting phased out. And I said, what, what do you mean
agile is getting phased out? I think it's market driven and it helps. He goes, well,
it's being replaced by CICD. And I thought maybe you don't understand what any of these words mean.
So yeah, CICD is a way to achieve the agile principles. And he got into another conversation
which involves modern testing. It's not there to be something new to try and push the industry
in some direction. We're just putting a label on some things that are already happening. And
many teams have come up with modern testing approaches without knowing modern testing.
And some people recognize this change is happening and want some tools and ideas to help navigate
how to survive or how to best transition this move.
Right. And I think this is actually a really good segue into the transition guide, right?
Which is, you know, it's not a thing that you're supposed to be able to follow and decide,
specifically tell you what to do so that you can get to the next kind of level of the capabilities.
It's a way for you to evaluate and understand where you are. And then from there, you can
build your backlog on what you could do, whether the focus is going to be on tooling or skills or
blend of both or improving the process. But at the end of the day, knowing what your team is capable
of, breaking down whatever assumptions you have on what a thing is or what a thing is supposed to be.
You're definitely better off from there, but that's just the first step. There's a lot more
that needs to be done to get you to the point where, for example, you're switching from
chaos to growing, for example, right? From your testing breath capability. So it's definitely
a good way to look into where you are. Yeah. So Percy is talking about for,
if any of the other two haven't seen it, is the Quality Cultural Transition Guide,
which goes along with Principle Number 4, which is the one that says we care deeply about the
quality of our team and we coach and lead and nurture them towards a more mature quality culture.
This is the one where 20 years ago, we may have had some managers, some more say testing is
responsible for quality, which we know is stupid. We knew it was stupid then. We know it's even more
stupid now. But I would say even today that as we're making this transition, that testers or the
people formerly known as testers need to be a big part and have some responsibility for driving
the quality culture. And this spreadsheet I put together on the Quality Culture Transition Guide
is some tips on how to help, not even to, actually, this is what missing, what you are going to talk
about is it's a list of descriptions of how you can mature your quality culture in several different
ways. But what's missing is the guidebook. What are the tips that help you? How do you do that?
How do you, this is nice to read all this stuff, but I'll open this first question up to you,
Percy, is how do you lead a team towards a higher quality culture? You have a guidebook,
but you have some rules, but no guidebook. What do you do?
Personally, for me, based on my own experience, one of the biggest detractors for this is not
really having a shared mindset, that that's really number one. So when we say that something
is something that not everybody agrees on the same definition, I mean, look, the quality itself
is a big question here, but getting everybody in the same spot, we talk about what do you actually
mean when you say regression testing, for example, which is probably an entire podcast on itself and
why that name doesn't really describe what we're trying to do when it comes to performing the set
of testing activities that we have for that, I guess, coined term. So the shared mindset is
definitely key. Getting everybody on a regular basis so that you will continuously communicate,
be able to encourage everybody that, hey, this is not the end all and be all of what you know about
what we're doing. So if you have test specialists, as testers, you have to have the desire to learn
some more and expand that circle of comfortability when it comes to just, okay, I'm just
testing this ticket, like what are the things that will be affected if I don't do this well.
At the end of the day, it's essentially a people problem, right? It's not going to be a knowledge
thing or a process thing, but like how do we get these set of people who you call as your team
members to share that mindset? There's going to be complications around how often people move in
and out of your team or depending on the resourcing model that you have within your company
on how you'd be able to deal with that. But yeah, that's just really the tip of the iceberg on the
challenges that you have with making sure that you have a common mindset on what we actually
think our quality culture is and where we need to be.
What are some things, and I agree. In fact, the definition I use of quality culture,
the first three words are a shared mindset, 100% on board. But how do you do that? What
are some things you can do to help build that shared mindset?
One of the things that we've tried so far has really been setting up a community of practice,
which is really just a fancy way of saying, hey, let's all come together. Let's talk about
something that we've learned, and then we'll break that out into something that we can actually
apply across the board. Or does it open itself up to more questions, more scrutiny? But at least
we're all doing it together. There's definitely going to be a few people who will take over the
conversation in the first few meetings. But as you go along, as everybody realizes that, hey,
this is a safe space for us to be in, to express our concerns, our questions, and encourage them
that, hey, no question is wrong. It's just a matter of you being able to either understand,
why are you actually asking that question? What is the context around why something is important
to you that needs to be broken apart? It puts you in a position where you give up whatever
assumptions you have and declare them on the table.
Yeah, I've been thinking through that while you were talking. It's a fun challenge. It's
a leadership challenge. I think, of course, there's the other things you can do. Just when you see
people do things that are... I'll back up a little bit. Quality culture is a very easy
thing to hand wave about. I've talked with plenty of teams that, yes, we care about quality,
but when you look one level deeper, there's a huge bug backlog. There's
massive amounts of tech debt and customers are angry. Those two things don't align.
You have to get past the hand-waving part and actually get some agreement and some alignment
and that shared mindset and make sure it's really true and do the things like rewarding
the behaviors you want to see and course correcting and realizing it's definitely
a marathon, not a sprint. It takes a while to get that culture. One of the stories I often
tell is how Microsoft got their security culture, which is one of the few examples I can ever recall
where a culture was created via mandate. It's a big bet. It's an expensive bet. It doesn't
always work, but in 2000, at Microsoft, year 2000, Code Red, Slammer, the I Love You virus,
we're all back to back to back exploiting vulnerabilities in Microsoft software.
And the whole company went offline for about a month where we took maybe it was longer.
There was massive security trainings and threat models that across the board and code review
tools or added analysis tools to find these potential, many potential errors. But that
quality culture lives through to today, or that's the quality culture, the security culture
lives through to today. Two completely different things. And I don't know that that worked because
there was a crisis. And usually by the time a company has a quality crisis, it's too late
and they're about to go under. So the challenge with building a quality culture is trying to
build that culture before it becomes an urgent issue. If your customers are all complaining and
you can't even get a build done because the CICD is broken or your build system is broken,
and there's just no way to get the work done, then it's kind of too late to build that quality
culture. You're digging out from the bottom of the hole where it's better to try and kick that
off. When things are running pretty smooth and people go, oh yeah, we're doing well.
You can use that quality culture transition guide to figure out, okay, how can we turn up the
notch? What can we do even better? Right. One of the things I think to be able to rally everyone
towards a particular goal is figuring out what is that shared priority that everybody has.
And that is a very difficult. It's a very elusive thing to deal with, especially when you have
multiple teams or if you have 140,000 employee companies. And that's kind of the need of
rallying point where you can start bringing things up. So let's say if we talk about Agile,
for example, because of the success of folks at Scrum, a lot of the misconceptions now when it
comes to Agile is that Agile equals Scrum and then Scrum equals the rituals.
That drives me crazy. Which is not. And like,
which is probably what was meant when that guy said that when they said
Agile was evolving into CICD, they probably acquitted Agile and Scrum. But anyway, go on.
Right. So at the end of the day, there's definitely going to be multiple, even though,
let's say let's stick to the Scrum context, for example, even if we're reading all the same
Scrum guide, right? Everybody has completely different definitions of or at least interpretations
of what the rituals are for, which one comes first. Now, it's just a lot of chicken and
the egg thing when it comes to like, if you do the rituals often enough, then it becomes natural.
Or the other side too would say, like, do what's natural for you. And then eventually,
it'll seep into kind of your team dynamics. But looking into what that shared priority is,
all of these things will break apart. So this reminds me of a story with,
have you heard of the company called Alcoa? Yes.
Right. And when they had that, probably in the early 90s, maybe, or the early 80s,
when they hired Paul O'Neill as their new CEO, and they were really having some issues
within the company. And what he did was, you know what, everybody cares about safety.
But the thing is, he did not define what safety was. But that became like a rallying call for
everyone else. And then from there, everybody had a direct responsibility to ensure safety
among everybody within their groups. And long story short, it can tuple their valuation,
their income. And they became one of the most respected companies in the world, one of the
safest companies in the world. It's just finding that one thing that everybody can rally about.
Personally, for me, that's still kind of elusive. I have some hints here and there, but
it's something that I do want to be able to bring forward and get some partners to work with
me across all the development centers that we have all over the world.
Yeah, this conversation, I didn't realize it until we've been getting into it,
reminds me of, I just finished reading The Phoenix Project, which is, I don't know if
you've read it yet or not, but it's a story about DevOps transformation. But the company
massive, or having massive quality issues, it's kind of like the story I described before,
they can't get a build out. It takes, even if they can get a build to finish, it takes,
there's approval process that takes forever to get something out. And they talk about how
that transformation works. But you and I have done these things before. I don't think we're either
one of us are particularly bad at them. My one gripe with the book that goes a little bit
too far into the world of fiction is that the transition happens too easily. It's like, oh,
all of a sudden it's CI CD everywhere. And they've remembered dependencies and they're
able to ship stuff all the time. And it's just not that easy. And I don't think it's
particularly hard because the technical part is it's hard enough. One other example is they
rewrote a mobile app and shipped it to customer delight in a week.
If I remember correctly, but mostly it's the people part, the transitional part that
drove me a little crazy. So it really ends up being a leadership problem or a lot of problem,
a leadership challenge. So it leads me to one question as people going through this.
And I think you may have some ideas on it is making this transformation requires a leader
growing your quality culture requires some leadership to do. What are some challenges
you may face if you're doing that like you and I have done within a company versus someone who's
hired as a consultant or a consultant working or someone working across divisions at a company.
What are some challenges that may make that full-time person on the team
more difficult or easier than someone who's visiting the team as a consultant?
Well, it's the idea of permanence, right? Where you kind of don't have that person who will be
like, let me try that in a different way. Just imagine you're hiring a head coach.
That's part-time, right? It doesn't work like where the head coach will only show up on game
day. It's very difficult to kind of force that. And then the learnings that you're supposed to do
as a team throughout the week, that needs to have a more kind of introspective eye of the coach
that gets you, how can we do this better? So the idea of always at the end of the sprint
always at the end of the sprint retrospective kind of gets thrown at the window from a
digital transformation perspective because there's a lot of things that a coach might see that needs
to be addressed right away instead of waiting for that to kind of fester. That can be done when you
have someone that's there and it's focused. A shout out there to the retro, one of the most
important meetings or probably the most important meeting you can have, especially in regards to the
quality culture transition guide because that's where teams have been exposed to that,
that I work with. That's the time we bring that out during retro time. It's like, oh, let's see
what we could do here. We just say anything about this. It's a nice reference during retrospectives.
There's a book, if you've ever read by, I forget his first name Maxwell, called The Five Levels
of Leadership. You've heard of this book? I have not heard of that book. It applies a little bit
here because the first level is you're put in a position of leadership, which means you've been
made a manager. You've been, or in our case, maybe you're the sole dedicated testing specialist.
You're the person who's leading the quality culture. You're in a position,
someone could announce you in that position. You could say, hey, I'm going to try and lead
a source of higher quality culture. You're in a position of leadership. As you know, at that level,
it doesn't give you any rights or privileges unless you're a company that has a very specific
emphasis on hierarchy. But it's that next level where you have to give people permission to let
you lead them. People have to give you permission to let them lead them, let you lead them. God
damn. People have to give you permission to let you lead them. What that means is you don't
just get your leadership by a level. You have to let people know you're there to help and they
accept that you have good ideas. That may be one of the hardest levels to get past. You have to
establish credibility. In Weinberg's Secret of Technical Consulting and in a book called Getting
Naked by Pat Lentione, they're both really good stories. The latter being a business novel like
The Phoenix Project, but much better. Showing how important it is to when you're trying to be
a leader for a team and help them through transition. To be humble, to ask questions,
to not be afraid to ask the dumb questions. Because what that does is that establishes
what it helps you learn, which is the important thing. But it establishes trust. People know that
you're not there just to boss them around. You really do care and you want to help them.
It isn't until you get to that level, you get to level three, which is where you begin to
produce results. Until you as a leader and you can again, much easier being that permanent part
of the team because establishing trust is not something you can do on a sporadic basis.
You have to be engaged. Once the team understands that you're there to help and they want you to
help them, then you can begin to move the team down the path of improving their quality culture.
You have to ping me later the title of the book. I didn't write it.
That would be a good next read for me, which actually does remind me with another
organizational book called requisite organization by Elliot Jack.
I have not read that.
Elliot Jacks. It's interesting because he looks at it in also the same, but this one is in
like seven levels or maybe even eight or higher levels than that, where he breaks it apart into
the amount of time that you have to be able to do your work.
The first level essentially are the people on the ground. Whether you're a sales splurge or
traffic be cop, for example, where your work is mostly routine. Then the second level is
first line managers. From a softer perspective, this would be
probably our leads or maybe senior developers who have more responsibilities, not just from a day to
day basis, but they look at things that need to be done, let's say at the end of a sprint.
Then the next level up is instead of focusing on the deliverables every two weeks,
now you have quarterly deliverables. The next level up would be your directors,
so on and so forth. Your vision can't be enacted up until you have maybe months or for CEOs for
really huge companies. They have years or maybe even a decade to be able to enact on something.
I think the way we look at it, especially from setting that culture, whoever it is that's
assigned for those needs to have a different outlook and make sure that everyone else
underneath the lower levels can also focus on their work and get their work done pretty well.
But you have a larger vision of where you need to be. Let's say if it takes a lot longer to
be enacted on. Tying that back into the Phoenix project, it's almost a typical
fairy tale story where everything is happy ever after. All the individual work that needs to be
done leading up to that point where they can actually release in a more consistent cadence
and they can capture feedback at the level where they can actually act on it.
That's the hard work that we're kind of, hey, instant coffee time.
You're not worried about waiting for your coffee beans to grow and roasting them and grinding them
and you making that cup of coffee type of thing. There's definitely a lot of, I guess, dimensions
that we can look deeper, but I have to get the copy of that book that you just mentioned.
I'll send you some links. It definitely helps. We've talked a lot of the strategic part. We know
it's a leadership issue. We know that it's difficult and it takes time and all those things.
But let's go into some more of the tactical. In helping teams improve their quality culture,
what are some examples of tactical things you've done? How have you addressed
specifically some aspects of improving the quality culture?
One of the first things that I actually almost always do when I get asked to join a given team
is that I ask them for what are the activities that everybody actually does?
So let's take a look at your last release and the contents of what you've released.
How long did it take for that to pass through your pipeline for that to get into the hands
of the customer? Digging deeper into that, then it shows, all right, we're actually spending 15
business days to do user acceptance testing because that's still a thing in my world.
We take a look at what they're actually doing in detail, breaking that down and see if we could
get rid of some of the things that are redundant. Most of the time, there's really very obvious
things that show us why, hey, why does it take you 12 hours to generate all the user data that
you need to be able to perform your tests? Because it's a person doing it and the automation
attempt was employing Allen's favorite tool, which is Selenium, to click through the browser
to create the data. So changing things like that into, you know what, let's talk to the developers.
Maybe there is an API in the backend that creates this data for us and you can just
see the difference where what used to take 12 hours now takes, I don't know, three minutes
to get things done. So this is an example of how the principles overlap and support each other
because it definitely improves the quality culture to get rid of that technical debt,
but you're doing it also by identifying and mitigating a bottleneck in your system.
Right. And then most of the time, because of how busy everyone is on their day-to-day
and the expectations, a lot of these things are just accepted. It's just like, yeah, it's
how things are done. That's the way it's always been. We're going to continue to do it. And it's
usually one of the most, I guess, poisonous things that will happen in any kind of team culture.
And that's what's so important. It's important that this is where you and I and people driving
modern testing can really help out as we don't, we're not good with the status quo. We go,
why couldn't this be better? It's the old fable that I won't retell today about
why the woman cut the ends off her roast beef before she put it in the pan and look it up.
I know you've heard it, you're laughing. But it's a great example of just, this isn't right. How
can we make it better? You have another one? It's really something that is very similar.
I've told this story a lot of times. I'm taking like three shots right away.
When I first joined the company that I'm in, it used to take us 29 days to upgrade a single site.
That includes all the necessary evidences for a company that's under specific
regulations for us to be able to release something. From there, they've been trying for the past
four years on how to get it more efficient with and without automation, with and without
tooling. But they still can't go past that 29 days for a single 29 day turnaround time
to test the site before we can actually push for an upgrade.
And what we realized was really just a ton of redundancy. So I guess you fast, I'm going to
pull a Phoenix project here. Fast forward four years, that 29 days can now be done in
90 minutes. And we can now handle, instead of just dealing with a single site at once,
we're dealing with 600 sites from an operational scale perspective for upgrading.
I think the key there really was all the silent noises in between the handoffs,
a, data creation, b, making sure that the build environment is set up properly, making sure that the
configuration schemas are correct and we're not going back and forth, looking into
more difficult bugs to be able to debug because it's just a flag that everybody ignores. And there's no
kind of sense of static analysis based assertions where we can now check that, hey, is this actually
the last known configuration that everybody kind of blessed and approved saying that this is
actually works. Before that was just all kind of throwing the ether saying, no one's looking at it
because we're too busy dealing with the UI stuff. And the other thing that we did with the UI stuff
was we converted a majority of our tests from Selenium based click things into just replacing
80 assertions of this element present into just a single visual test. So we work closely with
some of the more leading AI based visual comparison tools that's out there. And that really
accelerated a ton of what we're able to do. So now it's not just the testers that are consuming
that information, handing that off to the dev team, but now the product owners are actually
jumping in because we made sure that throughout that approval process, they would be included in it.
If it's a matter of, hey, there's a weird bug that the visual check has captured,
is this actually something that we introduce when we're dealing with internationalization,
for example, across multiple markets, we can't hire every single person that can speak a certain
language, which can be broke. So having something like this, and we can just hand it off to an
auditor or reviewer saying, oh, right, that is an intentional change based on the intent of the
wording that we're really trying to make. So it's an easy, fast way for us to flag certain diffs
and hand that off to the person and the person can easily understand without sitting on it for
days and days. So it's really a whole, I guess it's a whole process fix for us,
for that particular group. Yeah, sounds nice. I think as you were talking, I was also thinking,
we just need a book filled with these stories of how these improvements have been made.
I'm not suggesting writing a book, but I'm just thinking if I talk to you about all these choices,
I talk to my people around Unity where I work and that I've gone through this,
and there's all kinds of stories about how a good low hanging fruit is just going back through the
bug backlog for people that have big bug backlogs and deciding what are we going to fix and what
are we not going to fix? And let's take the bugs that we said we're going to fix,
just fix them now. It's a very freeing thing to free up that just bug tech debt,
but you have some process tech debt you're dealing with as well, getting people to...
I've helped people begin that journey towards collecting data to help understand where
customers are seeing success and failing. And it happens again, that happens slowly.
It isn't overnight, like in Phoenix Project, where you have nothing and the next day,
oh, we have all this wonderful customer telemetry telling us exactly what's going on.
It's like, this is an iterative process that has two steps forward, one step back to get
the right data. It takes a while, but it's worth the effort. All you're just looking at is,
what are we doing? How can we improve? What we use with that transition guide is let you look
at holistically at, I don't know how many there are anymore, eight different ways you can improve
your quality culture, different attributes, areas, and look and see what's going on,
figure out where you're at, figure out what different behaviors or tools or processes your
team could be using. So good examples of that. Here's an oldie, but it's a goodie.
Since you're talking about stories, maybe it's time to put the notion of a beautiful modern
testing book in your backlog. Way in the back of the backlog.
When I was a shout out to Adam Goucher as the editor and one of the contributing authors of
that series, but it puts you in an anchoring position, listening to the stories that everybody
had. You wrote something, Scott Barber's story was actually pretty good as well. It's one of
the things I can remember on top of my head, but it's things that, hey, this is what's happening.
I think this is what you're doing with the ABT 343 podcast is a matter of writing.
Yeah, maybe someday we grow into that where I curate a book like Adam did with Beautiful Testing.
That could work. We'll work out. We need to get some more stories. It'd be great to get some of
these stories of, I forget the name of the company I quoted yesterday in the Slack group,
Mercado, I think it was, who discovered they were doing modern testing before they heard about
modern testing. And I'd love to get those stories as well. Like what happened? How did you get
there? And they're at last seen to some extent do things that are like modern testing. It's
not a thing we're making up, which I've said before, but it'd be fun to gather stories,
people that discovered it without us because we're just there to put a label on it and to
help people that are going, what the hell is going on? My job is changing.
We'll give you a little bit of a map. Lots to do. It has been as always absolute pleasure
talking with you, Percy. These are good stories, fun stuff and a lot for me. And I would expect
for the listeners to chew on or think about. So thank you a ton for being on the show today.
You're definitely welcome. It's always a pleasure. You know what? Just a side note,
it was around this time when I first found out about the EBTesting podcast. And it was really,
I was reading up, scrolling through my Twitter feed and here comes Mike Blarson's list of
must hear podcasts. He had the best description of us.
Yes.
Of the next year. And I downloaded your, that was the first time I was actually picking up
family from California at that time. And it started playing as we were driving out of the airport.
And what you hear is full volume intro of the, that riff that you have in the beginning.
And I had to like turn it down because it was a shock. But then I listened through the ride.
And I guess two of my family members listened through the ride as well for the first EBTesting
podcast that the three of us shared that experience. So it's been like what, four or five years now?
And I do appreciate everything that you guys are doing. And it's grown into something.
And is it okay if I close with a question? Yes, absolutely.
I know we started with defining modern testing as the acceleration of shippable quality.
Has there been any nuances or changes to how you understood that the first time you and Brent
coined that term fast forward to now on what that means to you?
Yes and no. So what's happened to me is like the first, Brent coined that phrase.
This is actually a very good question because Brent coined that phrase.
He said, yeah, this makes sense. Sure. How do we do this? And then we started talking about
very early before we had a name for it, how we wanted to approach quality before we called it
modern testing, which as we all know, nothing modern, not about testing. It's just an antidote
to traditional test last testing methods. But as we talked more and more, and then when I got the
notion somewhere around in the sixties or ish that we should, not the years, the episodes,
that we should have modern testing principles and trying to iterate on those, is that I begin to
realize how much they supported that mission of accelerate the achievement of shippable quality.
What was odd, it was nothing, none of it was consciousness. It wasn't like, okay,
how does principle number two promote the mission? How does principle number three promote the mission?
I didn't even think about them separately. What I did, we did the principles, just trying to capture
all the stuff that Britt and I had talked about and aligned on that we cared about.
And probably what was the interesting part, the insight was that all the things that we
cared and aligned about without even thinking about it directly aligned with
accelerate the achievement of shippable quality. So that was really the bigger insight is that
I thought once the principles were done and we had iterated on them and then we had talked
through all of them and I put together talks on each of them and courses, the farther and the
deeper I got into internalizing what these principles were, what modern testing was,
and why we cared about it, it was just, I can't even call it serendipitous because you knew it
would happen. But the alignment with the mission just was super, I was gonna say supernatural,
that's a different thing. The alignment with the mission was natural and it just happened.
And it tells me that it all is fitting together as it should. And it really just goes back to
the values. We knew this was the right thing. We had talked about it a lot and everything we
had talked about aligned with that mission statement. So it's probably the backward answer
of what you're expecting. We never went back and looked at the mission statement and said,
well, can we make this better? We just left it as it was. Although one of my employees,
and I like this one, Brent doesn't, but she shortens it. One of my former employees,
still at Unity, says, accelerate the delivery of customer value, which rolls off the tongue a
little bit better. And I think it tells the same story. I think it's fine. But yeah,
it's all aligned with, again, what we think, but also what we see going on, which is nice.
It makes it make sense. For me at least, it makes me feel even stronger in
that it's the right thing to be talking to people about and sharing with the community.
Well, thank you.
My pleasure.
I really appreciate that.
That was a fantastic question. All right. We should wrap it up here. I will put your
Twitter handle. You have blog links, books, public appearances. You want to plug at this point?
Ah, Twitter's fine.
All right.
Just keep it simple.
Okay. We'll put that in the notes for the show, get this out in a few days. But
have a wonderful happy holiday, Merry Christmas, and we'll chat with you again in the new year.
Thank you, Percy.
All right. We'll do it. Thank you, Alan.
All right. See you.
All right. Bye.