Welcome to AV testing podcast your modern testing podcast your hosts Alan and Brent will be here to guide you through
Topics on testing leadership agile and anything else that comes to mind now on with the show
Hey Alan, oh wow that was loud
We're back and yeah
108 108 we're so prepared today. Yeah. Yeah we are
So this is the I have a string
for
You probably have noticed if you unless this is your first episode
I have a string of going on three episodes now where I've had something
Go haywire with the audio quality of this podcast on the positive note
Like your setup time today is probably the fastest has been since you've got the new gear. Yeah. Well, I
Actually, I'm getting caught up on my sleep. Maybe I don't know anyway today is the day that I hope the audio is good
So if it is
Send me a thumb send me a taco
you can go to you can go to modern testing org or the podcast hosting this website and
There's a link there to join our slack group
Yes, and in there you can send tacos that you can send tacos. You can also order stickers. I'm behind the sticker
Just remember it. I'll send that out today. Sorry. I
Did know how's the house the house is good. I'm slowly moved in
People I used to have my bookshelves behind me
I do a lot of video calls and my bookshelves used to be behind me and people were upset the
Bookshelves they do my new office configuration that don't work there
But I do have the dog behind me now the dog sleeps on the couch behind me all day
That's pretty our place replace the bookshelves of the dog, which I think is an upgrade
You still doing mostly work from home?
Three days a week right now, but two to three days a week
Actually, it's two days. It was two days this week and I don't plan and it's like oh I'm working from home today
It's like oh I've had meetings since
530 a.m. And now it's noon. I'm not gonna bother going into work. I need that window to drive to work
and sometimes I said meetings back to back and I start early because of Europe and
Sometimes there's some making in but I always go in on
Tuesdays and Fridays and usually there's one sometimes another day I go in this I work. Yes. I work from the office yesterday
Yeah, I got a pretty sweet home office gig at home, but I find
That I can't get work done
Number one
I'm easily distractible in the first place
Number two there are a lot of distractions at home
Yeah, it took me a while. I think it took me a long time of having days working from get used to it
Definitely in the new house. I have a new
An elevated compared to my old house level of production. I'm not sure why I'm getting a lot more done there
especially when the
Media room as we call it with the TV of my Xbox literally across the hall from my home office and
Borderlands 3 is begging me to come play
Yeah, I haven't I haven't even I haven't I so far I have not played Borderlands
Dear before like six or seven at night. So and I have to say
The game is a little buggy. I haven't even I haven't even downloaded it
It's like the first sort of noticeably buggy game I played and I've had since I've started playing it a week or so ago
It's had I feel like a dozen little updates. So it is getting better. I haven't even launched
X
Hell, I haven't even gone into my media room in about a month. Yeah, we want to go dust it. Okay
Anything interesting last thing from my end is
still
We've wrapped up now. I've the modern testing course on ministry of test
It'll be another few weeks to a month before it appears on the dojo
Brent was marveling over my dojo instructor sticker on my laptop. Oh, there you go. So that's why I have that
So excited about that anything with you before we get started
Took advantage of
The
Appliance sales that happens on the last 3d weekend I can I can never remember if it's Memorial or Labor Day
Oh, would you buy I bought a
killer
Samsung
new stove a
New Samsung refrigerator as well as a new Bosch dishwasher
Oh
We have a Bosch dishwasher and I have and and this is the appliance portion of the a Bt
Because now I have opinion. So which boss did you get?
The expensive one. I don't right we have an expensive Bosch in our new house. It's nice. It's silent 44 decibels
But it is nothing compared is a downgrade from the melee we had in our old house. Oh, sorry. You should have moved it
I I thought about I I thought about going back to get it
We and I took advantage of a appliance sale a while back I have become
Maybe I'm not sure at what stage of having teenagers has happened probably to everyone
But I have become one of those people that has a second refrigerator in their garage. Oh
I've been in that place since
In that place since I had a you know shortly after I purchased a house
Yeah, it is great. It is actually it's not even full but it's good just to have it
But the drama this time around is I for for a period of an hour. I had three
But I sweet talked the guys who delivered the last refrigerator to take the the lesser of the three away
So I didn't have to pay, you know
some random person to
Either two hundred dollars if you pay some random person to come and pick it up
They're gonna charge you an arm and a leg these guys did it for free
My reef my raising a refrigerator. Yeah
So is it the time where you can knock on the outside shows to us inside?
It's gonna knock on the outside. I can show you on the inside of my refrigerator
right now
The internet oh, yeah, cuz I put my washer and dryer my new washer and dryer on on our internet a few weeks ago
So it can tell me what loads are done
Yeah, it's weird and it's it's kind of like high-tech meets old people because we're talking about appliances here on a yeah
I there you can organize that a lot better. Oh, and here's the thing. Here's one thing that's cool
Doesn't really work well for the podcast
But for say like this thing. Yes this thing. Oh
Damn it. I can't do it on this one
Brent's pointing at his phone
All right. I sought to work through it. But there is a there is one of these damn apps a lot
allows me to bring crosshairs and say that thing I
either needed order a new one of these or
that one expires in end days or
All sorts of things this hooks up to to Google home
And then once you get up to Google home, obviously you can use
IFFT or
FTT or my FTT is the property. Yeah that one or Zapier. We're not we're not married either
in recently I dropped about
$400 on
Phillips hue
lighting for the media room
That you haven't been in in a month that I yeah, but
Literally, I I
Finished that purchase and installed it all like a week before
School started that's the main reason why I haven't got a mini room. I don't have the time
But at first when I thought I'm like why why everyone into this Phillips hue thing it's who cares
Hey, oh, it's cool
Alright, when you hook it up. Yeah, yeah to Xbox streaming and you can have whatever is on your Xbox
Have your room match the colors
It's cool when you're playing minecraft and you go underwater. The whole room is underwater. Not just the screen. Yeah
That may happen. I'm digging. I don't play a lot of minecraft, but whatever I'm digging I'm digging the IOT world
Okay, you need IPV6 for your house to get enough personal addresses through stuff
Just saying yeah, not yet. Yeah, so should we have something about?
Oh
Software, I guess we kind of a software. How about we talk about that not yet. So the other we're not ready
Okay mesh network. Do you have was pressing 30 seconds 30 seconds faster?
Come on you guys get there
Realize that I have gone through and in the last two months. I have seriously upgraded
The electronics of my house so mesh networking mesh network. Do you have one of those course? Okay?
Which one do you have Evo? Okay, I have the deco
and
OMG
Those things are awesome. Yes. All right now I'm done
Yeah, so and I thought I would hate like I've had the traditional router forever where I can go in and control and tweak everything
And on my deco the TP link echo for those of you looking it up
Just get an app with a handful of those settings, but actually it's everything I need to do
I can assign static IPs. I can it has some built-in stuff so I can I use the parental controls
Mm-hmm, that shut off my kids internet at a particular time
Question I get at least once a week dad. Can I have 15 more minutes of internet? I need to do some work
Oh really? What is it you need to do?
Research what research video
Good night. Good night
Beat it kid. Oh
Yeah, so
Been there done that we should have been there done
We have an all tangent episode once where we never actually got to anything, but that's not today. No, don't shut it off
Yeah, we have things I might have I might have the only episode in the last three months where there's not awful sound
Yeah, the the parental controls
So my daughter doesn't have anything I'm worried about yet and she's still too young my oldest
Has finally gotten through the hump
but there was times where
Not only was the internet
I
Did so many things number one?
Most most of the wireless routers offer the ability to do a guest network. Okay, I
I
Dedicated the guest network to him
gave a separate
Account and it's because my router at that time allowed me to remotely turn off and on the guest network
So anytime my wife sent me a text going oh my god, this kid's driving me nuts. My response was off
And
But that kid is a smart kid
and
And he's kind of has a hacker mentality like his dad and he'll find a way to work around it. So it
at
Some point in time I was creating mechanisms and chasing. Okay. How is he connecting the internet this time?
Okay, that one's gone. How about this time? Okay, that one's gone. How about this?
Yeah, but that's over
Okay, cool
So is this an all-male bank show?
Yeah, no, we just spent half hour doing tendons
By the time I edit it, it'll only be 10 minutes. Yeah. Yeah
Okay, should we have some mailbag questions? Is that correct? We do
I'll start while Brett looks up his phone. No, I got it. Oh, you got it. Okay. Go ahead
One of our listeners on the slack channel asked
This is kind of connected to a question. I wanted to ask
Oh, yeah out of context. I think Alan's gonna bring us bring the context in
I don't know what I'm doing. I'm just bored. I'm playing some video games over here. Let me know you know
This was the okay. Go on from what brain was saying
I got the impression that all Microsoft teams to move moved to the unified engineering work model
But from what I hear not you
Yeah, not true
him
We've talked about this before we have yeah
But what I hear from my friends working in Microsoft in Prague that developer tester model is still there and they are
Even unaware that in USA you work differently
When I pointed them to your article on the subject. It was the first time they had learned about it
So my question is is what is the adoption rate of unified engineering model in Microsoft?
Well, if you go by and this is by three coming up on three-year-old data if you go by address book information, it's 100%
Well, no, I'm not percent what I what I what I left
if you looked in the
They ever replace head tracks anything better
So you looked in the the employee tracking the employee HR system
There were I think I saw two or three people with the the word test in their title. Mm-hmm
out of
at the time
25,000 30,000 engineers care member here here in Redmond
The only teams that I know of that still have a
QA
element
Similar to what we would have done in the traditional world are those in the hardware space
and what a little different yes, and what they're validating is
essentially the
That the hardware that we were just delivered
is
Meeting standards before we start applying but but but but but let me let you all in on a little secret
Facebook even years before Microsoft made this move or that we don't have testers were able to test our own stuff and
Facebook like Microsoft
employees a whole lot of
Contract testers and not full-time in the address book, but there are
thousands and thousands of
testers dedicated to testing Microsoft products paid as contract employees not as full-time employees
Yes, but the unified
engineering adoption and again, I'll say in in in Redmond
By payroll cost by headcount by any of those measures is not only the dominant situation
It is by far the dominant situation. Yeah, it's odd to me
I'm not sure about the teams in Prague or I'm not sure how they're set up or how they could be
So separated they would not have heard of this before. It seems weird
Here I think the three years time difference has made you forget one of the more common things
that is rampant in Microsoft and that is not invented here and
one of the
easiest ways to
To continue to support a culture of not invented here is
To make sure you don't talk to any other team
True, but those satellite teams tend to work with other teams like my like when I was on teams
It had a chunk of the team based in Prague
Did they yep? Okay, cuz I was about to say I don't even I didn't even know we had a development sub in Prague
This leads into I think I don't know this shows up in the mailbag or not
This leads into a video that came out in the last couple of weeks by a youtuber
slash
Former Microsoft employer named barnacles. That's not his real name. I don't know what his real name doesn't matter
Where and Brett hasn't watched the video
I watched it because I had a bunch of people point me to and say Alan
What do you think of this and the gist of the article is this guy is a pretty good speaker
yeah, he has a reasonable following on YouTube and
he's
as I mentioned former Microsoft tester on the Windows team and
his basic premise is
Windows 10
These is getting buggier and buggier and every release is like we're stepping over a
minefield of bugs and
this is because Microsoft laid off all their testers for Windows and
they should hire a test team back to bring back quality and
One of those statements is true and two of those statements are false
I would say one is half true. Maybe one is half true
Well, and and even in its explanation of the and it's hard because I've been away for a while
So I have to make stuff up
Let's kind of go through that I can bring I can bring in some details to catch you up
You'll feel like you've watched the video. So let's start with the first question
And this has been a great one to have Steve Rowe here, but I think you would have hand waved a little bit
I don't know Steve. Let us know chime in on slack
is
Windows 10
Buggier is it does it have a bug or a quality problem and you don't work on Windows?
I know you probably don't want to answer in case any hi in case soft you listen to our podcast, right?
So I don't know the answer to that question
Steve Rowe definitely
would
And again, I'm not certain that he would
share it. I do think that that there is a
So I mentioned half I do think it's a half truth, right so
It did absolutely start when Microsoft got rid of their testers
What that organization did not do? Oh
Did you want to leave there? No, no, no, I know I know where you're going. Okay, you went right where I thought you would which is great, right?
What they did not do is something that Alan and I have
Talked about a lot of times Alan said told or shared this guidance
I don't know 30,000 times on stage
what the
You know the underwear gnomes
No, have you heard of the underwear? No, okay
so South Park
They they have these characters called the underwear gnomes and the problem that the underwear gnomes have
Is everyone goes to Amazon and others to get their shoes so they don't need gnomes to make magical shoes anymore
So they realized that they need to come up with a new business proposition
Okay. Now what they learned is
They have a three-step plan
Okay, and they had an idea and the first step is they're gonna go steal everyone's underwear
Okay, and they have the last step of the plan
Massive profit, so they're gonna start by stealing everyone's underwear
And that's gonna deliver massive profit now. The problem is
They don't know what step two is and even on their advertising the step two is a question mark
but this is actually a very good analogy it is metaphor go on but
Even without knowing what step two is that they have a clear step one
So they can start executing that while you know the the brain ear gnomes I guess figure out
What step two is that connects the dots between ceiling underwear and massive profit?
to me I
Use the underwear gnome metaphor a lot
It's not just at Microsoft
Microsoft because it's a pattern of behavior I see all of the time
It's just a huge amount of confidence that oh, yeah once we start this we'll figure out a way to connect the dots to to the goal
Some of those situations in fact succeed
Some of those situations don't and
And I would say with because I was there for the transition in Windows and I want to correct a bunch of
misstatements in the video
I'm sure we'll have a fraction of the listeners a tiny fraction of the listeners is this podcast has have watched the video but
so what I saw being on the front lines as transition to Windows was
One they did not lay off all the testers they
There was a time when they merged Xbox Windows phone and Windows into one big org
And there was some redundant people that were laid off
And there's some good people laid off there. I I
Fully on board that did out lay off the whole testing
but what they did was took the whole test team and said you're the data and
Quality team or something they put people into new rules or your developers
so they dissolved the testing more than laid them all off and then
The sort of the question mark happened and you could say there's a strategy that and I kept on going back and forth between thinking
there's no plan here big just a question mark and
maybe there's just letting a thousand flowers bloom and this is where I saw to his credit Steve Rowe just latch on to data science and
then go from someone who was
Definitely where there was a point in time where I think I knew more
About data science and Steve Rowe it lasted about a minute
And then he got excited about it, and then now is full-on like figured out how to make this work
so the thousand flowers blooming thing happened, but I feel like
There was a plan missing there as well, so I'm not sure quite the balance there, but anyway go on
Oh, so what I saw what I saw over and over again at Microsoft at that time
was
You could completely remove the test team
But then there was a complete assumption
well, then of course dev is gonna do the right thing and pick up the slack and
That was the assumption that I saw over and over again as
false
because
As many people want to call it a point point out when we bring up MT
But Alan and Bryn dev doesn't want a test. Yeah, that is absolutely true and
That is why we pulled in principle seven as part of MT is
It's the right thing for the business
We need to figure out strategies
to to succeed
Even though they don't want to
So I've yes, and now I want to get into the points of the barnacles video
Which are I hope go not only disagree with butter, but I flat out wrong
So I think he does have an argument that
There is more buggy behavior in the recent builds of Windows than maybe they were in the past. I
Disagree completely that having bringing back a test team to be test buddies
Is the right way to do it? In fact, let me talk about a few things. He says from my memory, which as no is bad
He said believe it or not
Testing needs to be there to be the gatekeepers. In fact, we called ourselves that we were the gatekeepers of quality
Oh my god, that triggered you
That's pretty much that might be a slight paraphrase pretty much
He did say we were called the gate we called ourselves the gatekeepers that well, that's the wrong way to do it
so he went off a few different times on dump files and and
I feel like he didn't understand them completely but he talked eloquently about them
But he said we get these mini dumps which we do from crashes and they don't have all the information
So what I do is a tester is I would look at the mini dump and I would debug it and make sure I figured
I'd make sure I get the developer at all the information they needed to figure out the right way to fix the bug and
They need someone to do that and I'm thinking do you did they also need someone to bring them their coffee in the morning
And lunch in the afternoon
It's like why are they unable to do that? He went off
for a while on these this codependency we've talked about how but it's weird because
Is it centering for me because these things we talked about as being inefficient?
he saw as
Necessary in order to generate quality and I use the word generate there purposely because it's really a big story about how
This video still with things about how the test team is necessary in order to test quality into developers crappy code
That was essentially his
So the story went from Windows 10 is buggy
The right way to do that is to have a bunch of people who do developers work for them
So it's less buggy. He even brought back the fact of you to bring back all the UI automation that
Windows 10 had
It's really like that and
And it's the one of these things like let's harken back to the old days when things were much simpler and easier
and so the solution to if a new problem pops up because of moving forward the answer is
Not always or rarely I wouldn't say never
Rarely to move backward if I deploy a bug to production
Yes
I want to roll back if I make a process change if I make a bet on doing things
Differently because I think it'll help my business proud principal one our priorities for the business and I screw it up
I may want to fix forward versus roll back and in this case
Yeah, I'm as you can tell I am one million percent against the idea that
Hiring a test team is the right way to
Fix any perceived or real bugs in Windows quality
Now and so in generic advice, right is
if
You realize you pulled the trigger too soon, right?
And and I'm not saying if Windows did or did not but there are multiple teams that I have observed
And were involved in where I felt oh
That team absolutely pulled the trigger too soon
Sure. Do you solve?
critical quality
Issues with the dollar sign
absolutely
Were I in a strategic role on those teams? Sure. I would go I would spend
The necessary money on vendor dollars to bring things up to speed
But now without a plan that was proactively communicated
around when these guys are going away and my expectations of the of
The people who will be left behind
See you would start with why I?
Absolutely. Yeah, and that's that's super important organizational change and I and that I don't want to I I don't want to be yet another
Microsoft employee harping on why Microsoft sucks and
You do that well already
I do want to mention that the issues with updating from build to build on
Windows are what drove me away from using Windows
Sure. So it there are issues there
And I think the end in my experience was you know being at Microsoft my bills were updated much more often
my experience was that
It's been over a year since I've used Windows, but my personal experience was yes quality did go down. I have I
have similar
similar
complaints on a broad aspect
I have no proof of this
But I do except for this is the thing that drives me the most nuts nowadays and I do feel like
UI design has taken a hit
right at the
Teams your your old product. Yep. Okay, it does weird things
with microphones
Like it didn't just pick up the default OS microphone
And apparently the only time I can go and change the microphone is when I'm on a call
And I'm like what the hell?
Right in you it has a settings button and
That you go to that one you click the settings button and it takes you to oh
Here's a whole bunch of apps you can install for teams. I'm like
Why is that not a downloads apps button?
How is that settings?
No, where do I change the goddamn microphone for this product?
The because I happen to have one of I got a new computer and the new computer
Is a desktop, but it's I don't know why companies still build these but it's one where the desktop has an integrated microphone
Who the hell uses that what the hell who the hell uses that nobody? No, no, buddy
That well, let me tell you the challenges
Of course that I guess they want to add it because it's ten cents
But I hate to do this in the context this conversation
But the integrated microphone on my MacBook is actually very very good. I use the one
shocking
Very shocking. It's the the MacBook microphones are very very good. I have a Lenovo
And I do conference calls and I'd say no one complains
Yeah
In fact if you I was on the test and code podcast maybe three months ago
Yep, if you listen to that my entire audio is recorded off of my MacBook microphone
Yeah, so just saying anyway go on
Where were we when it occurred and
Like I don't know when that article came out
The the one with the video that you're talking about. Oh just within the last few weeks. Yeah, okay
So that would be the latest example
When they were going through the transition I heard all sorts of dev and testers fighting it
Three years later I'm aware of devs devs coming to insane we need to do this
And I would say
to
Microsoft's credit most of those teams those requests have been denied
In in steel to bring back testers, yeah, okay, and I had a good finish then I want to build on that story the
Steve would do would do a much more detailed
job I
Guess the nice thing though is the fact that you and I are not on the teams
And don't know much about it except for the people we talked to it
Reduces our risk of or at least my risk of exposing an NDA
right and and to be fair an operating system is very complex and
It's the hardware ecosystem the fact that that PCs can contain a
Virtually infinite or combinatorial infinite number of
Combination of devices makes things difficult. I know how I said that right but
And if you look at Microsoft's main customers, which are corporations
They tend to buy a lot of the same PCs for all their employees. They get a much higher success rate
It's I think it's tough on the home user though. Well, and the other thing so I
Will say I am
Pro Satya I
Very say I'm too. I'm very supportive of the direction. I like I didn't leave because of him. I
Like that. He is taking a proactive
stance I felt
Bomber spent most of his time trying to defend a position and
When you when you need do that
It
Makes it just so much easier for a small upstart to come from nowhere and take your market, right?
I
Told this story before
Ten years ago or so. I was having discussions with a manager of mine and
They were like, oh
We own the OS market and we will forever
because we have
18 quadrillion lines of code and it is so complex and
Company like Android OS is my favorite example here. It came from nowhere
to dominance and it's because of
They took a service service mentality to deploy it
so
Barna Cleese or whatever the guy's name is
If we want to go back in time, there is one point in time where I'll agree
If we're gonna go back in time, we need to go back in the time before services existed and
Never create service and never create services and then everything he's saying is correct. But until then there's going to be
companies
Like that that were that that approaches ludicrous so I have two stories to tell
One is I was in a
some leadership training at Microsoft
15 years ago and there was a since retired air quote retired VP of
In I think he was in networking
But he was talking about this same thing as OS dominance and dad
I did it up and this is just the time the Chromebook was announced but not out yet
But I asked I said my question was pretty much along the lines of
The way I work today given the fact that
An information worker can work largely in a browser all day long
Do you see a need for Microsoft to compete with a lighter weight OS that?
Focuses on the browser experience basically I said should we have a Chrome should we have a Chrome OS competitor and his answer was
It's like the spinal tap answer, but our apps go to 11 says but why would you want that when you couldn't have windows and play games, too?
So that's not the point and they just kind of double down on well, I can play games in the browser
His whole line of questioning this whole line of answers to me were but we can do more with Windows
Yes, it's true, but you can
When you're trying to increase market share you have two options you can go after someone else's market share or
Like the smart people do go grab market share that hasn't been grabbed yet
Or create a new market or create a new market. Yes, which is kind of the same thing
the the other so that that happened that was yet another brick in the wall of my
my long exit
But the interesting story is now I don't fast-forward this to last week
When I had a conversation, maybe it was this Monday. I had a conversation with someone on my in my org
at Unity
Where we have I
Wouldn't call him a tester
I have someone who is a sort of a test coach testing quality coach for an entire half of the team
I think I want to hire someone else to do the other half of the team
I think it actually works out really well to have someone float and help and coach and not do all the work
And I think that's a right way. I think it's like it aligns MT very well
I need that coach there
But anyway, they said their question was I think we need to hire a test team and they thought I would be oh great
I can build my empire and hire testers and I told them why they were wrong
They said but but but but but and which is gonna dovetail into our next question a little bit maybe
But my answer the answer was no and then it was no and they said but but what about we have to
For this particular part. We need to test across
60 different phones and this and I said great
We have
Bit bar we can use for that. It goes no, no, no we can use for something. Okay. Okay
There's a little bit of stuff
We need to spot check on each of the phones and make sure things we have to do we need eyeballs on it
I'm not against eyeball testing and not I'm not in the automate everything camp. So it's okay. Cool. Cool
That's the perfect thing to hire out. I would not hire a test team a full-time tester to come in and check
the not to
degrade
Offshore teams or even even near store teams that do this manual verification
I would even give them narratives and do some exploratory testing for us, but I would definitely contract that workout and
They didn't once I kind of explained that view
there was
Right now this is just Monday. There's the the reaction was somewhere between yeah, of course you write Alan and and
Well, let me ponder that a little bit. They're sort of thinking about that
I think that makes sense to them. But anyway, that just happened. So I am NOT hiring a test team
However, I'll probably hire one kind of senior coachable tester in San Francisco. Hey three
At some point in the next few months. But anyway
Did you have more on barnacles? Did you want to dovetail this into the next mail bed question?
Yeah, look we can we can go in the next mail
Like and I if I remember I'll link the video it should be easy to find
I think it was shared a whole bunch of times. He makes a joke about the video going viral
I think it actually did sort of go viral
But
Yeah, it's worth checking out
Only to get your own only to build your own opinion versus the one I've created for either
It it is human nature
to resist
change
The the thing like as you talked about right a long term
long term
I mean, I'm this is not the prediction episode
No that comes up in another few months, but as you talked about right
You can do a lot with just the browser alone
Will there be a concept of a universal cloud OS?
Where maybe whatever limitations browsers have get fixed
The cloud is growing the cloud is not gonna go away and
Well what we're observing is
What people want is compute?
Not anything underneath it. Why do I even need to know there is hardware in today's world?
Right in what we're finding is is that so you can play games friends
I don't need to know that so it for those who have studied object oriented design
Right what we're seeing is is
Encapsulation even in the compute space and it continues to grow right
Microservices everywhere is going to be a thing that happens
Right, and then you hook that up to IOT or right? I am more worried about
Things just magically happen and no one knows why anymore
because they we
Humans just don't have the ability to pay that much attention to the complexity
And if we have individual teams deploying these small little widgets and and we have millions of teams and millions of widgets
Right it just to me feels like it gets a little bit closer to
Magic I was talking with my daughter just yesterday and
She's super excited about her having her phone
And she was asking about laptops and phones and right now Samsung 10 are actually
They're making a statement that their phones can be used
in a place of a laptop and viable a
Make a
phone with a terabyte of storage
I'll essentially
in memory
Right, that's I mean if you can deal with the the small form factor
You're good to go. Yeah, and interesting
I do want to get to the next question in our last 10 minutes or so here, but I built a new
home computer maybe coming up on three years right when I left Microsoft and
on your recommendation I got
The what do they call the m1 m2 m2 drive? Isn't that thing cool? It's cool
I've also got an SSD. I figured okay, I should I feel like I need a gig of
Storage a gig a terabyte. Thanks
512 m2 and a 512
SSD I
Forget I have the SSD because the 512 m2 is more than enough
I just don't have enough stuff that I store and this is I started syncing my Google drives
To my box as well. I just don't store that much stuff on I don't keep them any artifacts locally
Right because you have it, you know used to be
You're adding
You have your computer for a year you add another hard drive to it
You keep on adding storage till you have this massive storage and I remember doing this for years
I just don't need as much anymore. The only reason why I have
storage on my box at home because I do the same thing I'm like
Hey, if I just load it up to to one drive
I have a lot more confidence
that
That's gonna be protected and secured and backed up than I do if I did it manually
Yeah, because I hate doing it and I'm lazy. Yeah, I have rule of three for backups. So we have a
server at home a NAS server which is backed up continuously to
Actually Amazon I pay for carbonate
so Amazon is Prime members at 60 bucks a year for a terabyte and that's
I say just under that because photos are free
Then first stuff I have my entire CD collection over CDs
Ripped to flak which is lossless audio and that's all backed up to Glacier storage. I pay a dollar a month for that
dollar 50 maybe
Yeah, it's just there for like I don't want to re-rip them all again, but I want so it's I spend
$15 a year just to make sure never have to re-rip my entire CD collection. So I have about
Three thousand CDs in boxes sitting underneath my bed and I have
No idea what I'm gonna do with these things. Yeah, I mean
The hundred dollar a year Spotify subscription. I'm good. Yeah, it is
Shall we call not ripping these things I'm not playing them. I don't know what to do
All right. We'll do go to the next time. So I do want to get into the second question. Let's do it briefly here
So can you read the question?
The questions long we have 10 minutes. I'll summarize it. That's that's what I hoped. Okay, can you summarize the question? I meant to say hi
Alan. Hey, how's it going? I am fine. Thank you. I
Work for a QA agency. I'm all aboard on MT
But ultimately I go to my clients and they say that's great
Here's a bunch of test cases. Please go automate them
So the question is is how do I apply MT in that scenario?
That's an excellent question. It is so anyway, we're out of time
It'll generate more questions we can talk about yeah, no, let's let's do it. I'm kidding
Yeah, no, I think it's it's tough because you're getting paid
In a situation like that you're getting paid to do what?
The customer wants you to do if they tell you that you need your job is to go
Clean their bathroom. I guess you do it or you quit the same thing with
Please run all these test cases reminds me again going back to my first day at Microsoft when
My manager gave me an Excel spreadsheet full of these UI test case these test cases
I said great when you need these automated because oh, no, we don't have time to automate
You just need to run these every day. So I automated them anyway
My first act of defiance at Microsoft took about two days and I never stopped but in this situation
I think it's tough because on one hand
There's what the customer wants versus what they need and obviously you can't go in there and say no
I'm not gonna run your test cases. I'm going to transform your organization into the 21st century
That's not what they want to hear
But I would say and I sure you have some ideas as well is sure you go you go do that testing
But you start doing some things that enable
The growth of the quality culture and maybe that may be quality culture is where you start with principle
Number four is where you start in a row click. This is you do the testing but you talk when you go
Deliver the bug to the developer as barnaclay's is talking about as with some huge awesome thing
You have a conversation about so cool. Do you want to?
Do you want to pair up on fixing it? Do you want to pair up on testing it when you have the fix ready?
Can we talk about how we could have prevented this? What do you think we should do differently?
Think we could add tools and see I should we have a CI system?
That'll make my job easier because then you guys would find these bugs what test Oh my favorite question ask the developers
When they say like you please test this for me if they were to say that to me, they're not that stupid. I would say
What tests have you already run and just to get those conversations going say no, it's your job
Well, actually no, my job is different. I would say it's even as a QA agency is look I
Can't come in here and find all your bugs for you. It's not gonna scale that way
I'm gonna find the bugs that you can't find. So let's look at this as a bandpass filter
So there's a bunch of bugs that you are more suitable and more able to find
I'm not gonna be your safety net. I'm not gonna be your
It's we're gonna be more efficient. We're gonna have a better relationship
We're gonna deliver higher quality software together if you find the bugs that you're capable of finding and over time as we work together
You're gonna get better at that
But for now
Let's talk about what testing you're going to do and then I can figure out how to build on that and make sure we deliver
A high quality product together. I would have a conversation kind of like that and see
Where that builds to and obviously it's gonna go in one of ten thousand different directions
it is interesting given like the
They're in a contract position
but
the
Specific scenario I think is actually something we spent a good amount of time in the same episode talking about
in cases of crises, that's that's
appropriate so
this particular person said
Their scenario. I don't know if this is real or just
Hypothetical but their scenario was
Their company or him were being hired
To convert manual test cases to automate
All right, that is one of the levels of hell I think
It is
But let's let's do it this way
startup company
Right it the the the role of a startup is to find a stable business plan before the money runs out
Right and so one of the first things
Why I'm not saying it's right or wrong, but one of the first things that's going to be abandoned in
In a situation like that if you're out of time
You're gonna go the quick path. You're not gonna not gonna invest in automating the test cases. You'll run them
But you're not going to invest in automating them
the
and again
Probably the wrong thing to do
But it seems like a time-saving cost at that moment
And it's primarily because people don't really pay attention to all the missed bugs that they're now having to fund
instead of writing new features I
Am perfectly okay that once you realize you have that as technical debt and that is actually bottle necking you
I'm perfectly okay spending money to buy it down
There's a technique to I mean my read my my
Hell reactions because not all air quote manual tests can be air quote automated
That's it's a different is a test design problem
There may be a bunch of tests set. Yes, we could automate these
There may be a bunch of tests like no actually it makes sense to have eyeballs on these
we should not we should make sure we just do a little sanity walkthrough or
Realize it's never going to break and not run those tests at all
And there's another group of tests like maybe we need just write a diagnostic tool that will tell us what's going on
that would highlight issues that happen like this, but take a list of
Test cases that are scripted and to automate them is I think more often than not a fool's errand
Here's or at least approached blindly. Here's what I would do
Here's my answer to that question in what I would do in that person's shoes and
Generalizing what you just said, okay?
So I'm being hired and being paid to do a job. I will do that job. Okay, but I
Will write up
at some point when I have sufficient knowledge I
Will write up a
proposal that would very much align with MT
Titled
Here's the things that in in the process of doing work that I learned and
and I'm now going to give you as
Recommendations because you're my client
For the explicit purpose to making it harder for you to have to make the decision to hire me or someone like me
It's a tough thing to do as a consultant because or as a contractor because you're coming in you're hired to solve
Earlier I said how I'd use contractors to solve a short-term problem, but you're coming in to solve a short-term problem
But you want to also give them a long-term solution
and
In this particular case, even if you were in a QA agency
I
Would do that because it would positively impact my brand with that company or every other client I have
They go so they I would officially turn myself into the Mary Poppins of QA
That might even be the name of the company if it's not trademarked. I'm sure it's trademark
Alright, so we will we will we will dig into this later as more questions come up
But hopefully I can get this released and the sound doesn't suck
All right. Good chatting with you Brent and you Alan. All right