Welcome to AV testing podcast your modern testing podcast your hosts Alan and
Brent will be here to guide you through topics on testing leadership agile and
anything else that comes to mind now on with the show hey Brett hey Alan it's a
podcast time is it I've pressed early I've pressed all the appropriate buttons
I think you were clipping a little and now we can go hey never mind going fine
it's always interesting and and you know how you get a bias when you have some
knowledge about something and you assume that everyone has the at least basic
knowledge of what you're talking about yes like I can fake it with statistics
you've heard me fake it I have you cannot fake it with audio no there's
probably some things like you do is it is it jujitsu which martial art do you do
take one though take one though sorry I know nothing you could talk to I have
zero knowledge there's no basic knowledge other than I can sort of
pronounce Taekwondo you did that quite well thank you very much
so I didn't do it well so you're saying you got two out of the three words
correct welcome to the A B testing podcast where Alan and Brent were the A
and B and A B testing will guide you through whatever as you can tell comes
to mind right so perhaps semantics so shall we get on with the what's what's
going on should we do topics right away and freak people out some people just
skip through the first 10 minutes of the podcast waiting for us talking about
something interesting yeah yeah so I took a brief trip to Sweden I saw you saw me
in Sweden I saw a video of you in Sweden oh oh you want that I only watched the
first half of it because at the same time we had I think his name is yao yao
do a presentation I don't know there's the the three least two of the three oh
the 343 podcast you did with Dave lots going on in the world of A B testing
it's like a whole corporation no for sure except we the we don't make any
money and I'm I'm sure the surprises you I am vastly more interested in what
the three have to say than what you do yes you should you should and so I went
to or dev and in Sweden flew into Copenhagen took the train probably one
of the best run conferences ever I bet that I've been to this is a devops this
is your first DevOps it's not a dev it's a developer conference okay there was a
testing track but the testing and quality track but there weren't really
many testers there but let me get there quality the number of speakers the
quality of speakers it is a huge conference imagine I don't know how
many people were there but my room had a hundred ish people in the testing
quality track people like like Jez humble you know Jez one of the authors
of accelerate and the author oh yes absolutely he was also a speaker there
a track speaker okay so on the day of my talk I showed up early outside go I'll
go to the keynote I'll check out my room first make sure I know what it looks
like I'll go to the keynote I go to the keynote I'm going I hadn't looked at
the really looked at the program in advance I wonder who they got here and
what they're gonna talk about and I don't know if you were ever read the
book everybody lies good book on data he oh wait this is the author that did
a whole bunch of when Google made their search data public he did a massive
amount of research and found really really high correlation between search
for racial racially derogatory terms and Trump voters found out that far more
people search for porn that admit minute anyway he was the morning
keynote speaker okay so that I have not read it but that is one of the many
books that I have purchased and is sitting in a stack that I'm hoping to
absorb the knowledge through osmosis brief tangent I also have this problem
of buying books that I don't get to read I've been I was really good for a
long time a little bad right now about four or five behind not too bad one
thing I've started to do to rather than buy the book but to hold a
placeholder for it is I do like the Kindle thing where I haven't sent me
the first chapter for free and that's sort of the placeholder when I'm around
this is I can read this chapter maybe but maybe by the time I actually get
around to reading it may not be relevant anymore so that's my new plan oh
so you so you load the first chapter in your Kindle it's sort of a placeholder
and it ends up being like a to-do list yes exactly right and then you go oh
and if I ever actually read chapter one yeah I like this strategy so that that's
what I do anyway or dev great conference I had a good time with my
talk the recordings available I watched part of it I've never really watched my
speaking much but I actually I'm curious what people have to say about it
because I created a presentation where I would I was planning to adapt it
depending on the audience and their experience so if I were to give a talk
on modern testing principles and and how they've been used to the three I would
go a lot I would not go much into explaining the principles but I would
dive into all kinds of examples and examine some of the controversy and go
on and on and on in this room there were maybe one or two people that had
heard of the modern testing principles so now we have more people to know
about them there's also maybe 90 plus percent of the audience were developers
and what I found is the development audience were very very accepting of
modern testing principles because they're not that much about testing or modern
and you didn't get to the end but one I'm just gonna get I'm gonna get one
little spoiler because somebody asked and the inevitable question should
testers be able to code and where Brent would say yes I said it certainly helps
and and then I elaborated as I do and I said something something to the effect
of and they should but if you know how to code you can use that to write tools
to help you do testing I wouldn't spend that time writing automation and then
the next person said I have a question did you just say did you just say testers
shouldn't write automation and my answer was yes that is correct but I'll
elaborate because now I know you want me to but it was it was perfectly set up I
love that question anyway good conference I ended up I went to a big chunk of the
conference on Friday the day I presented also I arrived on Wednesday didn't go to
anything out there too late Thursday I went to a few talks ended up working a
lot from my hotel room had a bunch of stuff going on one other tangent is
Netflix does not have Brooklyn 99 in the US okay but every time I go out of
the country it's available on Netflix for me to watch so I watched a lot of
Brooklyn 99 from my room and then I downloaded a bunch to watch on the
plane on the way back I can still watch the downloaded ones that I downloaded in
Europe but I can't download anymore while I'm here so it's like I have to
drive to Canada or something why is I don't know licensing deals I'm not
involved in Brooklyn I'm not involved in Amazon's licensing deals Netflix Amazon
whatever it's a it's a fluid download thing also of interest is Disney Plus
are you signing up for that no I'm not neither am I and I've heard and I've
heard it matter it really I've heard it said kind of a hot mess I think it'll be
a matter of time before I will feel obligated I'm not sure I will ever feel
obligated for that so I'll just I'll just ask one question yeah Marvel or DC
Marvel right and I think that closes it eventually yeah but what if I already
own all the DVDs yeah even then that doesn't block it five ten years from
now they'll be like a way for you to play your DVDs you're right and actually
I own digital copies most of those but anyway one thing was interesting I want
to elaborate on one point before we get back into our topic that was last
week's topic that failed is I mentioned the audience for my talk was mostly
developers and I talked quite a bit with one of the conference coordinators after
my talk about how two points to make I have two points to make and then we'll
go on to our topic no I actually I think this is an interesting topic
right there's there's a lot of movement in this is the first time to
my knowledge that you've presented this to primarily a dev audience and one
observation there and then I the first observation was is the controversy in
the principles is much less so there to an audience of developers of a lot more
head nods in fact anecdotally when I've even at testing conferences people to go
thanks for giving a name to what I already do those people are primarily
developer type roles anyway with a little bit of quality background maybe
remember when we wrote the principles without the one that would cause the
biggest uproar is one more we say where the testing role may be eliminated oh my
god my livelihood you're ruining the craft but I feel like we've been able
to talk about that one quite well and people have they get it they go yeah I
can I can picture that world what has been more controversial at a lot of
talks about this at the conference was principle number five where we say that
only the customer is able to evaluate the quality of our product and we take a
lot of everything from you just expect the customers to do all your testing
because you're lazy or my customers special or whatever flavors of those you
want I still believe that now we can is worth talking about a little bit
because we do take not only a lot but continued grief people come across this
one it really triggers a lot of people and they make some arguments which I I
kind of see where they're coming from but they're also in some cases getting
lost in the semantics of the customer as a software developers it's off for a
team I want to make software that helps help someone do something better that
person I'm helping or something easier remember customers don't want software
they want their problem solved right I want to help people solve their problems
help people do things they couldn't do before help people do things more
easily than they could do before help people get their eyes opened up to new
things they could they didn't even think they knew they could do those people are
my customers so let's say for example I am the team building software for a
medical device that well we've had some famous bugs with x-ray machines I say I'm
building a software for automated collection of and dosage of an x-ray
machine for various uses who is my customer person that's impacted person
being x-rayed the person using the device so I can have multiple customers
the doctor the hospital may be the one that buys the device for me but I think I
believe my customer is anyone it's the person's his problem is being solved
which is it can be a multi-layered customer well in that case right so I
and correct me if you disagree I'm just I believe it's yeah that would be no
concerns there Alan so if you think about it from from a two-pronged approach
an x-ray we don't want to just a simple thing we don't want to over irradiate
our clients yeah because that would be bad they would die right but what's the
reason why they're getting an x-ray they're having a problem right okay
purpose of an x-ray is diagnostics yes tool it's it so with you so far the
the person under study is a key customer here as well as the person who's using
the tool to do diagnostics is is a customer as you know I broke broke a bone
in my foot recently it's still not entirely healed it's one of these slow
breaks but it's a lot of work for for the doctor to go what the hell's wrong
particularly if it's a fracture right could you there's a be a different
treatment for a sprain strain ligament versus a bone fracture and the and the
amount of the fracture etc yeah you need to know what's going on so if they can
produce a higher confidence diagnosis faster then that that x-ray versus say
traditional x-ray devices is going to be a preferred one and also I want to dive
into this little bit so there's there's value in we all get everyone gets the
value in the in the diagnostic software but also the software we create should
do no harm that sounds a little bit too much like Google it should not the the
the side effects the the it shouldn't have unintended consequences that detract
from the value it should so who values an ethics yes so who evaluates the quality
of that other consumers I don't know I'm trying to come up with a new version
yeah what I've discovered so here's the thing I'm gonna take an aside that's
actually relevant but maybe an aside I'm not surprised that dev audience was like
wait why are you setting up here telling me things I already know right but and
that's hyperbole it is because I I I do weave some stories in and I want to go
actually I'll go back to that in a minute but go ahead and go on a lot of
my portion of developing MMT came from my own personal experiences like helping
moving to unified engineering right I was ahead of a dev team and we've
recorded this several years ago or where I spent a lot of time I had left tests
and I said okay now why would I bring a tester back into the system what
value would they add and I realized would have caused more harm than good
having a specialist in right I had a smooth running Kanban system I had a
process with dealing with very rapidly errors in production there wasn't a value
for me in a test specialist at that point in time and thinking about from
from a dev perspective I find it interesting when I go and talk to dev I
don't have these semantic discussions I don't have to clarify what is quality I
don't have to clarify what is customer and and I'm trying to in my head going
what does that mean what is that it like there's there's definitely a key culture
difference between a dev specialist community and a test special there is
there is and that just got me thinking of an epiphany that immediately blew out
of my head because I was thinking about too many things at once yeah it's
it is and I am super old I'm about to have a birthday congrats I'll be a hundred
years old I don't think that's true not quite I'll still be in double digits no
but times ticking for me March 5-0 oh yeah I remember that one so I was really
drunk so I want to back up and then move on I kind of put a cap on the
maybe a temporary cap a trial close on the principle 5 controversy I think I
truly believe and I and I still I believe people I hear arguments all the
time and how we're and against it all the time I still truly believe that is
not only a valid principle and worded correctly but one of the most important
principles nuts pretty much I mean that's stolen from a chapter of Reese's
book I think five and one are the two most important it's you don't get value
from your engineering effort in touch in the hands of customers and even with an
x-ray machine I may find building an x-ray software I may give the doctors
the soft before it even actually hooks up to the x-ray machine to make sure
that I may give them the software a prototype that does doesn't do the
x-ray but so they can use the software and it'll have mock-ups for example of
how it may give the feedbacks to make sure they understand how to use it that
using is intuitive and then the way they use it is the way that I thought they
would use it so I can adjust as needed I may do all fun developing this x-ray
software I may do all that work so I can get that customer feedback before I
actually start implementing the the hairy x-ray part yeah absolutely I
think it'd be a great way to do that a lot of the things and we could go
back to how about the software for an airplane that fails and causes it to
I would put that in a massive amount of simulations with pilots and well before
I put that in the plane no I think I think on the on the the quality
discussion there's a couple of thoughts right number one going back to briefly
back to this difference between the tests and dev culture right I remember
when I went from test to dev with a strong passion around quality I felt
oh oh my god I am a lot closer to the customer I can now actually influence
quality which leads me to and fully agree and that leads me to the second big
takeaway and this came up in my conversation with the conference
organizer after the talk as well which tied into my observations at the
conference which have tied into my observations and you know when you
reflect on years you go oh my god you have a revelation you go how is I so
stupid they never get to this before you've been on the channel you've heard
me talk about this and I mentioned it to a few people internally but I am
realizing that DevOps whatever it is is it a culture is it a role in my five for
Friday last week I pointed to a podcast that talked about it and what's
interesting in this coding blocks podcast I I would say I put the link
in the show notes but I'll forget look up coding blocks and find it they talk
about DevOps it is haunting when they talk about DevOps how much it sounds
like testing and how much they talk about specialists really just want
someone with us but that specialty you don't want to have a DevOps team and
going oh my god and not just that point but points over and over and over
and over and I'm realizing that as far as accelerating the delivery of
customer value or accelerating the achievement shipable quality DevOps has
far more to do with that and or an infrastructure team working on
accelerating the team in way in safe way in ways that ensure safety and quality
is a farm hands down far better way to do that than QA oh and I ran and talk
about bringing the quality perspective to a product team when I was at
Microsoft on teams my last project there I was hired as the quality guy at the
quality coach and then I had a manager who was kind of a dick and it kept on
yelling at me every time there was a bug and it's like Jesus this is 1990 2015
2016 but I ended up taking over all of the infrastructure team everything from
developer desktop to customer deployment and that gave me a lot more control I
got yelled at a lot less still wasn't super happy but it worked so since then
I you sacrificed you sacrifice something I can't put a finger on it for autonomy
maybe but let's move on because that was that was a good learning experience for
me and more learning in retrospect I but that was I actually also managed a lot
of offshore testers so it wasn't wasn't the best experience so let me move on
to my current role at Unity and we'll we'll splash back and forth between
hold on I'm not done with the last topic no no no we're we're easing in here
we're gonna go back it's gonna it's gonna we go ahead that's great there's I
keep in the back of my head I keep thinking about the experience and this
difference man I do think there's something important there and it occurs
to me like hey Ellen do you think testers should code no yeah I'm actually
gonna change that and you said Brent will say yes and I'm gonna say and when
Alan said that he was right but I'm gonna I'm gonna change it now because I'm
actually now wondering if Tess can really understand quality from the outside
meaning in a and when I think through processes you and the listener should be
aware that at first I go to the extremes when I went from test to dev that shift
was very much going from theoretical to actual previously I stood on principle I
stood on theory I said things like what you want the customer to do your testing
for you needed and right we had an episode we had this whole conversation
when I was in a dev role the accountability the responsibility was on
me to prove to to provide value so I'm gonna say yeah test should code but even
further they should get on a feet they should be coding a feature see I don't
fully agree I think there's so I think the the path for a quality specialist
to be effective as and an impactful on a software team is not to specialize
solely in testing but the paths they can go into are wide and I think I have
found I don't think we disagree but you said feature and I think this dev ops
this infrastructure role is a very common path for testers I think whatever
so we both agree they should we want specializing generalists not
specialists yes okay what I'm proposing because there's one commonality that
occurs to me for both you and I we both coded features yes we have right it
doesn't have to be a big one so this testing specialist that I'm talking about
could they be assigned a small feature and be an own that in the end just
for the experience yeah that's exactly I'm not I'm not against it I don't think
it's a requirement I think it's a good idea yeah I'm trying to come up with what
is the key thing is that we have to de-theorize the testing specialist
position yes that's it theory always breaks apart in the face of reality
right there's a lot of thought experiments there and yeah and all right
I'm done now my the modern testing course on ministry of test there's a
lot of thought experiments there like in episode 7 one of the exercises is what
would need to change on your team in order for it in order for testers not to
meet it just think through it just just not saying quit must think get
yourself fired so just think about what would need to change maybe the list is
huge maybe it's short just think about yeah there's a lot a lot of theory
there so now this will still tie into my point from earlier is I've been
thinking about this move to DevOps and what people do and I have a small I
wouldn't call it a QA team so I have one I have two people who on my team
former testers okay one of former lead very experienced knows how to code super
smart guy he is basically functioning as a test coach for a huge part of the
organization what I found is that our developers do pretty much 100% I'll say
95% of the testing they know how to do which is that's a that's a greater amount
of testing than maybe they knew how to do six months ago but not probably still
not enough so having someone there who has that breadth of experience to just
think about new ideas have you thought about this should we try this has been
really really helpful also at the same time he's he's sort of half in a DevOps
role and I would consider him part of the DevOps team but he just happens to
some quality coaching and in fact I would view him as longer term as DevOps
but he has the testing expertise so he's gonna end up coaching there we've
talked before about this were just like you have a database expert or
performance expert or a front-end expert or a react expert having someone
with some experience and expertise in testing is a good value add for the team
but being a total specialist of being a bottleneck is not a good idea so I had
an interesting we added one more person to my team through acquisition
acquired a small company they had one QA person but it's interesting how much
it's weird when you have a manager who is not like me at all but we tend and we
get we get to our conclusions from different angles but we agree our
philosophies are highly aligned and I'm not sure how or why because we came from
different directions and backgrounds but interesting conversation he asked about
this person QA person in the New York he didn't use these words but I think at
first he was worried there were more of a traditional QA and I'm gonna I'll
paraphrase the whole conversation but basically I think what he wanted to find
out is could this person be it be a test coach like the other person on my
team okay and the answer is yes but it made me think more about people with
test expertise in modern testing growing in the test coach roles or test
consultant roles and I realized one thing that a skill that I've been
working on but an interesting thing is there's a level above it where I need to
one area where I want to get better it as coaching coaches when I rely on
coaching from my team so much that makes me realize that I need to and how
to coach coaches right yeah I have a similar problem and it's essentially have
I ever shared the definition of empowerment please do so Brent
empowerment is trust that the person that you're empowering will make the same
decision you will in your absence I think I've heard that before yeah I am
spending time empowering coaches I'll use the term coaches in this context on
my team in order to scale right I need this I need more
guide ers in order to in order to take one of the key things that I'm doing
right now and have it go viral right right now it's bottlenecking behind me oh
bottlenecks are bad you should I want to get the coding blocks podcast again
because you got to listen to it you'll crack up they have a long conversation
they're talking about whether DevOps should be a role or a culture and I
and I believe it's a culture but that you may hire some DevOps folks to help
there and in the middle of that argument they had a nice long
discussion over where they don't want the DevOps team to be the only people
that do that stuff so that stuff bottlenecks on them sounds familiar huh
good strategy so it's very much I mean DevOps is very much a there's some
expertise around things like Kubernetes and Jenkins and CI systems but you want
to empower the teams around you to use those tools miss and come to you
when they need expertise to figure things out that whole role is at Unity at
least is a small team imagine so 200 engineers working on a very profitable
business and there are five people working on six people maybe working on
infrastructure and DevOps and tools so obviously a lot of it is them building
the base and the rest of the engineers absorbing their output one way to make
sure that team isn't a bottleneck is to not overstaff it because it's small
because it's because it could be a bottleneck make it so that if it were a
bottleneck it would be so painful to death to do something about it right
which is kind of like the way I actually I believe that's why basically
three people across these 200 plus engineers who have some testing
expertise with me being one of them make sure that we are not a bottleneck
or when I was a when I was the test guy the quality guy on teams I wasn't a
bottleneck because I was if I would have had a team of ten people who would
have been the testing bottleneck no but the other key thing is leadership and
in this case so I have seen teams with your same degree of staffing and the
same degree of power that you have go a different way it is just a flip of a
switch Ellen in your brain that makes this a coach model versus a command and
control right if you could just as easily take your three people and turn
this into command and control structure I suppose and with your background be able
to articulate it's the right thing for the business you and I both know it
wouldn't be I know but it's it's do you think it comes really comes down to that
flaw because I inherently believe in autonomy and giving people a framework
and getting out of their way and and coaching as a leadership style I would
argue that sort of attitude is becoming more and more prevalent among tech
leadership I think it is and they and I think it's because I'll tell you when I
changed my mind accountability is an important thing and every person in
leadership role is going to have a different philosophy but they're all
accountable for something true some of us are risk-averse some of us are
that I don't know what the opposite of risk-averse is but take a damn the
torpedoes mentality when I when I went and I learned the Kanban model and I
learned that shipping small things faster continuously integrating getting
that feedback loop so I can respond immediately if we screwed something up
not only was better in producing quality but also reduced risk right and true one
million percent true yeah and and so a lot of it comes out of the decision
making factor in in prior roles no we're shipping on this date right and so I had
to spin up risk mitigation mode to because again I was accountable for the
the risk that we shipped and the more that that loaded up the more time I
needed to be able to evaluate the risk and the more it further loaded up the
more I lost confidence of my ability to evaluate the risk so when I learned and
when you're in that mode command and control is critical because you need to
make sure that somebody somewhere randomly doesn't do something that
completely changes that risk equation because you're already having a hard time
figuring out what it is right but with this other model I'm like oh yeah you
know what you think it's right Alan do it make sure you have a monitor make sure
it turns itself off within the first five minutes you realize you're wrong
just help people stumble towards success right so I want to tie this in we got
about 15 minutes left here to our oddly rambling discussion in the last podcast
and it was odd one of the three said they really really liked him we weren't
sure why but because we spent most time exploring my role at Unity the
conversation really got thrown for a loop because my official title on paper is
director of program management and there's a skew because Microsoft has a
odd view on what program managers are it's different from the industry and we
spent a lot of time just trying to clarify what that was so my title on
paper while works I want to reframe that around the discussion we just had so it
was so wouldn't help last week but I consider myself a delivery director or
delivery manager but then that sounds too much like your release manager you
you accuse me of being that's not quite it at all but then Percy reminded
us we had this conversation a year ago almost a year ago when I was thinking
about this job and you said Alan it sounds like you're a release train
engineer which is a term from the safe world and bread test safe training and
the definition the RTE the release train engineer facilitates the agile release
train or you know TM facilitates processes and execution escalates
impediments helps manage risk insurance value delivery and drives continuous
improvement or in short the RTE helps the team deliver and get better and
that's actually doesn't describe my entire job because I have some other
coaching aspects in there but that's largely what I do I try and I I try and
help the team learn from failures learn from mistakes and try to improve and
overall make sure we're getting value to customers actually the way I put it I
think I'm this last week I try and balance velocity and quality so under
that and that ties into what you were just talking about so does that and then
I'm gonna get into the question we never answered last week does that framing of
my job as release train engineer since you know that language does that help
you understand what I do what my responsibilities are yeah in the last
cast the topic was what what KPIs it wasn't really KPIs like as someone with
quality experience or as a quality leader in a release train engineer type role
I'm paraphrasing to fit better context this time what would be some things you
would do or I can't measure within there what would be some things that
you would do or measure along those lines yeah I've spent a lot of time
thinking about that and also thinking about this one witticism part of our job
what's a witticism word I made up okay just checking when we talk about
quality it occurs to me that a lot of the times it's getting overloaded oh yeah
right it's there's there's three words that I'm finding one of the definitions
of quality is a word that means 11 different things 10 different people well
the thing that's really interesting to me is that in the test community right
we've known that the only the only thing testers can agree on around the
definition of the word test is that it has four letters other than that there's
no agreement on what is test true but customer and quality are also
ambiguous apparently and we learned very recently that customer was ambiguous
I sure but in your role right it's two phases there are two aspects build the
right product build the product right cliche and cliche right so those yeah I'm
involved I'm involved in helping teams get better at that but I do also
partner quite a bit with both product managers and product marketing to build
the right product so let's go back engineers don't know how to build the
right product that's one thing need to be told how to do a lot of the time
right in decomposing that how do you how do you reduce the friction to tell
them what to do and most importantly so that they self-learn it so I had a
conversation and I should ease into this if we're different direction while
product marketing or product management may have a good idea based on what
they've done talked customers research whatever to figure out building the
right product we don't know that until only the customer can evaluate that
absolutely so it's all a bunch of hypotheses so that's where my role steps
is a great understand we're trying to build how can we what's our path to get
that feedback as soon as possible I had a conversation yesterday with with
someone at Unity I'm talking about a project that they said was a failure
that may not have been his words or may have been his words and expressed
disappointment yeah and I said so I was at a failure and he talked about things
and and blah blah blah blah blah end of story the product was a failure
because it was canceled or redirected or whatever and never really solved the
customer problem and I said let me rephrase that again so get rid of that
that face this product was a failure I want products to fail that's where we
get to learn but this product took three months to fail when I think we
think we could have made it fail in a month and that's that's that's what we
need to learn from I want products to fit I want us to reduce the time from
product hypothesis to customer impact customer feedback and if it takes if it
takes three months to figure out the building the wrong product that that is
something to learn from I think it depends on what you're making but you
want to so here's a product idea blah one of the things I help teams discuss
and I think we're off the track here a little bit but we're not is what is our
path to figure out and this is the right product how are we gonna validate
this as soon as possible and what I'm finding is to the less experienced their
idea of the minimum viable product is much more expansive than what I think the
minimum viable product may be so that is a I haven't heard that discussed much
the far as how to make how to really identify the MVP because what I've seen
in practice is people call the minimum viable product something that I saw this
on I've seen this for years and years and years it's a certain definition we used to
call beta yeah what they call the MVP is far far far more than minimum so one
thing and read and one of the three listeners can point with this exists
but one thing I've been working out a lot is helping teams narrow down their
definition of minimum and I haven't seen a lot of writing or I'm just thinking
a lot of the talk about this is something we that needs to be explored more is how
do you take what you think is minimum viable product and make it a truly
minimum viable product that's one aspect of my job from a strategy that's easy
we are all over the tangent world here I actually don't do you know this all
makes it's all connected I am briefly considering everything you just said and
go okay is this the next most important so for me it's easy a minimum viable
product is the smallest thing you can ship where you gain the greatest amount
of knowledge around should you continue to work on this thing yes okay I have
had this particular conversation with multiple different people I always
bring up the Reese example because I think it's beautiful they had spent six
months and realized that they had spent one day building an advertising website
that said click here to download they didn't even have to implement the
download that it could have returned a 404 and they would have learned in one
day what took them many man-hours in six calendar months to learn yeah yes yes I
think it's and this has been true for my entire career in software I think
there's too much faith from developers that the customers will want the thing
they're building and we need to use customers and data to understand that do
you know who Stephen Blink is no Stephen Blink is was actually the
inspiration for Eric Reese he is a professor at Princeton he highly
recommended book four steps to the epiphany also I would link it but I'll
forget look it up he shared you know I paused there he shared if one of the
three if you just want to be an admin on the podcast website and and want to
go and happy to have it happen just gonna throw that out there anyway he
shared see now we're we're a B test coaches we're realizing that I'm the
bottleneck I'm right right I know I know my limitations so I'm looking to
delegate yeah yeah now I have to take a moment because I completely lost my
train of thought he shared no I got that part Stephen Blank shared inspiration
for Reese oh you're talking about developers great developers developers
developers so I happen to happen to go to a place where I saw Stephen Blink do a
talk and one of the phenomenons that he talked about was was venture capitalism
in Silicon Valley in that the culture had been changing and VCs had learned a
heuristic which is if this is a company trying to get additional income if they
had a head holy of sales already hired odds are we're going to say no why
because it was the head holy of sales let's say a VP of sales or VP of
marketing their primary job is to go talk to the customer now usually the
founder is the inventor and one of the problems with inventors and I'm going to
say this a problem exists with developers as well is the NIH phenomenon
we've talked about many times my idea is awesome and it is absolutely better than
yours if you have a VP of sales and they go out and they try to flight this
idea and they realize the customers don't want it let's say you're the the
CEO and you have this my shit don't stink and I'm the VP of sales and I say
Alan no one wants this idea right you have two choices reevaluate your belief
in that of your idea or reevaluate your belief whether or not I'm a competent VP
of sales long far longer story short VCs nowadays they want you the founder to
do the customer connection not a VP of sales because they have learned you
trying to hawk your wares to customers helps to you to get the feedback and
understand where you're wrong yes and an irrational belief of righteousness kills
startups yeah and but you see so much of that not in startups as well as within
companies I saw that Microsoft 150 million trillion times right and this
is why this is why I always take the term product requirements nowadays and I
change it to hypotheses yes I am I am trying to purposely make people realize
doesn't matter how important their belief is there's still a chance they're
wrong of course and the first thing we need to do is evaluate that as and many
textbooks talk about this the idea of falling in love with your ideas yeah and
I always fall back to and going back to customers don't want software they want
their problems solved and if you don't understand if you don't have at least
three different solutions to solve the problem you don't understand the problem
well enough that's from Weinberg slight paraphrase focus on that and realize I
mean here's it's a hypothesis you can understand the problem and go here's
my idea for a solution you get you get some feedback on it you either you
pivot or you persevere yeah I think about right just before you and I met
this morning I was staring at a report that one of my directs and I have
collaborated on and that whole report its whole purpose in life is to shine the
light on everything I can think about about why I'm wrong yes that's a good
way to look at it and that helps I think I've brought that up recently it might
have been in my in the course it might have been in the talk but I feel like
I've talked about that recently yeah prove the negative hypothesis yeah so
there's the the you want to you want to aggressively try to prove the negative
hypothesis and then hope you never do yeah sure and but what I find it's a
nice lens to put on that every time I actually prove the negative hypothesis is
hugely valuable in my role my currency is credibility yep right when I stand up in
front of a crowd and I have my data scientists hat on and I'm saying this is
what this is saying people are going to take action and and I don't want to come
back next month oh yeah remember when I told you that never mind yeah I'd
right when I'm doing a public presentation this is an aside that when
I'm doing a public presentation in data science mode it really hurts me because
I cannot allow my natural tendency towards hyperbole out that is dangerous
I think we've decomposed enough for discussion we will talk about continued
topics of whatever comes up in the world as we continue our path towards a yeah
we'll see ya we'll see ya oh my god soon I thought of something else I wanted to
mention earlier but then I forgot to bring it up so I thought about bringing
it out those at the clock I said no I'm not going to so that's all we're gonna
do today okay I am the master editor of this podcast and I am NOT all right
au revoir