This is the AB Testing 343 podcast, a podcast where we ask one of the three listeners of
the AB Testing podcast, three questions about almost anything. ABT 343 is a fun slice of
what's going on in the world of modern testing. Let's get started.
Welcome once again to the ABT 343 podcast. This week, the one of the three joining me
is none other than Chris Canst. Welcome to the show, Chris.
Thank you for having me.
This is exciting. We have crossed paths many times and I'm glad to have you on the hot seat.
So are you prepared?
Nope.
Me neither. All right. We are set. It's just like when Brett and I do it.
Yeah. Which by the way, I think are some of the funnier aspects of it where you're
just trying to figure stuff out because in some way that's just reality where you're
just literally trying to figure stuff out and come up with the best solution to something?
Yeah, it works out surprisingly well. And that's the, I'm sure we brought this up once
or twice on the podcast. That's how it started. We would have these interactions and meetings
and some way with Michael Hunter. I don't know where my, he's a tableau now if I remember
correctly, but he said, you guys should have a podcast and record these conversations.
So we did and we still have it. But this is not about Brent. Brent who? I don't know.
Today it's the AC testing podcast with Alan and Chris.
That's right.
And I'm going to throw you a softball to get started. Tell me your story. How did you
get into software testing? What was your path from there to here?
Yeah. What was my path? I know people don't like this term, but I did fall into it.
I literally got into testing after college because that was, I had a friend who worked
at a company in Southern California. I was living in the Bay area at the time. I wanted
to move to Southern California. So I had a friend who got me an interview at a company
and I just sort of ended up in the QA department and worked for a large company. It was AIG,
started there, worked there for a couple of years, worked for Countrywide for a couple
of years. Basically, I went through all the companies. There were big enough companies.
People sort of knew what they were doing, but no one could tell me what it is. There
was very little expertise, it seemed like, in the companies outside of people just had
a lot of domain knowledge. So I started working for smaller companies, startups. And
as soon as I started working for startups, I had to figure out what it was that I was
doing. Because it turns out in traditional test management, which was what those larger
companies used, it was a lot easier to sort of just go about your business and do things
without it having to contribute value or direct value to the business.
It was big enough organizations, big enough testing organizations that as long as you
were doing the same thing that everyone else is doing, it's assumed that there was
value creation. This is part of the reason why I really like the modern testing principles
because as soon as I joined my first startup, it was very clear to me when I was providing
value and when I wasn't because the company was small enough that the individual impact
each person had had some positive or no impact on the business.
So there's a little bit of a tangent. I've been in software quality for 15 years,
software testing and software quality for 15 years. I've worked for big companies, small
companies. I tend to like working for smaller companies, smaller startups. Part of that
is just the impact that you have. And the other part is big companies do like to do
traditional test management. And I'm just not in favor of that at all.
But outside of... So I currently work for a company called BloomNation, which is in
Santa Monica, California. So I am in the Los Angeles area. BloomNation, if you go to BloomNation.com,
is a marketplace for flowers. You can put in your zip code and get connected with local
florists to buy flowers. But our big business is that we're a software as a service platform.
We actually bring those florists online, build them an e-commerce site, all that good
stuff. And so that's what I do. I'm a senior test automation engineer there, which is going
to be fun because you talk about how much... Hold on a second. I'm making a note to make
fun of you in a minute. Go on. Go on. Yeah, it's fine. It's fine. That's part of the reason
I wanted to do this because I think a lot of the things that you preach against, I
either sit in that situation or have come up through that situation. It's going to
be good times. I'm glad you're preparing yourself.
It's going to be fun. So in addition, I've been in software testing and software quality
for 15 years. I have been a longtime volunteer and am currently a board member of the Association
for Software Testing. I run their webinars, help put on the conferences, make decisions
at the board level. I do some writing at kens.com and a few other places around the
web. I also occasionally speak. So I have actually been speaking about the topic, about how
I became a test automation engineer. And I've got some modern testing portions of that
influence in the presentation I give, we can talk about. I also run basically the largest site.
It's a community driven site of software testing conferences from around the world at
testingconferences.org. It's an open source project. Anybody can contribute to it. But
that just grew out of a aspect that I saw wasn't being covered in the testing community,
which was how many software testing conferences and workshops are being run around the world.
So that's a little bit about me.
That's a whole lot about you. I have more than three questions and I only have two left.
I don't know. Prepare yourself for complex and multi-part questions. But first, a tangent.
Interesting at Bloom Nation. And I think it's a great idea to just make it easy for these
shops that obviously can't afford a technology department to build up their e-commerce site.
It's interesting, one because it's interesting, but two because just recently, maybe last week,
I met someone virtually. I met someone who did the same work. I forget the name of the company,
but they basically made the same thing for wine companies.
Was the company called Drizly?
I don't remember. I don't remember. It just made things click. It made me realize why,
because I buy and drink a lot of wine. Why so many of the sites all felt familiar. I thought,
are they owned by the same parent company and they're not. They used to use the same
e-commerce software.
Yeah. It turns out to be a really big and important business too. If you think about
Amazon just dominating everything from an e-commerce perspective, but still, Amazon's
really small in the global terms or in the United States. The United States has something like
$500 billion is done through just commerce retail sales, and Amazon probably does
$50 billion or $100 billion in total.
Amazon still has this really small market share. From a perspective of a business, a small mom and
pop business, being able to go online, even if that's not your forte and your expertise,
that could have huge impacts on your overall business, whether you're like an alcohol,
like a liquor store or a pizza shop or a florist.
Especially now, right?
Especially now.
Everything. Yeah. Interesting times we live in. Before we get on, this doesn't count as one of
my questions, but how is it going for you in California or just in general dealing with
the new scenarios of life we have right now?
So I'm doing okay. My wife is a nurse, so that aspect of it is incredibly complex because she
has to deal with COVID patients. Yes.
So that's where the stress comes from, but I used to work from home
by choice, and now I work from home not by choice. So it's fine. I keep telling myself it's fine.
We don't go out too much. We do a lot more cooking at home instead of going out, but
otherwise it's fine.
Well, give your wife a huge round of thanks from me because that's a
well, hopefully not thankless entirely, but that's such an important job right now.
I can imagine that could break some stress.
Yeah, a little bit.
Okay. Now let's bring you some stress. Why is a test automation engineer important?
What do you do to convince me that that has anything to do with modern testing? Go.
Yeah. So I had, like I said, I've been doing this talk about how I became one. And so
the story that I like to tell is that I had been just a QA engineer for the longest time,
senior QA engineer, whatever you want to call it. And in that role, I did a lot of exploratory
testing and then I did some automation. And now my breakdown of exploratory to automation,
it varies week to week, depending on our releases, but it's like a 60 40 split between
automation and exploratory testing. And at least in our company for Bloom Nation, we basically have two
products that we're working on. We have a new application, which is in react and node.
I have a bunch of really good front end engineers who have built this. It's a greenfield project.
It's been around for like a year, maybe a year and a half. It's really well built.
They're very into testability. So they've got, you know, unit integration level tests.
And we just deployed some UI automation using cypress. This will get a little bit into the
the modern testing frame of how you like to sort of, um, I'm basically a coach in that role.
So wait, and so wait, you're doing test automation and you're, you're not using Selenium.
Well, I am just not on this particular project.
Okay. No, fine. Fine. Because I actually am a lot of people have
pushed back a lot on cypress and a test cafe, which I really like as well.
Well, thank you. Thank you for giving him a run. They can believe it or not. They actually
can be a good solution. Yeah. And I mean, any tool that I use has to just make sense for the
particular problem that I'm trying to solve. And so we can discuss that a little bit. But the reason
that cypress made sense was this is a node application. This was an application where
I really wanted to give my developers the power to because they were so, uh, test infected is
probably a well common term, but because they write so much, write so many tests themselves from,
you know, using jest and, and to shallow render components and do all that kind of stuff,
it makes sense to, so basically what we decided is that it made sense to use cypress.
I did the initial deployment of the framework, wrote the first test. And then, uh, one of my
developers has since gone. And one of the problems that we found when I wrote it was that
it's a, essentially a single page application, but it was just, it uses some graph QL and it
uses some technologies that made it really hard to just interact with from a UI perspective.
And so having gone through and wrote those things, I was able to write a bunch of stories and work
with my developer to basically go, listen, can we re-architect this? Can you open up some of the
APIs in the underlying system so that we can see what's going on and use some of cypress's
built-in methods to actually work with the node application in order to make the testing
better? And so he did that when my developer, Aaron, he actually went through basically
re-architected and made it so that cypress could pull in a lot of our like server fetches and
that kind of stuff. And then rewrote the test that I did made it a lot more complex,
but also made it so that it better fit into the development workflow. And now it's set up
such that they can continue writing tests for components and they can use the server,
they can use the server data, they can use a lot of fixture data. And basically the test is now,
in testing terms, we'd call it a lot more glass box where you can actually see the implementation,
you're actually relying on the implementation to automate some of the UI. But now it's this
really great fit where, and that's what cypress made a lot of sense to do.
Cool. It reminds me a lot of times that's been before I knew I was coaching or consulting,
I thought I was just being lazy. I would write a test, a test, stick it into CI or stick it
into the build pipeline. And so now we have a test to make sure this never fails.
It would run, people would ignore it, and then it would run and fail and go,
oh, it's caught a bug. Great. And then once they knew it was there, they would add things to it.
I don't have time to write all your tests. I'm just going to make it as easy as I can for
you to do the right thing. Yeah, that's the approach that I took with this. And it just
sort of fit that it worked. Okay. You're slowly digging yourself out of a hole,
but still a test automation engineer. Tell me more about how that relates to modern testing.
Well, so I make it a lot of people mad, but I know you have good answers. So go for it.
Well, let's see if I do have good answers. How does that relate to modern testing? I mean,
I have to look up what the principles are because I don't have them memorized.
That's a prerequisite for being on the 343 show, man.
Well, I didn't pass the quiz you gave me. So there's a lot of things about how I approach it
that are, and we can talk about modern testing principle-like. And so really the coaching is
about just expanding the testing abilities and know-how across the team. That's principle seven.
And so while that doesn't necessarily, in my case, reduce the need for a testing specialist,
the idea that I can work with my developers just across our applications, and I'm still developing
this skill because I don't know exactly what a test coach is, but being able to just give them
a tool and build it out and then be able to help and coach them as they build out the tests.
And by the way, do the code reviews on those tests contribute? I've actually contributed probably
a lot more for code reviews on unit tests and that kind of stuff. That is actually valuable.
But so from a modern testing principle, it's really trying to coach them and be better about
understanding what it is that they're doing and how to test better and build out that function
functionality to allow it.
All right. I'm getting convinced. Again, because it reminds me of probably the first time. It was
the first team I was on at Microsoft where we didn't have any dedicated testers. And I'm not
sure. I was given one of my typical jobs where Alan go figure out what to do. And I did a whole
bunch of code reviews of unit tests, a bunch of code reviews asking people to write tests.
And basically I taught a entire dev organization of about 70 people how to write testing,
just almost all through code reviews. So definitely a good way to consult or coach or help people
improve. And then I really love that because if I'm a big proponent of testers doing code reviews
or at least participating in code reviews. And one of the first places I tell them to look is
if there are unit tests on those code reviews, I naturally gravitate to those because I can see
what they're doing. I'm like, Oh, cool. You're passing in a string here. The string is a phone
number, but you did it twice. Why are you doing it twice? Shouldn't one be like a crazy, you can
start to apply your testing mindset to that kind of stuff.
Yes. And testing is the test written for an application, actually reasonably good documentation
for that application. Yeah. And that's exactly what I did. Even if you don't know a lot of code,
it's like a language. You can read it and understand it versus
usually at a much faster rate than you can speak it and be fluent in it.
I was going to say it's about being literate, like code literate, but not actually being able
to program. So if you can be code literate, if you can read it and make sense of it and
talk to somebody about why they did it, there's a huge opportunity.
Yeah. So my, in a nutshell, you start with where are the tests, then they add them. And then you
ask questions like, should we test this? Or what else should we test? Or let's try, you can sound
like a genius just by saying things like, Hey, let's just test one thing per test. Or,
Hey, let's try some invalid values here and see if we're handling handling errors. Oh, yeah. Wow.
Great idea. So it's a, yeah, we're fully in alignment there.
And so I will say that this works really well for that new node application. And then it's like a
whole other world that we can talk about a little bit more why I think test automation
engineers are necessary. I live in this like two different worlds where the node application,
where I have my developers, and we're doing all these things, I'm doing the code reviews,
they're adding unit tests and all that kind of stuff. And then we have our older
monolithic PHP and magenta application, where almost none of the same stuff applies.
I need to dive in on one of those things you said, why will we always, because I disagree.
So we're going to have it, we're going to discuss this tangent or tangent section or
something's going on here. Why do we always, why would we always need test automation engineers?
I can't speak of why we would need them other than I can tell you why I needed currently.
Okay, that may be better. Because that makes sense. The generality doesn't. But tell me about
the context. What's going on? Yeah, exactly. So context matters. And so when people like you harp
on this, and I'm like, I can't answer this as a global question. And even when I give my talk,
I can't answer it as a global question, but as a specific question. So we have outside of our
React application, our main application, our main e-commerce platform is on PHP and magento.
And we have platform engineers, PHP developers, who I have in that work on site with us, just
regular employees, great developers, they write unit tests, they write integration tests, I do some
writing of integration tests, I tried to write some PHP unit tests for magento, I spent like
two weeks and wrote 10 of them. It was this very frustrating process for me. But we have
a bunch of contractors that we use as well. And so in that world, they're not very good at writing
unit tests. My developers on site for platform engineers, they ask for unit tests, they rarely
get them. My CTO is, although he came up from the development side, he's not a big proponent,
like he would rather have no unit tests and a feature delivered than a feature delivered with
unit tests. And so a part of that comes that doesn't have an impact on my node developers,
because they are a lot more tests infected. But when it comes to this particular application,
and our development process and workflow, there's not as big of an emphasis on it. And if we can
skip it, then we skip it. And so I was actually hired to be a test automation engineer,
to actually write a UI, build a UI framework to play it for the magento ecommerce stuff,
as a safeguard against some of this stuff. And so ecommerce, it actually makes a lot of sense to have
UI tests, you literally want to go through and make sure you can collect people's money.
So I have a limited set of targeted UI tests that go through and make sure we collect people's
money. I have some targeted UI tests that are around SEO and making sure that we have the
specific tags and kind of things that we need. But in that world where you literally can't,
if you think of the test automation pyramid, and the model that it implies where you have
lots of unit tests, and you catch bugs there, and you have lots of integration tests, and you
catch things there, and you have a smaller set of UI tests, we do have that smaller set of UI tests,
but we really were growing the integration tests as well, but the unit test coverage is just
lacking. And so that needs sort of by definition, a lot more love from somebody who is not the
developer themselves. You had me till that last part. Yeah.
I can tell you kind of regretted saying it just as soon as it came out of your mouth.
It's not the way I meant to say it in that like, so in with my no developers, like I can build
something for them and say, Here you go, this is completely integrated, because everything is
basically been built in a way that it makes sense that I can that we can include this as an organic
part of the process. And with the magento PHP application, it's not organic at all. So
whereas I'm going to use some testing terms here. But so as with the node application,
where the UI tests are actually more glassbox, the magento UI tests are fully blackbox, they have
no idea what the code is, the underlying code is they're literally just going through the business,
the logic, and, and checking out and doing those kinds of things. And so because of that,
and this all really stems from the development process that's around it, because of the
development process where there isn't so much of a way to tie everything in or even a desire
to tie everything in. That's, that's the particular part of the particular problem that I solve.
Okay, I do. It sounds like you are doing a reasonable job of accelerating the achievement of
shippable quality. I'm trying not to be a bottleneck is what I'm there you go and accelerate there is
the right words. And at your company and in your role, you've, you have a specialization sounds
like you have influence. It sounds it's really you could be. And here's what I think it's the
semantics that are going to change in the future. What the company like yours needs is they need
someone with your ex they need someone with your expertise, someone actually they need.
Whether you call yourself a tester or a developer who happened to have a specialization in test
automation, you'd be doing the same thing. And I think at I would be willing to bet that a
companies that perhaps make a similar thing without someone they call a dedicated testing
or test automation specialist, that a developer has picked up most of the same tasks that you
are doing now. I think given your background, you have some more experience and expertise to
make it work right now. But I think it's semantics. I do want to go back on one thing and underline
the test automation pyramid slash triangle for those who must make the argument.
A lot of people look at the, they see the, probably almost everyone's seen the picture,
but few people have read the accompanying article where Mike Cohn says that for that top level,
just write as few of these as possible or a few of these as needed. And in your case,
the money flow, not only is that necessary to make sure you take people's money,
I would argue that that's a test that needs to run in production and fire an alert if it fails.
That's one of the goals that I have is to eventually be able to do that. Right now,
we rely, so like the upside for us is that we have regular, I mean, so we use data,
we use a bit of data, we don't use it as extensively perhaps as we could,
but we do have a lot of monitoring in place. And at least for the e-commerce flows,
and we have people going through that every few minutes. It is funny, though, New Relic
has an application, they pitched it to us, we use New Relic for our application monitoring,
and they have other applications that they sell as a part of their solution. And one of them is
literally, oh, yeah, if you can write some JavaScript, we can constantly go through your
checkout flow and tell you when things don't work. And I was like, are you guys just using Selenium?
And they're like, oh, yes, we are. And I was like, okay, so we're not going to pay you for that
because I can do that on my own. But it was one of those things where you're like, we can just keep
going through your checkout flow and then alert you when things happen. I'm like, yeah, so can
we? Like, that's not a big deal. But we haven't done it yet.
You have to put yourself in a, without your experience, someone else may go,
well, that sounds amazing. Do your magic for us.
Yeah, but everything has to be so like, the way I approach it is, and I'm very specific when I
say we have a set of targeted UI tests. And what that means is, and we, like you guys harp on this,
I harp on this too, you don't want hundreds and hundreds of these things. You don't want to just
always be creating them because then you are one not improving the business, right? You're creating
a mess of maintenance. One of the things that I like about my current infrastructure is like,
I don't have to maintain stuff very much. I use so I use WebDriver IO, that's a JavaScript version
of Selenium. I've had to do a lot more maintenance recently because they upgraded to version five,
and then just came out with version six. So I'm, I'm scrambling to upgrade. But outside of that,
I can basically just walk away and my tests work for the longest periods of time. And I don't have
to typically worry about it. So I'm trying not to create more work for myself, so that I can go
and do other work. That to me is very modern testering. Yep, I can't I can't argue with that.
I want to change the subject for one last question, because there'll be some dives here too.
I have you have helped change my feelings toward AST, the Association of Software Testing over
the years. So can you talk about how you got involved there? If or how you've seen the
organization change, just catch me up. Tell me about what's going on with you and AST and
just do that. Tell me, tell me about just do that. Just just, yeah,
I won't get into the the my deeper questions yet. So let's just start with.
Yeah, and we should have those deeper questions because we're going to get there.
We're going to get there. So I found the AST because I was I started working for a small
startup. I was I just on my first testing conference, which was star West. And the
reason that was important was because I live in Los Angeles, and that is down in Anaheim next
to Disneyland. And that was groundbreaking because I got to meet other testers, see how
other people did things. And then all of a sudden, like it didn't necessarily make I
very quickly came to the realization that I knew nothing about the thing that I was doing,
and had been doing for several years. So I went looking for other ways to learn. And I came across
the BBST courses that AST teaches. Those are created by Chem Caner. He gave those out. That's
all free, open source. So if you go to testingeducation.org, that is a lot of the
BBST material that the AST uses. And I took all the courses. The courses are crazy in depth.
They're all university level. You can't memorize stuff. You it's not just like you go through a
MOOC and you answer a bunch of true and false questions. In order to pass the class, you have
to work with people from all over the world on projects in a sort of in a pretty realistic way,
except in a very distributed way where sometimes people don't participate at all, and you're left
doing all the work for them. And then in order to pass a class, you have to
take essay questions and answer them in a way that shows that you understand the questions.
And so that was such a huge challenge. The courses required 10 to 15 hours per week,
which is crazy to do when you're working full time. But I ended up doing those. I ended up
learning so much that by the end, I went back and looked at the first course that I took. And
I was like, how did I ever pass this class? I'm stupid and terrible. Like I didn't understand
how to answer questions. And then I eventually was like, this is great. I want to start teaching
this. I started teaching that. I've probably been teaching with them for over 10 years. So
I'm an instructor. I help teach the courses. I'm actually now that I'm on the board of the AST,
I'm actually going back and updating all those materials as we speak to try and make them more
modern, make them easier to read. And so my end, the AST was founded by a lot of testing
luminaries. James Bach, Ken Caner, Doug Hoffman, all these people that have these deep roots within
testing and specifically context driven testing. And I think that obviously has influenced the way
that I understand testing. But I also just find it just hugely historic and rich in a lot of
testing knowledge and that kind of stuff. And I've had the chance to teach alongside
Ken Caner, I've had the chance to teach along James Bach. But of course, the AST is different now
and Ken Caner is retired. We've had conversations within the AB testing Slack channel about
everyone's experiences. And these are individual people, they're flawed people.
People don't get along with everyone. In fact, James Bach is very controversial.
That's an understatement.
Yeah, yeah. His rapid software testing stuff. I don't agree with some of the stuff that they do.
Like I'm not a fan of testing versus checking. But that's okay, because I know when it's useful,
and I know when it's not, and I can navigate those things. And so as a part of AST, the reason that
I became a board member, and the reason that I do these webinars, which thank both you and
Brent, you guys both did great webinars. I'm trying to make sure that people that are in
context-driven testing or not, that they have just this wide range and understandings. And really,
I like to highlight the disagreements. Because the disagreements are real. These are real things
that we all live in. You don't have to live and die by them, but you should be aware of them and
the pitches and the things that people are talking about.
Yeah, let me dive in a little bit deeper. Your involvement in AST has helped me change my opinion.
When AST was first formed, I joined because I thought it was a good thing. And then
both Chem Caner and Caner, I think I told the story. I won't tell it now, but if you go back
on one of the podcasts, I'll tell the story about how I really pissed off Chem Caner for
doing literally nothing. Whatever. Doesn't matter. Moving on. And Bach and I have sort of a,
James Bach and I have sort of a truce going now, but I would just push back on him just trying
to be a jerk sometimes. And we kind of made up, we just kind of stay out of each other's paths.
But those guys have moved on. Like it's the people on the board now are like you,
like Ilari's on there, if I remember right. And Eric, there's some, you can see it's changing
with the times. And I really flipped the bit back on the good side permanently. Was it last year you
had charity majors as your keynote? Yeah, we did. And that's, you know, that's, that's having
someone who's big on observability, which is some of the basis of being able to test in production
or being able to trust production to understand what's going on. No, it doesn't mean the users
are doing all your testing. But that was, to me, that was like, Oh, they are caught up to
the 21st century. Thank you, AST. So it's good to see that happening. And the courses are good.
I've had employees at Unity take some of the BBST courses. I have another one might be taking
another one coming up here. They're ridiculously affordable, I think. I think it's like $300 for
a class. Yeah. So the upside and downside of the AST is it's all run by volunteers, right? So
everyone on the board is volunteer. Everyone teaching those classes is a volunteer that has
upsides and downsides. One of the upsides is it's incredibly affordable. Even we actually,
they're very global. I haven't taught a course that's been majority US and eight years, right?
They're just everyone from all over the world that do them. They're really affordable,
but they're also taught by volunteers. So you set your expectations around those lines. Literally
everyone that is teaching and taking the courses, they all have full-time jobs. They're all doing
that. But that's just the value. And it speaks volumes about people that do this kind of stuff.
They're doing it because they really, really love it.
And I will make sure I include links to... I wish it was AST.org, but that's actually some
other company's website. It's associationforprompertesting.org.
Yeah. It's way too long of a name. We've tried to buy it. It's too generic. But yeah. And so I will
say too that the AST is trying to keep up with the Ministry of Test. And to a large degree,
it's a lot of the AST is actually trying to figure out what we do now. Back when you joined,
AST was sort of the one group trying to do this kind of stuff. And again,
when you're dealing with just volunteers who are spending their nights and weekends trying to do
this kind of stuff, you only get so far. And trying to pull yourself out of the debates and
that you need to push people out who aren't doing the thing you think is right has basically passed.
And now we're trying to usher in this new idea of where does the AST provide value outside of
education. And so if you have any ideas, if you want to help out, please, by all means,
I'm all the ears. Or if you have a great idea for a webinar, I'm all the ears on that too.
Yeah. One of the things, because I think this COVID thing is going to go on for a little while
longer, is I'm going to try and do some more webinars. If you have anything you want me to
talk about, just let me know. I'll do one. I will. I'll keep that in mind.
I think that I don't have to travel that way. And yeah, I think people just need it now more
than ever. There's fewer conferences going on. So sign me up if anything comes up.
Okay. I'll do that.
Trying to think of random lame things I can livestream. So far my list is short.
I mean, it's all kind of funny too. So I think test coaching, we talked a little bit about this.
Test coaching is this very sort of abstract thing that I still don't know what it is.
And so when we did the webinar, when you were talking about, I forget, the abuse and misuse
of test automation, one of the things that struck me that we've already talked about was like,
how do you how do you help coach? And we sort of did talk about a little bit where you like start
with unit tests, ask people what tests they're writing. I think those approaches are probably
really valuable and very specific enough that people can get started. And I don't think people
talk about that enough. And so I'd like to see more stuff on test coaching just personally,
so that I can get a better idea of am I already doing this? Is this what test coaching is about?
Can I do more? There's all kinds of stuff. I will say too that I've done a couple of
lightning talks around the modern testing principles. And even at CAST last year, there were just,
you know, 50% or more of the audience knew what or had heard of the modern testing principles.
And so it's my favorite part about this is that it's showing people that this is what the current
state is and how people can look at that and go that doesn't like we're not even close to that yet.
And does that mean that you're just in a development process that's 20 years old?
And so I think those are maybe those things are all and so that's really informative. Because as
somebody when you go and do these courses, you start searching the web and you're trying to learn
about what is the current state of something, it is hard to really get definitive answers on that
kind of stuff. Even if they're wrong, these are models, right? The principles are models for
about how this thing looks according to the people talking about it. And so then you can
start to break that down and apply and see where it applies and where it doesn't.
Yeah, I, yes, yes, yes, and yes. One quick thought I had, then we better close here, is
I think test coaching is such a new thing. And it's people like Rob Meaney and Anne Marie
Cherrett and others who are talking about it. But right now, I think if you ask 10 different
people what test coaching was, they would give you 11 different answers. So I think it's emerging.
And it makes me think I need to figure out, and maybe this is a webinar or me just hosting a chat
session sometime, a sync or a series of syncs, it'd be good to hash it out and start to define
what that is. Because I think it's a lot of different things. And some of it's more
consulting than coaching. But when do we do one versus the other? I think it's growing.
You and Brent had this conversation. We did. I'm not even sure I remember what the difference was.
That's how subtle it is. Yeah, yeah. Yeah, I'll get into it another time. But it was fantastic
hearing what's going on. I no longer hate all test automation engineers.
I get what you're doing. Oh, good. And so that was a success. And I love to hear what's going on
with AST. I think, like I said, my opinion grows and grows. And it's a solid organization. So
glad to see you involved there and making such a difference. And of course, most of all,
thank you for hanging out with me for a little while today and being on the ABT 343 podcast.
Thank you very much for the opportunity. All right. Great talking with you.
And we'll see you later. Have a good one. Bye.