Welcome to A.B. Testing Podcast, your modern testing podcast. Your hosts, Alan and Brent,
will be here to guide you through topics on testing, leadership, agile, and anything else
that comes to mind. Now, on with the show.
I don't even know how to start this one. Hey, everyone, I'm Alan.
I'm Brent.
And we're back for the COVID-19 edition of the A.B. Testing Podcast. Does it have a
number?
We should change the episode to COVID-19 and not the 111 or 117.
Perhaps, perhaps, perhaps. So as you may guess, and you can never get the compressed computer
audio to sound quite as good as live, but Brent and I are not in the same room.
We are not.
I'm in Brent's basement. He doesn't know it yet. Wait, do you have a basement?
I do not. But if you were in my basement, I would know. Your family wouldn't, but I
would.
That sounds very, very creepy. So interesting times, huh?
Yeah. It's fun being in Washington state right now, huh? Although I guess it doesn't mean
much to you, I would imagine.
No, I think as I've maybe mentioned on the podcast before, I work from home quite a bit
these days. So it didn't change much for me. What has changed, and maybe we should do
a bit of a segment and talk on the impact it's had on us at our jobs and in tech in
general. All of my colleagues are now working from home as well. We have, of course, Washington
is everyone absolutely works from home at most of our other sites. I don't say highly
recommended. People are expected to work from home, but if they need to come in, they can.
But in Seattle, it's no stay home, do not come to the office.
Well, yeah, it's still only recommended, but that's 100% true. It's sort of a super strong
recommendation.
I was telling somebody that, let me just actually walk through from some experiences on my
client, then I'll ask how you're doing, how you're coping with it. I found it more difficult
to work from home at Microsoft. It could have been the teams I was on, I think actually
it varies from team to team and how they work. Or maybe that statement's wrong, and I evolved
into learning it once I began managing a globally distributed team. I was taking care
of my dad a few years ago, and I worked from home for two weeks while I stayed with
me. Hardly anybody even knew I wasn't in the office. I still effectively managed my
team and got a lot of stuff done.
So then when I moved into my current role about 10 months ago, believe it or not, I
began working from home more and more into the stage where I was working from home three
to four days a week. And then so we decided to, we should all work from home full time.
It really was no change for me. Somehow I've learned, and we can reflect on the things
that have helped me be productive and be a regular worker at home. Sort of my evolution
of becoming a work from home person.
With all that background set up, what's it been like for you the last couple of days,
weeks? How long have you been working from home?
It's now officially one week. And I will tell you, except for being able to wear my
pajamas all day long, I find it mostly a downside. So I'm still in the, what is it,
the learning, storming, you know, the little cliche manager speech about team
forming. I'm not mastered it. It's a change that I'm finding more irritating than
not. You have to cope, obviously. The next hit that just landed, as you know,
our governor has closed all schools in three major counties in Washington state.
My kids, my kids just began the first day of their six week spring break.
So is the quad just closing? Yes.
So I'm in the North Shore School District. And not only that, I'm in the Snohomish
County. North Shore School District is going online. So my son has been home for
a week already. His school is fully online.
I think that's because, is that because one of the earlier cases hit up there
and they had time to plan for that? Actually, the first case, the earlier cases
were with retirement home that was literally two miles away from my last
house. But that's still in King County. It's in Kirkland. For those of you, quick
geography lesson. States in the US are broken into counties and Snohomish
County is the county, one county north of King County. King County is where
Seattle and Bellevue and Red Bend and all the it's probably the definitely the
largest populated county in Washington and Snohomish is just a few miles north.
There we go. Back to our regularly scheduled Brent.
So my daughter starts online on Monday. They don't she goes to private schools.
So they don't have sort of the infrastructure say that my son was a
high school has. But I guess I will cope. I had a she's 10 years old.
I had sat down with her. I don't know. I don't know what you're doing with your
family. I'll tell you in a minute. Yeah. So my oldest that's still at home is is 18.
And I just kind of just bear with it until I can kick him out of the house.
My daughter, though, she's only 10 and she's a bit confused. And so I'm trying
to keep things as normal as possible for her. I told her last night today's
officially as the day off for her. But then this new paradigm starts on Monday.
And I'm like, yep, we'll talk about it over the weekend. But you'll still have
much of the same discipline requirements as if you were to school. I'm going to
get her up roughly the same time, probably not exactly the same time, but
roughly the same time and try to do some structure so that she still has
that. And then have to figure out the next thing to go is is that I'm worried
about is what happens if Comcast goes down. Right.
Or if Amazon stops delivering. Right. We have real potential catastrophes that
could happen. Well, so grocery stores are still open. I've visited several times
myself. Yep. I went yesterday, put my hazmat suit on, went out. No, I just I
just washed my hands before and after I left. Yeah, I've learned. I've learned
recently how to make your own hand sanitizer. Turns out it's super easy.
Yeah, I did too. So we do you buy a jar of aloe vera and then get a bottle of vodka
and then drink the vodka until you don't care anymore. Oh, you know what? That's
a that's a that's a good modification. It's something like that. I think I read
that somewhere. It's again, I think that's a vastly superior modification.
And well, for those who who just want to go with the standard way of making
it, you do need a you get a jar of aloe vera gel. You mix it with rubbing alcohol.
The internets will tell you the exact proportions. And if you have if you're
into aroma therapy and you have those what they call essential oils, you can
flop in a couple drops of that and then make it a scented hand sanitizer.
Beautiful. You know, I hadn't looked up recipes. I'd have to tell you I was at
the grocery store yesterday as mentioned a moment ago. And you know, they have those
little those stands of things they put up near the register for the impulse buy.
Yeah, they had a whole stand of ever clear. So my only thought was that people
were making sand hand sanitizer hand sanitizer out of it. So is it do you know that recipe?
No, but eventually that would work. What's the percentage of ever clear?
But it's like 180. It's ridiculous. I don't know if you can see my screen.
No, I cannot see your screen. Why shouldn't you use ever clear to make hand sanitizer?
Is a website hand sanitizer selling out of the source. But doctors say you're better off
washing your hands. All right. There you go, folks. Yes, that's what I do. We wash our hands.
Our soap our soap expenses are full. So let me I don't know if you're done, but I'm gonna go
ahead and talk about I mean, it's tougher with a 10 year old. Luckily, my kids are both teenagers.
We talked a little bit about expectations last night. And this is actually going to go into a
topic that that you will have some input on. I just mentioned the things we agreed on, we
haven't figured out a schedule yet. I do believe that teenagers work better on a cycle where they
get up a little bit later. So I will let them sleep in a little not until noon, but I'm fine
with tennis. But they know they have expectations of getting their chores done every day. And then
they know they may have a few extra. They have expectations of doing something because they're
not they're out of school completely. So there's expectations around doing something with their
brain. So expectations of reading a book. My son is working on a game and Python. He can,
I told him until you've been ready to throw your computer out the window,
you're not a real programmer. So keep going. And so my daughter is taking art history class on Khan
Academy for for AP credit at school, she's going to continue that and finish that. But just making
sure they have some intellectual things and then just getting outside, keeping a distance from people,
of course, because who knows which ones are going to be zombies, but just not being in the house
all day. And we'll figure out the the actual percentages later. But as as this these next
weeks evolve, but something I did when they were much younger, which I haven't done in a while.
And I know you've done successfully in the past is I'm thinking about setting up a Kanban board
for this was swim lanes for brain chores and health. Yeah. Making sure making sure that they
get a certain number of story points done per day in each column, and we can visualize our work.
I want to keep them from just kind of vegging out all day, which would be a really easy thing
for me to let them do. But I'm still in my office working 40 hours a week on phone calls on Zoom
calls like this one for about 30 of those. So I need to count on them to be self sufficient in
getting their crap done without me nagging them. Yeah, it's a hassle. It's around creating that
structure. And right now, I'm working as well from home. There's one thing I discovered that
the meeting behavior has changed. Oh, that's interesting because I do so many remote meetings
that I haven't really seen that. But I don't know if I told you this, I have a growing team now.
After not having one for a while, but I still don't have any direct reports in within 700 miles of me,
closest I have or San Francisco. So I'm curious to tell me a little bit more about the
what changed the meetings for you. We now have a whole bunch of people that have shifted over
untrained to full time working from home. And the first thing I've noticed is as everyone
complains is the hallway chatter has stopped. Yes. You have to find a place to replicate the
water cooler conversation. Yeah, you do. And what I'm finding is that they are in fact doing that,
but what they're doing instead of asking their three minute question and going away,
what they're doing is they're setting up a half hour meeting. We covered their three minute question.
And then it's, I forget the name of the principal. It's an old management principle, one that I have
observed a million times. And that is work expands to fit available time. That's Parkinson's law.
I spend three minutes on the P zero. And then I, I attempt to do some passive aggressive, hey,
so anything else? And, but then they go, well, since I have you on the phone,
can I go through all of my P one to P 250 items with you?
One of the things that's helped out a lot in our transition, and maybe, and I could be
reading this wrong, but the autonomy, most of our employees and I mostly have more senior
employees, they're very autonomous. They figure out what to do on their own and they do it.
They, they, we account on them to do their own prioritization almost all the time.
However, a couple anecdotes to throw at you. One is a couple of my teams have set up just
the morning coffee meeting, 15 minute zoom meeting, no work talk, just, you know, drinking some coffee,
asking, you know, how things are going, what's new with them, and that's helped them stay connected.
But the more interesting is, I don't know if you fall on the, the more introverted or more
extroverted tendencies. You absolutely do know that we're both INTP.
Are we both INTP? We are.
It's a spectrum, the introversion part. I like working from home. I don't, I don't miss
seeing people in person. Some people are really motivated by that. And I've,
I've never really noticed the impact of that. Everyone's working from home.
I have some employees who are very introverted. And after a couple days to a week of working
from home, they're telling me, I don't think I ever want to work in an office again.
And there's some people that have been home for a day or two and thought,
and are thinking, I can't stand this. I'm going to die.
So just being able to, as a manager, being able to figure out which employees are which and kind
of give them what they need, give them some more, if they need, if they need to be,
if they need people, give them more opportunities to virtually connect with people, do a water
cooler. I know some people are doing an open zoom meeting during the day. They just kind of keep
zoom open. People can drop in and say hi in a zoom meeting whenever they want.
You need to adapt. I think it's going to be interesting. There's been a culture of work
from home for a lot of people. We see them on Twitter all the time, at least.
And a whole bunch of people who are going to now have to learn it. I think a lot of
advancements are going to be made. So I'm pretty excited about that. And yeah.
Yeah.
So you're going to say?
No, it's like my team in particular is mostly introverts. Our usual daily standup has changed
from being around 15 minutes to consistently a half hour. And I think it's roughly that
personal check-in that you just referred to. The behavior I've seen is, again,
my personal autonomy feels like it has gone way down. I am much more beholden
to my meeting schedule than honestly ever before. And that may be what is driving me
personally crazy. There is a phrase I use a lot, and it's relevant in this case, and that is
too much talky, not enough to do it. And that's how I feel this last week.
I wonder if you'll find underlying... In fact, I would expect that you would find
underlying ways of working or principles that were actually affecting you before
the way you worked on your teams or the way I should say, the way we work in general on
our teams in the industry, that will only be highlighted now that everyone's working remotely.
I think we may discover some new inefficiencies as well as some new accelerants in how we work.
So interesting. So it's like drinking. The more you drink, different people become
different people. I think I can find a better way to put that. People are in a different situation.
They're going to learn some new ways of doing things, and some of those new things are going
to be things they should continue when they go back to their old way or their old situation or
environment. That's what I'm saying. Yeah, I have spent a lot of time just in the last week going,
I wonder what new patterns are going to pop up.
Exactly. And that's what I think we need to pay attention to and highlight. I think on
my teams, I actually have a hunch that our work will accelerate as people. It'll be a little
slower at first, and then we're going to end up getting faster. We'll see how well that works out.
But I'm hoping that's true, and I'm also hoping when we go back to working in the office, we can
take some of those things that have made us work better and keep doing those, even though we're
back in the old environment. Well, yeah, if you can identify it as the cause and then call it out
explicitly, like in a retrospective environment. Yeah, and I think one of the things we can do
as leaders in the software industry on our teams as we're going through this is look for the patterns.
Look at what's working. Look what's not working. We do these same things in retros now.
We can look at it a little bit. We want to look at it through the lens of everybody working from home.
Yeah, so do you recall feeling anything along the lines of what I'm doing now?
The sense of emotion, the sense of adapting, the sense of struggling through it.
Did you have any of that experience? Because I'm guessing not because you made an explicit decision.
It was also very gradual. I would work from home a day a week maybe before I moved to this new role.
The impetus for me working from home not wasn't me deciding I wanted to work from home.
I would have so many early morning meetings trying to talk to teams in Europe that it would
be noon and I go, well, students noon already. I've been in meetings since six. I'm not going
into work today. So that was really, then that happened more and more often. And finally,
I decided, hey, I don't have any meetings in the office. Why am I going to the office at all?
I could be productive during that commute time. So one of the things that worked for me was
being very gradual. There's a gradual change. I think for most people, the change has not been
gradual. It has been, I'm in the office every day, seeing my friends, having snacks, eating food,
and now I'm home and I have to make my own lunch. Yeah, my wife and I have a standing
lunch schedule on Tuesdays. And one of my favorite sushi places,
sorry, in the world is just down the street from my house. And I was, oh, hey,
no commute for either of us. Hey, let's go to Oceana. And it's interesting. She's like,
no, we're just going to have sandwiches here at home. So yeah, I mean, there's some impact.
There's another one that I've noticed with myself. And I'm wondering how you deal with this since
on this call, you are definitely the working from home expert. So I've noticed, I never had
noticed this before, but now it is just super clear and string in my face, the importance of
the commute for me personally, to transition into modes. And what I mean is sort of home.
Nope, I get it completely. I understand what you mean. In fact, one time, the time before I just
moved 12 years ago, we looked at a house, I mean, an offer on a house that was walking distance to
Microsoft. And one of the reasons we kind of backed out of the deal was that I wasn't sure
what I was going to do without a commute time, because that transition both to and from can
really help. And you get used to it. Yeah, I think still having a ritual in the morning,
a be a pattern helps, it helps my dog, my dog knows exactly what goes on in the morning. So
here's my day, I get up always a half hour before my first meeting. Why may you ask? Because I need
that time to in that half hour, I can take a shower. Because normally I have my camera on,
I did not take a shower this morning for you. But I get up, I take a shower, I go downstairs,
I feed the dog, I take the dog outside, I come back in, I get a big glass of water, I get a cup
of coffee, and I make sure that I've rehydrated and had a little bit of caffeine before I begin
the day. So I need that half hour. Otherwise, I can't. I'm not a full participant in that first
meeting. Now, I'm not saying you have to start your meetings at six, but that, that routine
is my commute. I use that half hour, where you can say you're driving for a half hour, my half hour is
me transitioning from my bed to going to work. So that works out. So you need some sort of
routine to replace the old routine. The other part is how do I transition out? Now, I used to
end my day, late afternoon, I would run to the gym. I just decided a couple days ago that I'm
not going to go to the gym anymore until things settle down. It's a gross, slimy place. It's
probably too much, but oh well. But the weather's getting a little bit better, cool, but clear,
not as freezing outside. So these last couple days, what I try and do at the end of the day,
when I'm done for the day, is I go for a walk. And that's where I catch up on the other thing
missing from my commute, which is listening to podcasts. Since when I commute in the car,
I listen to podcasts. That's how I stay caught up in all my podcasts I listen to.
I still have time to do that. End of the day, take the dog, go for a walk,
half hour, listen to a podcast, come back, wash my hands. And that's my commute home.
And this is my ritual, but I think the main tip there is have a ritual, have something
you do in the morning on your commute to work and something that counts as your commute away
from work. And it's going to be different for everyone. But I don't think the point is to
copy mine, but the point is to have one, have some sort of thing that transitions you into
the work day. Yeah, actually the work day transition for me is not the one to struggle
with the most. It's the end of work day. For example, this whole week, and I don't know how
long I'll continue to do this this whole week. What is common for me is when it's near the end of my
day, I will text my wife and let her know, hey, I'll be leaving soon. And then when I'm actually
starting the car and coming home, I'll text her saying I'm leaving. And I've been doing that every
day this last week, just because it's funny, because I'll text her and I'll text her, hey,
I'm leaving work. And then go, hey, honey, I'm home. Obviously, that's not enough time to sort of
drain all of the hot work stuff that was in your head just before you left
and into shifting the mode. I think it's something smart there that you sort of shut down work.
In other words, your commute time is part of your work day and you need to account for it,
not ignore it. Make it when you're transitioning to this, find a useful,
similar period of time, replace it with something that is not work.
Yes, exactly. Yes, I fully agree.
I don't have a dog.
Okay, you have legs, you can still go for a walk. Read a book, watch a TV show, do something,
and get out of work mode. But one thing to bring up is for me, because sometimes I will take a break
in the middle of the day to go see what the kids are doing. Or in fact, it's good. In fact,
sitting at your just because you're home, you probably don't walk around your house as much
as you may walk around the office doing things. So it's still good to get out of your seat
and get out of the cave that is your office once in a while. Yeah, do something.
Sure. What I've been doing on that front is, and I don't know, I have to think of this,
if I think this is good or bad, but it's right now making me happy. As you know, Microsoft is
leveraging Microsoft Teams for most of its working from home adventures.
And there is a desktop version and a mobile version. So those meetings where,
not all of them, but I would say maybe one in three, where I know it's mostly talking.
If I say anything at all, it's talking, I'm not going to be presenting. No one's going to be asking
me to do an on the spot analysis. So I don't need to be right on my computer.
I'll just take the meeting outside, take a break, go outside. If it's raining, I'll still meet my
patio. If it's not, then I'm just wandering around. Hey, I want to throw out one last tip,
then a transitory statement, and then a new topic. So my tip is, can I remember three things? It's
a big challenge here. Here, take bets now. The tip is for people doing one-on-ones for the first time
remotely. I've done one-on-ones remotely for the last coming up on three years, a ton of them every
week. It's really easy to get at a computer like, oh, they're talking. They're telling me stuff,
maybe I knew I'm going to peek over at Slack or Reddit or email or whatever. One tip I do is,
when I'm in one-on-ones, I always sit with my arms either folded or behind my head,
and those are in the view of the camera. Maybe it's weird, maybe nobody notices,
but it's my way of showing that I'm actually paying attention because my fingers aren't on
the keyboard. It also happens that I have mechanical keyboards so they can hear if I'm typing.
So I will first praise you because I too am one with mechanical keyboards. For me, it's more
defensive. So years ago in my career, I had an ergonomics team and I was forming carpal
tonal and it was discovered. The membrane keyboards is what was causing it because instinctively,
if the keyboard doesn't make a noise, I was pounding it with my fingers to make the mechanical keyboard
noise. But yeah, one-on-ones, I'm not having as much of a problem. I'm actually finding,
in some regards, I think I'm doing a better job as a manager with working from home with one-on-ones.
So what I've shifted it to is a lot more of having them do screen shares and asking them questions
about their work. So it's rather easy. So at home or at work, what I would do is that they had
something and then like an insight or what's common with employees. I'm really good at connecting
dots and putting the pattern together. And my team has learned that. And so what we'll do is
they'll come and they'll show me some random spreadsheet or something and then they'll say,
okay, do you see anything here? And I'll just start clicking away. And one of the things that
I have done that I think is effective is while it's rather easy to ask for permission to
manipulate the screen on their side, don't. But I'm finding that I'm using, as I tell my children,
I'm using my words more to be clear around those specific, you know, hey, click this, scroll up.
And then that does transform into more of a coaching learning experience.
All right. I'm going to have you put a pin in coaching. We're going to come back to that.
But I did want to make one call out the transitory statement from my three things earlier. And then I
want to talk more about coaching in the context of quality coaching. So the one call out I want
to make is to Ministry of Test. They, I think they're a fantastic organization. I would say that
even if there wasn't a modern testing course on their website, they have had to cancel their
second test batch. They canceled test batch in Detroit and they just canceled test batch in
Brighton because it's the right thing to do. Very mature. I'm glad they did it. But
one way to support, what I would love to see them do is do some, do an online conference.
And I know Joel says free, but I wonder if they did a, I just retweeted Rosie this morning who
said the best way to support Ministry of Test right now is to get a pro membership. And again,
the pro memberships are so much value there. Even if you don't like modern testing, there's
other courses on there. You get so much content. I'm hoping they do something like a pro, a pro only
webinar or pro only conference or pro only webinars or something.
I hope they can find a way to, I think it'd be a fair way for them to try and
keep some revenue coming in during this time when they don't have those conferences or find a way to
do virtual meetups, just keep people connected. So big fans, if you're listening from Ministry
of Test, let us know how they can help everything we can do, but it's going to be interesting
economic times for everyone going forward. So I want to just give them a call out and just
please give them your support. So quick comment, and then we're going to go on the test coaching.
Sure. I had not realized that's what was occurring. I do imagine that these conferences are a large
source of their income, right? The ability to do the conferences,
Joel's, but the OTC is all mine and free. Obviously, MOT could reach out to Joel and
figure out some of those things. But in terms of it being an income source, not at all certain.
I do think MOT is one of the better sources of modernized thought processes on this context.
And I would very much like to see them first of survive this. Second, I still see them
as a leader of the next stage for individuals in the quality space. And I think it's somewhat
saddening if they don't bounce back quickly and adapt.
Yeah, don't make it sound like the end of the world for them. I just want to give them a little nudge
in the right direction. So I can hear you typing, man.
Yeah, I'm actually going to go sign up for a premium account.
Oh, good for you, man. I want to talk about test coaching, something we've brought up here
quite a bit. And it's interesting to see there are more and more people like Rob Meaney and
Marie Charet and others whose names I've forgotten to mention right now who are doing
test coaching and seeing test coaching as something that is a natural evolution of
the role of the dedicated test specialist, which we're talking about a lot in our podcasts.
I probably even mentioned it in the Ministry of Test Modern Testing course and in probably
the talks I've given on modern testing. I have two people on my team and my org who I consider to be
test or quality coaches. So the role is growing. And then Lisa refers to this,
Lisa Crispin, as more of a test consultant. And it took me a while to take that to heart,
but I'm going to ask you a question. What's the difference between a coach and a consultant?
A coach has a vested interest.
I guess you could put it that way if you think of the external consultant who doesn't care. A lot of
consultants do have a vested interest. So I think it's possible for a person like when I think about
what I do, and maybe it depends on my definitions, but I drift frequently between coaching and
consulting based on context. With coaching, I want to change the behavior. Coaching is more about
asking questions. How do you think that worked? What would you do differently? When I switch
into my consulting hat, it's more of more direct advice. I'm helping them solve a technical problem
or I'm helping them solve a problem versus helping them solve the problem themselves.
It's subtle, but it's different. So let me offer a paradigm shift.
A paradigm shift in the middle of our podcast. Jeez, go for it.
But yeah, it's not a tangent. It's a paradigm shift.
Blah, blah, go ahead. All right. My son plays baseball.
Noted. You big fan of soccer. Me big fan of NFL. These three different spaces, I'll have coaches
and all have consultants. So what I do is when you ask that question, I go, okay, that shifted to the
most common place thing in my mind of where coaches and consultants exist. And what is their
clear roles? And then after sort of working through that, let's map it back to the space
where Alan asked and see if it fits. For me, I'm very tight with my son's baseball coach.
He's paid. But that spirit of payment, like that fiscal responsibility
mostly around survivability, as you know from Daniel Pink's studies.
Finances is a motivator, but it's absolutely one of the weaker ones. Social motivation is
significantly stronger. And he takes accountability. It's not accountability in terms of who to blame,
but accountability for who feels responsible, who's going to spend the time and dedication
to make it happen. Whereas a consultant, I kind of view a consultant as, oh, yeah, here's some
advice. So to take what you want from a consultant, throw away the rest. The consultant doesn't have
a horse in the race. That's the difference in my mind. Well, I think you're thinking of
bringing in the consultant from the agency. I think there's an activity of consulting
that consultants do. This is sounding very much like not me talking. But the way I think of it
is when I'm coaching, I'm helping people get through habit changes, changing their beliefs,
changing their outcomes, figuring out what's in the way of them getting the results they want.
So coaching is a lot of times therapist a little bit. Whereas in my consulting hat,
there's a skill gap I'm addressing. So is it a skill they're missing? I need to help them with,
which I do a lot with test coaching. In consulting, I may say, oh, you should look at,
there's a Python library that'll help here. Go look it up and run it. That's consulting. Coaching is,
what have you tried? It's more of the thing you do when I do one-on-ones, I'm coaching.
When I'm meeting with the team to talk about why their velocity or quality aren't where they
want them to be, I'm probably doing more consulting in that meeting. Maybe I'm putting
too much effort into breaking it down. And I know there is a little bit of stigma from some people,
including especially you in this case, that a consultant is this pointy hair guy that comes
in and tells you what to do and takes a crap on your stuff.
Oh, no, no, no. So consultants are fine in that case. I'm not certain why you phrase it that way.
I think you said they're not vested, which I read as the consultants don't care.
Well, but then, so I would say the consultants don't have a vested interest in you following
their guidance. Okay. And when I say don't care, I don't mean that, so there's an aspect of
apathy, I agree. But there is also an aspect of objectivity that I think consultants bring in,
that thing you accuse me of, hey, you hate consultants because they don't care.
No, that's not necessarily a negative thing. I'm just trying to differentiate it.
Okay. This has been a little bit of a tangent. I'm going to loop us back in. So I'm going to
ask you a different question. Is it about testing versus checking?
No, it's about my butt. The question is, do you have a definition of a test coach?
And then question two is, do you think test coaching is a natural evolution in testing?
Well, we continue to see more and more testers become test coaches.
And if so, I can go backward. And if so, what does a test coach do?
So I do, and I'm pretty certain you do too, on do we see more and more of this occurring?
Yes, we do now.
Just as a reminder, there's this thing that me and this other person worked on,
of the modern testing principles. And principle number four calls that out.
We care deeply about...
Coach and nurture our teams. Yes.
Right.
So obviously we believe it and we're seeing it happen. It would have happened. And again,
the thing to come back to the principles is we weren't trying to dictate some brand new thing
people wanted to aspire to. We've just been documenting what we've been seeing happening
in the industry for years now. Now it's snowballing a little bit. It's happening more
and more.
Do I see the quality coach position improving or growing? Yeah, absolutely. Do I see
it be the place that saves the test community? No.
No.
No, I don't.
I think there's a lot of variation too in what test coaches do. So can you sum up,
like what are the main, what do you think are the main duties, the main activities of a test coach?
Um, you know what? I think you should do that. I'm a data scientist. I've never shifted to the test
coach role. So I think everything I would be doing would be like a data...
I'll dive in because I was just going to correct you anyway. No, I was curious in your opinion.
So I'll do mine. You can give me your thoughts on this. So I think a lot of test coaches,
well, if you can go back to Elizabeth Henderson's Explore It book, I don't know if she called it
coaching in that book, but she talked about teaching developers how to do exploratory testing.
And I've done plenty of that and that's part of it. But what you're really doing at a meta level
is giving developers more ideas on how to test. And that's what a test coach does.
I mentioned this before on the podcast. When my boss asks me how well our team is doing at testing,
I honestly can give him the same answer every time. And this is the first place you want to
get. Our developers do all the testing they know how to do, which is good because they're
not expecting anyone else to do their testing for them. But it's also accurate in that that
statement implies that there is more testing they could do. They just don't know how to do it yet.
That's why I have me and test coaches. We don't call them that. That's not their only job.
They help the teams understand what testing may be missing. They help the team understand
what quality processes they may need to improve. Do you go to Principle 5? Is Principle 5 our
quality culture one? Whatever principle is the quality culture one? Four. It's also four.
Excellent. Oh, perfect. Four is the coaching principle. So they're helping teams look,
they're often running retros for the team. In fact, very often in my org running retros for
the team, not their typical sprint retro, but retros on incidents or retros on issues affecting
quality and velocity, which are my two main priorities, and helping the team learn how to
understand where they need to improve using the quality culture transition guide as a model to
discover new areas they may want to get better in. So to me, that's what quality coaching is.
It's helping the team understand more ways of doing testing and helping the team improve their
quality culture, their approaches that help them make quality software in the first place. So
they're accelerating the achievement of shippable quality on their teams.
I guess you could have a test coach for a small team. You could say like on an Agile team,
the one tester on a team of seven or so is the quality coach. I think that works. In my case,
my quality coach is doing it for much larger chunks of people, multiple teams. How's that?
What do you want to add or detract or? I love that a great deal.
I'm blushing. And obviously, so one of our listeners asked, what do we see on this front?
How do we see it? It's relation to modern testing principles. And we see something that's very
aligned, very strong. It's unsurprising. Yeah. They also asked around quality engineering.
And right now I'm on Google trying to disprove the hypothesis that quality engineering is just
a rebrand of software automation engineers. I don't even know. I don't want to figure it out.
And I'm actually kind of surprised you're using Google and not Bing.
Aren't you required by law to use Bing? Because Bing can Google stuff.
Now that was under the Obama era. See episode two or three ago.
I have used nothing but Duck Duck Go for the last few months and I'm not unhappy.
Duck Duck. Oh, really? The first time you've heard of this?
Yeah, you crazy kids and your new angle thingies.
It's an ad for research engine. Oh, yeah. You actually, you have talked about this before.
I don't know if I have or not, but I got sick and tired of it. Got to the point where Google
showing a full page of promoted links before you can get the actual links you care about.
I just can't handle it. Yeah, it's interesting because I just sort of block it out.
Anyway, so quality engineering, we don't know right now. To me, it just seems like automation
engineer rebranded. The term I'm encouraging folks to actively pay attention to is observability
engineering. I think that one's going to be really keen, really keen skill sets for those
currently in the test organization to shift into the new forming options.
Yeah, that could be a whole different podcast episode on observability. But we'll save that.
There's one quote here from Megs in the one of the three.slack.com, which says,
the quality coaches we've spoken to have been coaching teams to support them on their path to
being able to deliver software faster while reducing unplanned rework. It's been all about
delivery rather than testing, which I find, and I don't know if I've ever mentioned this on the
podcast, but I find that statement wonderful because when I talk about what I do, my role isn't
delivery manager or director of delivery because those would be dumb titles. But when I describe
what I do, it's all things delivery. I take care of making sure we can deliver as fast as we can
without breaking too much. Yeah, in some regards. It's balancing velocity and quality. That's
entirely what I care about. And this goes back to one last thing that I'll let you jump in and
then we'll close is you and I, and this is, I almost threw this out in, I was someone sucked,
someone I didn't want into a Twitter conversation, so I ignored it. But I'm realizing more and more
that there are luminaries in testing who only care about testing. They don't give a shit
about quality. They care about testing. And you and I are the opposite. I really could,
I don't care about testing. I know it needs to happen and I have ideas on how to do it well,
but what I care about is quality. And I think that's a big difference in the transition from
traditional to, and actually modern testing has been referred to as the quality school by one of
these, by, I think, I don't want to quote Michael Bolton on that, but I think it's what he said.
No, I guess so. I don't, I don't remember what the schools all are, but
yeah, we care about quality, not testing. Sue us. There's space for that. It's not a contradiction.
It's just, as long as people understand the scope of the context, when, when someone who does care
about testing talks about it, I'm all for people having their passion, right? And, and there is
a large amount of space for people who do care about testing and wanting to improve it.
You and I are more system based. We care about quality because that's what makes people,
a society better and happier. The, you know, principle five, we care about,
essentially we care about the customer's point of view. I think about when we talked about quality
coaches, I think about, you know, the, the last type of coach that was super popular, I was the
agile coach, and their role was around how to take their expertise that they know and help teams
achieve their goals, but faster. Right. And your quote from, from Meg's, right, it's all about
delivery rather than testing. It's that rather that bothers me in that one. I definitely agree.
It's all about delivery. That's a hundred percent true. But I think a quality coach is going to be
focusing on, right? What is, what is the customer experience? What does customer telemetry say? What
does customer feedback say? As well as testing expertise and identifying those bottlenecks in the
system due to lack of knowledge. And here I will say the quality space, which will include
testing expertise. Yes. I'm not saying it's not needed. I would, however, hypothesize that some
of these folks in who are waving their testing flag over test. I think one of the things an agile
coach or a quality coach can do is recognize the right amount of testing to do for a given
scenario. They're good at that risk assessment. They know it's the popcorn popper theory of
shipping software. You want to ship software at that. Think of microwave popcorn popping in,
in the microwave. There's a sweet spot where you've popped the most popcorn you can without
burning any. That's when we ship. Maybe even then, right? I'm a big believer in,
it's around risk control. So very, very small bags of popcorn. If I can, if I can,
if I can ship something super small and mitigate the risk, like, you know, for example,
ship it under feature flag, turn it on for an hour, then turn it off. Then I get a lot of
solid, a lot more solid information. Of course. Then I do with spending that same hour
testing. Now that doesn't mean I'm not testing as well. What it does mean is I don't, I won't
spend a lot of time proactively testing the hypothetical. For sure. For sure. That's exactly
it. So we are out of time. We will do some editing and then we'll get this out and then we'll see what
the listeners think. I'm Alan. I'm Brad and I'll see you later. Yep.