This is the AB Testing 343 podcast, a podcast where we ask one of the three listeners of
the AB Testing podcast three questions about almost anything.
ABT 343 is a fun slice of what's going on in the world of modern testing.
Let's get started.
It's been a while, but we're back for another ABT 343.
And this time I just realized I forgot to ask our guests how to pronounce their last
name, but I'm going to go with our guests being Melissa Pullman.
You would be correct.
Awesome.
So I'm good so far.
I haven't screwed up anything too badly so far today.
So welcome.
Thank you.
Thank you for having me.
Luckily, this podcast is always remote.
We were talking briefly just ahead of me pressing record how great it's been that
Zoom has stayed up and running and how much of our, at least my life is in services
hosted in places in the cloud.
I don't know where they exist in the real world, but they don't involve people.
Yeah.
I also feel thankful that my world doesn't involve people.
There's a statement we could take out of context, but yeah, it's been, how are you
holding up?
Where are you located?
I am located in Portland, Oregon.
Not too far from here.
How are things in Portland?
How are you holding up with the new world we live in?
Well, it's funny.
My coworkers were just chatting about that on Slack and asking, what are the
weird things you've started doing?
I'm like, I'm just living the same I did a week ago.
So my life's pretty much set up to be okay with self-sufficiency to some extent,
being a little bit prepared, being a homebody.
So I'm doing okay.
I don't have children.
So I don't have that added huge amount of stress that a lot of my coworkers have.
And it seems a lot of the other listeners and people who are on the Slack channel
are expressing.
So things are okay, but yeah, people, it's a lot of things have slowed down here.
A lot more people walking around during the daytime.
So it feels neighborhoody, but also be nice if it wasn't because of this.
Yes.
I actually have had the exact same experience.
For me, it's been largely the same.
I've been dealing with a few more coworkers, learning how to work this way.
And I take the dog for a walk every day and I just see people in their yards and
people on their porches because the weather has been a little nicer and it feels a
lot more neighborhoody.
We don't walk up and introduce ourselves anymore, but you know, other than that,
well, you'll know each other now, right?
We, we, we wave from afar.
New world.
As you know, AB 2343, we're going to ask one of our three listeners,
three ish questions, but with my tendency to tangent,
it usually ends up being a little bit more, but we'll,
we can go ahead and get started.
So maybe a good place to start is, well, first of all, we don't know what you do,
but I want to lead into that.
Like what was your path into testing?
Talk us through a little bit,
how you got from where you were to where you are.
Um, yeah, I got here in a convoluted, disjointed manner.
Um, I graduated college many years ago with a undergraduate degree in studio art.
And, uh, I moved to Chicago and worked a couple of years there doing things
that were not going to be long-term sort of career things.
And I felt a little bit more ambitious than that.
So I took some more classes, computer, you know, in the computer science area,
didn't get a degree cause I just got a job instead.
Um, and just kind of learned on the job.
So I've been doing tech, I guess you could say since, who,
God, 19 years now.
Wow.
So I've done some technical support, um, for small software company I've done.
Uh, and then I started doing, I guess, QA probably about what's it been 13,
but for about 13 years.
So I've, I've really been kind of learning on the job and going to
conferences that I was doing a lot of my work in a smaller town here in Oregon.
So it wasn't a meetup specifically for, for testing, but at the same time,
I think that was really great because I never worked for a company that had
kind of the old school, like QA team sits over here and does a bunch of
manual testing and then reports back and is the bottleneck.
So I've always been able to work really closely with my development team,
small, small teams, kind of understand what they're doing, learned more about
unit testing and kind of the development process and, you know, through those
years of seeing like all the different changes.
So at this point, I'm now working with a small startup and I'm the only QA
person and probably will be the only QA person, uh, when I was interviewing
for my last job, I really wanted to find a company where the development
team understood what quality was.
It wasn't the separate role or the separate person that does this
testing at the end that they're doing a really good job of as far as
they can with a startup, uh, with their, their side of testing and that I
could help them understand where gaps are missing.
Um, I can help get some of the more front end testing up and running
where it's needed.
And so that's kind of been my role the past few months and it's been really nice.
Um, it's, it's great to be with a team that understands kind of what
they were looking for, didn't have, you know, too many bad experiences
with the whole QA role in the past and, you know, expect me to just
do a bunch of manual testing.
So, um, I feel like I can really contribute a lot with the team here.
So that's where I'm at now.
That's great to hear.
I try not to spend too much talk time talking to myself on these, but I have
a few things to say is interesting parallel.
I don't know if you've, uh, listened to enough or if this even come out
on the podcast, but, uh, I wasn't a studio art major, but I was a music
major in college and then, yeah, if I found my way into tech support and
that's where I learned to test and to program.
And I, that part is very much in parallel.
I also like to hear is that Brent and I often say that we didn't invent
anything when we started talking about modern testing.
What we did was try and capture what we had seen happening.
The, your story is just yet another example to the many and many out there
of how teams are adapting to delivering quality products in the 21st century.
It would have happened to whether we talked about modern testing or not.
We're just trying to help people prepare and learn about the changes
that are happening.
So cool to hear what's going on.
Yeah.
Um, I'm, I'm not going to say it wasn't kind of difficult to find the right,
the right posting.
Um, I mean, there's still a lot of postings where, you know, it's just,
you're, you're an automation tester 24 hours a day and well, maybe not 24,
eight hours a day, sorry, um, in the role.
And it's like, well, that's not very interesting.
Sure.
I could focus on that for a year, you know, get my skills beefed up in that
area and you know, I was maybe open to that depending on what I found,
but this kind of role where I can be more integrated in kind of a bigger
picture, um, is, has always been way more interesting than me.
That's, that's great to hear.
It's fascinating.
I love it.
So just real quick, what is the, are you, can you tell me what company you work
for or what kind of work you're doing?
Is it, is it unannounced?
Is it secret?
Is it government?
No, it's none of those things.
Um, um, we are a startup and we are called bumped and, um, we're, we're still
trying to figure out, you know, some growth paths, um, hopefully with the
scaryness going on with the stock market, you know, we were not too
effective, but we are FinTech.
Um, so the application at the moment, um, is a mobile mobile app.
And basically we want to be able to have anyone be an owner of stock.
And the way we do that is that you will earn stock as kind of a reward,
um, or places you shop.
So, um, it's kind of like a loyalty program, but instead of getting points
or cash, you can actually get stock and feel like you have ownership of the
companies that you're shopping at.
Oh, that's interesting.
Yeah.
So, you know, we're looking on how do we expand it?
How do we, well, also stay afloat, you know, given, given the
times right now, um, we're, we're still hopeful, you know, we're still, we're
still fine.
Um, so, and we've got, you know, really creative people and sales and, you
know, everybody throughout the organization.
And so we'll, we'll see how it goes.
Yeah.
This is a great time to buy stock.
It's cheap.
Yeah.
I think it'll be even better in the few months, but hopefully not, not too terrible.
We, we, we got to keep on trying to find ways to make lemonade out of our
lemons.
Exactly.
Yeah.
And, you know, maybe, you know, once the stock market goes down some more and
you know, if this concept catches on, that will be a really great vehicle for,
you know, people who haven't been doing great to actually get some sort of
asset, um, diversity, um, just from shopping, from poor stuff.
They kind of need every day like gas or groceries.
I love that product today.
That's really cool.
Yeah.
You have had an evolution in testing and found what sounds like a really
great role for your experience.
And for, of course, what we talk about on AB testing with modern testing, but I'm
curious, what would you tell people new to a testing role to look for in a job?
Uh, so can I keep it in mind how things have changed?
You may have some good advice there.
Um, yeah, I, I was thinking about this because I, um, was talking to one of my
neighbors recently, you know, given we're seeing folks out and about more
and, um, found out that he is also in testing.
And so we talked recently because he's, he's still pretty new to it and found
out, you know, I'm not so new to it.
And, you know, he, he's in a role where it's more just manual testing.
Nobody on the development team has really talked to him about how to
deploy anything himself for the web app.
You know, they have people that are contractors that are offshore.
And so trying to understand like what, what is actually out there has been a
little bit harder for him to kind of get into because he's got a very myopic
view of what testing is.
And so, so we were talking about since he's in a web web app thing, you know,
just start small because he, he is seeing like where things are, are kind
of not working and, you know, I encourage people like what are the small
things that you see that you can improve?
Because changing an entire organization is not going to happen.
I've, I've been in many organizations and the bigger it gets, the more
difficult it becomes, because just a huge machine not just it's doing its thing.
But I told them try to get the application up and running, like learn
how your, your code actually works.
How can you deploy it yourself?
How can you get in there and actually see what's happening?
Learning how the calls from the back end are getting made to the front end
and then what data is going back and forth.
What are the tools you can use to inspect those things and, and interact with them.
So just trying to get control of as much information on your own so that you can
play around with it because I think at the end of the day, it's really, can you
learn something from it and having that curiosity and doing whatever you can
to get everything so you can do that.
Yeah.
I, I like the emphasis on learning and just what I've been having a career
discussions, a lot of my team.
And of course I don't manage.
I have two people who do test coaching, probably a very similar role to yours.
And then I have DevOps teams, of course.
And one of the things for all those people, I, being completely unafraid
to learn new things that take on things you don't know how to do is your
key to long-term success.
And I think that's true with, that's more true than ever with testing.
I've done some automation.
I haven't done like a full, like, I'm going to implement this framework and
I'm going to write the, all the tests and support and all of that.
But I have enough knowledge to kind of figure it out.
And in this role, I basically came in and did that.
And I wasn't really sure at first, but I figured, well, it's small enough.
And there's enough developers to help me that, you know, it'll be fine.
So yeah, don't, don't be afraid to just kind of jump in and figure it out
because every place it's going to be a little bit different, but the more
you do it, the more little things you're going to learn and you can, you
can do it better next time, if you need to do it next time, which you
probably will.
Yeah.
I was just thinking where testing has come from.
Of course the brain is a very good testing tool, but we keep on, you know,
just knowing how to use the, the web debugger, knowing how to make a
simple curl request, learning how to use postman.
If you have APIs, I've attended great workshops and online tutorials on
using postman for exploratory testing of rest endpoints.
And I think that's really fantastic stuff.
Oh yeah.
The developers a few jobs ago, like, yeah, we're using this to, you know, test
our endpoints and like, Oh, what is this?
And what are all the endpoints and how do I use it?
And I'm like, Oh, well, I'm going to start sending weird combinations of data.
And Oh, Hey, you're not handling it.
That's exactly what we should be doing.
Of course, you're talking to your neighbor who you found out was in testing.
And we also talked about the people doing test automation, the automation
tester, which I think is an odd.
I still think today is an odd and even more so today, an odd specialization.
I see it a lot for, I know I see it a lot too.
And, and of course that means they're writing selenium eight hours a day, but
there are some good uses for selenium.
Have you, what's, what's your view?
You've heard my rants and we had hugs on the show last year, but
yeah, I, I'm not using too much selenium, but I am having to use Appium, but
I'm using it through webdriver IO.
So it's all kind of the same command.
And I think my team is pretty good about understanding.
Yeah, you don't want to write a thousand UI tests.
That's kind of ridiculous.
But what we do want to use them for is, uh, for a new web app that we are
implementing, we, we need, um, accessibility enabled.
And so my developers are using tools within the front end for the components
and for unit tests to make sure that accessibility rules are being matched.
Um, and then what we can also do just in case something falls through the cracks.
And also because once a page is completely composed, um, we can run the, uh,
ax rule sets and use our selenium, um, tests in order to just hit the different
pages to then call that method to run our rule set and then report back, um,
whether there's anything else that was missing.
So I, I'm, I'm going, I'm hoping, uh, to get that in place in the next few months.
And I think that's going to be very helpful.
The other thing I don't think we're going to probably do any, anytime, anytime
soon is for checking performance front end.
Um, but I think that's probably another good thing to do if you have a lot of
content, um, depending on, I would say probably commercial applications are
probably more important for that to understand when things are loading and in
what order and how, and if it's slowing down kind of your, the user, uh,
interaction, no, that's not the word I'm looking for there.
Anyway, I can't think of it right now because I'm talking a lot and nervous.
So, um, I think, I think using selenium as a way, um, to integrate other tools,
um, but not for functional testing.
Obviously I can definitely agree that is a horrible way to do it.
You get it.
And I love the idea of, uh, plugging in the accessibility tool using selenium
just to navigate to the page, because that's not going to break about, or it's
going to break much less often.
And then I think on the performance side, you could, you have the performance viewer
in the debugger that shows you what's loading, how long it's taking.
Uh, but even accessing that data automatically.
So you just tell when there's a regression, Hey, all of a sudden it's
taking us 30% more time to load our components.
That's another great thing to do because my stance is I don't hate selenium.
No, no, I think it's overused for the wrong purposes.
But that's another conversation.
Uh, but, oh, I could tell you a story, but I won't tell you a story too.
Uh, the one, the one thing that does make me nervous is that, um, for
mobile apps, like that, that's still really hard.
It's really hard to test them and you still need a lot of, um, UI automation
because of all the different versions of, uh, phones and tablets and operating
systems. And so having an automated UI test is still one of those kind of
important things. And then you still have to think about all this data you
need to have in place in order to make sure things are in the right state.
Man, that part, that part's still kind of a beast, but, you know, at
least I don't have to worry about it for the web as much.
It is, but the same rules apply.
I think navigating to make sure the application doesn't crash or black screen
or, or A and R or any of those things that can happen is fine via Appium.
And because you're going to have such different behavior, if you use one of
the services like shoot, there are a bunch of services that give you a
mobile device test farm.
Oh yeah.
Brothers, staffs, staffs, labs.
Yeah.
And those are helpful to get that coverage because they're all so different.
But again, it loses its value when you start trying to do a whole bunch
of functional automation at that level.
Yeah.
And we have good separation, um, with our, our business logic front end
presentation. So, you know, we, we feel really confident for pretty much
the entire app of, you know, the data we're getting is like, we'll just
display it, you know, we don't have to worry about checking those
sort of things.
So yeah.
What are the challenges?
And I'm curious about how you found this role and how you found a team
that supports the role you're in.
Because as you know, we're watching the industry change with modern testing,
what, how quality is achieved on a team.
Yeah.
But as we go in that direction, do you have any insights or ideas on how
management needs to change or our testing or something about how
testing is managed and what changes you'd want there?
Um, yeah, I'm not sure how I found this team.
It was pure luck.
That's all I'm going to say.
You find you find your own luck.
Yeah.
Good job.
Patient.
Don't don't take that first job that you find because it'll just
end in tears.
No, no, you'll learn a lot.
Yeah.
I, you can, you can cry and learn.
I guess that's true.
That, that, that is something that is pretty, pretty frequent
occurrence for me.
Yeah.
I yeah, some of, some of the things I've seen and I, and I think we, you've
talked about it probably in the podcast a lot too is like, there's, there's
kind of still a lot of old ideas about testing is this one person does the
thing of testing and it, it seems it's been very difficult for probably even
larger organizations to understand how do you fit in kind of the skills and some
of the specialties of the old idea of that role into an entire team and people
are having a really hard time with it.
Cause like you're saying, there's still this automation tester role out there
and it's very, very specialized.
And why are we not?
And from what I've seen that people, the management management seems to also
have a hard time understanding, well, how do you find like career paths for
these folks and how do you train them?
Because well, they're not developers.
They don't know how to code or they're not DevOps people or, you know,
there, there's like so many of these fuzzy skills that I think it's hard
for management to understand how to not have to have a very specific job code
and career path for these people.
And for that, I have no idea what needs to change for that.
Maybe not dividing teams up into just development and then just DevOps and
then just like SRE teams is having those truly like fully across functional
teams so that you just have skill sets of people on a team.
And not worry about the titles as much.
And I think we ourselves need to train ourselves out of like, here's this
title you have and here's this, you know, career path you can have and just
like, are you engaged?
Are you learning?
And do you feel you're being fairly compensated compared to everybody else?
That that's kind of what I kind of how I feel about it.
But I'm also a lot further along in my career than a lot of other folks.
And it's kind of scary to think like, well, how do you get new testers?
Into the job market because they're not necessarily going to have
kind of that broad experience that a team needs to have as well as some of
the specialized skills.
So that I think that might be worth more thought.
Maybe not with me, but maybe in another podcast or folks who are on the Slack
group have any thoughts about that?
Yeah, Brent and I get asked a lot about how does someone starting off
in testing do modern testing?
And the answer is I think they don't.
I think the role you're in requires that experience and breadth as your team
grows and as you help them build this.
That's right.
Principle four nurture and something your culture of quality.
I should I should really memorize the principles.
There could be someone from the team that's able ends up being able to coach
quality as well as you can.
But I wonder if the path to wonder if I hypothesize and think that perhaps
the path to one path to becoming a modern tester or a person in a role
like yours is to come from development and really embodied that culture of
quality and engineering quality so much so that you can you can lead your
team towards a culture of quality.
Yeah, I don't.
Yeah, I don't feel like I've come from a development role though.
Yeah, and I think another path is but you you were on a team
probably before of testers and you have people to learn from and I think
that's the other path.
I think I'm trying to think if there was a reason I had an opportunity
to hire someone fairly new to the industry into it as a tester.
What things would I look for?
I wouldn't look for their desire to write a lot of automation every day.
I would look for a desire to learn that what we talked about before that.
That lack of fear in taking on new things.
Yeah, I definitely ask those questions and interviews.
Yeah, but then if they had people in a quality coach,
quality consultant role around them, they could learn from them and maybe
they're doing a little bit more.
Actually, I don't even they even do a little bit more hands-on testing at the beginning.
I think they probably would have to get the experience to
I think credibility build to talk about it.
Yeah, they have to practice some of those things.
But I think in most cases, I would probably I don't know if the path to being this
quality testing quality coach begins in testing.
It feels like either you just stick around for a lot of years and you try to learn as
much as possible and take on different roles depending on where you're at or if you need
to find a new role or like a larger company has a concept of kind of like this floating role
where you're working with development, you're working with a DevOps team, you're working with
maybe a production support team.
And so you're learning all those steps of deployment and production from beginning to end
so that you can get that exposure of that big picture and how things need to fit together
so that you can see kind of what quality really means for a product.
And it's not just did you write a thousand tests and they all pass.
I think it's a parallel as I mentioned, I manage our I think I mentioned I manage our DevOps teams
in our organization and they have a big impact on quality.
And we hired recently six months ago, a brand new junior, I'll call them,
but brand new developer.
And there's a lot of influence they have.
And the goal of a DevOps team isn't to do all the DevOps stuff because it doesn't exist.
DevOps was really never meant to be a team.
It's a culture, which is the idea.
The problem was the problem that solves is there was a time when services developers would finish
stuff and they chuck it over the wall to the operations team who would deploy it and monitor
it.
And they realized that was stupid.
So they came up with this DevOps culture.
And they took teams that were typically infrastructure teams that okay,
you're the DevOps team, you're going to help us learn this culture.
I really emphasize with my team that you're and they all get it and I didn't have to tell them
they knew this way I took over the team.
Their role is to help build that DevOps culture.
They're never going to be able to scale to do all the operations work.
They help teams deliver safely and quickly, which is very similar.
We never made that jump in QA or test.
We always had this team who were dedicated to, as you mentioned,
the very beginning to testing and building quality in.
And really, I know Lisa Crispin has posted a lot on devtestops.com.
And there's this, which is bringing test into DevOps, but which I don't mind.
But in a way, DevOps includes testing and quality.
It's about getting rid of the walls that make sure a role is going to do one thing
in delivering software.
I think a lot of people still don't understand the testing part of DevOps.
I mean, it's great.
Bring that concept in for beyond initiated.
But yeah, I've seen good and bad things.
I've worked with really great people that know all of this,
but maybe we're stuck in a company culture where we can't actually do the right thing.
And it's frustrating and you're trying to swim upstream against it.
But you do what you can and for as long as you can.
You're not making things worse, I guess.
Right.
In a role like yours, you're trying to help the team improve testing and quality and helping
them just improve.
And you end up bouncing around between a lot of different hats of coach and program manager
and therapist and tester and everything you can do to help the team to deliver quickly and safely.
Yeah, it's still really difficult because
having this type of role, it still feels like your voice gets a bit diluted
at times because you can't be in all those places all at the same time.
And so I think if people are looking at staying in this sort of role that you need to really look
for a team that already understands this and that you're not constantly having to follow up
and like, hey, did you push back when we're trying to deliver too quickly?
Did you make sure that the testing requirements and what are we looking for in terms of monitoring
and metrics at the end of this, have those been set in place and do we need to build tools for that?
Like, have all those things been discussed and you alone won't be able to just constantly be
screaming into the void and hopefully somebody hears you, you have to have a team that already
supports it. So it's kind of this weird chicken and egg thing. Like, yeah, we need the quality
coach, but we also need a team that already understands most of these things already.
It's more like you're just kind of like tapping people on the shoulders, hopefully the good angel
to tell them, yep, you're doing a good job. Yeah, don't forget to do this. Okay, yeah,
we're still on the right path and keeping the team steered in the right direction, I guess,
rather than having to pull them out of the mud.
Yeah, it's hard to jump into that role when they don't know they need you yet.
Exactly. Yeah. And it can be very demoralizing. I know I'm talking about the right thing because I
know we need to do this and people kind of nod and agree, but then don't take the action.
I've been there too and don't be discouraged. Just keep doing the right thing.
Yeah, I have so many questions and comments, but I think we better wrap up.
All right. This has been, thank you again for being honest, it's been a pleasure talking with
you and learning from you. Anytime. I hope my experience is encouraging that it's not all,
a bunch of people just writing UI tests all day.
No, I think, you know, keep fighting the good fight. Definitely stay healthy out there and
and keep learning, keep being unafraid. Absolutely.
Being unafraid to learn. Yeah, not a problem. Thank you again. And I'll get this posted by
Monday and our listeners can hear how awesome you are. I hope they agree. Thanks again for having me.