This is the AB testing 343 podcast a podcast where we ask one of the three listeners of the AB testing podcast
three questions about almost anything
ABT 343 is a fun slice of what's going on in the world of modern testing. Let's get started
We're back again for another ABT
343 and this time all the way from
Germany, I think is
Andres warm
One yeah. Hi. Thanks for having me. Yeah one just like the one on the ground and
But spelling wise it's it's spelled worm
Okay, that's a pronunciation. Yeah
For the for the Americans, which is I only bring that up because your nickname on our slack is really cool
It's it's a nice little pun
global warming and I love it I guess I
always
Always thought it's called one because earth one Jim is I think we have it's one
It works. Just just just just ignore my American ignorance. I love the name
I'm super glad to have
You know on this podcast I ask a few questions usually three plus tangents so more three or more questions
To one of the three listeners of the AB testing podcast. So as sort of a pre question, I'm curious
How did you learn about the podcast or modern testing?
Where did you learn about this thing that Brent and I call modern testing? I
Somehow stumbled upon your podcast. I'm not sure if I saw it on LinkedIn or on the MOT slack
someone linked me to episode 104 and
That was the first time I heard about the podcast and your your seven principles and
Yeah, and a few episodes after
Joined the one of three slack. So what did we talk about in 104? Oh, that's a great question
Maybe we turn off investment
Maybe I'm sure I could look it up
Just curious Brent sometimes remember these of course we have some episodes that we
Always remember like we know like we talked about so-and-so in such episode
It's caught leading quality with one
Sean
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah that one was a good interview with a bad recording
On the old equipment. We have better equipment. That's why this one sounds so much better a bit
How have you applied modern testing to any of the work that you've done, you know since you found the podcast
Since I found the podcast, that's hard. I
Because I didn't really do much. I
Just discovered it like a week or two weeks ago, and I'm currently without a project. So there's no real
real code base or team or product I could apply anything to I
Thought about starting an old part of my own podcast. Maybe I can
Introduce some quality there or get rapid feedback
Whatever
No, I discovered. Well, I basically lift the or some of the principles
for a long time
most things on the list I
Already did because I had the had the luck to to learn in a very quality focused environment
so
things like customer first
Quality inbuilt from the beginning and sharing knowledge and continuously improving
Have been always there as you said, as you said the quality the principles are very old
You
They're not so new nothing nothing. Yeah, nothing new you've made my point for me
So let's get the softballs aside
Let's talk about scrum. I know you are a
supporter of scrum and I want to talk about that and
also
That you have seen scrum used incorrectly a lot. So
Let's just go with that. Tell me about your experience with scrum
How your problems you've run into how it's helped with modern testing and I'm gonna sit back and listen to you
Teach me for a while
after I
finished my three years of learning to be a software developer, I basically did the
scrum master certification and
the place where I learned and worked
Knew about scrum. My my boss was a supporter of scrum and
As like scrum as like one of the best
methodologies to develop complex
software products
we had a team of like
five six people and
We tried to do scrum to be agile
no
No scrum implementation is perfect. We were always learning but
We were very aware of some of the
Missing parts of scrum. We didn't do scrum correctly, but we
applied as much as we could or as we wanted to
have an environment of
continuous improvement and learning and not doing the same the same about twice and
yeah
having having a customer focus and working with data and
one of the
Maybe I should tell about the project
So we have a little bit of context that I'm what I'm talking about
our little company of six people
mostly developed
event ticketing
system the storefront where you could buy tickets for for concerts and
museums and these things online
Pretty local and we had like
at any time
6,000 events active, which is I guess nothing compared to huge
I don't know what your local equivalent is
yeah, but for our team pretty pretty nice and
yeah, we
did this for our client and
one problem we
Often came back to was our missing product owner
because
When you when you go with the scrum guide you want to have like
self-sufficient
autark what was the term?
The word escapes me, but you want the team to have all the ability to do and make decisions and
Develop the product we
Were working for a client. So the client had
much say and
Which direction we went and what to develop and
Yeah, sometimes the the
So you could you could say the client was the product owner
but
you could
Yeah, and the role the role the person's the person's changed from time to time and we had better product owners and sometimes worse product owners and
and
Yeah, that was one issue
In hindsight, it would have made maybe made sense to
to fight for
autonomy
To say hey come we we align on the basic goals you want to achieve the basic like the customer segments you want to to
Talk to to have more conversion with whatever and let us handle the the tasks and how to do it and
How to get the feedback and
But in hindsight, that's easy to say
I'm gonna have you I'm gonna put you on the hot seat here with some special questions because I
have my I
Can't say that I hate scrum because I don't I think it's valuable and useful and often
Misused so I don't think I'm gonna tell you anything you haven't heard before I miss use
Let me give you some complaints I have about scrum and just kind of give me your answers on them
Just for those you listening along there has been no prep for these. He is completely on the spot. So I
will ask try to ask these in an open-ended way, so one is
The rituals of scrum there are a lot of meetings that go along with the scrum framework. There's the daily stand-up
Which we can go into which it has some pros and cons
When done right or wrong and as a tangent
It seems like every day on the internet someone publishes an article saying why agile doesn't work and they describe some horribly
Bastardized version of agile and you go. Yeah, of course you don't get it. That's why it doesn't work
so so going back to scrum rituals, there's the
There's the backlog grooming and the daily stand-up and the retros and there are probably a few other ones. I'm forgetting so
What are some pros and cons of?
Let's just stick with daily stand-up and
Actually, let's talk about all that lead up. What are the pros and cons? What are the ways the daily stand-up is?
Extremely important part of scrum and what are some ways in that meeting can be useless
Let's let's first distinguish between age and scrum
a child when I talk about a
When I talk when in my mind agile is the main resource for agile is the age of manifesto and
I love okay. I like talking about scrum more because scrum has a more concrete
Rule set you can compare to it and I'm gonna stop go on go on
I was gonna interrupt and give away your answer for you. So keep going
so
Whatever the actual implementation is you're you are doing
all the all the rituals mentioned in the scrum guide and
You can okay. That's our main source for doing scrum is a scrum guide and
These rituals have a purpose
These rituals don't add meetings or are a waste of time because any everything you do in these rituals
must be done to
build something and
scrum tries to
Say, okay. Why don't you use at regular intervals these ways of
communicating and collaborating to build something because you have to do it anyway, that's why the most
effective way of communicating and collaborating and
sharing new information aligning on goals
and get feedback from stakeholders and
Quality what what's the second part of the question?
Because I have a love relationship, okay stand up without leading you I'm gonna see if you can guess why I think the stand-up
It can be awesome and why it often isn't
through discovering I'm doing a lot more on
On the learning side because I have a project and I also discovered the liberators network and
the
Zombie scrum, do you know of that?
Yes, you read my mind you're in my head. Yeah, I guess. Yeah, it's very very interesting
You can boil that down to you have to have
passion excitement new things you don't want to have to
Trot over into the meeting room. Yeah yesterday. I did this and that now I'm not blocked. Okay, see you tomorrow
Yeah, you have to keep it fresh exciting and
one thing I'm
Recently learning is the importance of the sprint goal and in hindsight
That was something which could have helped us very much in our
Eight years of developing this event ticketing system and doing scrum there
Keep it. Yeah
Keep it interesting
Yes
The difference with you over a lot of people that have done scrum is they kind of pick a little bits of it
And it doesn't quite work. I think the sprint goal
It's a pat lunch. You only calls the rally and cry getting a team to a line about around something
I think that's super important as well
And then the zombies the zombie stand-ups people
Every day saying they're working on the same thing and it's the same thing that did yesterday and they're never blocked on anything
Which is really comes down to the importance of a good scrum master for the team
And I am missing out on there's a really good book. I read and recommend on
Being a scrum master and if you're doing scrum, I think go ahead
We didn't have a scrum master either
So that's the challenge that I think
It's
Incredibly important to have a good scrum master
Someone who knows what to do and can dig past those things and this book that I'm talk I can't find
I don't want to search for it any longer while I'm talking here
So I'm not going to but it does a good job
talking about the role of the scrum master as a servant leader for the organization and
Helping the team be successful and aligning them on what they're doing
Asking the right questions to get the team that did the right level of communication for that team to be successful
Which aligns very well with the agile manifesto and agile principles
Which I think a lot of people who do scrum haven't they think of scrum as being equal to agile for so
Thanks for calling that out that they're not and then
You are talking about people saying
Agile doesn't work because we are doing scrum wrong and I'm saying yeah, we are doing scrum wrong
But agile did work. I have seen enough people
Make mistakes with scrum that I prefer not to use it
But I have nothing against scrum being used properly
But I think you are gonna need someone to play the role of scrum master for it to really work well for the team
Honestly scrum is a nice transition for those used to more
Traditional models because it gives you you get nice little tight iterations. In fact
done poorly
Scrum is an example of the spiral model of software delivery can be a way of accelerating waterfall done poorly
but if you actually
Understand how scrum works within the frame of agile it can actually be very effective. So I have nothing against it
I just seems to be done wrong a lot
So it's kind of scared me away from recommending it to a lot of teams
Versus just coaching them towards understanding the principles of agile in the first place. I'm off of myself box in your notes
You said that you like scrum, but mostly for egocentric reasons. I'd like to hear some more about that
yeah, the the the best part about the wedding cry and and
the
consumer and customer centric view is
Motivation
Because I'm I'm deriving lot of purpose in my life for my work
So as long as you can convince me that my work is valuable
I will be much more motivated to work and
doing doing boring stuff doing stuff where I
Don't see the value for the customer doing something which is just thrown in the bin
Which was clear before and will totally demotivate me and I guess many people
Will suffer from this fate when they don't see the bigger picture then they don't see the value added when they don't make lives better
it's
It's easier to follow when you have some someone who's really passionate and has has you has you convinced that what you are building is great. I
Don't see that as
Egotistical to me that's about having a sense of purpose for your work
And I tie that back to Dan Pink's works like you need to have
autonomy mastery and sense of purpose you need to be able to figure stuff out and
Be able to do it and feel like you're in like what you work on matters and that's not egotistical
That's just it is taking care of yourself
But it's you know when I look at Dan Pink's those three principles that I just mentioned
It's kind of like Maslov's hierarchy of needs. It's what we need to do to be successful in knowledge work
So I'm okay with that. I don't call that egotistical
But it's if you give people work they enjoy that they feel like matters
They're going to do better work and create higher quality output. So I am all over that
Okay, good to hear that's good to hear as a much younger person than me. It's good to hear the younger generation
Figuring out that's important. So I like that. Yeah, I don't know if I figured that out of it's just really the
The awesome environment I was learning and we didn't have a scrum master, but we had
We had two people with scrum master certifications
my boss a really really great mind and
Always pointing out the the the problems
We had by by applying the scrum guide and saying okay
We have a problem with doing three weeks week sprints come let's try to let's try one. Okay, what is what? What is happening?
So he was basically a teacher coach mentor
And a great scrum master, but also the world shifted sometimes sometimes I was a scrum master and
He was focused on more on development. Sometimes someone else was
for the sprint
having trying to have more like an
overview about the the team and the the things we do
But that was very hard because we were all
developers and we all wanted to develop fancy stuff and great things and
Yeah, it's the focus sounds like a good boss excited about that
Hey one last thing I'd like to talk about which is the thing on everyone's mind these days
Covid so first off, how's it going with you with do you have a family you live by yourself?
How's it going with you dealing with?
Whatever is going on in your part of the world. I think in Germany things have opened up a little bit more but not much
Yeah, I mean it's
Comparatively good you see low numbers like thousands
But you see an increase now that schools and businesses are reopening again
Yeah, that was to be expected. I
Was lucky to to just have finished project and I could just go to the office
By myself or I could stay at home. I
Basically the whole April was on vacation
Yeah, and after that I was alone in the office
So no no contact there no risk. I have a wife I
Have a son who is going to be three years old
That's the really stressful part
Because yes, I have noticed that too
I have a lot of employees with young kids and I have had a lot of young kids join meetings
Which can be funny
but but related to the the risk of infection even even though the early data suggested that
children below a certain age aren't really suspect to the virus and don't face like severe consequences, but the long-term effects and
We have a grandma who couldn't visit
Yeah, and the soul
24-7 being a dad at home was quite a
challenge sometimes
Yep. Yep. Yep. Yep
So there is safety however in online communities and I believe you just joined LinkedIn recently
So what's that experience been like? Yeah, I thought because projects are slow. I just try to be more
active on LinkedIn, maybe
there's
Business value in that I'm quite
Surprised I'm it's already and it's already been proven valuable just to
It's just funny learning aspect. I'm I discovered a lot of interesting people a lot of interesting thoughts and a lot of updates on my
Knowledge of scrum and some different philosophies and advancements
Try to to to get into discussions and maybe
post one or two things I'm really
Confident about that's not we hashed that's some of which no thoughts and hopefully helpful to someone
Yeah, engaging in discussion and debates are great way to learn. Yeah, definitely
Congratulations on on get now. I should have done. I should have done that earlier. Oh
It is what it is
Great. Well, that's going to bring us to the about to the end of our time here today
But I enjoyed the conversation especially kind of dive in to scrum a little bit and kind of hearing what's going on in your world
I want to thank you again for joining our
Community at one of the three dot slack comm and then for volunteering to be on this podcast where we try and get a little
bit more information around people on the podcast
So thank you for that and any final words or or actually maybe share some ways people can learn more about you or get a
Hold of you out in the real world
It's hard in the real world. You can you can connect to me on linkedin
but I don't really have an a
Channel a personal channel to spread my my thoughts and joined one of the three dot slack calm
Warming or global farming there. Yeah, and also on the Ministry of Testing podcast
Slack, I'm sorry Ministry of Testing slack
Yeah, you can find me on the the vanity serenity BDD a guitar chat
Well, that's basically it. I think a lot of our community is bound to come across you at some point if they haven't already
Yes
It's good to have to remember
rememberable nickname
Yes, very much. All right. Well, thanks again. Say goodbye and we will get going
Thanks for having me. Bye