This is the AB Testing 343 podcast, a podcast where we ask one of the three listeners of
the AB Testing podcast, three questions about almost anything.
ABT 343 is a fun slice of what's going on in the world of modern testing.
Let's get started.
We're back again for another ABT 343, and this time with another name I had to practice
to pronounce.
Please welcome Yulia Bogre.
Hi.
Did I do okay?
Almost but that's no problem.
I'll take a B plus.
How are you doing?
Oh, fine.
Good.
A very active member of our Slack community.
Happy to have you as one of our three listeners.
Always exciting for Brent and I to hear more about what's going on in the world of R3.
And this is yet another COVID-19 edition.
Brent and I actually recorded episode 118 this morning.
The remote went a little better than last time.
I'm excited to get that out.
But enough about Brent.
Today it's the AY podcast as I like to call it.
And we have Yulia here to tell us all kinds of things.
As you know, it's three questions for three listeners, for one of our three listeners,
and tangents are allowed.
I think a good first question that's worked with a lot of people is just tell me about
your path into testing and what you're doing now.
Yeah, that's a good question.
I like how almost everyone was asked about it.
And it's nice to learn about other people in our community.
So comparing to others, I'm probably maybe the youngest one because my testing career
is just five years.
And this is almost my whole career.
I wasn't working as anyone else before.
I just came to testing after the university.
I'm initially from Kazakhstan.
So my problem was that I wanted to start working remotely right away because my
current husband was working remotely too.
So we wanted to go around the places.
And I was very, very lucky to find the place as a junior in the remote, fully remote
company, which was specializing in testing.
And they also provided testing courses for other companies, but for the employees
they were obviously free.
So I had a place to learn from the start.
And some of the people in that company or the community around it are actually very
well known in Russian speaking testing community.
So I think it probably was the best place to start being a tester.
And it wasn't a product company.
We were mostly outsourcing or outstaffing because we were contracted to do that testing.
But we weren't like throw of the board, some people do stuff.
No, we were integrated into the actual development teams.
So it was closer to real world product company.
And my last project was the most important one.
It was a government project.
It was very, very big, very, very, very motivated to work on.
And I also burned out on it hugely, but that's another story.
And the best thing that what happened on it is that at some point, and I think I
don't know how you like it, I was on the crossroads to switch from the so-called manual
tester to either be automation engineer, like write Selenium how you like it, or to switch
to be integration tester.
So in this case, it was a SOAP services.
And I don't know how it happened, but it was me or my direct manager, who's my friend.
And I decided to go to integration testing and not automation.
And I think it was the best decision of my life because I really just a fan of API and
everything that's about it.
Well, you know, my opinion on that there's a level of hell that includes people who write
Selenium all day.
Well, I actually write Selenium now, but yeah, it's, it's complicated.
But I think it was very cool that at that point in my life, I decided not to do that.
And to learn the actual skills and the area that was a bit different from usually is expected
to do from the testering career.
And then I moved to the Canada, to Montreal, and I had to find local job.
And it wasn't easy because, you know, you don't have a local Canadian experience.
You don't have a French suitable to work.
Like I mean, I can speak a bit, but it's not okay for day-to-day work.
And also I was very picky because after that government project, I couldn't move to, you
know, to test some websites, some kind of, you know, like store pages and something like
that.
And I also didn't want to work in Alsace and companies anymore because there's just not
enough level of agency stake in the game.
When you, when you have conflicting interests, you are either working for your company or
for customers of that product or for who you're trying to work.
So when I was looking for work here, I was looking for the product companies and the
product companies who do something meaningful.
I found one and currently I am, I have a very mixed position.
I write automation, yes, Selenium, yes.
And even because of the some project problems, it's in Python.
So it's not even easy stuff like, you know, Cypress or Task Affair.
It's a bit harder to do that in Python.
We don't have enough libraries in that language.
I also do API testing, sometimes UI testing, which I hate.
Okay, now I'm liking you more.
Yeah.
And I also not exactly test anymore, just this week, right?
This week, really, I think I'm starting to switch not being a tester at all.
And I don't know real name for this position yet, but it's something about developer experience.
What does that mean?
We don't think of a name to it yet, but what will you be doing?
So I don't know about how to properly name it because it's just two weeks ago, I actually
learned that there are special teams in some bigger companies that do that.
Developer experience is all about, so user experience is for regular customers who click
buttons and do this kind of thing.
And developer experience is for customers of API.
So what developer experience team usually do?
Thus, it's creating API guidelines, creating or researching tooling to help writing better
APIs to enforce these guidelines, prepare documentation, and sometimes even development relationships.
So when you communicate with your external or internal users of API.
So that's kind of thing.
Is it like developer productivity, would you say?
Or is this more on the experience side?
It's yes, yeah, it is.
But there is a level of authority here because you're actually creating rules like, okay,
we should follow this API guideline.
And I need all of your input for it.
So please leave your comments.
But then this API guidelines would be enforced.
It's just like we're making your life easier.
Yeah.
Yeah, and I think, I brought developer productivity because that's, if you've read the Google
software testing book, James Whittaker, or actually he delegated most of the writing of
that book.
But he talks about the move of quite a few of their testers into this developer productivity
role where the role was to make it easier for developers to do good work.
And in your case, it's an interesting twist on it.
I think it's good where there's some leadership aspect and some standards aspect.
We're trying to, and this is the challenge.
And my favorite leadership quote, which I've used on the other podcast quite a lot is leadership
is disappointing people at a level they can absorb.
And I think in your role and your team's role, it's a lot about figuring out not just
how many processes and guidelines can we make the team follow, but the right ones to make
sure it's because the results of the process should be to solve a problem around productivity
or as you put it, their experience, improving the experience and things like guidelines that
make code more readable.
Those are proven to show that they make code more maintainable, easier to refactor,
et cetera.
So I love jobs like that.
I have gravitated towards things that help internal developers do their job better.
I'm a big fan of that kind of work.
Are you excited to get started on that?
Yeah.
And that's why I'm hesitant to say that it's development productivity only.
It's because it's not only internal developers.
The reason is that we have external developers, external customers that want to use our product
in their solutions.
Oh, that's different.
That's really cool too.
Yeah.
So it's connecting these lines from our developers to them and making sure that all information
is in place.
Yes, yes, I get it.
A long time ago at Microsoft, I worked on a product that had this primary customer was
external developers.
I remember working on a lot of tools there to help them be more successful and putting
on, I'm not sure if this is part of your, really part of your role or part of the
charter or not, but I remember putting together workshops for them both.
They weren't online then.
Today I do them online, especially today today.
But I remember inviting a dozen or 20 of them to Microsoft to give them a couple days of
workshops on how to use our tools.
That was a lot of fun.
Nice.
Yeah.
It's actually one of the things that I was doing last week.
It's we are preparing a API documentation and before we just didn't have it at all.
So use cases and stuff like that.
I'm excited about that.
So you're working with a team of people working on the same thing?
Team of one.
So just you all by yourself.
Well, yes and no, because I need to connect with everyone.
And this is how company approach I mentioned to you before the starting podcast is that
the very, not the very, the most important thing is that generally I see the testers,
they are like, okay, I'm doing my job.
And that's it.
But as I see it, the really good job comes when you actually try to interact with everyone.
With not just developers and not just tech writers, though even sometimes I'm not using
testers don't even know who are tech writers.
I remember that on my previous project.
We didn't even saw the results of that work.
But also these sales with marketing, because these guys are working with our customers,
with our clients.
You should know what are they telling people about us.
In case of our sales team, they really, I think it's our first line of defense of knowing
what actually customers want.
Because our product is currently I think is most common on-premises installation behind
the firewall.
We don't have much telemetry there.
Nope.
Yeah.
We have a similar challenge to work with one of our products.
But yeah, that's a challenge.
Yeah, so people who work directly with customers are very important as a tester or as any other
member of the company.
You should talk with every department to understand it.
In our company, we have something called, how is it called?
Okay.
I forgot it.
But there is a management perspective of how the company should be open to everyone.
So every month, we have a meeting where we discuss financial statistics, what's done
in marketing, what's done in sales, how we can help them.
It's not just being in all your bubble, but go around and speak with these people.
It sounds like a really fun job.
And I'm already imagining some ways in which you may be able to apply modern testing principles
there.
But I'm curious.
So in your, you talk about only having five years of experience, but I think the number
isn't as important.
It sounds like you've had a good variety and breadth of experience.
So I'm curious how you've seen the modern testing principles manifest in the jobs you've
had and especially in the job you're going into.
Because I don't have very good memory, I have a memo with the principles and I will look
into it and just go one by one.
Brent and I don't have memorized either.
So the first principle is actually what I was just was talking about.
Yes, it is.
Yeah.
And I think last month, or maybe, yeah, I think it was last month, we actually, our
monthly meeting was suspended in preference of having the meeting to brainstorm our customers
who were in the red or orange zone from the support or from development or from the sales
perspective and generated ideas about how we can move them to green zone that they like
us more.
And as a tester, we had lots of insight in this meeting because some of the customers
were in the red zone because we didn't know about their environment.
And we weren't testing in that particular case.
This ended up badly.
So the priority is to understand that all our action can improve business in some way.
So we need to go around to gather information about it and act on it.
And that's where the second principle helps is system thinking, theory constraints.
You need to understand where bottlenecks are, where problems arise, where is the loss of
feedback.
Yeah.
And especially all these are ringing truths.
You're talking about your job.
I'll interrupt for just a moment.
But you're talking about you are the glue who's connecting a lot of different parts of
the organization together.
That's principle two.
Yeah.
Oh, by the way, I remember there was a topic.
There was some talk on the conference.
Probably it was shared in our slack about being a glue person.
Yes.
Yeah.
And it's actually what I like to do most.
And I think Melissa in the previous episode said that in some of the job description, people
just assume that you will do one thing and don't go around with it.
And that's not interesting at all.
It's way better to be that kind of group to understand everything.
Well, not being an expert in everything, obviously, but to help people do their job better.
Yes.
There are some of us like you and I and others who that's where we thrive.
I love being the, as you've heard me call myself before, the specializing generalist.
Yeah.
And a lot about a little and a little about a lot.
Yes.
No.
It's going back to the principles with principle number three.
Well, yes, I can see us as a force of continuous improvement, but in my experience, safety net
culture is not going away.
So I remember my previous company and its projects and well, they hired us because they
wanted safety net.
Yes.
But in your new role, as you described it, you have moved yourself upstream.
There are problems with it, I think, because maybe our company sounds like a startup, but
you know, this openness and stuff, but it's actually not this very, very old company.
We have such an old code.
Our testing framework is written halfway in bash because it was written before they wrote
testing frameworks.
So in this position, when you don't really have a lot of unit tests and stuff, yes,
testing team is safety net, unfortunately.
And to go from not from being safety net and not being safety net, you need a lot of stuff
to do, a lot of time to do.
It's not one year or two years.
I think it will take a time.
So that's why I'm a bit skeptical when you say that there is so the tip and port or not.
No, I don't think so.
I saw that several companies on my previous work and there was many people who are still
where they rely on testers.
Sometimes Brent and I choose to ignore those.
And I've often used the diffusion of innovation curve that was made famous in the Crossing
the Casa book that shows that there are always be lagers.
There'll be the, I forget the names of the sections, but we're not on the super forefront
of innovation, but we're out on the front of the curve.
It just means that a lot of companies are still back there.
Some will stay back there, but we're hoping.
But as you know, as you've seen from talking to people on the Slack channel and hearing
other talks about modern testing, this is happening whether Brent and I were going to discuss
it or not.
We just put a name to some things we were seeing that we liked.
So it's going to happen.
In some companies we know it's going to take a long, long time.
And the problem is that there is a kind of bias.
People who participate in Slack or even in testing survey, there are active people.
And I don't think that many people in testing community are active people.
There are a lot of basics there.
So I think there is a kind of a bias in the way of saying the whole picture.
Maybe there should be some scientific study, but actually, you know, pick up companies at
random in different countries, you know.
Yep.
And any of the surveys that come out, it's hard because the testers at those companies
aren't really involved in the overall internet testing community very often.
Somehow you grew out of it anyway.
But we don't always get a fair sample size when we do testing surveys or testing polls.
Any other principles you wanted to call out as interesting in the scope of the work that
you've seen?
Well, I have anything to share about the principle number five.
Love it. Bring it on.
Yeah.
Customer capable of only customers capital judging quality.
So that government project, I mentioned that I had the burnout from it.
And one of the reasons was that we were not really allowed to communicate with customers,
but we were seeing support tickets because we were the people who were called test analysts
and we had the task to analyze last level of support stuff.
And sometimes we saw things like people naming us alcoholic drunkards and stuff like that.
And I think a month ago I saw an article where in the comments people mentioned that they
didn't even think that this project had any testers at all.
Yeah.
That was not very good for your mental health because you know, you work hard, you try to
work hard, but this is government project and laws change and you need to change with
it very fast and sometimes laws doesn't make sense.
In our case, we actually had a problem when people try analytics, try to design the requirements.
They say this is some law doesn't make sense in conjunction with another law.
And they had to propagate it to the government that they should change the laws because we
cannot develop it like that.
It won't work.
Yeah.
So in this case, the problem for me that even though we work hard, you know, and people
like management team was saying that yes, you're doing everything we can.
But because there was not enough feedback from us to customer to explain to them why we
have some problems and or we know we have these problems and we're working on it.
But there are some priorities in place that contradicted and something like that.
We I still see that generally external developers hated it.
And OK, and this is all that matters in the end.
When you see that, yeah, you do your hard work, but people just don't like it.
That's it.
It doesn't matter what quality culture you have if people don't like your product.
Yeah.
Wow.
That's that's that's quite a story.
It does show that I mean, although you can the point that really struck me in there is
the thing Brent and I don't want to see people or testers move past is the idea that
they're responsible for quality.
You know, if the customer is complaining about quality, shouldn't just be one part of
part of the organization feeling bad.
Everyone should feel bad.
Well, I think in that case, developers definitely felt bad.
OK, good, good.
Long as everybody's in a little bit of misery, it seems fair.
Yeah, it seems fair.
That's great.
I'm you know, you've brought up a few times that I mentioned earlier that you're five
years of experience.
But in that five years, you certainly I certainly wasn't as far along in my career
as far as thinking about things and thinking about systems thinking, thinking
about how I could affect bigger parts of the team.
So the things you're thinking about I was not doing five years into my career.
So I'm impressed.
And another thing I've been impressed about is how much and of course, you know,
I'm old enough.
There really wasn't much of an Internet when I was five years into my career.
But you're all over the Internet, but not as Yulia as this name I can't
pronounce. I hope you can help me with it's obvious case office costs.
Help me out and tell me where that tell me more about that name.
So there is no proper pronunciation because it was created to be unique
enough to be searchable on the Internet.
You are so much smarter than me.
Yeah.
So at first, it was a very long time ago when I was a teenager and I had
to come up with a nickname and we were looking for the I think it was
Latin dictionary and I was sounds great.
It's birth in Latin, you know, teenagers.
And then I found out that it's not very unique nickname and I had to
extend it somehow and I just added some suffix like case.
Okay, whatever.
So it's now with a viscous.
But generally when people need to pronounce it a lot like in video games,
they just tell it like I was I've been so that's it.
That's the story.
But the fun part is that at first it was a viscous result.
And then I added because it makes it even more unique.
Wow.
You have such foresight to do that because I've told there's a long story
on my blog about where the name Angry Weasel came from.
But it is not a unique name.
In fact, there is another angry weasel on Twitter who has posted one post
ever like six years ago and can't get their handle from them.
And of course, Alan Page is the name of a famous American football player.
So there's no uniqueness about me.
And I've become searchable as I've gotten older.
But that is so smart.
Yeah, I did a little bit of internet stalking and I see GitHub repos
and references to your GitHub repos on Stack Overflow conversations.
It is highly searchable.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Someone by the way, if you search your name,
one of the third posts down is someone thanking you for something
you posted to one of your guests on GitHub.
Oh, no.
Oh, that's a very bad story by the way.
I admittedly only skimmed, but it was something about installing Postman,
I think, on Linux.
I broke Postman.
Yeah, I broke Postman at one time in my life.
It was so apparently GitHub doesn't send you a notification
when people comment your guests.
So I didn't notice that it was very popular.
I just created it for me to be able to install it.
Which is what those are supposed to be for, but yeah.
Yeah, but people started finding it, commenting it, using it.
And I'm not using Postman by the way.
And I'm actually kind of against using it now.
I saw you have a blog post talking about that.
Yeah.
And every day it got worse for me because I think they are
almost like sole PUI now.
People just assume that for pay attention you need Postman
and that's it.
But that's gentle.
So one day, their support team from Postman approached me
and said that they implemented native installation
and native update.
And people who used my yeast install Postman are not able
to update it because I had some special, I think I was
installing it on the root.
So they actually had to trace it to the my yeast
and asked me to update it.
You are internet famous.
That's fantastic.
That's just one thing.
That's a wonderful story.
So the good news is I'll put a link to your blog here,
but people who want to find out more about you
and just kind of find random information about you
can just search on Avas case, Aviscus,
however you want to pronounce it.
That's what I want.
It doesn't matter, but that is so smart.
That should be every teenager should do that.
Everyone should actually work harder to find a unique name
versus their first and last name plus some numbers afterwards.
I'm so impressed.
This has blown my mind.
It's made my whole month and it's only April 3rd.
Well, the thing is that my first and last name
is pretty unique as well, at least in Kazakhstan, Canada.
Yes, but no one wants to be stalked on the internet
by their first and last name.
It helps you separate the person from you,
the internet personality.
That's my take on it.
All right, we are out of time, but this has been great.
I've loved talking to you.
Thank you for volunteering to be on the show.
It's been great.
And any last words or are you on Twitter?
No.
You don't seem like a Twitter person,
but I will give the links to your blog in the show notes.
Anything else I should point to?
I don't think so.
If somebody just wants to talk to me,
just ping me somewhere where you find me.
Good advice.
All right, well, thank you very much.
Have a wonderful weekend and good luck with the quarantine.
Good luck to you too.