Welcome to A.B. testing podcast, your modern testing podcast.
Your hosts, Alan and Brent will be here to guide you through topics on testing,
leadership, agile, and anything else that comes to mind.
Now on with the show.
Good morning and welcome to the A.B. testing podcast.
Hello.
What I want to do today is take a deep breath and reflect on the last 114 episodes and
ask yourself why would you come back for more?
I'm Alan.
I'm Brent.
We're here for episode 115 of the A.B.
testing podcast.
And it's not like I plan it, but I just like to surprise Brent a little bit.
It's good to see you, man.
It's been a while.
It has been a while.
We have had...
I'm not even certain we have a good answer to why we need to come back for more.
Because it's like watching a train wreck.
People want to see what's going to happen.
That's probably the best reason I could think of.
Yeah.
So travel, holidays, other stuff.
We did do a show in 2020, right?
We did.
So this is our second of 2020.
It is.
We're a little slow.
We're going to get back on track.
I don't have any extensive long traveling trips coming up.
I am.
Of course, no one wants to travel anymore today due to the coronavirus, the virus
you get from drinking Mexican beer.
Right.
Is that right?
That's what I have.
I haven't been totally caught up on the details, but I know I didn't have any trips to China,
so those aren't canceled.
So anyway, we're back.
We're going to do a podcast and we'll do another one in a couple of weeks as well
and try and get back on track.
Is that true?
Is that our...
Brent, Brent, rolling your eyes and shaking your head.
The probability is greater than 50%.
After 115 episodes, Brent doesn't quite realize that people who listen to this silly thing
can't see his face.
Anyway, shall we just...
Anything particularly exciting or interesting to talk about before we get off onto our topics?
I'm going to Scottsdale, Arizona this weekend.
Going to retire?
No.
Play golf?
Watch the Mariners?
Go...
Did they train there?
I don't know.
Going to do exactly nothing.
And you're going to go all the way to Scottsdale, Arizona to do that?
Yes.
Because you're going to do exactly nothing someplace that's warm.
That's exactly what we're excited about.
I'm going to go be colder next week.
It's my yearly pilgrimage to Whistler to try and see if my aging body can still fly down
a mountain.
Yeah, it should be fun.
There's a lot of exciting things coming my way, coming up in the near future.
I'm apparently doing a presentation to Satya next month.
Share with you and the three.
Oh my God, is my imposter syndrome just proactively triggering.
Excellent.
We're going to talk more about that later.
That would have been a great segue.
It would have.
But that will get you...
That little teaser will get you to come back and listen to the whole podcast.
But you also mentioned, obviously I can't talk about it, but yesterday I can talk about
some things.
So Microsoft has a whole world crisis team that go through and run humanitarian missions.
You may have heard that we're in the news.
We have a plan where we're going to be completely carbon neutral, including retroactively sometime
in the next few years.
So there's a humanitarian aspect of Microsoft that is on the rise and growing.
But my team, which now has some renown for natural language processing, is within Microsoft,
has been called in to assist on the coronavirus stuff.
So I already know, for example, at least one thing the common populace doesn't know.
Not sharing that here.
Are we all going to die?
No.
Is that thing you can't answer?
Not all of us?
Okay, great.
No.
And if you haven't done research, so this is the thing that's very common with this
type of stuff.
So coronavirus is, in essence, a worse flu virus.
So flu virus you can die from.
Coronavirus, there's a greater likelihood that you can die from, but not significantly
greater.
So like Douglas Haddow would say, keep calm, don't panic.
It's not...
You can actually do a lot of harm by panicking.
People want to panic.
They want this to be the one.
The 20th century, the 21st century black plague.
It's not going to be that.
I think the worst thing that's going to happen is a lot of people are going to be inconvenienced
greatly.
All right.
Shall we start?
Yeah.
Okay.
I have to turn around and see what the topic on the board...
Oh, I should mention, we're in a whole new building.
Brent has moved offices.
Yes.
He's in a secret location.
I can't announce it.
I had to be blindfolded, had a hood over my head, a couple of people walked me out along
to the hallways, and I'm in the middle of a dark room, middle of a building inside of
somewhere at Microsoft.
So that's exciting, but let's just hope I get out in time to edit this podcast.
It actually...
So it's fairly new to me as well.
It took us a good five minutes just to find the conference room because I haven't been
in the building long enough to know these things.
And I was a little late and I thought Brent would be prepared, but I thought wrong because
I didn't want to.
I don't know why you would think that.
There was no reason.
So let's go ahead and segue into the topic you alluded to earlier.
You're presenting to Satya.
Yep.
And I have presented to Satya.
Well, I've been part of a presentation to Satya, which is way different.
I have also been part of a presentation to Bill Gates, and I have also was around
during the Steve Ballmer area.
So area?
Steve Ballmer era.
In my time off, I forgot how to speak, but whatever.
One of the three whom I've forgotten asked if we could talk about like what's different?
What was Microsoft like in the Gates, Ballmer and Satya eras?
So that's, I think it's worthy of an opinion.
I have opinions of all three.
I don't know how you want to structure this or start because we started about the same
time at Microsoft.
We both had a significant amount of oh, there has been a significant milestone.
I saw I'm now on an age where significant milestones just make me feel old.
You have no idea.
But last week I hit my 25th year.
Oh, wow.
Yeah.
I, where would I be?
If I was still at Microsoft, I was slightly behind you, right?
So I would hit 25 in.
Oh, June, this June.
Yeah.
I actually remember you being slightly ahead of me, but it would have been at Microsoft
since January, 95, but I wasn't full time until June.
So June would have been my 25.
All right.
Then.
Yeah.
So we're very similar.
You have less experience now on how the Satya era is progressing, but I don't know.
I guess I'll just start.
Should we stop and go backward or how do you want to do this?
So here's.
You want to start and I'll jump in with commentary.
Yeah.
So here's how I view and we will have different perspectives and I guess we can just talk
about what we see as a different perspective.
The way I see the three CEOs and it was it was interesting that the bomber and the
Bill Gates, at least during my career here, was very cleanly separated by decades.
Right.
Microsoft, as you may or may not know, started in 1975 in actually Albuquerque, New Mexico.
All well-known facts.
I did not join until 1994.
So there was nearly two decades of Microsoft before I came here.
Yeah.
And for context, because we joined about the same time, Microsoft was about 15,000 people
back then.
Probably 94 a little less.
It was 15 when I joined.
Yeah.
My, if you use batch numbers, those aren't sequential.
So I have a five digit batch number.
Mine too.
And I can tell you mine because it's not, it's not, it's invalid.
I still remember my numbers, 39630.
Yeah.
So mine's 5,000 less than yours.
But again, Alan believes they're not sequential.
I think at that time they were, but I don't know.
Don't care.
Not relevant today.
Here's how I see as the three different decades.
And I don't know if Satya has already been here a decade, but it's coming up on it.
Bill Gates, we were all about growth.
And the way I would specify that that decade was sort of the competitive innovation decade.
Right.
We were rapidly growing.
The way Bill ran things, he highly encouraged cross team competition.
In some regards, that cultural aspect is what led not only James, but I think also you to
leave the company.
Yeah.
Right.
Because it's competition over customers.
Competition is more important than the customer.
Internal competition.
Everything's about competition.
Internal, but it was the way to build up the abilities to compete for external customers
was to compete internally.
And that was still around.
When I worked on teams to jump ahead, there were at least two or three other groups that
thought they were building a Slack competitor.
Our team just built the one that Satya liked best.
Right.
And while I don't have a lot of visibility, I don't know too many teams that are doing
it today.
I do believe that they are still likely teams in Microsoft, both believing that they are
going after the same mission.
And that's that as a business strategy, I think that's fine.
It's fine.
It's not again, I got burned out on competition being part of the way we built software,
even internal within a team due to the way people were reviewed, the way the highly
competitive I must crush you to get up.
It's like this isn't helping people.
The incentive model in combination with these, these competitive, again, competitive innovation
strategies created a lot in my view, it created a long term cultural issue that actually
still exists today.
Not nearly as bad as it did, but still exists and is detrimental today.
New startups that are going into space similar to Microsoft, they have the ability to move
forward in a way because some of the teams within Microsoft are going to be busy stepping
on each other's toes, which will slow us down.
I'm reminded of a Steven Sinek story.
I believe was in leaders eat last, but I could be wrong.
Ray talks about I'm sure I shared this on the podcast before where he was at a Microsoft
exec offside.
This is in the Balmer era and he saw presentations from execs and 90% of them were about competing
their competitors.
Who are they competing with?
That team, that team, that team, and that company, that company.
Then he went to an Apple and they've changed also.
They have new CEOs.
Went to an Apple exec retreat within the same year and 100% of those customers were what
they were doing for the customer.
I think there's something to be said about corporate culture there.
Did you ever go to a, were you ever part of a Bill G review?
Not a Bill G review.
I mean, I've been in meetings with Bill, but never one of the official Bill G reviews.
So I had two, I had two unique experiences with Bill Gates.
One was presenting in a group of test architects.
The original six or seven of us gave a presentation to him on what was going on.
It was state of the art and testing.
And we just made, made stuff up.
But I remember him walking in the room and saying something to the effect of I'm glad
you're here.
I pay a ridiculous amount of money to hire testers for my company, but I don't know what
you do.
But after that, he was really nice.
He was actually interested in what we had to talk about.
He liked the techniques.
We showed him some model based testing stuff with some visualization and he loved the visual.
He wanted to play with the visualization for a long time, but we didn't let him.
We moved on.
But anyway, very super mellow friendly.
Yeah.
He was in a Bill G business review years later and he got the result he wanted and it was
it was good to watch him work because he was so smart and so quick and he could pick apart
anything and he would spot better than anyone I've ever seen where you had, where you were
right and where you were hand waving.
And to me, people knew this about him, yet they still fell back on.
I mean, just the idea that I would, I was watching a PM on our team get torn apart because he
went off script, started talking a little bit hyperbolic and, and he got ripped apart.
So it was about facts and data and not feelings and about knowing exactly what you're doing
and why you were doing it and backing it up and anything else was just shredded off
like meat on a bone.
There is a bit of advice that I give people and it's very relevant here.
I don't know if it prevails multiple different companies here.
A path of success is visibility.
And it's well known, hey, like for example, I'm doing a presentation to Satya.
I should be super excited.
I'm going to be visible to Satya.
That's going to grease the wheels for my triple skip promotion next month.
That's I think, I mean, that's hyperbole, but that's kind of how the old school guard
would view these things.
And I'd say very much the way it's viewed now.
I mean, I've been gone three years, but that was, that was still 100% the case three years
ago.
Go on.
It is not 100% today, but yes, it's still there.
Absolutely.
Like until, until much of the old guard keeping, keeping that old culture alive, retire or otherwise
leave the company.
AKA your last boss.
Yep.
I saw that.
Yeah.
The, it's,
That's going to be, and let me just a quick tangent.
That's going to be interesting to watch.
So my old VP is retiring and how shall I put this without being, I don't think anybody
in my old team is educated enough to listen to the podcast except for, except for Dan.
Hey, Dan.
It's going to be interesting politically what happens because that org, but push me over
the top and leaving, that org was built around people.
And this is not, you know, I, I, I think teams is doing well.
It's great.
This is not spiteful, but that team, the frustrating part, the biggest frustration
for me on that team was a leader who surrounded himself with people who sucked up to him.
And that is not my vision of building a good engineering or a good culture on a team.
So I wonder what's going to happen with someone coming in to replace him who I know of vaguely
it's a way different style, how that's going to work and how fearful some of those people
should be about their continued success in that organization.
Yeah, I don't know who's, I think there's some, and it's weird that you have to
worry in a company like that, like this, that, wherever they are, Microsoft, those political
things, those, those, those bits become very, very important.
But anyway, let's go back to where are we at?
Satya, we skipped bomber, but bombers, a whole story we want to get to know.
We're going to get into that one.
So the one thing the important in the, the yes, there, there are some things that,
Bill Gates era that still persists and it's, it's a negative aspect of the culture in my
humble opinion.
And it turns out based off of a report I saw recently of Bill's opinion too.
But he, he's like fine wine, man.
He's mellowed with age.
He, he, he, his focus on innovating was critical to this company.
And it was a big part of why our stock.
1 million percent agree, if that were possible.
So I'll go with a hundred.
Yeah.
Now bomber era.
So Bill Gates brought Microsoft to number one on all sorts of bars, including capitalization.
Meaning here we were the most valuable company on the stock market.
Now there's consequences that come with that.
And one of my favorite authors, Stephen Blank wrote a bunch of studies on this is that because
of the free market, you're pushed to sort of continuously play the king of the hill game.
And once you're the king of the hill, just by design, you end up having to defend your
position and that takes up so much energy, innovation stagnates.
Now bomber grew up in sales and was beholden to the board.
And we were in number one and the bomber decade was purely around how to defend our
position.
Okay.
Now there is a law that I've stated repeatedly on this one.
Any time I call it, well, the law that I've coined states, he who is defensive loses always.
You cannot win any game being defensive only.
And Stephen Blank goes, that's actually the natural thing that happens to large enterprises
that are the king of the hill.
And the biggest mistake that they make is they significantly underfund the innovation
in their desperate attempt to defend their sales.
And at that time, there was a lot of confidence as well.
Like I remember having conversations with my manager at the time and like we all knew
that Windows had, to build Windows, it had one quadrillion lines of code.
No company was going to go from nothing to competition on that overnight, except unless
they start working through an agile paradigm and prioritizing building one little incremental
piece of code at a time that satisfies the customer's needs.
Fast forward, Android OS as an example.
So I have an experience, yes, and I fully agree.
And I have an experience that from the bomber area, from one of his, I guess it'd be one
of his skip levels, so his down, it's one of the exact VPs at the time.
I was at some leadership training and he was our guest presenter talking about operating
systems and networking, et cetera.
I asked, because this is the time when Chrome OS wasn't around, it was thought of, it wasn't
really out there, and I asked him if, say, given the amount of knowledge work that is
done in the browser today, do you see any reason for Microsoft to make a lightweight
OS that could be used on lower cost computers for browser-based work?
Which I think makes a lot of sense.
It's not like Chrome OS has swept the industry or anything, but whether or not I'm not the
marketer that figures out what the next thing is is going to win, but I felt like there
was something there and I was curious about his opinion.
And his answer was literally, but you can't play games on those and on Windows you can
play games.
And I think that epitomizes, it's a defense of like, we have something that does this while
we want to do something else.
We have, we've solved that problem.
You can do games and use a browser.
If I classify the Bill Gates era as sort of competitive innovation, right, bomber era was
competitive sales.
We shifted from a growth approach to trying to protect our revenue.
What was the bomber era?
Do you recall when he started and stopped so I can frame that in my career?
It was around 10 years and no, I don't.
It's on Wikipedia.
All right.
Early 2000s to about 10 years later.
When bombers leadership, for example, Sanofsky used his position as the head of Windows, which
was the cash cow at the time or one of them to sort of influence features in other teams.
They were driving towards the only thing that matters is protecting Windows sales.
And.
How'd that work out in the long term?
I think time has shown.
So the one thing with the bomber eras is that is actually when we were, when the tech era
was strongly shifting between different worlds.
That's the shift to more of a services.
It's the shift to the cloud.
I remember watching all that happen and we were slow to adapt as a company.
That had been in many ways, not just in software, but in how software was made, engineering
approaches a leader.
We had, you know, I was in the room.
We talked about the S debt title and now we can't get rid of the title.
I'm very sorry.
Industry with the shift to cloud.
We did not innovate.
We followed for a long time in that area.
There were teams doing, doing real.
There were organizations doing things like blue, green deployments, testing and production
while we were still focusing on building up our environment.
Here's the thing that I learned as you know from my, my job history.
Bing has already figured it out, but they hadn't figured out a way to generalize it
to everyone else.
And I remember being, being like, Oh, you're not like us.
Well, we can never learn from you.
We had talks about being in, we had a talk with how agile worked in being being, you're
right.
Bing was probably, they might've been right there with the industry if not slightly ahead,
but definitely not as behind as some other orgs were, but that didn't happen.
But the thing is Bing, because they were fighting a, not only a losing battle, but
a severely losing battle with Google.
And at the same time, we were strongly trying to defend our, our sales.
Even if they had the leadership that, that could influence the rest of Microsoft, it
wouldn't have happened because all the other motivators were in the wrong direction.
Okay.
Satya part of his prior career is guess what organization he once had.
Bing.
Like he was well suited for understanding this new world.
He had already been doing it for almost a decade.
And the way I would classify Satya's thing right now is he's gone back to innovation,
but it's collaborative innovation now.
Okay.
That's new in the last three years.
That's new.
He's very clear on his messages here, but he's also very clear that there's a lot of
work to do to shift that culture internally to be a lot more collaborative.
There's still, for example, my team.
I'm doing a lot of work that benefits all of Azure, but I am funded by one specific
team within Azure.
My PM is an entirely different organization, an entirely different organization.
We are an example of cross-group collaboration success.
However, there's still enough of the old world practice that I am constantly worried,
wondering around when am I going to be notified of the reorg that moves my team
into the same organization as that PM.
Thus killing cross-group.
And one of the arguments I'm finding right now is actually me being outside of that
group actually strengthens the forward progress because I can ignore their
particular politics that may actually slow me down and they can ignore mine.
So it allows us a little bit more adaptability, a little bit more agility.
But we still have budget concerns, so there's still a semblance of competitiveness,
but the review has definitely softened on that front.
And yeah, we still have a lot more to do.
But the biggest thing in my view is that he's really pushing on innovation on
this one.
And if you read the news on the Microsoft stock quotes, there are now financial
advisors going with Microsoft motivation.
It's a matter of time before we're number one.
All right.
So I would re-summarize your errors as Bill Gates is drive for innovation.
Steve Ballmer is defend where we are and Stagnate.
And Satya is let's put the bullshit behind us and try and actually win again.
Sure.
How does that work?
That works for me.
I had a few reviews of Satya before I left.
I was in the room and I talked to him.
Very level-headed, very, I believe from my interaction with him,
I believe what you're saying.
My frustration definitely with James Whitaker's frustration is how slow the
ship is moving because of the old guard.
Yeah, I completely agree.
And you said win again and I want to tweak that because he is really driving that
and again, it's going slower than I think you and I would want,
but definitely Whitaker would want, but he is pushing towards it.
Whitaker even mentioned it in his last article.
He loved what Satya is doing.
The only complaint, too slow.
I mentioned earlier the humanitarian efforts and the carbon stuff.
Satya is pushing to have Microsoft win, but also to have the world win.
Yeah, and you look, if Bill Gates is still in charge of the company,
he'd be doing the same thing today because that's what he's working on.
Probably would be, I agree.
I think it was more of the young let's go out and make something exciting happen.
And I don't recall if Bill is still the chairman.
I think he is, but Bill absolutely has influence over the board.
But he's just not the CEO.
Yep.
And in fact, I didn't go to any of them, but during the bomber area,
there were still regular Bill G reviews with teams.
He would still come in for reviews frequently.
And that I think was part of their thing.
Like between the two of them, right, they always had the strong partnership
relationship.
He was the...
Yep.
He was always the tech guy, and bomber was sort of the charismatic sales guy.
Now, going back to...
So we started this, and I realized I'd never close on this.
So there's advice I give people who try to go and talk to their executive.
Like you told the story around PM coming in, and Bill could immediately see
where fact was and where hand weaving was.
When you were building a deck for an executive, the first and foremost thing
you should understand is that they cannot scale.
They cannot know the details.
So they have optimized, and they have practiced, and they have gained skills
in entering one question and one question only.
And that is, can I blindly trust this guy to lead this mission?
So when you're doing a presentation to those folks, your number one goal
needs to express confidence that you got this.
And different executives will have different bullshitometers,
but understand they're using it every single time, because they are accountable
for so many things that you do not understand, and you will often not even
get enough time on their schedule to know how...
To what degree your aspect of this is important to their mission.
Yes, I'm looking up a tweet, because actually Angie...
What kind of...
I can't find this.
I mentioned this on Twitter.
She had a question on Twitter around...
I'm at the paraphrase, because I can't find the tweet on my phone.
She asked about internal presentations versus external presentations,
and what do you do differently?
And I said...
I replied, because I have an opinion.
I have three presentations I give.
External presentations are about entertainment.
Okay.
Internal talks to my team are highly interactive.
I wouldn't do an interactive for a keynote.
It's like, let's get stuff out here.
We'll talk about it, ask questions as they go a lot.
Exec presentation is...
I think I said also for external tell stories entertain.
For execs, also tell stories, but using carefully researched and well-backed up
data and not going off on any tangents.
You have to communicate confidence.
Yes.
That's it.
Yeah.
And I tell...
I tell...
Yes.
And then be ready for any question at any time and have a confident answer.
That's not just preparing the presentation for confidence.
It's preparing the...
It's having the background at tip of tongue.
I have a different perspective than that for that question.
Like number one, if you are doing a presentation, the purpose of every presentation is to entertain
your audience.
Right?
A lot of people go, no, it's to inform your audience.
No, it's not.
It's different between a...
Like my external presentation is more of a...
I'll put it this way.
My presentation to execs is a documentary.
Still entertaining, but full of data and information.
You do it in a way that gets them excited.
Yes.
You have to do a different style if it's a right only presentation versus a read-write
one.
And here I mean writing a keynote.
You're right.
You got to be doing all the talking.
It's definitely not my preference.
I prefer the give and take with the crowd.
But that doesn't scale at a certain size.
In my view, the difference...
So Alan is better at presenting than I am, but my difference between internal and external
is external.
I will scrub corporate IP and then on internal, I basically remove the fluff slides from the
external to give room for interaction.
That's my difference.
Yeah.
I...
There's not much.
In fact, I may take a couple of the presentations I gave internally at an internal conference
and give the exact same presentation externally.
I have very little corporate IP.
I add some numbers, which I think are public.
Well, we're not a public company, so they're not.
So I'm doing...
I would have to scrub a little bit.
I'm doing a lot of data science presentations and...
Yeah, just put a bunch of math.
Yeah.
So, if you're doing math in a data science presentation, I kind of find that pointless
because you can just say, hey, look, here's a link to Wikipedia.
Go look up the math.
Right?
The data that I would be presenting almost always represents IP.
So I have to be very careful with that.
Understood.
Tell stories.
Anyway, are we done?
I'm not that we have time to get to anything else, but I want to make sure...
Was there anything else on the Gates-Bomber-Sautia era?
Did you ever present anything to Bomber?
I had a word once, very simple interaction.
He and I shared an elevator.
And I'm like, he looks familiar.
And I just looked at him and he looked at me like, what are you trying to figure out?
And I'm like, you're Steve, aren't you?
And he said yes.
Excellent.
Have a great day.
What a dork.
Well, so apparently I had not hidden my body language enough, so he looked at...
I mean, he was clearly going, sup.
Yeah.
I just tried to figure out...
Because you look a lot like him.
There's an anecdote from the Bomber era where...
Developers, developers, developers.
Well, that was actually during...
He said that during the Bill G era.
Correct.
But during the Bomber era, he did snatch someone's iPhone out of their hand and throw it on
the ground at a company meeting.
Yeah.
And again, defend versus innovate.
It's like, wow, this is taking off.
Maybe we should make a bunch of apps for this.
No.
So...
You'd have to go...
That defense...
So like here, this is one of the things, and this is something that I will state over
and over again, because every now and again, I run into something like this.
Teams that kind of will go, oh, you're duplicating our effort.
I'm like, no.
Right.
I have developed a great strategy for when I get accused of that.
But let's go back to modern testing principles.
Right.
That actually drives me on this one.
And this is, in my view, Bomber did do that.
And I think it was a tragic mistake.
Like look, Bomber, we had the Windows phone and it was competing with iPhone and we were
at least three years late.
Okay.
Yes and no.
I had a touchscreen phone with Wi-Fi in my hand years before the iPhone came out.
But here's the thing.
Even if Bomber was able to, we'll call it, negatively motivate all of Microsoft to go to
Windows Phone, and I don't remember, there was a period early on in his where we would
all get Christmas gifts.
Like we all got a Surface.
I used the...
Did we get a phone?
I don't recall.
Yeah, I got phones for years.
Right.
And like in terms of the market that we're trying to go into, even if all of Microsoft
were users, if they weren't vocal advocates, then all you're going to get is Microsoft
and that is a blip on that market.
Right.
It is small.
It's not even a blip.
A blip.
And that's part of the thing I think was strategically in error, just quite honestly.
And that's the point I was getting at.
I think not looking...
And that's, I think Bomber also epitomized the...
It was all about not invented here during that time especially.
It was not just for the internal tools like we've talked about, but we didn't look
about how we could, we as Microsoft at the time, could take advantage of and interact
with the changes that were happening.
We talked about web stuff.
The phone growth happened there too.
And we saw it through our competitive colored glasses instead of, okay, what...
How do we...
Instead of principle number five.
How do we ride the wave?
Like I said, instead of principle number five.
Right.
We had phone products and we were doing pretty well with them.
The ones that were all on the WinCEOS.
I loved my PDA phone, if you remember those things.
Yes, I do.
But Apple was out innovating us.
When we came out with Zoom, Apple was like, oh yeah, that's pretty neat.
Hey, have you seen our iPhone?
Like we were three years behind and still trying to play...
We didn't quite...
We tried to play catch up.
Yes.
And in those phases, you can't play follow the leader.
You have to play leapfrog.
Right.
And that's what's missing.
It's like, how do you leapfrog instead of follow the leader?
I like that.
And the thing is, I actually thinking back, I think a lot of the bomber era in analyzing
what happened, what went well, what didn't, helped influence my opinion around the modern
testing principles.
Absolutely.
Because I kept on...
By that point in time, I was teaching people how to do agile migrations.
And I don't know if you remember this, I'm sure you will once I bring it up.
Bomber had division by division sort of talking events with principle level folks.
Oh, I remember those, yes.
And I remember that I had already talked to three teams and major teams that go through
this agile transition.
When I first heard a bomber stayed out of his mouth, that we needed to shift to agile.
Huh.
Anyway, we got to go.
All right.
Yep.
See ya.
Bye.