What's the deal with I Stq B?
Welcome to a B testing podcast your modern testing podcast your hosts Alan and Brent
Will be here to guide you through topics on testing leadership agile and anything else that comes to mind now on with the show
Hey, I'm Alan. I'm Brent and we are back again for another episode of a B testing. I don't know what number it is
That's Brent stuff
116 that's what's that number in binary?
It's
Frantically counting on his fingers. Hey Ben
What's new pussycat Wow?
Have you ever been to Scottsdale, Arizona? Oh, that's right. You went to Scottsdale, Arizona
I've never been there because I'm not although I'm older chronologically. I am NOT that old. I
Understand the comment you are attempting to make know the comment was made
I
Yeah, I went there yes, the short answer is no, but that was that was more boring than the proper answer
Go ahead. I am you went to Scottsdale. I
Did you golf I did not so?
Did you sit outside? Oh my god?
about the heat oh
This is gonna be a fun adventure today
So never been to Arizona
Or
Scottsdale anyway, I realized after the trip that I had in fact been at Arizona before
My as a as a young kid Ling we used to do trips to Lake Havasu
Which has the London Bridge at the songs all about?
So I've seen that but I do I do recall it moved there. Yep
Have still have not seen the Grand Canyon
Anyway, what I did see
You know you know on every cartoon ever when they talk about the desert they show the the typical
Cactus with the arms yep to the side
That's first time I've seen those in real life and I was surprised by how
Gigantic they are they're like tree size wait wait how big are they?
They are so big
That they're tall they are that trombone sound effect like two to three
at least two times up to three times the size of a
Standard adult human it was kind of cool
It was neat that that
They didn't have light pollution at night, so you got to see the stars
Their night times were the same temperature as the Seattle daytime. Oh
So like 40 degrees yeah, I mean cuz it's the desert so it it just back and forth
We didn't go out exploring
The this was just a 3d weekend
And part of the point was just hanging out by the pool and drink
That part I like yes, we did
Unfortunately, we brought the kids with us all of them are just the two youngest the ones that still live with us. Yeah
We didn't even tell them our oldest until I send them a picture from the in and out and in Scottsdale
He's like what are you doing in California?
So he might be a little angry at us because it's the first time we've ever done a trip and not even ask if you wanted
to go
But it was it was good time
my we are now in the
moment of the year
And because it's sleepier
Which is tomorrow
Not for the podcast listeners, but for you and me leap day is tomorrow leap day. Yeah. Yes
Day is tomorrow. So
every four years ish
My wife is
Exactly two weeks older than me. She just celebrated her birthday Wednesday
So two weeks from last Wednesday
it will be mine and
I am
Officially moving a step closer to a RP. Oh, I've been a member for years
Yeah, it's I was talking with one of my employees yesterday and it there's this psychological
Thing that happens when you work in the software industry where the majority of people are 20 something 30 something's
And so you walk around you see everyone in their
30s and
You just you it's very easy to forget that you are not
Yes. Yes, I
Went down to the Bay Area yesterday for a set of meetings
We should talk about DevOps sometime. I don't know why this because it's so close to testing and I
It's so close to I think actually I think I've mentioned on the podcast that it is
The best tool I've ever had to accelerate the achievement of a quality that that's I was down there talking about DevOps
In California twice on my mind. I think actually I mean we could we should talk about it because I have a hypothesis that
DevOps is is
in essence a
Service oriented actual
implementation of true
agile
Yes, I mean but just like everything else in agile. There are fantastic ways just completely effort up
Absolutely true as well one quick little bit. I'll just we'll get back on the topic of the day
I promise but I find it interesting
You know DevOps was never meant to be a role meant to be a culture that got rid of throwing things over the wall
not from Deb the test but from Deb to
Operations and the idea of a DevOps culture meant that the full team anyone on the team could deploy or
Whatever culture where it's easy for anyone to safely deploy rollback, etcetera their stuff
Which helps fulfill several of the agile principles?
The DevOps role has grown out of that for some reasons that some of us used to fight now
We just throw our hands up near say yeah, we I think we get what you mean as long as you do it, right?
But what I'm finding as I have an open DevOps position on my team is that
As I look at resumes of people who say they do DevOps it is
Just as wide if not wider than the resumes of people that say they do testing
Wait, why do you have a DevOps position on your team?
Your team I run you're hiring
Okay, so are you hiring?
Because I'm confused
I work at Unity. No, I understand just just didn't know I just making sure that how much alcohol you drank anyway
Well, so to me it seems like you're hiring an SRE role
because as you
Stated DevOps is a cold it is it is really in the okay. Let me be clear
Do you want to know where DevOps go 10 years ago? I would have been hiring for a
Infrastructure person a platform person a tools person
Okay today the fancy sexy things to call those roles DevOps. Oh
I did not realize that I hate that with great intensity. So the team I the team I ran at
Microsoft my last team basically was a DevOps team
Airquote that the listeners can't see DevOps is what you call people that build all the tools and
Processes and things that allow you to quickly and easily ship stuff to customers. Okay, so can can we start?
Trying to rename this one. We can't DevOps
Infrastructure to can't we can't the ship has sailed we can only ride on the ship. Oh my god
Okay
so
Let's talk about the thing that's been working through the modern DevOps principles
Alright, let's go and actually we've talked about we'll never get there because there are I think from Jez humble
Don't quote me the three ways of DevOps
Which are three things that I don't have memorized right now, but I remember reading them thinking
Oh, these are aligning very very very very well with the modern testing principles
So let's talk about the I
STQB vision on the future of software testing because it's been flown around a lot
We're gonna go through it in a little bit of detail and talk about our opinions
There is one line in it that I'm sure we'll get to
That one line out of the whole thing and not that the whole thing is like super awesome or anything except for the one line
but the one line that has triggered
Absolutely triggered a large handful of people from the test community
So we'll go over that and some of the repercussions have come out of that as well
So so let's go ahead. Well, you have a point. Whoa. Whoa. Whoa. So I don't know if this is the line that you're talking about
No, not that I'm very curious as to what ideas
You contributed to this paper
Okay, you want to get right there? Yeah. Oh, yeah, I
Think it's easier to
Get into that later. So my okay, that's fine. I will tell you right now. No, no, no, no
We you brought it up. We can't leave it go now if you go to the acknowledgments
We could have held it as a cliffhanger. No, you screwed everything up again
So we go to the acknowledgments and the team thanks the following leaders who were interviewed and gave ideas for this white paper in alphabetical order
blah blah blah Alan Page I
I'm not saying I didn't talk to them, but I don't remember talking to them. I don't know
What the interview was I I feel like maybe a couple years ago or a year and a half ago
I could have talked to someone
But I don't know what I said, I don't have a transcript or notes I can't find anything on my calendar
I'm not do you think this paper?
Was under development for a couple of years. It may have been I don't remember it certainly I certainly haven't talked to anyone
Recently at the very end again. I'm old and I do acknowledge that and I do acknowledge that I drink a lot
But I do not remember by it's maybe it's a different talent. It's weird. I have this vague
Like I have this vague recollection of
Someone asking me to talk to them, but I do something like guest podcasts that it could be one of those that I did
there's enough of a
vague recollection I could have talked to someone and I do
I
Get contacted for whatever reasons for a lot for just
Research interviews and things for various publications
I don't recall this one, but I do enough of these things that I may have said something to him all that said I don't
recognize I
Mean other than the obvious things that we're going to agree with in this paper that we're gonna go through in a minute
I don't really recall any specific things. I may have said or even if I actually talked to these folks
So that's my and we should let me come back to that because that my name being in this has caused
more than one
More than one alter not an altercation is wrong
a
Conversation on the internet because my name's in this paper
So let's go ahead you want do you want to start with something or do you want me to start?
How do I go through this so you can start?
This is a very short paper and I'm probably gonna forget to link to it in the show notes, but just search for the
Istqb vision on the feature of software testing if you're and again
I usually put a sentence about the show on the website and if I remember a link
I'll put it there, but I realized that 99% of you just listen to this thing
What's the end the 9% of three?
Rounded down the two so two of you rounds up to three two of you
Whatever want to do two of you probably just play this in your podcast player and never go to the website
But there's a link anyway
the first paragraph is all about
Trying to establish the credibility of Istqb
So I'm gonna skip that one and then they say the out the statement that then this is not controversial
Software testing is a complex topic. I'm gonna skip that but one thing in paragraph two will start with is
True and I could have said this I could have contributed to this
Significant change in the software. I didn't say this nevermind
Significant change in the software doesn't discipline is on the horizon and testing has become a quality assurance driver engaging other professions and professionals
Not just software testers. I'm not even sure why I underline that anymore except for the fact that
All of this has been true for years as far as I'm concerned
I don't know what's futuristic there
But I do think change is coming in the discipline in that it's in everything we've been talking about in modern testing
Yeah, no, that's why modern testing exists. We want to talk about the changes happening to how software testing is performed
well, so a lot of people's favorite episode of
Of a retesting every no everyone's I
This point in time. There's a lot of people who haven't even gone back to that episode
everyone oh sure
Where we did the where you dropped the is TQP
Quiz or questionnaire or test on me. Yes, and you failed I did fail
Suck it
So I think like captures us on this one is is the statement that significant change in the software testing discipline is on the horizon
Now that's something that we very much agree with
now the question is
Do we agree with what that change is?
Right there's surely in that some second part of that sentence
Make honestly, I'm having a hard time
Decomposing it and testing has become a quality assurance driver engaging other professions and professionals
Not just software testers now one way to interpret that could be the quality coach
Maybe but the one thing I don't like about this is it doesn't go it
I thought it maybe mentioned coaching and what spot it could be
misremembering ever read this in a week or two, but
it still
Views testing as a distinct and separate discipline and not an activity of software development, which is I think not the future
But anyway, go on. Yep. No, no, I'm I'm good. You want to talk about the next paragraph?
I don't even know. Okay, there's nothing there. I feel like I could write a
One paragraph version of this whole paper. There's a lot of there's a lot of stuff saying testing is hard
We worked hard to figure out the testing is hard
Yes in the future it gets harder
Technology blah blah blah. I think you may be over simple. I mean, yes, it does seem like a
lawyer in test wrote this
Right because of the the language that they're using
That's lit
Software lawyer and test. Yeah
Like on the vision the vision that they talk about
First and foremost, I don't know why they've done this but I do I do think
That in their vision they are potentially playing it's safe
Because they keep referring to this term called testing technology solutions. Yeah, I'm not sure what that means. That just mean tools
No, I took it to mean tools is that wrong? No, I'm pretty certain they mean AI. Oh
Well, we all know AI is gonna change everything or not
Yes, so surely it's talking about future. They mentioned AI in this video if you go to
So here if later on in the document
They have a section called the clarifying section for the vision of software testing and
and
They describe testing technology solutions as follows the testing technology solutions will have quote
intelligence in quote built into them
Yeah, there are several trends including AI which will address effectiveness and accuracy of of
Testing other systems and can be used to develop innovative testing technology solutions
over time these
Testing technology solutions will evolve into
Learning teaching engines they will learn from testing experts, but we'll also learn from other
testing technology solutions and from themselves as
software development or development evolves these testing technology solutions may be integrated into software development technologies, okay
All right, I get it. So that describes
AI and the process of building and
Training AI so one thing before I get into the controversial statement one thing I don't like about this paper is
complete lack of specificity
So it's very broad stroke ish things are gonna change and it'll get different
Oh, so no, that's fine
Maybe that's the thing that where they picked up from you right because it's this is following our prediction episode paradigm
If you just say things hand wavy
Yeah, I if it's I'm not happy with the writing it so beyond that
Let's dig into this. There's one thing in this clarifying vision
Which in the paragraph above the one you read which let's go ahead and get into now before I go on because
It's this is the one that has triggered people lots of stories to go on here
Software testing is moving towards more automation. No, it's not so
Okay, that one has that's not the future that's been true for the past
Gazillion years. No, it's not though because they're mutually exclusive. Okay, let me get on to that
Because I assume that's going to go off so it says but then it says the part which is
I I get what they're saying
I don't agree with it
but not to the vehemant degree as some of the people that have
Stocked me on LinkedIn have over time a software testing will become fully automated and embedded in the processes and technology
It's in the overall software development cycle
Now you can make your voice cuz software testing can't be fully automated you can automate checking but testing requires
Exploration and investigation and the computer can do that
Actually it can
So what computers can't do is
Well, actually and that's not even true
I was about to say they can't do inductive reasoning
But that's not actually true either
So I have written and I put this in Twitter and I'm gonna work backward is that I've written plenty of tests that do
Investigation and helped me explore the application
there is
so what happened was
more than once I've been tagged on LinkedIn because my name's not acknowledgement section and
Someone who has not read the whole paper but just that line has decided to go off on
the fact that
She only checking can be automated which is bull and only testing can be done by a human and this
complete and utter gatekeeping on this concept that yes, some tests have a binary result and some tests don't but
the
insistence on
having people use the right language and an inability to infer from context and an
Inability to see past your private little vocabulary that only exists within a microcosm of the software development world
Just is not helping your cause. It's not making you look good every time
And this is I know that there are listeners who are in that who believe in context-driven school
I think context-driven is fine
It's some of the dogma that's coming out of the the people that have developed that which has caused problems in the industry
And I'm fine because those people
Deal with people brand new to test don't know what they're doing. They're not
Air-quote technical they've been thrown in to test things and they've been shoved at a conference and there are people in the industry who make
Their livings on testers that have don't know what they're doing and are shoved under a mushroom and don't know
blah
Why a mushroom?
Because there's there's some mushroom thing. They're in the dark and crapped on it. Oh got it. All right
So look I get it I get it I get that you
Follow two people in all of software and they believe and you believe that only they have the right answers for everything and you must
regurgitate everything they say
versus thinking for yourself, but for Christ sakes
You need to think a little bit wider if you're going to be a successful knowledge worker in the 21st century
So anyway stepping off of that rant on to another one
I got tagged as like them post because you need I want answers Alan
I want answers for this statement
Someone said that to you not in those words
But they went through and they found the they started with just a couple of us who were tagged in there
It's easier to find but I think they went through it eventually tagged everyone they could find from that
Acknowledgments list looking for answers on why they thought why we all thought testing could be fully automated
Well now you have a podcast to send them to
That to me
That does does the amount of heat that you're getting are you suffering deja vu?
You know, it's the same. Yeah, I mean
It's not deja vu. It's
recursive to me it feels
We have a different version of to me. It feels a little bit like a
Different version of the white knuckle
Holding on to the past that we experienced
when you and I
essentially came out and said
Not only is testing going away at Microsoft
We agree with it. No the testing role is going right not the testing. Yeah. Yeah, and and people I tell people
Alan you've been in testing a long time
I said I've dissolved the last like I have a bad habit of dissolving all the test teams
I work on because it's the right thing to do right so this I think is
What they're stating here the is TQP is essentially
one way to interpret it is
The final mail to the coffin is
Coming. I don't think it's worded in such a way. I don't think it reads that way
I think you could read software testing will become fully
automated
right that means
number one if you're in testing the robots are coming to take my job and
and
It means it's not going to dev
Going to the computers, right?
People would argue and you and I work almost entirely on back-end services API's
Very little that the customer sees there are a lot of people
testing the things the customers look at the UI's the interfaces the interactions the workflows who
Insists that that must be tested manually. They must use their
fantastic
investigational exploratory skills that work at the speed of the human brain
To test those things in order to protect the customer from bugs
What do you say to those people that's easy?
companies who who
Have test leadership
That gets influenced and buy into that philosophy
Will be destroyed. Yeah there and those people are deeply embedded in job preservation as well
They're not you and I and you know, you've seen me do this every role
I'm in I try and work myself out of a job for better or for worse
But there's this opposite effect among many of these people where they want to dig their heels in and make sure their job exists forever
Why do we automate?
Because we're bored. No, we automate
We automate because we're trying to scale engineering
Time that to engineering hours. Okay AI. What is AI?
artificial intelligence good job
AI
In essence is automated decision-making. Yes, that is what AI is very well put
So yes currently a lot of a lot of the software automated testing
I would say a bulk of it is
Checking right. Hey, I expect this to pass. I expect this to fail
We know
Hell I know I've implemented the you've already admitted to implementing
Exploratory absolutely as possible sure and with AI
You can make
Exploratory much more intelligent. Well, if you think about let's go and wait and then you combine that with product telemetry
When we're in the service space
Sorry
If you one big thing in services and applications now is growing is observability
not just the logging and monitoring being able to know the state of
What's going on in your application at any time and full observability?
Now if you start adding AI into observability AI is great at pattern matching
It can start to recognize when if it's connected with the with the internal structures of the software
It can actually I could
We could create AI to do just-in-time
Diagnostics and recognize when a current state is one hasn't seen before
like my soft your software system has reached a state that
The AI has determined it shouldn't be in that's not theoretical. I know no, no, no
I've actually written this in my I've written this in my head a little excited. No, no
So yes, I know it's not theoretical it's possible and likely happening I
can
Date it is happening
So the main point is I think a lot of the folks who are freaking out over that
There's other stuff I want to get to which is equally as controversial this it's really cool
There's two statements that should trigger the crowds that I'm speaking about this one especially
But there's another one another section. I'll get to in a moment
But yes, I think people are blocked
They aren't thinking big enough
They aren't looking at a big enough picture and they don't realize that some of these things are more
Possible than they think they are because they get stuck in their vocabulary and their dogma
Yes
Yes, and
I love it when we have episodes where I get to rant and I'm not even done yet. Oh
Yeah
Now it's interesting
Because I didn't know where we were gonna go me neither about this thing
So I don't know what your next statement is but there's one thing I want to bring up. Yeah, you all yours
I need to I need to lower my pressure. I'm gonna check the stress level on my on my smartwatch
so the I would love to
Be able to conclude that is TQB is actually seeing the same things we are
Now what I think is interesting is what what they are proposing
Might be different and we should get into that
But here's a statement that I think is
Just so friggin important
I'll read the whole paragraph
The perception of quality of software systems continues to change
okay, and
We've talked about this a million times
the the
1986 definition of quality is bugs and
That is bullshit in today's world
Get over that is not that it is
customer of the business that drives that that perception
Continuing on is affected by factors in the marketplace
economics technology culture
software technological innovation and
globalization the business
the business
drives the
interpretation of this perception of quality
No, only the gatekeepers of quality could tell the person. Oh damn it
Go on so we that one future of testing
White paper we talked about a couple years ago
One of the things they called out is
that
business leaders
really felt
testing
Need to step up and understand how the business drives its business
Okay, there is another section in here where they call out
QA needs to shift to decision-making roles. Yes, and I cannot you actually finish that I want to get into that next right I
Completely agree. I wish this whole idea of
We just provide information to the stakeholders. So let me go ahead and get into that
Because there is a big and I can name drop here
so Michael Bolton over and over and over again and then through the the blind followers
I'll call them blind followers because they don't look outside of that that echo chamber
Insists that
Testers get out of the quality assurance business because I think
labeling yourself as purely an information provider is
a
very passive rule and not an active role in software development and
Probably more importantly I I don't see a career path there. I don't see I mean, there's no growth there
What do you do provide better deeper more information? I
Don't know why someone would want to be part of a software development team and they weren't actively participating in delivering that software
Here's my reports do it whether you want not my choice. I can't make decisions above my pay grade, which is crap
It falls into the same group who in fact these guys do it too. This happens a lot in just in general
People like to blame the pointy haired managers. Oh, we can't do proper testing because our managers won't let us well
My manager at Microsoft in my first day gave me a list of test cases and told me to
Run them every day and we didn't have time to automate them and I had them automated three days later because they were crap
But anyway, let me go on to this section, which is at the end of the clarification section
I think my papers a little out of order by now
responsibilities of testing professionals
blah blah blah
Accelerate the incorporation of evolving text methodologies and tools in the testing technology solutions
Okay, get rid of the get rid of the testing technology called technology solutions. That's DevOps. That's what we do
That's what that's what DevOps does or or even modern testing
We accept we we make sure we're using the best tools we can for testing for deployment for delivery
For static analysis code analysis CI CD. We make sure we have the best tools we can use either
bot
OSS built ourselves to make sure we can deliver as quickly and safely as possible
Well, but here's the thing because remember testing technology solutions that the AI one is
Essentially, I think it's I think they talk about AI indirectly, but I think they're talking about methodologies
They talk about it directly. I just read it. I know but they don't even use the word AI. They don't talk about it directly
They do they did
Where the hell is it? I don't know. So another one is again
This is I think a direct jab at the information provider community when they say which is why I'm so surprised that
Get out of the quality service business hasn't come up because people are so obsessed with you can't automate everything statement
But they say in this paper be a major
Decision maker and major not a decision maker not providing information not giving your opinion
Be a major decision maker in the risk assessment and quality readiness of software solutions
Holy crap. Yes
Don't be an information provider. Listen to me
Stop being an information provider you have the information. I don't understand people don't want to be a decision maker it it drives me
Bonkers that that you think that's above your pay grade for some reason get involved the people in this role in the future
Have to understand the business. Yes, they are
already
experts around
Risk assessment and quality readiness. Yes. Okay
what the ask is here is do the analysis and
bridge between what the business cares about and
What your data shows I think it's important to bring up because I think
Some people will say well, it's not my choice to choose whether we ship or don't
That's a business decision and your priority is improving the business and you need to be
expert my job as someone who's been in and out of testing for 25 years is to help
Entire organization balance velocity and quality. Sometimes I slow them down. Sometimes I try and speed them up. It's a balance
blah blah blah
Embrace new ways of software development and production
so yes
Follows modern testing principles use improvement. Let's find new ways to do things better theory of constraints, etc
And ensure comprehensive risk assessment and quality readiness, which yes doesn't mean you do it
Elsewhere in this section they talk about the need for software testers to provide leadership and move in leadership positions and modern testing is a lot
About leading teams towards better ways of making quality software. So hells to the yeah
So I think there are despite the fact that I'll let you on a minute here
the
Community has focused on the one line is pissed him off
And I think if a lot of people were to dig deeper
they would find several more lines that would piss them off and I encourage them to do so and
Enter the conversation because I think they're actually entered the conversation
Thoughtfully as if your career may depend on it. Yeah, it's just it's just
There's gonna be a long tail. Yeah, we've if this falls back to them talking about modern testing
Yes, stuff is changing if you fail to recognize that if you dig your heels in I
Have no guarantees about your future employment opportunities. All right, you're going to say so
The number two that you talked about apply common sense and ethics effectively into the learning cycles
I skipped that one you can talk about it. All right with the testing technology solutions
Right. So I'm going to one of the the page
Titled clarification section the ethical aspects of decision-making
by artificial intelligence
Hopefully will be resolved and this requires a level of human intervention in the testing technology
solutions where ethical judgment is concerned
okay, so when
they are
Absolutely saying that the testing technologies
60 plus percent of the core of the definition of that is AI and
they're viewing
Tester's role is going to be a judge of ethics. I
Think that role needs to be there. I think there needs to be a human
That's judging that
I
Don't know that testing. I don't know that I agree that testing professionals are going to be the experts in that space
Well, I don't know either. Yeah, I mean you look at me. I'm not very ethical
You're being snarky I think you are well, yeah, I mean you're not a you're not a rule follower. I'll say that
But the human condition is absolutely
Something you're concerned with
But I don't see it as testing professionals to do that. I actually
Because right now the typical testing professional doesn't understand how these things are built
so
one of the things and I think there's a
interesting cap we can put on this conversation is I think in order to
You have to get out of the echo chamber. You have to look at opposing views
I I do this politically I do this with testing to the software
I look at people that hate TDD people that disagree with modern testing principles try and figure out where they're coming from
It's always a motivation there. Sometimes it's job self-preservation. Sometimes it's something else if I look at the motivation of is TQB
Although there are some things we agree with some things we may not agree with some things
We don't I don't like the way the paper is written, but that's beside the point. I can say for certainty
You know is TQB is in the business
Of selling training and certifications
So if the testing role were to go away completely
They'd be out of business
So I have to wonder a little bit around the motivation and again predicting things is hard, especially about the future
So if they see these changes happening, they never see the testing role going away
In fact, the first paragraph talks about the changes in the testing discipline. I
Wonder what they think this means for them and their business
What are the what do you think these statements if this future plays out what changes in Istq be?
So in that light, let's let's now decompose a section called clarifying responsibilities of testing professionals
Okay now first off
This could in fact be an objective report
Funded by Istq be right. Maybe they haven't
Published a document that is useful to identify
Istq be's response to this feature. Maybe they just did a
study and
Wrote it up in an objective fashion
But this says testing professionals shall need to embrace the new methodologies and technologies around software development and testing
with the intent to
Integrate these faster into their testing technology solutions. Okay, that is something that we've been stating
right the role is to accelerate the achievable a shiftable quality and
The testing professionals they need to shift and stop bottlenecking and instead accelerate the shipping. Okay
Well that first statement
Could Istq be?
Do a further study and adjust their certifications around that probably
Right these new methodologies and technologies a big portion of that's gonna be agile
Could they move and they do an agile certificate at like a agile certified tester or something something like that
but would their
Curriculum move to cover
Learning new technologies or leadership as they like I think it will have to absolutely and what would make their leader
I guess would be they could I could see Istq be this is pure speculation that we're endorsing this by any means
But I could see them in the next couple years coming up with a test coach certification
Sure, sure. I think that would make a lot of sense. Maybe you just solve their problem for them. That's what I'm here for
I'll take and they'll probably talk to me about it and I'll forget talking to them and I'll forget I'll also forget to collect my fee
Darn it. The testing professionals shall be required to pick up the pace of
Bringing greater testing capabilities to the software. Hell. Yeah, right? Nothing wrong with that
The try and argue with that one. I'm waiting. We should do a sentence by sentence debate on this over the internet
Anyway, go on in working on behalf of the users
Testing professionals will be required to learn how to teach
the testing technology solutions to
Continually improve the quality of software solutions and development. There's the coaching
No, but they're teaching the testing technology solutions
Yeah, I don't think I think I think AI is included in there. I don't think it always means AI I it primarily means AI
Alright, well agree to disagree and here's what they're saying
They're saying testing
professionals
Move to what's done in data science as an expert
and contribute their knowledge into an AI that becomes their responsibility to
train up better ais for testing and
They may even be saying that there is a portion of data science that they're expecting that these folks
Learning capture. I wish again. I wish this paper wasn't written in so much code
Me too, but if you were is TQB
It and you would probably want to do it this way to couch a
Little bit of the hate that's gonna come to you
Right. We already know because we did it with modern testing, but I think we're much smaller than I see QB
We're definitely much smaller reach when they sent this out
But you know you got to give him credit but this whole they got people talking about this paper this whole last paragraph I
mean, it's
Long worded. It's only three sentences and it essentially says the testing professional
Job will be to automate themselves out of that job by training up the testing technology solutions
Testing professionals walk to ensure the testing technology solutions incorporated self educating lessons and learned capabilities
Which provide continuous improvements? They're talking about a learning system. I dig it
I dig it so and can can they build a new certification around that? Yes
What happens when those testing professionals succeed carp launch across the domain where where I see QB has a reach
I see QB has to come up with a new version of this because it's over again
feature of any feature of testing doc or
Presentation or whatever it's going to be wrong. I've given a couple of these in the past. I've given feature testing talks
They were way wrong. It's really what's the
This one's actually more futuristic, but a lot of it we see is happening now
Well, and the thing that was brilliant of what they did. They didn't put a timeline. No, of course not
But they got people talking and I'm disappointed and I mentioned this
There is so much in here to tear apart and to talk about and discuss
Anytime you have an essay like this, it's not about
It's not an experience report where you can say well that didn't work for me or whatever
This is speculation
to
Inspire discussion and it has inspired discussion, but I'm disappointed in the overall testing community that
the
Debate has been around the one line around automating everything. I think
Failure to recognize the context of which that line is stated and failure to recognize the other highly debatable points and discussion points in the document
Is a failure in I don't know what I call it critical thinking or system thinking
It's a failure in thinking and looking outside the box and there's a I'm sure there's a fallacy around this where you get
It's like the moth to the light
Fallacy, here's the most controversial statement. Let's focus on this instead of finding the other points to debate as well
Whether you agree or don't agree and there's or like or don't like this paper
I think there's value for anyone it's not just testing not just testing in software development
To think about which of these statements may or may not seem
Applicable or valid and have a discussion around that the thing I
command is TQB with this paper is
In my humble opinion
There's no way to interpret it
other than
testing
professionals are at risk and I commend
Istqb making this a paper
That tries to explain it
Because they know if they were to just say if they were just to say the Istqb version of test is dead
No one's gonna hear but that's a defense for many. I mean, that's the objection
For many to this paper. They say purely
Testing is not going away
Therefore this paper and its statements are invalid
and again because I actually think
Istqb has a great deal of infrastructure and a great deal
to gain
by not publishing this paper
True right. I think this paper is pointing out a direction that is
Contrary to how Istqb has built up its current that is interesting. Yeah, you're right. Why would they?
Because like I said goes back to their business choices
Interesting and it's in my view. It's because the trends that we and others have been seen
Are now obvious to Istqb as well and also and maybe
Interesting to point out before we close here is that Istqb publishes paper
I've seen I haven't looked for it, but I haven't seen them
Discussing or defending this paper a lot. They've kind of let it just sit in the community and let the conversation
Let it they're letting a thousand flowers bloom, which I don't know if that's actually true or not
But it's interesting to see that all of the discussion is from the people disagreeing with the paper and there aren't I
Haven't seen anyone from Istqb talking about why or what or anything
No, but that's just the the noisy few it is that are
Right now being defensive after all this discussion
I would like to say I still don't remember if or when I talked to them or what I said
So but some of the but I can see now how some of the things
Could have been inspired by what I said. So there's that
All right
Thanks for our book report. Thanks for listening to our book report on the Istqb vision of software testing
I am almost an hour later still Alan and I am NOT. All right later