Welcome to AB testing podcast, your modern testing podcast.
Your hosts, Alan and Brent will be here to guide you through topics on testing, leadership,
agile, and anything else that comes to mind.
Now on with the show.
Hey everyone, it's Alan and Brent, and this is AB testing.
Of course, do you know that by now?
Because by the time you hear this, I've put the intro on top of this.
Anyway, 128.
Is that right?
Just say yes.
Yes.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
We were going to have a guest today, but I think I messed that up.
I was talking with it was the same guest we were going to have like three or four weeks ago.
And we had an email conversation where we said today, but then I never I don't think I ever said that calendar request follow up.
So yeah.
And yeah, well, I think I'm going to take.
100% of the blame there.
There's there's another potential issue there as well, because the last time we had to reschedule because they the guests asked for nine o'clock.
They did. They did.
But I did confirm eight.
Their their daughter was sick.
Child was sick.
Anyway, we'll try again or they may pop up at any time, in which case we'll change subjects, which isn't out of the ordinary anyway.
No, quite. Yeah.
Good to go on that one.
What's new with you?
New with me.
Oh, well, my son officially.
My second son now officially attends your alma mater.
Country Western you.
So it's it's interesting because of the covid times and he is in a well, relatively new relationship.
And his girlfriend is now a senior.
So he met her when he was a senior.
And because of covid and the couple just can't be separated.
Here is an interesting thing.
So the the girls parents basically have moved my son into their home and he.
So it's weird.
So I had the whole the whole reality of some sort of moving out for college.
But none of the drama, because it's sort of a stealth move out like he hasn't he hasn't slept in his own bed.
In months.
And these are the days of our lives.
Yeah, right. But I in in one regard.
So my son during during grades, essentially six through twelve, you know, there's a there's this old saying that hard work pays off over time.
But procrastination pays off now.
He he lived that up until meeting her.
She actually is already getting offers from Ivy League schools throughout the the world.
She's strong in academics and she is at least within Washington state, a champion swimmer.
She's actually teaching him, you know, what to do.
And he's got a new perspective.
He sort of woke up and was like, wait a minute.
College after college.
It's like me. So I better get my shit together.
And yeah, anyway, we'll see what happens.
My oldest started college.
He's doing the Running Start program.
So he's actually a junior in high school.
He's going to finish high school and take full time college classes at the same time.
I am completely supportive of that.
My oldest didn't do that.
I kind of wish he had.
He did graduate with just he had he had six AP passes under his belt when he went off the college.
Which shows not really good for anything.
Oh, dude, that when I when I did it, they weren't good for much.
And that that took off almost a semester and a half of G off off of his plate.
Yeah. So when I went, the credits counted, but my major required so many credits.
I didn't need extra credits.
The credits count of it.
They didn't count towards any of my requirements.
So they were pretty much just some here.
Here's some free credits.
Yay. Oh, so my youngest.
He he's doing the computer science program at, again, your alma mater.
He passed the AP exam and that allowed him to get credit for and skip
CS, whatever the first CS, the class is the CS 101 equivalent.
So he's in CS 102 now.
I mean, I don't even know if the numbers are right.
All right. All right.
Go kids. Yeah.
Yeah. So back on.
So what I have one thing I want to share with the three, which is actually two things.
Exciting news to share with the three.
One, we could talk about a little bit.
One, I would just make the announcement.
We can't talk about it.
But after that, we had a great request to walk through how you and I started
in this industry and where we and how that got us to modern testing.
So we'll do that in a moment.
But the one announcement I'm not going to talk about just all just for reasons
is Unity, as of this morning, is now a publicly traded stock.
We have entered the IPO game.
So that's exciting.
And then something happened to me at Unity a few weeks ago that has not happened to me
since 2008 or so.
Do you know what that is, Brent?
Two thousand.
I think 2008 was the last time this ever happened to me.
Got a guess.
You got a good review.
Well, no, I mean, I've had good reviews, but you're on the right track.
I got a promotion.
Oh, nice.
So I am now a oh, and two things happen with this.
One is are you a VP of something?
I'm one. I'm one level below a VP.
I'm a senior director, but also my boss looked at what I was doing.
And because I had this program management name in my title and he said, that's stupid.
You're now a senior director of engineering.
So I'm a I'm a real boy now.
Nice. You're in.
You're an SD.
Yeah. Yeah.
So that's pretty cool.
I'm excited.
Lots of you know, my org is much bigger now.
We talked about this last time.
I'm not going to go back into it again, but the promotion was in process long
before I took on that org.
It's just recognition for making our stuff go.
And now I just have to make it go better for multiple reasons.
One, the promotion, but to the previous subject.
So yeah, IPO. Yeah.
And I'm trying to find it on the Web.
So what's the ticker?
You. You.
One letter. You.
Wow. I'm surprised.
I mean, that's cool.
It's a surprise.
You haven't been taken.
It is pretty cool.
So yeah, it's at a static price right now.
It's in the price discovery phase.
That's probably all I should say about it.
It should start trading actually shortly.
OK, so anyway, let's get on to the main topic.
And as we all know, the show is about me.
But today I'm going to step aside and let you start.
So as I mentioned before, the question is we had one of the three
on one of the three dot slack dot com say that they would enjoy a history lesson.
It sort of evolved into we should do an episode or two
talking about how we first independently
and then together came to a similar belief system around modern testing
because we both started purely in the testing world.
And then we took different paths to get to this
violent alignment we have around modern testing.
And it'd be good to talk about that.
So let's start with you and we'll do this is like the
I love the comic book origin stories are so good.
I used to love them.
So let's go back to you in 19.
Wait, we want to go back to to to 19 something.
Hey, you know, we can we can breeze through it.
But I want to do is you started like did you have a tech job before Microsoft?
Or is you start here on it, start there out of college?
Started out of college.
OK, so you came into an STE job.
You are a software test engineer.
Oh, so yeah, you don't have to walk through.
Well, on my first day and then on my second day.
But let's walk through like giving the brief recap up to the point
where you realize that, you know, we need to change this old way
where there are any turning points or triggers along the way.
So let's just start at the beginning and I will interject.
But talk about your origins as a software tester
sometime in the mid 1990s at Microsoft.
So it feels like we should have like
way back sound effects.
I'll help you.
Yeah.
They're negative.
Yeah, thank you.
So way back in the day.
So I graduated college in 1993,
December 1993 as a double major in math, science and computer science.
And I had started college as a math major.
They required multiple different programming courses in there.
And it wasn't too long where I realized, oh my God,
I way love the CS stuff
more than the math stuff.
And I bolted on the double major.
And God, maybe a year after that, it was still so I double majored.
It ended up taking me five years to get my undergrad.
So about a year after I bolted it on,
I was in love with Microsoft.
And so I spent the last two years of my career
with a single focus on I'm going to Microsoft.
I think I've shared, I know I've shared on my employment here,
even though I had an interview
and all of that was somewhat accidental.
Microsoft wasn't the polished process engine it is today.
And I discovered on my first day of employment here
that it was for a intern position and not a full time position,
which is what I thought.
Like the offer letter didn't indicate.
I wish I still had that.
Yeah, I should have saved mine to mine.
Mine had me show up to orientation on the wrong day.
So just say, yeah, remember, at some point,
we have to get to the turning point.
So you're going to have to speed up this part of the story.
Back then, I was just trying to think through.
So I had
I not only knew I was going to go to Microsoft,
but I knew I was going to be a developer at Microsoft.
And I'm trying to recall how how so my intern position was in a test role.
And I think I got seduced by
by either the hiring manager or the recruiter.
On the story that we used to tell way back in the day around an S debt.
Oh, no, no, no, you're you're a developer.
You're just in the the the test discipline.
Right. You recall that because I think you were
you actually once led the charge on keeping that story alive.
Maybe maybe I didn't know any better.
But we can talk about that in my origin story because I didn't do that.
I didn't know any better.
Like hindsight, 2020, I can look back at it and go, yeah, I don't
I don't even remember what the story was, but I could tell you it was bullshit.
Anyway, fast forward.
So immediately after that.
So I found out that I was in an internship.
Not only that, that the internship had a had a a deadline of three months.
And I'm like, whoa, OK, so I just moved up
me and my fiance for a job that's three months.
Oh, my God. How do I springboard this into something useful?
So I don't want to spend all my time on this one, but it was essentially
we got that to be
moved to six months and at the end of the six months.
I went through a whole bunch of interviews.
Turned out I had failed them all.
Funny, funny story.
I'll say funny story.
Found out later on that it was it had been because my hiring manager
had actually blackballed me.
It's good to know.
I just want to remind everyone that the asinine politics of Microsoft
have been around since the mid 90s. Continue.
Oh, yeah. So and before.
But yeah, and this guy is no longer at the company,
although I will say he survived a very long time.
Now, the question is, obviously, why did he blackball me?
Well, it was because my office mate
was an attractive female
and he was a pig
and on multiple occasions said things, did things with me as a witness.
And he needed me to protect his career.
He needed me to be gone from the company anyway.
No, not anyway.
I. Yeah, go for it.
How in the world did this person survive?
For me, I mean, as they survive, I I.
God, I hate people like that.
I really, really hate them.
Really, really.
I just want to put that in there and you can go on and I do as well.
And we can dox him later.
I do as well.
And I will say that when it comes to issues
like sexual harassment or any sort of what do they call it?
Any sort of discrimination policy violation,
Microsoft is much better now and
I don't know if it's perfect yet, but one of the things that they do
on any of these things is they hire an independent outside counsel.
Whereas back in those days, HR would handle it internally.
And I am positive.
That is the reason why he was able to survive at the company.
There's a myth in software, it's especially true at that time,
and actually for many years at Microsoft that people go, I'm going to go to HR
about this HR are there to protect the company, not the individual.
And it was especially prevalent there.
And I'm glad that they're doing that now because that's that's fair.
But I guess it just sickens me.
I had a friend who went through similar stuff eventually.
Eventually, her boss left Microsoft with fully vested options
to spend more time with this family.
That was always the joke.
People were execs or senior people were fired.
They were leaving to spend more time with their family.
And everyone, everyone knew what that meant.
It's changed now.
Execs don't spend more time with their family.
And it's it's.
Do they now pursue other interests?
Uh, they I saw that after they they're working on special projects.
But which is outside the company.
Oh, no, no, no. So so, yeah, special projects is where you put the person
who you who you can't haven't fired yet,
but you need to get them away from their team.
Right. OK, so anyway, tangent to when when they leave.
I mean, you can't even the silence is deafening when they leave.
We're like, what? That's old news, right?
I get it. OK.
So anyway, you have eventually started at Microsoft.
You're into your blackball.
Let's get you hired and then actually work towards the point
where you begin recognizing that testing isn't the schnitzel anymore.
A buddy of mine at that time
hooked me up with a contract gig
and some friends he had over in the exchange.
Turned out blackballing didn't work so well
through the contact or the contract recruiting channels.
So I ended up being a contractor on a test team.
And at that point in time,
I was happy with anything.
And it turned out I got lucky and got on a very sweet team.
With a very strong set of managers.
I was a IC for less than one year at the company.
My my new management staff saw my potential, saw my hunger,
saw that I was good at problem solving and
like I even remember having conversation like yesterday with my manager
that he's like, yeah, just as a heads up, within the next nine months,
you're probably going to be a lead on this team.
Yeah, we did. We did make people leads very way too early
in their career at that time.
Well, for me, hindsight, 2020, I think he made a this
this same manager I'm thinking of is is still to date
the best manager I've ever had.
And he saw he saw something in me
and he was able to sort of carve it out.
Right. If you think about the Michelangelo metaphor. Right.
And I remember because every job I had ever had,
I've been moved into management, but I had viewed those as jobs.
And this is the first time where I'm like, oh, my God,
I've actually freaked out when he told me that.
And then I spent the next next nine months sort of watching
every manager that I respected in what they did
because in prior examples, I got promoted to management.
But because I hadn't yet learned the distinction between management
and leadership, once I got there, I sucked.
But because I had a strong work ethic,
like I ended up doing all of the work myself
just so that my quote unquote team looked good.
And I'm like, oh, my God, this is my career.
If he does that to me, I'm going to tank my entire career.
But I learned leadership very quickly anyway.
OK, so you're leading testers doing their testing grunt work.
I'm leading testers
just a year or two after that, I became a middle manager.
And, you know, this is all the world where it was on prem products, etc.
So there's that, etc, etc.
OK, God, that was probably ten, 15 years of that.
OK, and then somewhere, I think it was around 2002. OK.
We're finally into the proper century.
Awesome. Go on. Yep.
2002, this horrible, horrible, evil, evil thing
started creeping into Microsoft.
And that was this this bullshit, agile stuff.
Right. Where where people were coming in and talking about.
Oh, no, we're not going to document anything.
We're just go ahead.
Yeah, you say I remember that.
And it wasn't even that many people.
There were like a few people here and there going, yeah, we should do this.
And and Microsoft doing their typical not invented here would say, well,
that won't work here. That's that's interesting.
But that's for other companies.
Yeah. But then there were some teams.
So back in those days, so somewhere in here, right,
we did a transition from the PUM model to the the functional model.
And this is moving from this is the editor oversight.
The PUM model is the product unit manager where every part of the business,
even even multiple parts of a single business would have a PUM, a product
unit manager who would manage the full team working on that across all disciplines.
We moved to a more siloed approach
called extreme siloism, where you had a huge test discipline,
a huge dev discipline, a huge program management discipline.
Working for high level people reporting to the like a general manager
or a VP running the business.
And this went on for quite a while.
All right. Back to you, Brent.
Yeah, the the PUM model kind of optimized for knowledge sharing around the product,
whereas the functional model optimized for knowledge sharing within a discipline.
It was interesting because I happened to be on the team
where the functional model was piloted.
For most of the folks in that team,
that we viewed this model as abjectly failed,
but the executive whose idea it was,
you know, that the data will be tortured until it agrees with us.
That stupid idea got pushed through all of Microsoft anyway.
So at the same time, Agile was starting to creep in.
And back in those days, you would go to a particular team,
a particular culture, and you could discover very quickly which discipline ruled.
You would find that some teams had a primarily a PM culture
that essentially, if you think about Animal Farm,
one of my favorite quotes from Animal Farm is,
all animals are equal, but the pigs are a little more equal than everybody else.
In this world, like a PM culture,
they would have more votes or a dev culture.
There was never a team I experienced
where tests really controlled the culture.
Exchange got close.
Exchange got close, but it ended up being
more around the people, not the discipline.
So let me add one counterpoint to that, because there was one time in my career,
in my career at Microsoft where that was different.
And that was on the shit show known as Windows Millennium.
And I remember we put someone who had no idea what they were doing
in charge of the development team from because just for context,
Windows 98 was going to be the last version of consumer Windows ever shipped.
And once Windows XP, I think it was no Windows 2000 was delayed.
Marketing came back and some other teams came back and said
we had another version of Windows, remembering at that time,
Windows, this is pre like Internet download,
the Windows was the main ship vehicle for a lot of smaller applications,
everything from Internet hearts to some other diagnostic tools built by other teams.
So they quickly pulled together a team to work on Windows Millennium.
And it was very clear from our GM who led our triad, as it was called,
what my role was going to be.
And the role made sense to be on the dev team.
So I went and chatted with this person.
They were going to make the dev director for this product.
And he was such a total dweeb and had no idea
that I went and did the same exact job for the test director.
In that case, if the dev team might have had the power,
they were more equal than the rest.
But for me, it was like the thing I tell people when I recruit them to Unity,
I tell them it's easy to do good work here.
It was easier for me to do good work and do the same work better on that team
than it was working for the dev director.
So slight, slight, slight twist to your story, but still more or less holds true.
But it reminded me, I wouldn't remember to add it in my story.
So I wanted to add it now back to you, Brent.
So the casual stuff was coming in.
One of the things that I remember early on,
because I had a bunch of mentees at that time.
And again, they would come from teams where the dev leadership,
number one, controlled the org or, you know, mostly controlled the org
or the product direction, the strategy.
That's what I mean by controlled the org.
And they had learned about this,
this new fad called Agile.
And one of the things that started happening is they were rolling this out,
even in the world where we were in on-prem products, right?
The term CICD hadn't been invented, right?
There was no continuous delivery whatsoever.
But there was a lot of things that were considered overhead
that really appealed with dev.
And since they were controlled, they just made it happen.
And so I would have a lot of mentees coming to me and saying,
wait a minute, my dev team is saying that they're going to be agile.
So I'm not going to get any sort of documentation
for which to build my test plan.
Now, back in those days,
you did not F with the test plan, right?
That because, as you well know,
one of the biggest, most important value propositions
that the test team provided that the test team
hated being one of their more important services
was scapegoating at product release.
Right. And so if a dev
was going to not give me documentation,
right, certainly that's going to be optimizing for scapegoating.
And how do I avoid that?
Because I hate that aspect of it, like the question of
why was this not tested before?
So very much at that time hated this idea of agile,
hated it because it essentially victimized the test discipline,
which at that point in time, I was quite proud of.
Then I went to a team that Alan and I both worked on,
although never at the same time.
I think we overlapped by like a day, maybe a week.
And his and my experience of that team is very different.
Well, you left at the sort of the end of a
end of a thing, and I joined at the very beginning of the next thing.
So you had the previous experience and I tell people
and we can name drop here my two years on Xbox One
were the best five years of my career.
It was such a horribly.
I mean, I had fun working on it.
And I'll talk about this next time when we talk about
sort of how I came to these beliefs, but horribly, horribly, horribly run product.
People running the show there had just didn't have a clue what they were doing.
It's it's a miracle that Xbox One came together as well as it did.
And I will actually take a chunk of the credit for that, but not that much.
But anyway, go on, Brett.
Well, so I won't speak to what happened when I left.
I hold out hope that that the leadership at that point in time
did a solid job on cleaning the house.
But I will absolutely say that was an organization run by Dev.
And in this case, controlled by Dev.
And I almost literally mean it that way.
I don't think that that's the case anymore, thank goodness.
But they had they had bastardized agile and
used it to justify cowboy.
Essentially, we get to do what we want when we want because that's agile.
And in particular, like the the principle around scrum
that you don't hear talking about so much anymore,
but the principle around scrum around management
being not only useless overhead,
but a negative value proposition to the scrum process. Right.
So we as an individual dev team, we get to do what we want
and not even management can tell us otherwise.
And somehow that organization made that stick
and it put tests in a really bad place.
Testing, it was still our job to find the bugs before release.
But the way things were set up, it was pretty much guaranteed
that that wasn't going to happen.
And so that that caused me to
the documentation was an initial threat.
Right. As I said, I'm like, oh, God, OK, how are we going to do anything
if we don't get solid documentation from our development team?
But what even but this particular experience
said, whoa, agile is enabling
enabling teams to to be completely
disorganized, completely dysfunctional, in my humble opinion, that time.
Yeah, at that time.
And because this is still true today where teams take
organization teams, people
Brent's like the only person in all of the podcasting world
who will eat his breakfast while podcasting.
I'm hungry, dude. Sorry.
So people read selective parts
and make their own interpretations that actually internalizing and thinking
of it as a system.
So we've all seen these. Oh, agile means no documentation.
We're not saying that.
We're saying that the developers Brent was working with at the time
were taking the parts of agile they felt like for fun.
And and they were rationalized and justifying.
Yeah, justifying poor behavior because air quote, it's agile.
So then you left that team and went somewhere magical.
Well, actually, further.
So what I did is
by that time, there was enough information on the web to to do a search
and realize that that the that there are a large number of teams and companies
that were not converting agile into cowboy and succeeding.
Right. Things like accelerate in those studies.
They were far.
I mean, they probably weren't even a glimmer in the Kohl's eye at that point in time.
But it wasn't it didn't take much effort to realize
that a lot of companies were were really succeeding with this.
And one of the things that I looked at it, I'm like, OK,
so my understanding of agile has got to be wrong
because no company would stay in business if agile meant
what this group is doing.
And so that caused me to to to understand it
far more deeply.
This is also the time where I went and got
I did a whole bunch of reading.
I did a whole bunch of I hadn't gotten done the safe thing yet.
But then I realized and started deploying it within my own team.
And I realized, OK, I understand a bit of why agile works.
And at the same time, I was done.
I was done with that org.
I needed to move on.
So I moved to Bing.
And whenever I make a decision.
Hold on. Just people know Bing is a search engine just because they may not know that.
All right. Go on.
Thank you for that public service announcement.
Bing powered by Azure, which is actually true.
But all right. Go on. It is actually true.
The so I went to to Bing and I took finally after who knows how many years
I finally did achieve my initial goal of working at Microsoft as a developer.
Join Bing on a data team.
Well, actually, most teams in Bing eventually end up being a data team.
And because they were a service organization,
agile was a necessity.
And so I joined a team that was actually hunger, hungry to
to to do agile. Bing was actually where
the the combined engineering model, as it was described, started.
So I happened it had already been in flight about a month when I joined.
I am fast forwarding.
I deployed an agile paradigm.
I did not have a test team per se.
I as as I think I've shared on the podcast multiple times,
a good portion of my developers at that time were former testers.
And we started going through and shipping products
and thinking of it as an end to end system.
OK, what do we have to do to minimize maintenance costs?
What do we have to do to get this product out?
And once we finally shifted over to Kanban,
that sealed the deal for me, because it made me realize that
what one of the things that that test did
is the minimize risk of of a negative customer impact.
Well, and to be clear, I mean, we had a discipline do that,
but I was just that's a line I give all the time.
That is the purpose of testing, regardless of who does it.
We just had special people dedicated to that.
Right. And so during that whole experience, I was
I was constantly thinking, OK, number one, you know,
because we're trying to shift to combine engineering,
I really don't have a choice.
However, I do have test talent underneath me.
And I could I could just say, all right, you know what?
Yeah, you're a developer, but you're going to develop test automation.
I could have done it. I did.
And I'm glad I didn't because what I actually found
is that the testers underneath me
did a better job at shipping production code.
Same. And the biggest problem with them, though, is is
and it's not and I'm sure you've encountered this.
Back in the day, one of the prevailing problems with S debts
was sort of a self-esteem issue around their coding ability
where the low. But I'm just a tester.
I can't write production code.
And I wouldn't say that was widespread.
And we'll talk about this because I I wrote code that shipped in
I nearly are all of every product I ever worked on as a tester.
No. So I wasn't afraid.
I just didn't I just didn't like doing it that much.
But anyway, I think that I could see that. But you go on.
Yeah. So I didn't I didn't suffer from this either.
There was this view that I saw quite often from from testers
that essentially production code and magic are not too far apart.
Right. It's a view I see today with with data science.
I am where I spend a good amount of time, particularly with PM
orgs, I spent a good amount of time trying to demystify data science.
I did have a a long argument with a guy from sales
just a few months ago where he was just absolutely convinced
that AI was already solving every problem he ever had ever.
You were doing agile on this team, getting the hang of it.
And how did that lead you?
Like that was still 15 years ago.
So what led you down the path of that?
Wasn't that like 2000?
Oh, it was not. No, sorry. I'm off by a decade.
That was like seven years ago.
Yeah, I think it's seven eight. It's creeping up on a decade.
Yeah. And then we started the podcast, which in hindsight
has always been about modern testing.
Maybe it's almost about five and a half, six and a half years ago.
Shoot. So right around that time we began the podcast.
So what led you from that point towards things
that are more modern testing ish?
As I as I went through it, I kept on asking myself,
when would I hire a specialist?
When would I hire a specialist?
How would a specialist improve
the business KPIs for what I'm doing?
Every time I actually had a positive answer to that,
oh, I would do this because of blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
I found that it was quite easy to come up with
what I needed to do immediately to adapt within my organization
to then eliminate that.
You follow?
Where essentially, as I kept on doing this and realizing that,
number one, the biggest, most important event in my life
was on that particular topic,
was the day so we had we had already shifted to Kanban
and my someone on my team shipped a bad change
and our service was on the floor, just on the floor,
realizing that we knew it near instantly that it was on the floor
and that because it was a single change,
because the Kanban model doesn't batch all these things
into a big chunk,
it took us five minutes to back out that change to revert it.
And I compare that to my prior life
where it would have been a month test pass beforehand
and still had the risk that that change would have gone out
and dropped the service on the floor.
So as you know, a lot of modern testing is stolen,
probably more borrowed, sorry, borrowed, not stolen,
borrowed from lean than agile and Kanban, a lean concept.
And of course, lean and agile aren't separate things,
they're overlapping, complimentary things,
but lean startup, obviously a big influence
on what we ended up with.
So just really quick, and we can,
we'll get to a point where our stories begin to merge
with the modern testing principles,
but what led you to think, well, let me ask it this way.
My observation is that you discovered agile,
figured out how to make it work,
and then in fairly short time,
sort of shifted to more of lean approaches.
How did that happen?
Is that a correct observation and how did that happen?
Oh, it's essentially our second scrum-based sprint.
We completely screwed the pooch.
We would do scrum iterations every two weeks.
And our very second sprint with me as the new team lead,
we worked very hard, completely refactored our entire system.
And everyone had a belief that they understood
the interface contract between the components.
And hindsight 2020, it became clear that everyone's belief
was 80% correct, but the other 20% was enough
to make each integration point fail.
And we ended up spending three months to undo and repair
the damage we had done in a single two week sprint.
Because we had done such a huge refactor,
reversion was not possible or sensical.
You missed something in there.
And as we've discussed before, it's very easy.
That's why I shifted to lean.
Yeah, it's very easy in what do you call it?
Scrum, it's the default for team shifting there
without any discipline is scrum or fall.
Yeah, anyway, so just to close,
because we're at time now,
but that was really the eye opening moment for me
is when it comes to the idea of modern testing,
was that there were faster ways to get the feedback
back to my developers that they had just written a bug
than a test specialist team.
Yeah.
And this then got tested,
because as you know, I then left Bing
and on two different occasions,
I was part of the leadership team
helping that organization shift to unified engineering.
And I saw these things,
these same sort of phenomenon repeating.
Damn, right?
What came out of modern testing,
or what is now modern testing is sort of a culmination
of the focus and the perspective
as well as the experience.
Like when testers come to me and they're like,
well, why am I blah, blah, blah?
No one loves me, blah, blah, blah.
And I just look at them and I go, oh, well,
it's because you don't actually understand your customer
or your business.
Go fix that.
So let me recap this in the more close.
So you started off with the interesting start as a tester,
grew into a lead, watched Scrum done poorly,
moved on to a team that was a lot closer to Agile,
did that, shifted towards lean,
and that eventually grew into what came as modern testing.
So-
And well, to add to that, in the entire time,
reevaluating when should I bring in
my last decades experience into this
to improve forward progress?
Yeah, and that's what we've talked about a lot
on the podcast up to now.
So next time I'll tell my similar story.
It'd be interesting.
And then we'll try and remember the time
when we crossed paths, I know pretty much when it was,
it was we first crossed paths in around 2007.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
I think that's, I think that's, no, no, no, no, no, no,
maybe we'll figure that out next time.
We'll figure that out next time, right?
I think I'm right.
Hold on.
Oh, Jesus Christ.
You're not right.
I think maybe.
I was.
Life with Brent.
This is gonna be the worst ending to a podcast ever.
Oh, you know what?
What?
You are right.
No, nevermind.
It's the best ending ever.
Can you repeat that last line one more time?
Well, there's two things.
No, no, no, that's not what you said.
You said you are right.
So you are right.
Number one.
And number two, I am still right.
And number two, my LinkedIn resume is F'd up.
That has nothing to do with me.
No, so that happened when I was the TM of Media Center.
And I know that was 2007 to 2009.
My entire recollection of what years things are.
I think what product,
what was I doing in my career at that time?
So I remembered, I remember where I was.
I knew what it was.
Okay, we're gonna hit the other side
of the modern testing origin story next time,
including a little bit of,
and again, because I'm right.
Even though I'm chronologically older,
I'm more mentally acute
than old, old forgetful head over there.
True.
Say it again.
You are right.
There we go.
All right, I'm still Alan.
And I'm not.
And we'll try this whole thing again in reverse next time.