Welcome to A.B. Testing Podcast, your modern testing podcast.
Your hosts, Alan and Brent, will be here to guide you through topics on testing, leadership,
agile, and anything else that comes to mind.
Now, on with the show.
Hey, everyone.
I'm Alan.
I'm Brent.
And we're here for episode 128 of the A.B. Testing Podcast, your wonderful podcast for
all kinds of cool things.
It's a story.
No, don't sing.
By a lovely lady.
Do not sing.
What have you been up to, Brent?
COVID, COVID-Ding, I guess.
COVID-Ding is cool, man.
I really like being home in the same chair all day, every day, and talking to people
all day.
It's great.
Yeah.
My wife asked me why I'm going to work, and it's essentially because I can.
Because I cannot stand.
I really cannot stand work coming to home.
I like to keep those lives separate.
I actually like working from here.
Yeah?
Yeah.
I was talking to the YouTube crowd before, and I'm actually taking some vacation days
at home coming up, because I was talking about the fact that Microsoft, Microsoft,
Microsoft, is it pronounced softer soft?
I'm not sure.
At Microsoft, you're limited on how much vacation you can carry forward from one year
to the next, but you always accrue vacation.
Unity, same rule, you care, you limit on how much you can carry over, but there's also
a limit on how much you can accrue.
Meaning I hit a max vacation I could possibly have, and I was no longer making more vacation
from my weekly work.
Oh, I see.
Lame-o, so I'm taking some vacation days to do some chores around the house.
My first one's next week.
I'm pretty excited.
I'm a good old working forward week next week.
That'll be fun.
The other thing I've been doing is I now own a bunch of our Google contract, and I'm
doing a lot of work with finance to make sure our cost predictions are accurate, which
is a whole lot of fun.
That's sarcastic, because I know how much I don't know.
Gotcha.
But we're getting closer.
I'm faking it.
I still find the right questions to ask, and we're getting there.
We're getting there.
I have no doubt that you will.
The cost thing.
Okay.
Shall we go directly into the meat of the show?
It's a story.
Oh, God.
What did I say?
All right.
Last time we talked about how you...
Even my dog is mad at you.
We talked about how you got your start in testing and how you moved away from it and
kind of how you stumbled into modern testing along the way.
I want to tell my half of the story today.
Hopefully, my dog will shut up.
I shut my office door.
I don't know if I should let her in, let her cry in here, or then she'll be quiet
or what to do.
I'm going to let her do her thing and see what...
I think you should let her in.
In a bit.
So let her in.
Oh, my God.
Let's get started.
And I'm going to count on you to ask questions appropriate or move me along as
needed.
I'll start at the beginning.
I was born.
No, I'll fast forward a little bit.
I think most people know I was a music major in college.
I graduated and I taught school for four years.
I went back to grad school to get a master's in composition.
While getting my master's, I learned how to use computers.
This was...
I used a DOS-based music software notation program to do most of my work for grad school.
I got really good at it.
That company is no longer in business.
I do have the source file still on some five and a quarter inch floppy disk so I
can do nothing with them.
But after I got into grad school, I was actually planning on going back into teaching,
but there was so much red tape after taking a year off to get back into teaching and
fees involved that I just decided I was going to do something else first so I could make
the money to go back to being a teacher.
So I got a job as a bicycle messenger.
I live downtown Seattle.
I did that for a while until it got really crappy.
It was almost as toxic as some of my software teams I've worked on.
But I bought a Sunday paper for you youngsters.
A paper is a way people used to deliver news before we had to read it.
And I got a Sunday paper and went through the Want to add.
That's what we had before we had monster.com and LinkedIn.
And I looked through all the Want to add, just kind of circling some random jobs to apply
for.
This was 1992.
Maybe 93.
I don't really remember.
93.
And one of the jobs I applied for was to do tech support at a company that made music
software.
And I applied for the job and I went through a rather lengthy interview which I finally
got the job for.
A rather lengthy for an $8 an hour tech support job.
I started about two weeks later.
I showed up on my first day and they said, oh, by the way, you're also the software
tester.
Another few hours went by and someone said, by the way, you're also our network administrator.
This is what happens when you join a 17 person company.
I said, great.
I've never used a network before this morning, but it'll be fun.
So I learned as I went.
Go ahead.
It already sounds like that you started off towards exactly what our friend Jimbo describes
as the definition of the test position back in the day.
Someone who does the remainder.
Right.
Everything else.
Well, what I did there was I did tech support and on our peak days we got like 10 calls
and 90 plus percent of my calls were actually helping them with windows problems, not with
problems with our product because windows at this time windows 3.1 then there's windows
3.1 with multimedia extensions.
People bought these sound cards and put them in their computer and tried to get them to
work and they didn't know how and there was this was before plug and play.
Although I helped them edit their system any and win any file so their stuff would work
in general, not for our software.
Once they got windows to work, our stuff would work fine.
Very few of my questions about our software, but the rest of the time was fun because
one of the programmers there took me under his wing and made me learn C. He taught me
the three most important things you need to know about C.
What are those pointers?
Pointers and pointers.
We got a beta version of the first version of MS test and I began to use that to write
some automation.
I didn't know what I was doing.
I just automated everything.
It was really stupid, but it was a good learning experience for me.
I tried to use their API.
I figured some stuff out.
In the end, I ended up writing our setup programs because those were largely based
on visual basic, that setup language at the time.
So that was fun.
I was doing some stuff.
I got promoted all the way from $8 an hour.
I got a big raise to like $35,000 a year.
Then for the second time, our CFO asked me to turn back the clock on our network
server so we could shove a few more sales into the current quarter.
I thought, and this was a public company, by the way.
I thought, you know what?
I don't feel good about this.
So I quit.
Yeah.
And by the way, not because of this, because I'm a parent, the worst things he
did, he is banned from ever holding office in a public company again.
So the just desert said, follow him around.
So I quit and I went home and I got out of paper and there was a bunch of
software testing jobs.
I know what testing was now.
I thought I was good at it.
I didn't think I was great at it.
I thought I was good at it because I could write a bunch of MS test automation.
Raise your hand if you know a million testers like that today and just, just
substitute selenium for MS test.
And I applied for a bunch of jobs.
You know how I applied for them?
I wrote up a resume and a cover letter and I used my fax modem to fax it to
people because that's what we did then.
This was 1994 end of 94.
And then I maybe fall of 94 because I, my first day at Microsoft was the,
whatever the first work day in January was in 1995.
And I was hired as a contractor and I worked, they hired me because I knew
testing and new networking.
And this is where I have the famous quote of, I talked to my manager.
He handed me this list of test cases in Excel.
And I said, go great.
When do you want these automated by?
And he said, Oh no, we don't have time to automate.
You need to run these every day.
And I thought, huh.
And I was bored of that.
That was like a Monday out.
I was bored by Tuesday.
So I automated them by Thursday and then did a bunch of other work in
my other time.
So I, I started breaking the rules around day three.
Another good story from then is the story where we had a bug quota.
I was expected to find like 10 bugs a week.
And of course I would make sure I found, I re sorry, I would make sure I
reported 13 or 14 or 15 every week.
Cause I wanted to exceed, but if I found more, I would save them for the next
week that didn't want my well to dry out.
Oh God.
So I worked there for a while and fast forward.
I was on a six month pro contract.
This was in the days of perma contract, but no one told me that it was just,
it was just going to get renewed.
So my contract began to end.
I interviewed for other jobs.
Okay.
And I was offered a job.
This is the story.
I don't tell very often, but the job offer I got was from ST labs.
I actually, uh, this was the company, one of my interviews with with James
Bach and they offered me a job and I took it.
I said, yes, I'll take your job.
And I went to my manager the next day and said, Hey, my contract's up in June,
beginning of June.
So, so January, best spend like five months.
But anyway, my contract's up.
So I'm going to take another job.
And he goes, looks at me with the face, like, whoa.
And I said, well, my contract's up.
So I got another job.
So, uh, just want to let you know, I'm gonna start there in two weeks.
And it was, this was a contract job at ST labs, by the way, but I didn't,
you know, I was fine.
I was young, healthy.
It was good.
So, wait, wait, pause.
Yeah.
Because you just said something that, that tweaks my head.
So was it addition?
No.
Okay.
There was eight months where I was a contractor and you know how
most contractors go through volt.
I did not.
My company was software testing labs.
Is that the same company?
It could have been, um, yeah, it is some contract.
It was a contract testing place.
I mean, they, yeah, it could have been.
And Bach was what?
Because I actually never.
Wow.
So I was going to work.
I was going to, I was going to work at site on their, in their office in Seattle,
which I thought was great.
Cause I didn't want to commute to the East side anymore.
So, you know, I told my boss that, and then I went to my office and I was
doing my work cause you know, I didn't have a short time or that it was thawing.
I like working in software.
But then his boss came to my office and said, Hey, uh, I heard the news from Doug.
And I want to know if there's a chance we could get you to work
here at a full-time job.
I was so confused.
I would love to have had a poker face, but I said a confused face.
I go, Oh, sure.
That'd be an option.
And they sent a goodie bag, uh, with an offer letter assigned to it, to my
house, like the next day.
So, uh, yeah.
And I said, I said, I, ST labs.
And I said, well, I got a full-time job counter offer for Microsoft.
I said, well, well, we can, I said, yeah, it's all right.
I think I'm going to do this thing.
So I did that.
And of course in their hurry to hire me, they got my, but I supposed to go to a
new employee orientation, but in their hurry to hire me, they got the date wrong.
So I never went, I never went to new employee orientation.
I skipped it.
And then I worked on windows 95 and networking that finished.
I worked on what was going to be windows 97.
And then I was part of Bill Gates discovering the internet.
So I worked on IE two and IE three.
I was, I didn't like working at internet explorer.
So I moved back over to windows 98.
I'm going to fast forward.
I was on windows 98.
I was doing a lot of API tests for networking, which was a ton of fun.
I took all the GUI tests I did and I maxed them to a hundred, uh, testing at the API
level.
So I, in hindsight, I don't think I need to test all that stuff, but I liked, I
liked learning.
I liked writing tests.
So I was, I was learning to write code pretty well in the end of 98.
I was also writing most of the API tests for GDI and user.
Those are the core components, the user level components of windows windows 98
shipped, I moved to the windows 2000 team.
It was probably called something different then.
And I worked on video capture drivers at the time when there were only about
three cameras available in total.
This would have been 1999 or late 98.
I worked on those for a while.
I worked for a guy named Brad Carpenter.
It was a ton of fun.
Did a lot of work.
There was no guidance on testing.
I just wrote a lot of automation that made sense mostly at the API level.
Again, I learned calm, calm, uh, component object model.
And then I loved, I loved calm and then the marketing department said, Hey, man,
we need to do another version of windows.
We said, what?
So we did another version of windows.
They pulled a sort of a skeleton crew.
This is the story I tell.
I think I've told it on this podcast where I knew what I wanted to do.
And our GM knew what he wanted me to do.
Uh, during windows 98, we ignored debug windows and I love like turning up the
warning levels all the way up in my compiler, runtime analysis all over the place.
We ignored the debug version of windows 98 and it does so much for
application development because of all the additional checks and asserts.
And it would not boot.
Wouldn't boot.
Just like booting.
You couldn't make it.
You couldn't get it even get very far in the socialization.
And I had a wonderful learning opportunity.
So first off, I said, I want to work on this and Tom, our GM said, Oh, we'll go
talk to, to go talk to this guy leading our dev team.
I talked to him.
I thought he was a buffoon.
I said, I don't want to work for this guy.
We'll talk to Nick.
Maybe we go talk to Nick about it.
So Nick, Nick is kind of not, not as much of a buffoon.
And I ended up doing that job working for Nick.
I was going to be partnered with a person who was one of the pioneers in the windows
kernel, and he and I were going to pair on this.
I was so excited.
I was going to get to learn.
And then I think the stock went up and he retired.
So I had to do it on my own.
And so this is where I learned x86 assembly.
I'm probably going way out.
I haven't got to modern testing yet, but I just, I like to make stuff go.
I was mainly driven, not because I wanted to work in assembly because I knew
the value of having a debug version of this thing, even if nobody was ever going
to use it and I had a ton of fun on this product.
This is where I pioneered some of Microsoft's initial static analysis
tools and fixed a bunch of those errors and windows and windows millennium.
Me, which also stands for marketing edition, because it was the reason
marketing wanted us to ship it.
Remember at that time, windows was the ship vehicle for a lot of products.
You can just go to the internet and download stuff like internet hearts
and other crap like that.
They wanted to, they wanted a version of windows to ship with.
So there was, there was no app store then.
Right.
This is actually, we're finally getting somewhere.
So after that shipped, uh, our, our GM or a VP went on to take over, uh,
windows CE at Microsoft.
So I went with him and worked on that.
I managed the test team that did for a while that did all of our driver
kernel, everything, low level, actually everything except the actually.
What didn't I didn't do graphics.
Oh, actually, eventually I did graphics.
So I ended up managing huge chunk of the test team.
I decided I wanted to get out of being a manager for a while.
I didn't, it wasn't, I don't like managing.
I love managing.
I don't really like managing at Microsoft that much.
So my manager said, well, what do you get?
My manager said, I want you, you know, windows just made these test architects.
I want you to be a test architect.
So I became the first test architect outside of core windows over in windows
CE, and that's where I joined the test architect group, where we had these,
these surreal discussions.
This is also where I got a little bit of imposter syndrome and I began
reading books on testing and I read a book on testing and I thought, oh,
I know so much about testing.
Oh, now I feel like a test architect.
And then I read another one and I thought, Oh, now I'm a little bit confused.
And then I read a third one said, Oh, now I think I need to form my own
opinions because there's a lot of BS in this technology.
So that's, that's how I got thinking about testing.
So fast forward.
Also on that team, I built a CI system for our, because people were
breaking the build stuff was breaking.
So we put a, put a gate in place where tests had to run.
Uh, certainly wasn't continuous deployment, but we made people go through a,
I was going to say, pause cause back then we did, we didn't call it CI.
We called it a gate.
Yeah.
A gate or a gauntlet.
Right.
We, we didn't really have CI per se.
Cause like the goals and the, and the, what happened.
But what I've even, even without a title, we can get out of the semantics of it.
Uh, in, in, you know, backsplaining or in hindsight, I was getting rid, I was
slowing the team down to speed them up and I didn't know why I was doing it.
I'd never heard of lean at the time or anything, but I knew if we slowed down
a little bit upstream, it would be better downstream and that happened.
So I worked on org for a while.
I ended up moving.
I ended up managing a small tools team.
So it was kind of one of those ICs high level ICs that manages a few people
versus some manager, managing a lot of people.
And that worked well for me, but there was an opportunity when Harry
Robinson namedrop Harry went to Google and he was working in an
organization called engineering excellence, which at the time under John,
it was John Devon reported to Bill Gates and engineering excellence
reported to John Devon.
Oh, I want to go get that job.
And I got that job as a test architect and I started doing technical
teaching, that sounds stupid.
Yeah, I guess it was.
I taught testing to test, to testers and designed some courses, gave some
courses, ended up running that team.
Uh, Microsoft, I was Microsoft's director of test excellence.
I was in that role when I wrote how we test software at Microsoft.
Some of you may remember that gem.
It's not that old.
And then it was during that time that I met a man named
Ren Jenson, wait, this is, we did this last time where you
couldn't remember years again.
No, no, no, no.
Cause how did you get on?
How did you get on the TLT?
Again, I was director of test excellence.
And part of that job was to play sort of the chief of staff for the
Microsoft test leadership team.
Okay.
Got it.
So that's, I think where I think maybe Whitaker had introduced us just
either before or during, but I was getting you to come to those meetings
and be a part of that group.
Then at somewhere in there, you began coming to these test architect
group meetings again.
That's where this podcast was born.
Because we would have these conversations where we would have good conversations.
And as much as I make fun of Brent, I respect him.
And I think he's, I think he's smart and does a lot of good stuff, but I
know I can give him shit.
We'll actually, by having a more vigorous debate, we'll actually get to a good solution.
I think the reason the principles have held up, if you compare it to the ones
that originally wrote what we have now, they're fixed because we were able to
work together and debate and do those things, but we would have such animated
discussions during these test architect group meetings.
That Michael Hunter, who I believe is now at Tableau said, you guys should do a
podcast with, and then the podcast was born sometime in 2014.
Is that right?
You guys can, you guys can go look at that and figure that out.
Yeah.
So at this point, I am still tester, tester, tester, but I haven't really
done that much testing.
I probably, it was probably since, uh, actually the, the last time I did full
time testing is like I do testing or test automation from as part as the
majority of my day would have been windows 98 because, oh, sorry, windows
2000 testing video capture drivers.
After that, it was making debug versions of windows working on low level
components, I ended up being the person that debugged the kernel crashes and
the stress runs overnight.
And I, I love that stuff.
Uh, when I moved on to windows CE, I was a manager, so I wasn't testing that much.
I did a little bit of brute force automation once in a while, but I was
mainly actually figuring out, I was doing again, debugging.
I love debugging.
I ended up doing a lot of it when I joined, uh, text excellence group.
I for sure wasn't doing any testing.
When I moved to Microsoft link slot was communicator, then it became
linked and then it became Skype for business later.
But I worked on that.
Even there I was coaching testers.
I was teaching testers to do exploratory testing, not developers, but testers.
Uh, and having fun with that from there, I went to Xbox where
I worked on infrastructure.
I forgot that there were two teams we were on just again, twice.
You were on the server side.
Holy crap.
I was on link.
You worked on server.
I worked on the client team.
No, when I think when you were on, when you were on link, I was in media center
and then media center through a series of reorgs.
That's how I got on the Xbox.
And by the time, by the, yeah, I'm trying to remember where was
ever a time I was on link server.
I don't remember if we were ever on link at the same time.
Watch Brett quit enjoying unity right when I retire.
No, no.
Actually.
So yeah.
Okay.
So I want to get to the modern testing parts.
So all that.
So I've been in all these roles.
I've been test architect manager.
Uh, it was, so we began talking.
It was probably around the time I was in Xbox doing infrastructure that Brent
to tie it kind of tie these timelines together, that Brent was doing agile
stuff in being, I thought, cool.
For the record, uh, the infrastructure, I can't even call it a team.
I ran infrastructure on Xbox as a virtual team.
It was all just open source style, inner source style.
There's one thing actually.
So by that time you were no longer, well, obviously you were no
longer in the education org.
Right.
I went from the education org or the ex engineering excellence org to
link and then to Xbox.
But you'll correct me if I'm wrong.
But if I, if I remember correctly, even when you left, you still
ran community events.
Yeah.
I kept running, uh, not test leadership team, but there was a, uh, at
one point our T kind of off, maybe it, maybe it's relevant.
Uh, we had a technical commuting, technical TCN technical.
I don't know.
Q tech.
Well, TCN came to me and said, Hey, we want to have a group of senior
level people in the testing profession.
Remember we're still siloed.
There's still massive test teams are still 10,000 testers of Microsoft.
So just the senior people want to get together.
Cause we have funding to do that.
And they, they had a lot of money to feed us food.
We went to baseball games.
It was soccer games.
It was great.
And then we had the quality and testing excellence community, which I ran
for about two years, uh, and then TCN went away and I got my time back.
I was an Xbox.
Brent was learning agile.
I'm getting him to talk on panels and be part of these Q tech
conversations is agile.
Still very different, but it's dark conversations.
Like in that time you can accelerate the achievement of simple quality thought.
Oh yeah, I get that.
When Xbox shipped, I went on a sabbatical and I came back.
Actually I took a ton of time off.
I went to Australia for a month, came back for a few months, went to France
for three months and then came back.
But during that time I was working on the stupid science project known as
Astoria, which was the dumb thing to make windows app.
Sorry to make Android apps run on windows phone thought it would
have been a much easier effort just to build just to make the window shell
or run on the Android phone, but whatever.
I'm not in charge.
That product was never going to ship, but I wanted to learn Java and
I wanted to learn Linux and it was fun.
I just did random things, took it on.
It was great.
Uh, I got bored.
I got so, so bored.
I loved my manager, but I was bored and I told him I was bored.
He said, yeah, I don't know what to do.
I don't want you to leave, but maybe you should.
So I did.
And this is where I was because we didn't have a test team.
This was the big move that happened.
Then is I skipped the whole big important chunk in the early parts of this org.
We didn't have, we moved from X box to the stupid app and
we didn't have any testers.
This is my first time coaching testers on how sorry, coaching
developers on how to write tests.
Can't believe I almost skipped this part.
I did most of it through code review.
I would ask questions like, Hey, where are the tests?
Oh yeah.
We're going to get those in the next check-in.
Uh, no, you should probably test check in the test now.
Really?
Yeah.
Cause how, why does the code work?
Oh, I get where you're going.
Yeah.
I'm going to write some tests.
And so I have a few of those conversations eventually gets to, Oh great.
You have tests.
And then I critique the tests.
Why does your test doing 15 different things?
When your test fails, how about you?
Like I've gone through this pain for you.
So when your test fails, if your test fails, no, when your test fails, maybe
you should have some logging to know why.
Well, I'll just hook up the debugger.
Is that really the most optimal way to do?
Oh, I get.
Yeah.
Oh, that's cool.
Good idea.
And then for all these things, the more I bring them up and then other
people would almost got to be a, what would Allen say?
And then after awhile, I wasn't needed to be on to pay attention to code
reviews because all the questions I was asking about improving tests
were getting asked by others.
So it was great.
And again, I didn't care too much because the product was stupid.
So then I moved to, I moved from there to, uh, this was fun.
I moved to what eventually became Microsoft teams.
And we all know this story.
I love the product for awhile.
They didn't have any testers.
They hired me because I knew about testing and a big part of my job
was to coach the help developers do better testing.
I did on some places and other places, they were just happy to have their code suck.
I won some battles.
I lost some others.
And what they gave me was a million dollar budget to go hire contractors
offshore to help get this testing done.
The idea was it for it to be a stopgap.
So they keep moving forward while they address their backlog of missing tests.
And to be clear, they had a hundred, this is, I'm sure you've all seen this.
They had a hundred percent or not a hundred.
They had like, seriously, like 90 plus percent code coverage on their unit
tests across the board.
Nice.
And what does that mean for quality?
It means it's perfect ship it.
Or you're missing 5%, but who cares?
Yeah.
There's, there is so much in conversation I've been having even today is the gap
between works and good is much bigger than people think.
And, um, code coverage covers, which of those topics?
It covers works kind of covers, covers some of what's major tests covers the code.
Does it mean the code works?
Anyway.
So I learned a lot cause actually I found out, this is where I really found out.
Cause I was doing less code review and more kind of hands on working
with folks and then the test.
This is where I really discovered that, wait a minute, developers can really
do good testing and even though I complained about them missing some stuff
that could have been automated.
When I sat when I said, okay, let's, let's do a hate, hate it, but we did a bug bash.
Let's, let's work on finding bugs and I gave them ideas.
I gave them some heuristics.
I gave them Elizabeth Henderson cheat sheet and we had developers find bugs
that I think only the best testers in my career would have found.
They absolutely were able to pick.
They just needed to know it was okay to, to use their brains and
engage and do some testing.
And I had light bulbs going off that.
Oh my God.
I spent so much of my career and we need to backtrack a little bit here.
When I was in test excellence, my job was to celebrate the career and profession
of the software tester at Microsoft.
We had 10,000 testers and I worked on career paths extensively to describe
what it would be like for testers to grow all the way up to the highest levels.
And man, the cognitive dissonance, when I taught developers to be that good
and testing that quickly, it's like, holy shit.
I wish I knew then what I knew now because I did a bunch of shit wrong.
I learned a lot there about teaching developers to test and in, we weren't
very agile, but we, I learned a lot of things about shipping in an agile way.
So we're able to ship our services on demand, which was great.
We shipped our front end once a week.
I wish we could have shipped it more often.
And that's, if I think I would have stayed, what would have got to
a stage where we did that.
I know after I left, they did so much of non feature flagging and shoving stuff
in so that we could weekly release that customers asked them to slow down the
cadence, I don't know if that's better or not now, but we did a lot of cool,
all the cool deployment tricks for the blue green deployments.
And we did, we actually deployed our, what was going to be the
next week's build in rings.
They still call rings, their rings or circles.
So like, we just push them buttons.
First it went to just me and my organization.
And then once our test team did their steps and yes, it's pretty good.
We'd roll that out to all of the organization, then to all of Microsoft
before we'd really sex, internally.
And I love that, that phased rollout.
We did it in steps versus a slider, but learned a lot about how to
deploy in the, in the real world.
So I got fed up with my manager for being a dick and I quit.
I had a new job.
I, I, I talked to the folks at unity and they said, Hey, well I said, Hey, uh,
I'm thinking of leaving Microsoft.
Do you have any jobs?
Cause they had approached me like a two years before I said, actually,
I don't have that other job.
I have a new job.
And I said, what is it?
We need someone to run our services QA.
I said, question one, what is services QA?
And they said, Oh, all of our guy was my boss for all.
I didn't really know.
It's like, Oh, we have a bunch of stuff that it's in the internet.
In the internet.
What it ended up being is when I described it, it was all the parts of unity
that use the internet.
It was everything from the website to some stuff in the editor to things
that are peer services like analytics and ads.
And anyway, I, this was a great job because all my interviews were all about
getting to know fit and feel and not about stupid whiteboard things.
And they never even asked for my resume until they forgot that they needed
it in order to give me an offer.
They're like, Oh, Oh yeah.
Just realized you know, resume from you.
That's cool.
Here's one.
And so I started in, I didn't, of course, I spent my last two
teams not having QA, but I didn't join.
And you remember this next, we were talking a lot about this as I joined.
And I still remember our very last podcast at Microsoft when, uh, we drank
some tequila together while we podcasted.
That must've been a while back.
I didn't join unity with like, Oh, now I'm going to get rid of these testers.
I joined unity thinking, this is going to be fun to manage a QA team.
And the challenge there for me was learning how to manage a
globally distributed team.
Very little of my team was in Seattle with me or Bellevue.
Worldwide, the unity Bellevue office is known as the Seattle office
because, uh, who knows where Bellevue is.
Right.
This is a lot fresher in my mind, but I remember a point when I realized
you know what this is because they're all, it was agile ish across the board.
So all of my org were embedded into other teams.
And I was there to help them and coach them, help them to do the right
things and give them advice and things.
And that's what I realized, maybe it was on a podcast.
I said, it's really a community.
And then like literally like less than a month later, I was rereading agile
testing and Lisa and Janet said the same thing in their book and agile
manager's job or agile test manager's job is to run a community paraphrase.
I thought, Oh, well, I'm glad I'm just discovering this now.
It got to a point, maybe six months in when I realized that the right thing
for me to do for unity's business and for the career of these people was
to get rid of them all and I fired none, but I helped all of them move
into different roles at unity into dev roles, into quality coach roles,
into DevOps roles, someone well respected.
And he knows I'm talking about him.
Someone well-respected across our entire org, who was a QA lead reporting to me.
And now he's like the, one of the most respected DevOps folks across the org.
It's probably the most I didn't set out to just see what the right thing to do.
So within 18 months or so, or maybe two years, it took me two years.
And it's funny how Brent used to joke about how I changed jobs every 18
months to two years and said, no, I don't, but mother effers, right.
Confucius say find the job you love and you'll never work a day in your life.
So I'm going to talk about even my new job now or what's happened since then.
After about two years, I, my team was gone.
So I moved into what was then called our monetization org, which is
ads, some other businesses.
Now it's a much bigger org and I have many more cool responsibilities.
But it was really those first two years of me at unity and going through that
process is where we solidified and in my head really embraced what is modern testing.
That was the question I was going to get to is, is, um, like to me, your
experience on teams feels very much like how I felt about my experience on Xbox.
You and I had fundamentally different experiences in that organization.
Um, I was lucky enough to be put into a position where I was, my role was to do
whatever the hell I wanted, as long as I provided value.
So it was, it was good.
It was easy to have fun, but anyway, go with Xbox.
Yeah.
No, I, when I left Xbox, a big part of it.
And in, I tell people don't leave a team, go to a team.
Um, in that particular move, I did both.
I was very much motivated to get out of Xbox because I thought the culture
was just entirely dysfunctional.
And then I wanted to go to a team that claimed that they were doing agile and,
uh, was actually happy about it.
And they were doing services.
I wanted to go, I wanted to go and find a place where I could learn by
entrenching myself, um, how software works differently in that environment.
And it sounds like teams was that for you, teams was sort of your Xbox.
It was like, I learned, I learned a lot in teams.
I used to say on teams that it wasn't until I ran all of the infrastructure
in DevOps that I really began to have an influence over quality.
And I've heard some, I've heard people say that too.
Like there's so much ability to have influence in a good DevOps team.
So I learned that there.
I had so much influence over the quality by controlling our deployments
and having an understanding of how to deploy.
I learned a lot of basis.
It was just a little bit of a toxic environment and it wasn't a product in
the end, I loved anymore because product mistakes being made in choosing to.
Again, going back to lean, I had also developed my own principles by
doing small things well, and those things weren't happening.
I didn't have control over that.
I just had control over the, the end of the sausage maker, but I learned a lot
about influencing quality and how I can control that from a, uh, infrastructure
point of view and the same thing is then three years later or two
years, two and a half years later, I got the hang of it.
I realized that now I own those same things plus program management.
And don't get confused on the Microsoft program management, but I control
the aspects of how our engineering teams do their estimations and deliver
and get, get them to think about the things they need to think about
to be ready to work and to be done.
Now I have even more control over the quality of our products.
Cause I, I control the whole sausage making machine.
The other teams I work with focus on product development, everything I do
and my teams do enables them or blocks them.
It puts them, puts the right guard rails up, I should say, so they
can deliver quickly and effectively and with quality.
So I definitely learned some of that basis in teams going into my time at
unity while I loved accelerate the achievement of quality.
And I think we had already had the modern versus traditional much earlier.
I believe I was still at Microsoft when we had that debate.
I can't quite remember.
I don't think so.
I look, I feel like we recorded that one in Lincoln square.
I have, I have a memory.
It could be, I could be wrong, but worth looking up.
It was definitely while I was experiencing a team or teams moving from
traditional, even if it was actually, they were moving from agile or fake agile.
And again, Lisa will probably listen to this episode eventually agile testing,
as she and Janet describe it is wonderful.
Too many times in my experience, it wasn't, it was still the embedded
tester was the one doing all of the testing.
And that's unfortunate, but I saw his teams were the embedded tester was doing
all the testing and wanted to move that to real whole, whole team quality.
When did, when did you move to unity?
Uh, January, it spent almost four years because Barack Obama and I both
quit our jobs on the same day.
So we recorded that on September 2017.
Oh, wow.
Yeah.
Wow.
It was after.
But then the principles came up and I really think we formed, I don't know if
I've answered, I think without answering it directly and walking through that, I
think maybe I've answered the question of how I came out of my career ended up
getting to modern testing.
It was sometimes it was actually rarely purposeful.
Here's the thing that I think that I realized that is common in both of our
stories.
Number one, there was an element of just had it with the dysfunction
that caused us to move on the team where I'm where, and then move on to a team
where number one, we both had autonomy.
Uh, well, actually we both had an autonomy around how we would execute software.
And we both made a decision to try out this agile lean thing and furthermore,
realized, holy effing crap that completely works so much better than pretty much
the best thing I had learned in the last 20 years.
I'm drawn towards efficiency.
Yeah.
In fact, I loathe inefficiency.
So if I see a better way of doing something, I'm drawn toward it and it's
just something I've definitely discovered, especially in the last, uh, few years.
Yeah.
I remember in, in, in, again, you weren't pursuing, uh, you said it like, Hey, the
first thing I did was realize I needed to get rid of my team.
No, it actually, it actually took several months for me to get, that wasn't
what I wanted to do at all, but it got to a point I was like, Oh God.
Yeah.
I'm the, the, the orb, the light that I was being drawn towards was one
more, he didn't have dedicated testers in our services orgs.
No, but that wasn't what you were trying to do.
What you were trying to do is get rid of the, uh, what do we call it?
The co-dependency.
Yeah.
I was trying to ask, I was trying to run an effect.
Safety net, right.
Um, the,
I'm pointing out that one thing really cool to call out is during that time,
one of the things I did in building this community was I had 90% of my team,
plus some guests hang out with me in Bellevue for three days.
And Brent came and gave a talk.
Yeah, that was fun.
That was fun.
The there's, there's three times you asked me to come into a talk.
One was, uh, that agile panel, uh, way back in the day, way back
at Microsoft at Q tech, the second one was around the combined engineering
transformation.
I had left big at that time and I was executing it in the power BI org.
You asked me to come and talk about that.
I remember, I remember, uh, very fondly that one cause your joke then.
Do you remember what your joke was when you introduced me?
No.
Uh, you said some of you may or may not know, uh, this person, I don't know how
he's going to do a 30 minute talk because I'm fairly certain he can't even
pronounce his name in short than 10 minutes.
Cause it all true.
I would say the same thing today.
That's not a joke.
That's just, that's just expectations.
Yeah.
So it was well framed because you, you started it off with that challenge.
And I remember I nailed my time, but you're right.
If you hadn't done that, I probably would have been the cause for going over.
And the third time was, uh, was a sort of a data culture discussion.
Uh, it was actually, uh, essentially the modern data oriented techniques for
looking at and improving quality.
Right.
And that actually eventually became one of the decks that AST did or asked me to do.
And it's up on YouTube now for those who care.
I'm still thinking through your story and the similarity.
And I think the similarity is these were sort of things that we've been
actively thinking about for a while.
I can even maybe even, uh, generalize this more is one of the things we wanted
to do when we started the podcast was help people who were going through any one
of these transformational changes and help them understand there was a greener
grass on the other side.
And one thing common between you and I is we embrace change.
We're not afraid of change.
We'd like to try new things a lot.
And we're not worried about screwing stuff up.
We just want to try new stuff.
Yep.
The concept of best practices, uh, hum, uh, that humbles me.
That would be the exact opposite direction.
Uh, a noise, uh, irritates me greatly, right?
Best practices are now.
Right.
Uh, anyone who studies systematics knows that once you have a current practice,
you got it eventually the whole system readjusts and constructs new problems.
Like a example email came out emails.
Fantastic.
It's fast, right?
I can, I can, I don't have to write a letter.
I can, I can just type a letter, send it to Alan in five minutes.
And I don't have to call him going, Hey, did you get my letter yet?
Did you get my letter yet?
But then what happens is it creates a new problem.
Okay.
It reduced the friction also for all the people who I don't want to get crap from.
So now I'm buried by emails.
Like I, uh, I get calls from Alan.
Hey, Hey, Brent, I sent you an email like three days ago that
you haven't responded yet, right?
I get the same, goes back to the same initial problem.
I've never called Brent, but I do remember this guy, Carl,
windows CE would he'd, uh, I'd see you walk up to my door and just stand there
in my doorway, we had, we had offices, the doors you say, did you get my mail?
I don't know.
Well, can you read it?
I know all the time.
No, I can't read.
I probably got your mail.
Send me, send me a dead tree mail.
All right.
So I like the parallels there, the parallels.
We got to kind of wrap up here.
So what, so that's kind of where I got where Matt and ask me, ask me a question.
Yeah.
One question.
So for me, I can remember like yesterday when, when it all clicked in and why I
knew this was actually correct versus me just rolling the dice and go, I'm
pretty confident in this is going to work, but not actually knowing.
Did you have such an, an aha moment where you go like, Oh yeah, I am never,
I am never ever going back.
Kind of, kind of.
And for me, you know, we had talked about this stuff and I had done it in practice.
I thought, well, maybe there's more context I'm missing and it's not working.
And probably not only going to work if I'm there and it's just too much.
And then I went, we came up with the principles and we thought they were
going to keep on changing for a long time, but they really haven't changed.
And I presented them at test bash in 2018, I believe.
And the number of people that came up, this is a test conference.
I thought I was going to scare the crap out of them.
Right.
The number of people that came up to me afterwards and said, Oh my God,
you're describing exactly what I do.
Thanks for putting a name to it.
I thought, what, what?
Cause I had given a talk a year earlier called testing without testers.
And I don't think I even believed it was really how I did it and how it kind of
could be done and how I was cheating by using contract testers, but it was
really talking about coaching developers.
But moving from there to the principles and covering everything that
kind of has to work together.
And so much of that, as you and I will agree is stolen from lean and the lean
startup and agile testing that you kind of backsplend our way into that.
But it really was probably test bash.
When I thought when it became something I thought worked for me, that's something
I knew could work for everyone.
That was my, aha.
Okay.
And I got to tell you, I've had groups I don't even work with at unity as late as
last week, pull me into a Slack channel conversation.
Hey, Alan, we're doing this thing.
I can't tell you what it is.
Uh, how do you think modern testing principles would apply here?
I don't even know you and you're talking about, Oh my God.
Wait, wait is model modern testing principles, like a, a, a well-known
brand within unity.
No.
I mean, no, I, I have done no, I've done zero evangelism inside of unity.
People just find it and go, Oh, Hey, this looks valuable.
And they try to say, Oh, and this guy works here.
This is cool.
Or the other way around, like who the hell is this guy telling us what
to do LinkedIn search, uh, angry.
We, well, what the hell, right?
Maybe goes the other way.
Happened more than once.
That's the, that's cool.
The, um, yeah, I remember back in the day, no one's asked me to do this, uh,
in a while, but back in the day, I had teams coming out of the woodwork,
asking me to walk them and onboard them to agile.
Yeah.
I remember.
All right, man, we got to close it up, but we're back on for
every two weeks now, right?
Yeah.
Cool.
Hope you all enjoy the new time.
New bat place, all that stuff.
I'm still Alan.
I'm Brett.
We'll see you next time.
On the AB testing podcast.