Welcome to AV testing podcast your modern testing podcast your hosts Alan and
Brent will be here to guide you through topics on testing leadership agile and
anything else that comes to mind now on with the show we are back for another
episode hey Brent how you doing I'm doing swell Alan wow you know it's it's
been a break huh it looks like what August 17th yeah we had a three-week
break we shifted crap goes on that happens we are inconsistent but we are
consistently inconsistent sometimes two sometimes three occasionally four
occasionally one week between episodes I was just sticking through I was looking
at the last the last episode we get something that I think we're not super
accustomed to recently and that is we got praise for it high praise shocking what
did we talk about in that episode I don't know and then you called it Azure
powered oh I did because you talked about Azure so I called it we were
talking about names for Windows I think and as you're powered it made sense to
so unlike this episode so yeah here we are hello people watching the live stream
I'm sorry that it sucks but we'll do better do you have like anything new we
should talk about before we dive into talking about me you just can't stop
fidgeting with the crap around you can you yeah all right I think I so we've
joked in the past about the podcast being a DD written I don't know that I
mentioned before I have a child that has been diagnosed with it and I haven't gone
in but if it's genetic I think yeah I don't think you need to go in the other
thing positive news see I don't think we talked about it so you remember that I
screwed up my hand my finger yes I do remember did we do an episode post
surgery no no we did not so I did they plant a chip in you if they did I can't
tell all right what do they do hey everyone Alan hopping in here for a
little overdub I've just edited out about 25 minutes of Brent talking about
the recent surgery on his hand friends okay he was little anxious before the
surgery but now we can get back on with the podcast so on the podcast I think part
of our partnership is I'm representing the IQ side of the house and you're
representing the EQ not to say that Lisa no that's totally true you're the
smart one I'm the entertainment in your case though it's not that you're a
dumbass either although in my case I tell my team I have two emotions I use I use
neither of them very often but when I do I am all in that is all I do and this
one yeah it was anytime I can I can go wow I cannot push this emotion into its
little box where I normally put emotions it's the right thing to do is take any
emotion that you feel squish it up into a metaphorical little ball as tight as
you can and shove it as deep inside of you as you can and keep it there right
right exactly right and then you know you put it in a little box and then you
take that box and you squish it up into a little ball and you put a little
another little box and then you go find some deep and then you lock the box
absolutely you lock the box you hide it in a little dark internal corner you you
you close and you lock up the door to that little corner right yeah I mean we
could do this forever yeah yeah we're not we're not good but we get the point
so you got your hand you got your hand fixed and it freaked you out and now
you're better well not entirely now you're getting better getting better now
they're gonna amputate your hand I don't think they're gonna go that far
discussion like if they were to do that right should I go with like full-on hook
are you just like gonna stare at your hand the entire episode they it's that
maybe quiet right you want me to do something else maybe no you're yeah
play with your hand play with your hand hey I want to talk about well your EQ
thing reminded me of a story I have to tell now and then I want to talk about
the other thing I want to talk about which is me but you'll have it inputs we
are in the middle of we do promotions twice a year in our org at Unity and we
have modified very carefully because I know at scale it's gone very badly we
have modified sort of what Google do for promotions we have Oh promotions here in
this case does not mean like PR events it means hey annual review time blah-to-blah
promoting no we don't really do annual reviews but we do we do look at people
for promotion twice a year and what we do is at Google as many of you may know
an employee can anyone can choose when they want to be they feel like they
should be promoted and they prepare a packet of materials describing what
they've done and a a panel of people independent not your manager goes and
reviews that ours is very similar however we the employee doesn't do it by
themselves it's the manager recommendation but it's a collaboration
between the manager and the employee that makes sure that it's fair and then
we're in the middle of this but anyway blah blah blah I'm leading one of the
panels and for a couple of the more senior promotions and I I lead some
meetings at unity where I have to be strict father figure no you know the
how should I describe this no I get it you're the you're the adult in the
room you're the one major adult in the room and make sure and and really push
stuff along and be good this was a small panel of senior people and we had really
good information prepared and the goal of the meeting is to reach alignment on
a bunch of criteria of evaluation and but we had all the information needed
to do well so I'm kind of having fun making sure it's fun to go through it
and there is one of the newer directors who haven't interacted with a
lot one-on-one and I was doing my normal joking around and he said something
that I both felt good and bad about at the same time he goes and I won't try and
do his Scottish accent but imagine this is Scottish I've never seen this
Alan this Alan is fun and I thought well that's nice you this you're having
a good time here but I'm sorry that you don't think I'm fun all the time I
have to project my my fun Alan more often so I feel bad people think I'm not fun
yeah did you bring patron into the meetings you introduce people to the
group hug no and no yeah so that's been going on I have a couple of my folks
being promoted I have no idea how they're doing I prepared packets for
them I worked with them to prepare them and we'll see how they are reviewed one
cool thing about this process is the goal of the process is not to get people
promoted the goal of the process is for people put up for promotion no matter
what happens with the promoted or not that they feel like the process is fair
and they get good feedback as part of the the committee like I still have to
prepare and consolidate a bunch of feedback that my panel has written and
what we'll do is we'll give the decision along with a page of feedback on things
that they're doing well the areas of growth we'll give that to the manager to
present to them so it's a it's a cool process so anyway if I made me think of
a fun Alan versus unfun now so my favorite part of that is if you
remember the part where I'm fun the part my is that your favorite part where
I'm not no okay the so I think I think my experience of you is probably 60% the
fun Alan and then 40% the pain in the ass adult person Alan sometimes you have to
get people to get stuff no good get it good no I get I can and to be clear I
can get people to get stuff done fun but yeah I yeah we all get so in my team
there's actually a name for it and I have an employee Oh is uncle PD the fun
Brent or the unfun Brent no I haven't told you the uncle PD story no but I
don't want to hear go on go on with story number one is there's a name for
within my team and and one of my employees who's also super high in EQ
she's the team's monitor they think of it like a like a testing and production a
live site alert system and she's like up guys Brent's in command mode so it comes
from the fact that so if you remember long long long ago I put you through the
strength binders stuff yes I still I just pulled that out recently one of the
strengths is one called command and that's not one of mine it's it's not in
my top five but it is in my top ten it's something that I use not every day but
maybe once a week once every two weeks and when I'm in command mode it's
essentially in the next five minutes a decision is going to be made that's
that's command mode I don't care where the decision comes from I would prefer it
become from from you all and it's something something beneficial to everyone
but come hell or high water there is going to be a decision in the next five
minutes that's that's command mode it in a nutshell the the second story I have
already forgotten it no no we can skip uncle PD for now but I want to give you a
quiz I want to give you a quiz first then uncle PD and then my stuff you give
yourself yourself I'm gonna give you a guy of my top five strength finder
categories in front of me I will give you one point for everyone you can guess
giving it to me so if I just stall off don't look at us so okay you don't get to
know so the one the one I I experience all the time so one of my strengths is
called individualizer and what that means is I'm I'm actually really good at
seeing the strengths of individuals okay okay good good what am I know you're the
guy's your arms are folded so you're not typing one that I know of and I see all
of the time uses all of the time it might even be your number one I don't
remember the order is a cheever that is number three nice job I work hard and
possess a great deal of stamina take immense satisfaction in being busy and
productive a productive more than busy yeah the the thing that's interesting
about achievers is so every strength is also a weakness is this like the job
interview when you say do you have any weaknesses yes sometimes I work too hard
yeah so that's not something I would say but it would something it's something
that you would say potentially as an achiever but the the the weakness it's
really what drives achievers achievers are allergic and that's just absolutely
the right way of saying it they are allergic to being idle they cannot stand
idle time which which ends up being kind of a crappy thing when you're stuck at
home all the time so you end up working a lot yeah no I'm imagining like your
backyard is frickin weed-free the front yard is looking good you're like crap I
need something to do on the weekends oh what's the last time we fertilized home
depot trip right crap like that for you here I'm kind of cheating now cuz I'm I'm
not leveraging my individualization I am just trying to remember I will I think
it was one as well numero uno I figure out how to get shit done and then get
well so actually the thing that's interesting is futuristic in one of
yours no it's not and I'll actually just give them to you so they can move on but
strength finders a book if you buy the book you can pick the quiz and evaluate it
I thought about doing it you can pay for more advanced stuff but I like it does
describe it reminds me what I'm good at what I need to which is good for me
sometimes when I'm just doing a bunch of different things number one is
strategic which is faced with given scenario quickly spot the relevant
patterns and issues I do this all the time number two you're not gonna be
surprised with is learner my superpower to success is I am totally unafraid to
take on stuff I haven't done before and figure out how to do it as I go along
and I leverage my strategic in order to do that number three is talked about is
achiever number four is analytical and really it goes the strategy as I think
about all the factors that might affect the situation and number five is
intellectual and appreciate intellectual discussions so none of these should be
surprising it isn't one who knows me so yeah actually I would never in a million
years have remembered the mine so so the one thing that's interesting about you
being like your particular package of top five I mean it's well suited for the
role that you're in the strategic is number one and I don't want to go this
isn't the strength finders episode no it's not but what most people will see
of you is your first strength but the thing that is fascinating about about
the strength finders stuff is that in general what your goal is like you're
gonna give it this way you use the top four strengths to achieve some goal around
the fifth one so usually yeah in my case it's it's not true but I will say that
in the majority of the folks that I tested that one with it is true like this
is something that Gardner so Gardner put together this thing and they have done
like 50 years of multiple different sort of tests on it the thing that I find
fascinating in your top five that's interesting and I think taking back it
makes sense with sort of your personal struggle is so these things fall into
individual pillars and in none of your top five none of them is anything relating
to people whereas I have two in my top five I wonder if it makes a difference
that I mean these should be my strengths no matter what but I remember when I took
this I was an IC but I don't know I'm not gonna go too deeply into it I do want to
talk about people and especially the learning attribute so how does your team
learn new stuff like what opportunities what what circumstances occur when your
teams have the steepest learning curve what happens in your product and I'm
totally I'm trying not to lead you but I'm just curious can you think of a
circumstance where your team went on a steep learning curve oh I'm like the the
one that's the most prevalent to me is I'm still in the middle of it right
starting back in May I doubled the size of my team with all new non Microsoft
folks so a variety of them had industry experience in the past but not here at
Microsoft and introducing them to two concepts number one the Kanban concept
it is definitely not typical to even if you're in industry to run a data science
team using an agile method it's it's it's coming up it happens more
frequently now than it did say five years ago but it's still a typical not
typical this matter of fact having any structure at all so when we grab the
bunch of these folks a couple of them came from academia which has their own
sort of long is more of a waterfall ish type process right their job their job
was to research research produced papers there's a six to nine month structure
and that might even be the best track for for postdocs when in industry a lot
of the times companies will hire what they hope is a unicorn they will hire a
larger companies don't do this but smaller companies they'll hire a data
scientist because they know they need one and but then the guy shows up and
they don't know what to do with them they don't know how to manage their career
they don't have the mentor so those folks get accustomed to a good deal of
autonomy once they figure out how to survive in that environment so what I'm
dealing with right now is actually in the second one is my expectations of the
data scientists is that they pick up the development skills as well my goal in
one to two years is that I am fully a full stack data science team if it and
then in three years four years I'm actually gonna shift it it's
essentially we're a development team with a strong specialization in this so
you're in a growth path to get there on your vision we are we are but every
time we get a new set of people with their old culture it kind of slows down
the team dynamics so for me and remember the A B testing is since the A comes
first it's about me the biggest opportunities for organizational
learning and I'm a big fan of Peter Senge's fifth discipline about learning
and I liked I do a lot of things in retros etc to focus on learning in the
organization but but the the bumps in learning for the organization happen
when we have incidents in production when something when we have an
operational surprise and we can find because there's we we don't just ship
crap things happen usually because of the cascade of failures a bunch of things
going wrong at once and both people problems and infrastructure or
environment problems and something goes wrong and we get a massive opportunity to
learn new stuff that we can share across the organization so I also just recently
as of yesterday doubled the size of my team well that is a bigger thing right
because your team is wasn't tiny to begin with if I recall correctly so I have
about 60 right now total but what I what I cover now in my organization is the
organization I added is the it's an internal group name so I'll just describe
it maybe let's put it this way so the big the big new thing I picked up is our
site reliability engineering team the team of about 20 people 18 people who
manage our incident process for all of unity around the world okay so any time
there's an incident we have a bot that spins up a channel people drive
discussions make sure we get to get the mitigation happening people help shepherd
the issue bring in the right people etc so that team is with me so now I get
to any worry I had in the past about not getting optimal learning over
incidents is now my fault and the other the other pieces right which is good
right the other pieces I picked up are more of DevOps sort of teams they're
working on infrastructure company-wide so I'm also now responsible for not all of
it ninety percent ninety five percent of the infrastructure we use to deploy
services across the entire company okay no big deal you got this no big deal no
big deal just go ship no problems but it's fun because what happened with
this latest merger we did by last time my team grew which was only a month ago
the last time my team grew we merged actually the org that I used to be in
largely with the org that I'm in to put almost all of our services in one place
but now even the services that aren't in my organization are supported by my
organization in some way fun stuff all stuff I like to do I like to work on
the stuff that makes things go so I'm excited about it I haven't even met
with most of the I met with all of the people who will become my new direct
reports already but I look forward to getting to meet more of the team these
people I've worked with I've worked with all of them in one way or another up
until now just because I'm always in the incident channels in my other roles
trying to figure out what's going on and to push things along so lots more
to do so we could go a couple different directions from here you can just ask
me random questions about the org and what I'm going to do or we could talk
about incident management in general because it's a bunch of different ways to
do that but before I do that I want to share one one observation that came from
this merger last month we have another we have a couple new directors in the
org and when we made this announcement internally to my peer group one of the
more senior people said is an SRE just a culture and not a role and before I could
even answer my manager said yeah same thing with DevOps I thought it was
interesting that I'm glad he got where I was DevOps is not a role it's a culture
we have a team to help promote that culture and the SRE team does the same
thing so I'm glad everyone recognized that right off but where do you just
already answered my question because damn I'm good on a recent episode of a be
testing on it Brit discuss WTF is Alan's new team's name oh yeah we talked about
that before I I was gonna call it delivery but now I was just pretty close
but I threw that away once I I knew I was picking up everything else and so
it's back to being called it's back to being called Alan team for now because we
don't have a better name Alan team at that's cool you can use the at sign you
just caught that blow is this thing on not on not on that was your question oh
your question was what to call the team I don't know what to call it not gonna
worry about it the right name will evolve as we grow but one thing I had
noticed is my local organization DevOps team and the work they were doing was
overlapping a lot with this global infrastructure group and to the point
where we had to have a discussion just before this or this reorg was announced
where we were trying to figure out where should people ask questions about
tool X because you own it but we support it or we support or we own it and you
support it so now it's all just it streamlines a lot of confusing
situation to think of our customers being the people trying to develop
services across unity there's confusion and where to ask questions or where to
get support or what to do a certain situation now we can streamline a lot of
that much easier sounds so I'm excited this is a good and I have people on the
team go oh this is so great to have these things aligned so yeah yeah all
part of my so how did SRE come into this like so SRE were part of that group so
there was a group of it's a reliability engineering group but they also handled a
lot of infrastructure tools and groups that that group included probably half
the team were doing tools and infrastructure work things like managing
the github relationship and and some other company-wide tools and as part of
that SRE is also company-wide so they were separate so now that my DevOps org
actually is almost in all of the services unity not quite company-wide but
pretty close it made sense to just emerge the company-wide stuff and and
even my DevOps team does do some support outside of just our organization so now
it's all just the charter now is all just our org supports service
infrastructure deployment company-wide okay so makes a lot of sense why you want
to talk about incident management yes yes because while I complain a lot about
things that happened at Microsoft and how I've been not did not that I noticed
when I was there but when I left I go oh this can be better Microsoft did a
pretty good job at incident management and in most cases having development
teams own a larger part of it than we do here right now and having very small
SRE teams per organization so I want to talk about the pros and cons of that
and my last team at Microsoft Microsoft Teams which by the way I ran in a browser
on Linux for the first time yesterday and it worked so congrats to Microsoft
for finally catching up we had a very we had two people on our SRE team for
Microsoft Teams and their job was entirely to just really play oversight
we had the first person called the first person page was not the SRE team it was
the developer who owned the particular service that went down which I kind of
like the difference is between that and what we do at Unity is the SRE team
gets the first page so they can jump in and create the channel and monitor
things but within seconds the the appropriate development owner development
owners are involved in figuring out what's going on with the incident I also
know that at Microsoft Teams handled teams to handle production incidents in
different ways so I'm curious what have you seen as far as models for handling
production incidents and what do you think has worked well or not well one
of the things that's interesting right because you shared your perspective and
so I got to figure out at the same time I got to answer your question and figure
out okay what's what's what may or may not be an NDA violation one of the things
that's interesting is but this scenario you talked about but there's another
there's another bigger problem when you're trying to do this at scale and
Microsoft so we talked about Azure what is that good question what is Azure it's
a it's a very pretty color I was gonna say the same yeah that just loaded a
whole bunch of candidates but I think we we've killed our tank control yourself
I think we killed our danger quota for today the and maybe for the next step
possibly but by then we'll have forgotten it doing it at scale is a
challenge you throw in addition to that that is a metaphor I've been testing
internally the last couple of weeks in terms of trying to get people so I'm in
I'm in several executive meetings and trying to set a metaphor and and a lot
of regards as your like this is like a set of Lego blocks we have a whole bunch
of Lego blocks matter of fact what was the the cool robot version of Legos my
son even has a set of it it's the one where you can program it and cool do
cool things the mind yes happy to help Brent right so but the one thing that
that so we have all these components all these little different little blocks but
as we've talked about before customers don't want software they don't even if
they come in nifty little components what they want is a solution to a problem
that they have in a lot of regards unlike Legos which has a very clean
interface for connecting components together we don't there's and so one of
the challenges is not only do we have to know when we have a an incident right
the the team that actually had the monitor to detect it may in fact not be
the team that needs to be on the line and so there's a whole lot of
infrastructure around how do we how do we quickly get how do we quickly
identify who is the relevant knowledge expert get them on the line so we can
start knocking down the incident there's a lot as you might expect there's a lot
of process with that one right and that is one place where the SRE team here
locally has spent a good amount of time on optimizing it it fails a great deal
we still end up having like the old-school bug ping-pong issues you
remember back in the day I recall and but generally what happens when there's an
incident there is there are three entities that get called into a a public
teams me currently improving the name that we use for this so a call is spawned
the conference call is created and three people get immediately at it that's that
is a key the the current incident manager within SRE the current incident manager
from our customer experience team that because they are the ones accountable for
socializing any any customer-centric message that we're going to send out say
in a broadcast or to to sit say the set of impacted customers they're the ones
that own that messaging and then a person who owns the monitor that triggered okay
and then on that call there's there's a lot of positive handoff we we and again
there's that quest for what's the cause as quickly as possible who's the who's
the knowledge expert to go even deeper okay there's a lot of post incident
process as well so this is the part and and all that
administrative it was very interesting Brent actually it really it was
interesting but it's the it's the post part that I think I care about a lot of
work to happen to make sure stuff gets resolved we drive we are not as good as
I want to be at our time to detect and time to mitigate so we work on improving
those but the work on improving those doesn't happen during the incident once
the incident is resolved the other thing our SRE team does is make sure
that we have a one a RCA document and sometimes it's depending on the team it
can be more of a tax it's filled out versus driving towards a learning
experience and also make tracking to make sure that improvements are being made as
a result of this and that some of those improvements or where applicable our
organization wider company wide and not just a quick fix on the team so in
driving those where was I going with that oh other thing is I define you
know we define incidents as an operational surprise so we're pretty
liberal about opening these so one thing having the large slightly larger SRE
team helps is we have prior one incidents which are kind of what you're
calling about which require all hands-on debt let's get this resolved as soon as
possible that's where I really worry about that time to mitigate and time to
resolve but sometimes something is just wrong it's not causing any customer
impact but we know from our monitoring and alerts that it's wrong and we'll
open up an incident on that because again going by an incident being an
operational surprise we're surprised by the way things look CPU usage up by 20% in
this node okay let's go let's open an incident go look at that if we don't
understand it right away and then we'll take the time to figure out okay we
got this then we can the chances are from that we may find something we've
learned and in systemic behavior that we can go either implement at an
infrastructure level to make sure there's better monitoring in place or
just to educate teams on why these things may happen so they're not
surprised by those in the future so those I don't know how often I don't
recall doing the latter class at at Microsoft as incidents but we try to
track all those operational surprises just to make sure that not just the
customer facing bugs our customer facing issues cause that reflection to
happen but taking all opportunities we can find to learn and get better so one
of the tweaks I'm gonna make to the system is I feel like the process of
analyzing incident doing a root cause analysis document has become a little
rote like and task like and not emphasizing learning so I think that's
one of the tweaks I'll make that's again going back to my learner attribute
I'm really stoked about that as so I am it it fascinates me how often I find that
you're working my work or an alignment unfortunately in this particular so it's
something my manager knows this it's something that I have been trying to shed
from my responsibilities for the better part of the two years but he and I are
partners on it and he refuses to go alone which understandably where I am
here's his shoes so we have a post-mortem process is what we call it
we have there is a non-trivial retrospective that occurs for each of
these things and we do those for the prior with the ones that have customer
impact we do an in-person retro as well and there's an expectation of what we
call repair items that will get communicated the SRE team has done a
I'll give them a C plus B minus on this because those processes the identification
the post-mortem and the repair they too have become as you call wrote right and
they're they're a bit of a make work exercise and whenever I get on a meeting
with with with folks I show two stories one of the the biggest issues and and I
don't think I'm violating India by sharing this because I think it's a
common value you go reading those SRE thing it's a problem that they have as
well although I suspect well Google wrote the book on SRE literally I think I
think they just have a maturity that we in Azure only have in in in it's not
holistic it's not it's not something that is part of the whole Azure culture
just yet anyway we'll go through this one of the things that I have noticed so I
read every post-mortem every month the quality of these things just rain
I see the same thing one of the statements is what was the customer impact
okay um yeah I cannot tell you the number of conversations I've had with
folks around the answer to that question is a friggin number yes and actually
that's what we track there you just went that's exactly what we track because
sorry I mean it's like a type something a minute ago Julia recommended that I
installed the MS Teams app or said there's a Teams app available for Linux
I said no way I'm installing that crap but I had two quick thoughts and I've
forgotten one of them one of them there's I think our roles aligned
because even though neither of us or anything close to a testing role we both
are still driven by the modern testing principles that's our life and so we
of course we align things those way but in our incidents out there's a field a
must-be filled out field which is not customer impact but revenue impact and
people have to go work with the BI team and figure out if there was a revenue
impact and put it in there and I track that because I want to know one of my
metrics I track is percentage of net revenue lost due to incidents so that
customer impact comes out as a number and that number has a dollar sign in
front yeah the interesting thing is so we spawned up a process about a year ago to
try to pull to do exactly that in our case though that data is considered at
the source is considered GDPR and once you put those four letters on any data
source people like whoa nope not not touching that one nope nope nope nope nope
because every data point I have to add you know 60 weeks of effort to guarantee
I'm caretaking it it's just a lot easier to say nope come on Microsoft's
rich just pay the fines yeah no one wants to be the person that's first in
the news for doing that one either Facebook we're already first in the news
yeah no I mean like internally and I don't want to be the first Microsoft for
that one no thank you someone else can go first let me tell you a couple things
that that I've been beating hard on this topic one that was very helpful and
another one that that's sort of my new meme so the first thing is I find one of
the problems that we had about two years ago is the way we define the SRE
process we're essentially so you called it priority we call it severity okay and
it's essentially the class of the incident is defined by a single value a P zero P
one and technically our prize is seven yeah so I've done a lot of work to get
that to be two values not one and the main reason why is if you look at it well
I don't know how unity operates so if a if a if a low do you categorize your
monitors do like if this monitor fires it's it's a 75% chance it's only going
to be a P for no okay so when a monitor fires is every monitor treated like a
potential oh shit we it depends but we have mostly smoke alarms okay so you
have a yeah you have a so when you you're gonna have a signal to noise
problem that you're gonna try to you probably want to work exactly it's
getting better definitely very good in some places but it's an area I'm working
on a person so I do like so Google in their SRE book they talk through their
which by the way is an excellent freaking book it is and it's interesting
it was published I don't know ten years ago now and I think it's still very
relevant to to today because there's so there's a lot of folks who like Google
developed this from from essentially the dominance in search and both just like
within Microsoft like Bing has forgotten how to succeed at managing
incidents that the rest of Microsoft in some areas has yet to learn yeah and
and keep in mind that Google is not a search engine company Google is an ads
company that happens to provide a search engine in order to further their main
business and that's similar to us in the fact ads are their revenue and in
the large part of my organization that is true as well sure the what I was
just saying is that the they detail a review process that they specifically
have spawned up to essentially evaluate the goodness or the the goodness of fit
for monitors and and they will they will have the authority to remove a
monitor from the system hey you know what the last nine times out of ten this
thing created noise this bad boy is gone what I have done in is change it to two
variables and I call them impact and urgency okay because one of the things
where our current system that prevented in it way we had modified or was doing it
that your system you don't have a worry about it you you don't yet have to worry
about it just remember that the the scale that we're talking about is
fundamentally different between unity in in Azure here the number of different
teams and I'm red different people it's just a fundamentally different scale but
so the the impact is intended to mean like how bad is it okay urgency though
is how is was how quickly this someone need to get on it and now the reason why
I wanted to separate those two is because when they were combined together
people only got on it when the impact was bad in other words we didn't have
something in the system that said hey this thing went down we better get on it
right now because in the next five minutes we know from the domino chain
in the next five minutes that's going to lead to a major outage someone needs to
get on it right now to prevent an inbound outage not an already occurring
one for sure move it to be more of a preventative thing and we have teams that
started using this they're very successful unfortunately it created a
confusion because they were like well wait a minute what did you why did you
declare this as a as a seven one when there's only two customers impacted and
they came to us and they're like you guys are breaking the press blah blah blah
blah blah and I'm just like nope they are not and I will go to Scott Guthrie
if you even hit oh yeah go straight to super God yeah slightly different I
think my approach is slightly different but I think the same impact is again
we don't have the scale and when our stuff goes down well some of it can be
really bad but I mentioned these pry two instance or just an operational surprise
everything is a pry one by default and the first thing you need to do is prove
that it's not if you're if it's just a learning experience the first thing you
do is prove with data that it's not a pry one we assume everything is urgent
like an operational surprise we have to assume it's a from initially that
it's something we need to jump on and then if someone says oh this isn't that
big of a deal the assumed next step is but I'm gonna I'm gonna prove that and
then once they've proved yeah this is not a big deal it doesn't impact anyone
they can show data to show that and then they can go investigate it at us
at a slightly less urgent level so what will happen is what I'm saying is
we discover this of the urgency and impact sometimes in that initial
investigation there might be an incident that says it starts with installs or
down 10% in this region we'll open that as a pry one like well oh this looks like
just an a reporting anomaly prove it yes it is reporting anomaly oh nope
reporting is right this is a real big thing so we have to get into the we
have to get into the investigation of the incident before we can start we got
someplace eventually any final recaps or rebuttals or things I just want to share
very quickly so one of the things that I've discovered repeatedly in the in the
from reading the post mortems over and over again and I'm actually publicly
beginning the question has anyone done any analysis specifically on whether or
not the post mortems or even the repairs that were targeted have had an impact
because the thing that I've seen over and over again is what's happening with
Azure right now is everything is not even the 1% scenario but rather the
point point zero one percent scenario right it's the really rare scenarios can
have a particularly big impact and because of those we right we have an
issue where the repair items in my humble view are unlikely to actually
ever be needed again like this incident is unlikely to ever reproduce the the
other thing that we've discovered is one of the major causes is that every
single one of the major causes is actually manual intervention that that's
that a developer had no choice but to override an automated system and they did
so in there and that's how I'm viewing it like anyone who wants to do a manual
intervention is actually a victim and we need to figure out what broke in the
process when I do retros with teams one of the part of the speech I typically
give at the beginning this isn't about blame not about blah blah blah it's
about figuring out what's wrong in the system that enabled this error to occur
right all right that's a good way to close it all right good to do that I
see you again I think next time we're going two weeks two weeks we have a
guest unclear whether they'll allow us to livecast them so I'll keep the
channel posted thanks everyone I'm still Alan and I'm Brent or vois