This is the AB Testing 343 podcast, a podcast where we ask one of the three listeners of
the AB Testing podcast, three questions about almost anything. ABT 343 is a fun slice of
what's going on in the world of modern testing. Let's get started.
Time for another ABT 343, and this time we have a fellow Unity employee. It's Melissa
Eden. Hey, Melissa.
Hey, Allen.
We've already been talking for like 20 minutes, so we're already kind of warmed up. So that's
all she had for me. Just a hey, Allen.
What's up?
All right, great. So a listener of the podcast, right?
Yes. Yeah, for a long time now.
This is the podcast, as the intro says, where we talk to one of our listeners, one of our
three listeners. This is our like, is this like our eighth or ninth third listener?
Yeah.
It's very confusing math.
It's that new math.
Do you know the story about the three?
The one of three or the yeah, kind of like it's kind of probably worth repeating for people
maybe starting here is that very early on, like in the first six months, year of our
podcast, Brent and I used to joke about our three listeners because we are a new podcast.
That's how many podcasts new listeners have. But then people would walk up to us and say,
hey, I'm one of the three. Like, oh, cool. And we knew what that meant. And it kind of
stuck. It didn't help when somewhere in the fifties when Percy created the one of the
three dot slack dot com. So now it's the official. And then I have stickers that on the back
of this laptop I'm recording on that you can't see, even though I'm pointing at it, which
say one of the three. So that's where it comes from. And I've talked enough for one
of the one ABT 343. So are you ready to answer three ish questions?
Yeah.
All right. I was thinking of asking an algebra question, but I'm not smart enough to think
of one on the fly. So instead I'll ask you about your career. So you've been, and I
should know this because I hired you. I know you've been at unity for over a year. How is
it two years yet? No, not quite. It'll be not quite. So you're right in November. Okay.
Year and a half. We'll call it a year and a half. So you've been in a management position
for all of that time. Pretty much. Yeah. What have you learned? What have you learned
about being a manager? What would have been some of your big learning point you can cover
whatever you want?
Well, one of the things I've had to learn more patience just around like people and coordinating
and understanding and perspective. That's like I always, I thought I was pretty much a patient
person, but when you start mixing in somebody other than yourself, that you have to actually
guide and talk with and have conversations on a regular basis and make sure they're
doing okay. It's you have to kind of double or triple what you're normally used to because
they have to process and they have to come back and it's sort of like a very long math
equation. So that's that, that part's been interesting. So patience and then also learning
how to do leadership and management without doing command and control to an extent or
being like a drive by or drive through or kind of like that combination of trying to
balance like how much is too much management or what's just enough or who, how do you
interact with people to give them guidance, but and also emphasize what's priority, but
not like, you know, micromanage them to death. So it's, it's, it's, it's a balancing act and
not not be completely like hands off either because that, you know, things will happen
and then you'll be like, Oh, how did that get completely off the rails? And then so
it's, it's, it's like all the spinning plates and everything. So some of that,
let's, let's pop the stack there for just a minute. So the leadership and management
thing, I love if you could elaborate on a little bit. So what have you, I mean, you
knew before you took this role that there was a difference between leadership and management.
So what have you learned about that? What have you, what are some of the insights you've
had in learning how to split and balance those two aspects?
For me, they go hand in hand, but like leadership, I feel like is being able to stand up and
either make a decision and then have, you know, have people actually believe that you
can follow through with it or they follow through with that decision or, and then management
is actually managing the decision you made, whether it's good or bad, right? So if
you decide to do something as a leader, then you pass that down or you, you know, you
disseminate or what's the other D word I'm trying to think of? Not defer. It's a Monday.
My brain is saying it's Monday. What is it?
It's okay. I can edit this part. So I'm trying to think it's the, what is that word? It's
the delegate.
Thank you. It's a D. Delegate. Yeah. So I mean, we, when you delegate to people to get
something done on a decision that you decided on, like, I feel like leadership is making
the decision. Delegation is the management part. And then also dealing with the result
of that decision is the management part. So there's, there's, cause leaders can make
a decision and then go off and do other things. But when you're managing, you also have
to deal with the end result of whatever you decided to do. So that's been the...
Well, you have to deal with how that decision impacts people.
Well, yeah, that's probably a lot more concise way of putting it. Impacts people or impacts
the product or impacts even customers to an extent. Like if I say, no, we're not going
to ship something and I need this tested and that understood and this fixed and I've
delegated that in a way and other people have taken those on, then I have to, I also
have to understand that I'm also dealing with like, and other people are dealing with the
decision of holding a release for whatever reason, or if the opposite, you know, we
decided to ship something and it's, it makes an impact because there was something else
we didn't catch, then I also have to deal with that decision in a way or try to mitigate
it the next time it comes back up. So a lot of the job is not only, and that's just around
the product. That doesn't even have to, that's not even encompassing having to deal with
decisions being made with, you know, how people are feeling or, you know, if they're
sick or if they're not being challenged enough at work and they want to learn more or if
their career development is slow or too fast or any of those like personal decisions
that people have to make, then you have to help them make those decisions as well. Like
I don't have to, but I think as a good manager, I point them in the right direction, at least
so that they can make a correct decision, hopefully.
Their success is your responsibility.
Yeah. So learning that and learning, you know, I already had inklings that that was
the case, but definitely learning how to do that and how to do it, how to get better
at it and recognize when I need to do it. It's like when I need to step in or ask
a question or, you know, double check and just say, hey, is everything okay? Do you need,
is everything good? What can I try to help with? That's been a learning process.
I think it came easier as time went on and as I've had more people to be able to help
delegate things across. It's like, because originally it was a three team group. I came
in and then one moved to development and then it was two. And then we started hiring people
about six months after I got there. So it's been interesting for sure to go from a very small team
and trying to survive like that work and help that person and help myself to a larger team where
we could delegate things. And you can actually see things shift and change with the teams when
you realize there's enough work for four people that two people were trying to manage. And that's
pretty interesting as well. And there was just a lot of things like technical and personal and
skill-wise. A lot to learn. One thing I like you described very modern test-ish,
testing-ish, MT-ish in your description, which I really like, which pushes back on
what one thing I don't like about the context-driven school is that you are describing yourself as a
decision maker whose decisions matter, not someone who just provides information to someone to make
those decisions. I think that's really important as a leader and a lot about the modern testing
principles or about how you lead your teams towards a higher quality culture.
Well, I used to be like that. It was like, I'm giving you the information. You have to make
the decision, right? I think that in some way is a cop-out. And some people would point that out
when I was doing that. I mean, it depends on the system I was working in. But as a lead,
as a tester, as someone who is trying to help make a decision, it's not my decision alone.
Like, I feel like it's more of a quorum now. Like, if you're running things right,
everybody helps make that decision, I think. And whether I'm working with the
lead developer or another tester or ops or whatever, we all weigh the decision together.
And if my decision is different from theirs, we try to understand why. I think it's more
important to understand, come to a conclusion that everybody can agree upon versus saying,
oh, here's my decision. Whatever you decide, it's up to you. It feels like...
Yeah, to me too. Full agreement.
So I have a bonus question for you. Sorry to put you on the spot, but I think for context
of the last question, this would be good, is can you talk just briefly about... Because your role
has changed since he started at Unity. I think it'd be worth talking about what you're doing now for
your org and what your team is doing. Actually, this is like the third time it's changed. I've been
there a year and a half. So I started out as a QA lead. So as a technical lead. And then
about six months in, shifted to management because I hired a team. So I was managing about four people.
And that was interesting and trying to get that moving. And then recently I've also shifted
to more of a quality coach or quality consultant. So we have a team now called...
I did something clever. Quality Elevation. So I just named it.
Oh, a new QE. Awesome.
A QE. And it caught on. I was just playing with a name to give the team a little bit of...
Because I wanted to get away from assurance or acceptance or having the QA. So I felt like
hey, what are we actually trying to do? We're trying to elevate quality. We're trying to raise
the bar and help the teams raise the bar. So called it the Quality Elevation team.
And Steven liked it. So it stuck. And now we're...
I don't hate it.
Good. Yay. But it's the idea of actually helping the teams find ways to
measure and perform whatever they decide and whatever we help them understand that they
should be targeting. Different quality metrics. Just different process tasks that could help them
understand where their gaps are. So it's a lot of consulting with the leads, consulting with the
teams, working with the teams on technical gaps and issues. Anything from automation to tooling
that could help them raise their quality. So that includes figuring out what analytics,
figuring out what kind of automation they need to put in place. And even documentation. So it's
all of the encompassing things that are kind of out of that functional testing realm
that's away from it. The teams are really owning the functional testing. And we're owning
how to get them the things they need to actually improve and move faster. So I'm digging it.
It sounds like you're accelerating the achievement of a shippable quality.
I am. I'm actually really happy about it. Because I feel like I've come full circle
back around to where I was when I was at ThoughtWorks and what I was doing with ThoughtWorks.
And that mindset of having everybody own quality and then trying to just take it one
step further and like, hey, let's introduce this and let's do this. And it's been an interesting
journey this last year and a half. And I really am encouraged and excited about where this next
phase of my career is going inside of Unity. So super cool. Yeah. So a coaching question for you.
Sure. I know that you from your testing experience, you are a great problem solver.
Whether it's your team or developers you work with, what are some things or stories or adventures
or whatever you've learned in coaching people to solve problems? How do you help? How do you know
when? It's a tough thing because you just want to do it, not delegate it. But when do you...
How do you approach that partnership of solving a problem together?
Yeah. I think it is... I've gotten better at delegating. Especially when I know that there's some
technical aspect that would take me a lot longer to ramp up on. If I can explain it well enough,
it's somebody that has more technical expertise in that area can pick it up faster than me.
I try to find that person. So that's the problem solver. It's like, I'm going to try to find the
person to solve this problem that I know we have. The other thing is just having conversations and
suggesting things. And whether people try them or not, or just planting the seed and they come
back around to it, that's okay. And just offering up solutions that could help in the moment.
Everything from root cause analysis to retrospectives to, hey, could we treat... What if we tweak the
sprints just a little bit to do something different? And even if they push back and they're like, no,
we're not going to try that right now, sometimes they come back around and they'll try it later.
So even just having a conversation about a problem that might not be solved right then,
or a delayed response is good. Trying to enable people to solve the problems themselves is a little
bit harder. It's hard to identify too, because oftentimes you don't know that you've had an
impact or you've had a conversation that's had an impact that somebody solved a problem with.
I think that happens more... I've seen it more on the career side of things when I've talked with
folks about mentoring and career inside the company, and they're having a difficult problem.
They're trying to get developers to do more unit tests, or they're trying to get them to
try something that could help. I'll ask them, who's the ally? Who do you have there that
could help you that sees your perspective that could help you demonstrate to the rest of the team,
whether it's pair development or pair testing or whatever? And they're like, oh,
this person can help me. And I was like, okay, well, then set up a time and kind of demonstrate
it and get moving on that and work at that problem from that direction. So it's a lot of
coaching and talking about... The other thing that comes up is they'll ask me, they're like,
oh, what do I do about this? This is a huge problem. I'm like, well, have you had a
conversation with that person to see if you can solve that problem? And then they'll stop
and it's like, oh, that's a good idea. I should go do that. And then sometimes I hear back,
oh, I had a conversation. This is great. And this is how it turned out.
So sometimes it's just suggesting the obvious, which is funny, but true. It's like, hey,
did you give your critical feedback? Did we talk about... Did you get a chance to talk about
this in three cues? What can you do to help improve your situation? Whether that's a technical
problem or a personal problem or a process problem. Sometimes it's just like, hey,
what else can we do to help you? Let's come up with brainstorm some stuff.
I find that just giving the person space to think through the problem and have somebody
like be the rubber ducky really has helped quite a bit. It helps me too. I have a bunch
of people that I do this with. So I feel like I've just sort of also be that person. It's like,
hey, my whole career I've talked with other people. It's like, hey, I'm doing this. Is
this right? Is this wrong? What is this working with? How's this working? And I feel like I've
provided myself to a certain extent to do the same thing. And I see the benefit of that.
I think other people see the benefit of it too.
Yeah, it's tough. I have learned to ask questions like, what have you tried already?
Yeah, that's a good one.
What do you think you need to try next?
Yeah.
Those are good cop-outs, but they actually work.
They do because it makes them think of like, oh, it's like, have you gone to talk to that person?
It's also sometimes I have no idea. Sometimes I get pulled into solving a problem.
I don't know what's going on. So at least by asking those stalls,
I don't have to go into advice mode right away. And often, I can't tell you how many times I've
had employees come explain a problem to me they were having. And then the process of
explaining it to me go, oh, I got it. Nevermind. Bye.
I've also done, this one works really well. And I like doing it with developers. They'll come to me
and they're like, okay, I need all of this testing. And then I'll stop them and go,
what have you tested already? And they're like, oh, I can go do this. And I could go do that.
And I'm like, okay, great. Let's yeah, let's do that. And they'll go off and do it and come
back and be like, oh, I found some other stuff. I'm like, that's awesome. Let's make sure we're
tracking. So I feel like that. Yeah. Yeah. What, you know, what have you done already is definitely a
great question. And it does seem like, like turning the question into a question. It's like,
you're asking me a question, but I'm going to ask you a question, which is fine.
I think sometimes we just need somebody to help us jog our brains.
Yeah. Yeah. Just give you new things to think about. There's like the really good,
like a really good swimming coach. I'm not a swimmer, so I'm going to make something up here.
Might say, might ask questions like, do you feel like your hands are in the right position?
Like you don't want to change too much at once. Just give them the one question to
think about for the next lap. Right. Like how did that feel?
Those are, so those are like in sports coaching, a good coach just ask questions about what's going
on to try and get someone to think about what's happening. I think it's very applicable to use
things like that in managing knowledge workers as well.
So trick from my therapist, and she's done this several times. She's a somatic therapist.
So it's not only about like what you're saying, but what you're feeling at the time that you're
saying something. So I'll be talking about something and she'll stop me and ask me like
where I'm feeling that. Like how does that feel to say that? Like what is the feeling
that's coming up? So I think it's a very similar thing. Maybe that's a little bit deeper
into it, but the idea that you're kind of thinking about the different connections between
the words and the actions, right? Or the words and the feelings and trying to understand how
those two actually fit together. But we can do that as managers. I think when you have the developer
come to you say, Hey, I found some bugs, right? I found some issues. That's just great. But you
could also ask at that point, it's like, how do you feel about that? They go, it's kind of fun.
And just acknowledging that is a pretty powerful management or leadership tool as well.
Yeah, definitely. That's not something I've done yet, but I think that I
am writing that down right now.
I'm here to help. So one thing the listeners don't know is that Melissa and I chat every other
week anyway. I hired her at Unity and I'm happy to hear of her continued success. So
we check in and make sure things are going well. So one last question, one thing I never tell
someone I'm hiring into a management position. It's one of the things all managers have to learn
at some point and it's nothing short. And the re maybe the reason I don't describe it is not
bait and switch. It's because you just can't know what to expect. So with that lead in for any
aspirational managers out there, this one thing I want you to dig into and share some stories on
for awhile. And that is as a manager, you manage people and sometimes you need to hire people. So
I would like to hear Melissa's adventures and hiring because I'm sure there are some good bits of
information and or stories that we may need to change the names to protect the guilty,
but we'll see what happens. So what's it like? It's always, I don't know how I could prepare you for
it. So I'll just say that. So that's my attempt at an apology. But tell me about what you've learned
hiring and recruiting and that part of the manager's role.
I've learned you need to be really engaged with the recruiter.
Like and early on you said patient. So maybe that comes up here again too.
All right. I'm going to shut up now. Definitely. Definitely patients.
As a manager, one of the first things you need to learn how to do is really engage with a recruiter
and that's a process like learning them, having them learn you, setting expectations.
That's probably the hardest. And I've been through a couple of recruiters now
and everybody's different. It's like every person you hire is different. So
one of the things that some recruiters are really good at making sure that you have a diverse pool.
Some of them are very focused on the technical aspects of what you're looking for. So then you
have to remind them that you want a diverse pool. There's also, you could have a really
diverse pool, really technically sound folks that are interviewing and then your salary ranges
are out of place with the folks that you have in your pool. Like there's all of these aspects
that I didn't really think about when I came in and was like, Oh, I'm going to hire some people.
I'm going to hire the best people I can hire. Well, I have to hire the best talent I can find
and the most objective way for the money I have available. And I think I didn't entirely
understand that equation until I was forced into it and then realize that sometimes you have to,
this really good candidate over here is really expensive and this other really good candidate
is not asking for enough. And it's like, how do you balance all that on top of a
trying to make sure that you're not throwing the baby out with the bathwater when it kind of comes
with different aspects of hiring for women or hiring men or hiring people of color and making
sure that everybody has a fair shake and developing a rubric and standardizing how people
are interviewed. And because I was the team manager that had to hire the most people, I got to
develop all of that as a first time manager for our office because we didn't have it.
It's one of those things, Ash Coleman actually asked her, Tess Bash Brighton, like, what should
I do to make sure I'm hiring the right folks and making sure I'm doing it objectively. And she was
like, you need a rubric. And then I was like, well, how the hell do I do that? And then a very
nice chap that I'm totally forgetting his name sent me a copy of his rubric under penalty.
It's probably a good thing that I don't remember his name, so I'm not going to divulge. He was like,
please don't tell anybody I shared this with you. I was like, okay. But he gave me...
I'm glad I do not have to edit a name out of the podcast.
But he knows who he is. Hopefully he listens. But he's really cool. He sent an example to me
and I took that example and then created our own template. And then everybody in our group
adopted that. And it's really helped, I think, to change it from sort of this gut feeling about
a candidate to something a little bit more objective. It's still objective because everybody
interviews differently. They will ask the same questions, but there's still that individual
perspective on it. So yeah. And then developing a way to measure technical talent in a way that I
thought actually fit the role that people were trying to take on versus some really esoteric
coding test that really didn't fit what we were doing at Unity. So there was that aspect of it,
too. And I think the end result was I got four really qualified people. And I'm very happy with
the team that is no longer going to be my team because I'm developing a new team. But those people
are very talented and they're doing really exceptionally well. And that, I think,
if I point to one success I've had this year was doing that. And I feel like I did the right
things and I hired the right people. And I don't know that I would have been as successful if I
wasn't very brazen about asking all the questions and staying on top of the recruitment. It's like,
hey, do I have all the resumes? Did I look at everything? Why do we have more men in this pool
than women? What is your exclusion? How are you filtering these things? And I probably annoyed
the crap out of a lot of people, but I just asked a lot of questions and just kept at it.
Because I wanted to make sure we hired the right people for the job and hired the right talent
and got talented people in the door that had skill sets and potential for growth and potential
to teach people things and really understood what it would be to be on a team and to also have that
independence and the drive to learn for themselves but also be willing to work in a cooperative. Which
I think is really hard. I think there are some aspects about software development that are still
hanging around that you have to be this hero developer or hero tester. And I really tried
very hard to hire people to squash that. Like, hey, I need you to work independently, but I also
need you to actually cooperate with people too and work in a team. And then I'm pretty confident
that the people I've hired are good at doing both. So that's more than anything. I'm really
happy. Yeah, that's great. I often speak of the need to train recruiters and often what happens
is you just get them where you want them. They move on to some other role and you go, no, I have
to start over again. No. So we just filled the final two openings on my new team. So both of
those people are starting on Monday. So that would be very nice. And then I don't have to
talk to recruiting because I'm not planning on doing any more hiring at all in 2020. And
I feel pretty good about retention across the team. So I think I'm done because it takes a lot
of time, right? Oh, yeah. Like from, I think that's the other really frustrating thing is a lead time
can be anywhere from three to six months to hire somebody. I think other people definitely
underestimate how long it takes because then you have to go through a hire, like recruiting.
So people send resumes all the time, but then they have to go through and kind of manage all of
that. And then you have to work with a recruiter and then they have to have a phone screen. Then
you have to have a phone screen. And then there's the different technical thing aspects of it. And
then onsite interviews. And then if you're interviewing three to five people per job
opening, which should be the minimum, it shouldn't just be like a one shot thing. Then
yeah, that all takes a lot of time and people get really frustrated if it goes too fast or it goes
too slow. And it's like, I get it. Sometimes I get frustrated about that too. And I understand
when it's not easy on either side of that fence, like being the person that's in that hiring
process or being the person that's trying to hire somebody because you want, you just want to do the
right thing. And sometimes the process does not make it easy to do the right thing. Yep. Yeah.
Yep. Fully agree. Well, although we talk all the time, or at least frequently,
it's been great having you on ABT 343. I will post links to your blog and to Twitter.
Anything else I should know about on the internet you'd like people to have a link to?
No. Twitter's good. And the blog is still going. I need to put up a, it's been an adventure. I think
the last time I posted was December. So I need to update my manager year one to manager year two
or something. Oh yeah. You have an update due. Yes, I have an update too. And of course, I
gave up on blogging, but I sort of fell in love with the five links every Friday thing. So I do
that. And sometimes I find some good ones in there. Uh, so yeah, that's my thing. It's not really
blogging. It's more of re what's that called re blogging. It's really, I'm just taking five
things I could have tweeted and putting them into a blog post at the end of the week. Yeah,
but it still works. I retweet that tweet all the time. And I, and I look over those blogs,
I don't read all of them, but I do, I do look them over. So it's, it's worth it. I think, um,
it's one of the things I like to do with my Twitter quite a bit, uh, especially on the technical
side is, you know, somebody blogs something or posts at it. Oh, I'm a, I'm a retweet person for
sure. Cause I think it's cool. Yeah. All right. Well tag me on Twitter and she'll retweet your
tag coverage of reach, reach. All right. Well, thank you. And we'll see you soon.