Welcome to AV testing podcast your modern testing podcast your hosts Alan and
Brent will be here to guide you through topics on testing leadership agile and
anything else that comes to mind now on with the show hey we're back for another
episode of I forgot what's this podcast called something Bart Bart
there's a thing ago when I first met Brent and I was sort of the chief of
staff for this test leadership meeting and Brent would show up there and I would
mess with his name just to see if he was paying attention he loved it he was
Brett Brent Burt Bobby Sue I don't know yeah it's it is a challenge to come up
with something uniquely insulted or insulting with with my first name well I
had a colleague in college by the way this is the AB testing podcast and I'm Alan
and he's some name starts with a B I went to college with a trumpet player named
Doug Burt last name B-E-R-G-T and it was so easy to call him his name was Doug
Burt little flippy flop bug dirt he did not like that name I don't think that's
like there's a lot worse names to call someone right apparently Donald is one
of them as an example yes that is a name that is like nobody's gonna be naming
their kids Donald anymore that's for sure no or Karen Donald and Karen those
names just aren't used anymore yeah yeah the the Karen meme whoo
certainly not in the next six months are we gonna see too many Karen's being born
I think yeah and I think if the Phoenix project takes off like it should no one
will name their kid Brent either because Brent is synonymous with bottleneck which
is weird because you're not but I'm afraid you're going to be overthrown by
the by the power of media again you you're saying I'm not because you mostly
talked to me right I mean if you should talk to my team I don't know that they
would agree with that statement a matter of fact actually that's one of my biggest
my team's grown in size and we got a bunch of new people on here and and
these are like green horns straight out of college and one of the things I am I
have a couple of them that really struggle with decision-making and
they're like oh well I had this really myopic decision can I set up an hour
meeting with you so we can go through it oh no no you can't no you cannot please
send me please send me a message and I'll look at it yeah what was I gonna say
oh a couple things that reminds me of the topic I wanted to talk about today
but there's I need context so we are live-streaming once again and once
again last-minute apologies I we were not going to live stream this one because we
hit we're going until about 15 minutes ago going to have a guest on the show
and I did not want to subject them to that madness however that changed I
won't give away the guest it's gonna be fantastic but they had to reschedule at
the last minutes just Brent and I and I think we came up with a pretty good
agenda on the fly as we usually do I am super excited about the guests but we are
live-streaming and it's last minute the next time we live stream I promise I
will try I promise that I will try to get an announcement up in our slack
group which you can join if it's called one of the three dot slack calm there's
an invitation link on the podcast website and probably the easiest way to
get there is to go to modern testing org where you can read the modern
testing principles and yeah yeah yeah so all that intro to episode 126 I believe
aside my calendar so the corona calendar bump as I call it was just beginning to
subside and then as I mentioned last time on the podcast my org is growing adding
some additional technical program managers not product managers Brent
program managers to my org also I have added so we merged a big parts of two
parts of unity together I have added additional DevOps engineers to my role
essentially doubling the size of that team I have expanded the size of my
documentation team that's about doubled as well and I've added a few other odds
and ends to my org in fact longtime listeners of the podcast will know that
four or five abt 343 ago I had Melissa Eden on the recording talking about what
she's doing at unity I originally hired her to work for me on my team when I was
director of QA for services and when I moved away she moved to another dev
director did some really great things and part of this reorg is I get her
back oh the long-term plan is there so Melissa so Melissa works for me again
she is already kicking butt super excited so my org is a little bigger and then
also because I manage the matrix and my boss came up with a good description for
what I do that I don't think I've shared before but it stuck with me I run the
engineering operating system so if you think of engineering as an OS that it's
like all of the I make all the systems go Brent does not like that no no no no
if you're on the podcast you won't know this but Brent doesn't like that but it
but it actually makes sense what do you mean I don't like that you made a face
like I can tell when you're making a face because normally you're like this
level ugly and you were like a new level I go oh Brent taking it taking it
to 11 so because I'll to comment on that in a minute but the point was
because of that and going back to your schedule time with you so many meetings
my calendar has because people want to go I need to touch me every single new
lead in the org hey I need to know how things work can we have some time
together and I go sigh yes here's some pre-reading because I've already
documented everything you're gonna ask but the introduction and the face time
is good so I am meeting with a lot of people across the org which is good I'm
not complaining too much about it I'm not complaining about the people I love
talking to the people it helps get things done what I'm complaining about is the
45 hours of week 45 hours a week I have in meetings for the next three weeks yeah
no tell me about your face it everything you just said said kind of
aligns if you are you know director of the engineering OS you're essentially the
chief cat herder actually yes I'm I'm sometimes I call myself chief nagging
officer yeah I like that the CNO I just try and I try and help people make good
yeah it's it's very much a process problem when a lot of those regards it's
it's I actually think cat herder is a great how do you how do you enable the
right amount of autonomy because as we know command and control sucks you are
you are absolutely in a position to evoke all kinds of evil with respect to command
and control absolutely I actually am one of the few people in the entire org me
and the people that run our SRE business or SRE operations who actually can carry
a process hammer and I am very careful in where I you find nails and hammer
them yeah yeah the thing I the thing I mean the thing I like about you being in
that role is is you know the responsibility and you know that if I if
you could get business converged autonomy down at the root level you're gonna
you're gonna create an environment of awesome however as you call out you can't
be afraid to to use command and control not liberally what's the opposite
carefully I wouldn't call a command and control it's adding just enough process
it's putting up some bumper rails where he needed so teams can stumble towards
success right and as long as you are kind of reminds me of a story so back in
the day I was in Boy Scouts and I was trying to get the bicycling merit badge
and in the bicycling merit badge you had to do a bunch of really long bicycle
trips and the last one was a 50-mile trip my dad joined me on that trip and how
he joined me is he followed 10 feet behind me in his car beeping every time I
slowed down if the hill was to did that help help it it was motivational
it did not inspire me to ever want to do another 50-mile trip as a as a teenager
but I did get to the goal right so there's motivation is a is a careful
thing yeah you can use it to get to a goal but how do you get it how do you
use it so that the next goal achievement is easier it doesn't scale if
the the virtual father has to follow behind in the car for every person
taking a bike trip right I could talk about the New York the whole episode and
we'll we won't we'll only talk about it for half or maybe I'll say five minutes
and then I'll expand to 15 one thing is that up until now and we'll have this
continually we've had these program managers embedded in the teams and I
have all but one or two of those will actually stay there and help their teams
but they haven't thought about how to scale that across the org so that's
gonna be it'll be interesting to sort of dotted line manage that group so it's
kind of it's a little bit like my old org where I will have some there are
some PM's that will be embedded in the teams they work with which I think is
the right thing for that for sort of a senior level technical glue role but
I think it will also be good to use that group to begin to figure out what are
those bumper rails those lightweight processes we need and what are the
fewest we need to actually be most efficient so I'm looking forward to that
but I will learn more about that as we go one of the PM is reporting to me is
very much in the the data he loves data and analysis and knows all the cool
Excel tools reminds me of you Brent a little bit and I gave him all of my
project-level data on delivery rates and he did a bunch of analysis and came
back with this gradient gradient color-coded chart showing me the projects
that were more than two standard deviations away from the norm as far as
delivery and I said yep those are our three problem projects so no surprise is
there but instead of anecdotally observation observation based anecdotes it
was data-based solution so I think while that one was not insightful I'm
confident that he is going to help find insights in the way we deliver across
the org because we're moving now to a stage where you know up until a week or
two ago we have 60 60 ish projects in flight across the organization things that
are actively being worked on that was a little customer value we are rapidly
getting to a stage we're going to have nearly a hundred different projects in
flight across the larger organization that can have customer value those things
ranging from two-week experiments to sometimes three-month projects to deliver
a whole new SDK or functionality to a customer so getting some consistency in
how we track those things and how we how we improve based on how we deliver
those things is going to be fun yeah it's gonna be interesting to hear that
that journey right I don't know of any team that has tried to take the journey
to that scope and has done so without heavily leveraging command and control
and in shame of it and that that hopefully is just due to a culture at
the company that is now dead yeah that's the opposite of our culture so I would
be very surprised if we got there so the I think the bigger worry from our
leadership is that we don't add enough process to keep things under control but
that we but also that we retain autonomy I'm about to make a decision
one of my few process hammers we have one part of the organization we can make
it here right now on the podcast what are we making your decision oh no I've
made it oh okay I've actually made the decision it's actually one of the few
times I'm going to imagine a functional team that split across three team leads
so imagine with the team being roughly two pizza size imagine that three of
those teams together actually work on a big part of the project you with me so
far so imagine three teams of six to eight dead who are all part of a larger
team a larger okay delivering like say they're delivering they're delivering
fruit their project is fruit and there's the banana team lead and the
apple team lead and the orange team lead this is horrible metaphor but that's
they're all part of delivering fruit now imagine that they all use completely
different project management tools and completely different project management
techniques okay so far not hard to imagine oh well now imagine me coming oh
you know what I know I'm gonna piss all of you off at once in the in the sake
of a greater good and have you all use the same project management tool so you
can work better with product so you can't we have a better chance of doing
what's going on so I can help you more and it's one that none of you are using
right now so you are gonna feel the pain and I'm gonna help you through the
pain and we just have to do it and they're gonna cry and they're gonna
complain but we're gonna do it anyway and within a month they're gonna be
happy yeah it's I've it reminds me of a similar strategy I've taken before
right it's essentially instead of having them fight amongst themselves over
who has the greater tool you basically come in you've defined it and now
temporarily they are unified as a singular team on hating Alan in his
dictatorial that's exactly and then right once once they align on hating me
they'll have a better chance of aligning generally going forward I'm happy to be
the first thing their hatred towards me in this case I'm happy to be if that's
the first thing they align on great because that means they can align and
they can rally around that a hundred percent on the same page that a hundred
percent the the other thing too I mean I've shared this on a podcast right
there is a there is a phrase I rarely use well I don't know if it's rare I
probably pull it out of my back pocket now once a quarter and and the phrase is
and I think you could imagine all sorts of places to use this but the phrase is
hey guys here's one one place where I want to take an opportunity to remind
everybody that I work really hard to make this team appear to be a democracy
watching Alan Parse I'm gonna pull that one out I like that that that goes from
your back pocket into my back pocket thank you for the love I think it's they
they stop pause wait a minute he works really hard to make it appear but he's
implying if you can hear you can you can almost hear the gears like oh right
right so every now and again you I find that I have to reassert that ultimately
I'm accountable in the way I've decided to to make decisions is to push decisions
down as much as possible yeah however and and I do try to work hard to such that
people forget that I have veto power but every now and again I need to pull it out
because we're in the weeds it's not a sort of reminder of everybody that that
I'm still the guy in charge I could give a shit about that it's just oh my
god you are so much in the weeds it's gonna take three months for you guys to
figure out how to get out of the weeds turns out I have a weed whacker we're
going we're going in this direction so it's interesting you brought that up
with whatever you said a moment ago about them being the decision makers as
I've added 15 people to my org I've met with them all individually by now at
least once as well as in some team settings and one of the things that I
continue to iterate because anytime there's a move like this there's some
thud some fear uncertainty and doubt that comes with it so I reiterate my
style is I and one of the things I've said to everyone is I believe decisions
are best made by the person closest to the work so I am rarely if ever probably
never going to jump in and make a decision for you I can help you
brainstorm that decision I can help facilitate a discussion around the
decision those things I'm good at but I'm not gonna make those I was talking
to one of the new DevOps engineers yesterday and just talking you I'm so
glad you're not a micromanager and I'll work that way it sounds like you're a
lot like my last manager say great I said and I want you to know just for full
transparency we may have a discussion sometimes it gets into like a solution
or a tool or how something we could do and it is not never going to me telling
you what to do or telling you what decision to make it is purely me getting
excited and living vicariously through your work since I don't get to do that
anymore that moment where you've you've gone you're what is it the the seventh
stage of of grief right where you're no longer in denial you're I have acceptance
you're like yep I don't do things anymore but I still have this need okay let me
try to do vicariously yeah that's all I can do at this point given the the
variety of projects of functions of disciplines I'm managing across the team
and by the way for the people in the livecast I changed the view from speaker
view to showing both of us at once so you can see when Brent makes faces when I
talk but if you prefer the other view let me know should we wait the 20
seconds whatever I'll glance over it chat once in a while there was a really
good comment someone said oh man I missed the first 15 minutes and then before I
could type anything in perzy reminded them that nothing good happens in the
first 15 minutes anyway it's it's the Brent and Alan BS show one other thing I
was going to mention about the new org to see if I can remember one interesting
thing happened is one of my oh actually this is something worth talking about
because this isn't optimal but I think I'll make it work at least for the
medium term in this merge I have gained a DevOps team and I've gained a
documentation team which means I have two documentation leads with teams and
two DevOps teams with leads and some various other ICs right now I have too
many direct reports I want to flatten that a little bit but I've always been
hesitant of having two you mean unflattened it right you have too many
direct I want to unflatten it a little bit yes I knew what I meant damn it so
the challenge for me is I want to get past the their org versus our org stuff
even though right now functionally I have leads from my old org and leads for
the new org coming in so I do have plans and everyone is on board on
learning to on getting a stage where they can learn from each other and begin
to share work across them but I need to consciously start to blend them into one
kind of like the Brady Bunch I need to spend time making sure I can blend them
into one team and I don't stay into the X org and the Y org over time so
that's something I'm working on but probably something I'll come up that
there's no immediate problem I just always avoided having it's not a great
way to do a merger in this case I think it makes sense for the short term I have
to figure out how to it's top of mind on my challenges as far as bringing the org
together yeah I don't have enough business so it's like the way you've
described it so far so far right unless there's a sort of a red thread that
ties everyone together team identity is absolutely gonna be critical and is is
the way you've described it's gonna be hard yes and there's another challenge
that I'm gonna crowdsource to the three and to you but to the three indirectly
through you is I didn't worry about having a team identity when I had my
team of eight DevOps or yeah eight DevOps and three doc writers three or
four doc writers sorry I should know one two three three doc three and a half
doc writers ones on loan and a few other random ICs it's I never worried about
describing what the identity or role of my team was it's very much in the even
with DevOps is very much still been accelerating the achievable quality and
also I have docs because they have a huge impact on the customer perception
equality and stories there one of the things I want to crowdsource to the team
especially now since I have you know eight people in Docs and 15 or 16
people in DevOps and and six other ICs working on various quality and PM
initiatives is what does my team do what should I call my team right now in
Slack it's called Allen team and I don't like that I want to find a name for my
team and the best I've come up with so far which is which is the wrong name but
I'm hoping by being by it being so wrong that people will come up with better
answers is org name dash glue yeah yeah I'm actually thinking of
yeah I don't have I mean I have a name for you it's not a good name
I don't think is gonna fly if you know it we can work through the acronym right
and go if it were over here right the first letter would be Azure so that you
mean yes yes right Azure oh are they oh wait wait wait can I help with this so
can the next version of Windows be Azure operating system for business net Azure
Azure operating system Azure operate as your OS for business is the new name
for Windows you heard it here first announcement yeah so you forgot power
right would need to be the power of your operating system for business as your
powered OS for business no power the power of Azure OS for business net got it
anyway yeah it's not it's not a functional name but essentially I'm thinking about
our friends comment so many years ago and have you put yourself into another
position where you run the everything else org have I lost you no no no cuz is
this thing on while true I can actually say that no one sees it that way okay well
that's good that's good but on you know for better or for worse people still see
because of title only and the way I run projects and the engineering operating
system it's Alan's program management org which is not right at all either so my
org is the majority of our org is DevOps our customer for DevOps and for
all the rest of my org except for documentation is to enable our internal
teams to kick ass and deliver quickly and safely to customers when I add
documentation to the mix and again I fully believe it fits because we've made
so many improvements in the customer perception of quality by improving and
adding documentation even in the eight months I've been running that org that
it really fits a lot with quality and there are some people that remember that
I have an extensive quality background and so they say oh Alan's quality team
but I really don't really have one of those either but I'm still like what
do you got what do you got how would we and then so I got one versus the
remainder yeah the actually yeah the remainder is what I was trying to do I
know but I couldn't page load it the way you just described like first off
I'm like you know what injury engineering operating system you know EOS
sounds would be kind of cool you run the EOS team right because no one's heard of
that before but then it's probably not inclusive enough of everyone in your
organization right if your documentation team is their output is is intended to
go straight to the customer right not not to both directions we do have some
internal docs they work on as well that helps out marketing sales etc but yeah
largely to the customer but what about the quality operating system right the
problem is is that acronym is QOS yeah that's already taken and the the Q word
what I think they may get it in this org I yeah that would be internal yeah
the Q word I worry a little bit about about pigeonholing I gotta tell you
yesterday on Twitter I thought it was funny someone mentioned and this is fine
I wrote this in an article 15 years ago as well but that you shouldn't blame bugs
on testing literally 15 years ago I go dig out the article where I talked about
the one that got away article for sticky minds and you know blaming bugs on
testing is does it work it's a whole team thing someone was commenting about
that yet again very adamant about it lots of threads on yes tough this is
ridiculous it's hurtful and yeah I totally agree but what it made me think
of wasn't and of course the tangents are here is I actually ask that all the time
now why did why did we miss this in testing but I'm not blaming it I'm not
blaming anyone I'm trying to get to the root cause of why we let a failure get
to production so what I'm digging in with a team on who developed and tested
their own code and I made some comments that said I still say this but you know
I say it's all the time the difference in context is that my the team I'm talking
to is a team that developed the code as well as tested it and people which I
thought was interesting and insightful it talks about how things are changing
and boy did I got busy because of my 45 hours of meetings a week and came back
and people were all up in arms like the author's the author the original
people like you don't know my context it's like that's great and and it's an
anti-nice guy I know him and I like him but apparently I triggered the hell out
of him and then people jumped on the the whole we were getting rid of testers
thing and I thought oh god I did not mean to trigger this I just wanted to
talk about this is interesting is this thing that I used to be just as adamant
about I have a different view on because the way I run engineering
systems now and people just it was a I didn't realize it was a massively
triggering tweet for a lot of people and I apologized to everyone I offended I
stand behind my words this stuff works for me it doesn't mean it works for you
because I never said that I'll edit that out but just pisses me off anyway
what were we talking about yeah I'm ignoring you know I'm trying to find it
the Twitter's right the so already proposes I could just be release
management but I think that's there's something to that it is there's
something around how we release I think release management has some other
connotations yeah I don't like the word management in there right it I don't
like that right it's essentially it evokes essentially Alan is the the chief
bureaucrat in charge well in a way I am it could be release and engineering
operations speed wagon so you could be a real speed wagon I'm just throwing shit
out there yeah you know you get a good idea Brent right you know a lot of ideas
and throw the bad ones away but a very good idea on a different tangent is the
idea of calling the operating system Azure warp speed or AWS for short because
that one's a winner what were you talking about after you were going me I
was making random comments after I was ignoring you I started making random
comments around release management I mean that was like 30 seconds ago though I
don't think your memory has gotten that bad no it hasn't Bert the base off of
this I mean I like I current I mean it's not entirely inclusive right what you
could do is just throw together a bunch of ideas get your leaders in a room and
say hey I want something I want like I wouldn't crowdsource this with me in the
three I would crowdsource this yeah that meetings already on the calendar for
next week but I want to try and get some of the and again one of my
techniques for getting ideas out of people is to give them all of the bad
ideas to start with because then they will try and improve on those and
actually get somewhere so I'm what I'm looking for from the three is here are
all the things that won't work perzy asked like how is different from SRE or
site reliability engineering and they are on the tail end for us at least and
I think generally SRE are looking at things after they're deployed and I am
trying to make sure like if I do my job really well SRE's job is easier
because there's fewer incidents and fewer oddities or operational surprises
coming their way anyway yeah I definitely have a leads meeting next week to go
over this where we'll come to a conclusion and present that to the team
the following week that's my so I put a deadline in place it makes sense anyway
do you want to that's my org we'll hear more about that in the Alan talks about
unity section of the podcast which will continue but we also oh we're out of
time no we got the time go we have a mailbag question which is definitely
worth unpacking and talking about can you wait do you know how to read I do you
read the question so I could listen to it again because I ignored you last time
you're at a chimney except for the one part I liked
folks this is from who and who I whose name I presume is not Kristoff had us
right he's got an accent mark over the s I have no clue what that means in any
language let alone his so I apologize for that no that's yeah I think I think
that's legit I'm sure it's legit I just don't know what it means in terms of how
I'm supposed to think it's a change or a something like that anyway Kristoff we
apologize but we're gonna go over your question yes hey folks I have a question
about deployments and creating an adaptive culture I hope it's the right
place to ask yes it is it absolutely is having pre-read it we have a mobile app
and are doing loads of experiments we're also a seasonal business so of course it's
essential that we release fast and often currently we do weekly releases
regressions take a day multiple teams contribute to that repo and if we release
a bug our rollback time is also crap due to review time on stores I assume app
stores in that case we have got some automation working on doing less manually
but because of how long it takes to restore the previous version we won't be
able to be more adaptive and move really fast we moved away from agile
testing framework and doing a variation of modern testing it's and seems like not
having continuous deployment is holding us back and keeps us working in a
predictive manner any tips on what to try out so let me try and paraphrase for
understanding so for clarification it's how do we do the lean things that you
and I preach so much in a mobile app where your release process is limited by
the time it takes to get to submit and get feedback and get approved from the
the app stores for Apple and Android that that inherently that's a bottleneck
how do you work around that bottleneck in the system yeah I think that's a good
summation I mean there's a couple one thing that I think is an interesting
question is or statement rather is we moved away from the agile testing
framework and doing a variation of modern testing that let's dive into that
first before we go into solution mode so I'd actually like to understand more
what that means because I consider you know the the modern testing principles to
be you know maybe an evolution or maybe an adjunct to agile testing it's you know
we care more we I guess the only differences are we have a an emphasis on
data which is not in agile testing is defined by defined by Lisa and Janet
and that may be it we may emphasize coaching and consulting a little bit more
but I don't I don't think that much but it's not that much different so maybe
it's just more lean than agile because you and I talk about lean so much and so
much of our modern testing principles are stolen many more of those are stolen
from the lean startup than they are from the agile testing book but both are
influences no so one of the things that's interesting and we've talked
about this in the past when we were forming up modern or MTP right the like
they moved away from the agile testing framework and doing a variation of
modern testing the implication there is Christoph has a a feeling that that
modern testing is a replacement framework right it like implies sort of tactics
and steps and you know a criteria by which you can evaluate whether or not you
are successfully deployed modern testing and I have no doubt that right I do
think modern testing has gotten to the point where it's absolutely bigger than
us and not not controllable by us anymore so I have no doubt that there
may be a belief around hey there's a tactical framework and a progression you
can take you know when I think about it you're right data coaching the other one
though principle seven right principle seven could easily be interpreted as
moving towards unified engineering oh yes there's that one too I forget about
that because it just happened so naturally for me yeah I would say if
there's anything that's a modern testing framework call is sort of a be
hyper cynical hyper that's cynical critical hyper critical on your need for
test specialists right you probably don't need them the way you think you do that
is to loop back to our previous topic quickly and jump back on this is not
reporting to me but we do have some dedicated QA in my overall new
organization and I met with the dev lead in charge of that organization and they
not in so many words asked me if I was going to get rid of their QA team and
that answer is basically what I gave them I said there's no my charter is
never to get rid of QA my charter is to make sure teams are as efficient as
they can be in delivering quality software to our customers and sometimes
maybe frequently or very often in my past sometimes that means QA move into
different roles that help optimize and accelerate the achievement of quality
better so interesting you brought that up because that conversation came up as
well this week in my so so what's the real answer the real answer is probably
god I hope they don't listen to this podcast but they do the real answer is I
expect at some point that team again I have dissolved so many test teams without
laying off a single person I want to be that clear I don't know testers I work
to make sure you find a role where you can be most effective in what you're best
at so I imagine that will probably happen with those people in the org
they'll move into various DevOps and development and maybe quality consulting
roles yeah that that's I can't imagine that not happening in an org that I'm
in charge of so I know the thing is but you have to disappoint people at a level
they can absorb and I can't it whatever you do a reorg you have to let things
keep going more or less as they're going for a little while and then boil
the frog in the direction you want to go in but again going back to principle
seven is and we're way off tangent on this on this topic but it isn't that
you get rid of the testers and like this Yahoo article and just taking away
the safety net it's you may get to a point where you realize you don't need
dedicated testers anymore and I like to try and help teams get there yeah it was
interesting because so the reason why I asked that question is as you laid it
out I'm like okay let's imagine I'm in Alan shoes and this question came to me
and I realized I don't know that I would have been as smooth as you were in terms
of responding but I knew the answer almost instantly right it like the way
the question was posed the fact that it's a concern says to me there is an
extremely high chance that there is now an in-place safety net that needs to
be worked through yeah but but my role requires a high level of emotional
quotient and leading people on a journey to get where I want them to go agreed
agreed so back to the question back to the question so tips to try out what
what's what's your tips so what I would do have done would do is one way to get
around because this this app store turnaround is real especially when when
one or more of the app stores sort of have moving goalposts I shouldn't say
sort of the goalposts on what it takes to have your app approved and deployed are
moving so sometimes almost the identical app that was approved last week cannot
get approved this week so the way around that of course is to do have
remote configuration and fig fig your flags feature flags in your app so you
can take a bug fix or a new feature that you think is correct and you can even
deploy with the feature flag turned on and the app at startup of course it
would require again you're stuck if your app doesn't is an offline app and
doesn't require network access you can't do this but ideally when your app
starts up it can look at a server see what flags should be turned on or off
and do its thing and then if you need to roll back all you do is flip a flag on the
server that feature is turned off and you can continue you can you know tweak
it for the next release but you're not breaking anybody in the in the short term
you have I think you have likely far more experience with dealing with app
stores than I do I have a question for you yeah maybe there's a lingo so
there's two kind of deployment models or update models I see with app stores right
there's the one where an app detects the local version of the app detects that
there's a bit of update in the app store and redirects you to the app store to do
that update right that process obviously requires you to go through the the app
store gauntlet to get an update rolled out right but then there's the other
model where I see sort of a an app deploys and it's sort of a Chrome around
the app but doing say business logic updates or you know UI changes where the
Chrome is is consistent but the app itself updates from within itself yeah yeah
I could see that I don't know how I haven't done that before and that's a
great way to do it but it kind of seems the the app store owners want so much
control over their apps like a massive amount of control of what gets approved
I can't imagine them approving an app that works like that in the first place
without some wheel greasing somewhere so I actually haven't used that model but
it is another great way you could do this and I'm I've seen a lot of apps I
don't know how they get those approved and what the agreement is with the app
stores where they can do that but that's a that's a really an ingenious idea and
I've idea and of course you can download definitely download additional
assets or or some updates outside of the app store so I guess my advice is
look into ways you can work around the app store requirements because what you
want to do in the theory of constraints is identify your biggest bottleneck hey
our biggest bottleneck is the turnaround time and submitting to the app store and
figure out how we mitigate that that bottleneck and one is feature flags but
there may be a deployment option that's actually approvable where you can do some
classification at least of updates outside of the app store process which
would be great but you're right as I think about it a lot more apps should
do this so and for context you know we don't deliver apps we deliver tools with
multiple SDKs people can use to make apps but we have to test that process so
we test it by submitting apps and seeing what Apple and Android's policies are
so we can anticipate those for our customers and give them the right advice
and things to do so my experience there is limited from that perspective but I
am familiar with at least at least of course a feature flags but anyway
there's got to be a couple ways to mitigate that bottleneck that have been
actually tried and proven from an app store perspective look into those like
when I read this and I'm actually reading his responses on the three have
come in this this question came from the select channel and by the way before you
get there the three are awesome because one of the things I look for in a
community is self-sustaining and people ask questions all the time and Brent or
I not only don't need to answer them but rarely if ever is there a case where
the three don't respond better than we could have in the first place so love the
three thank you for being there all three of you go on absolutely love the
three that is just a strong self-supporting community like if you're not
on it get on it it is worth your time and then the other thing I wanted to call
out I haven't listened to the latest 343 but Danny fought damn that dude is
awesome yeah I am so jealous that he's working through the the the wine bird
biography like I mean actually writing the book and all that that's probably
not the thing but the fact that he had enough exposure and talking that he's
he's actually capable of doing that like that historical context I'm absolutely
jealous of Danny on that's just fantastic now going back to Chris
offspring like when I look at this like the very first thing I would want to try
to balance he calls out like they have a problem with rollbacks he has a CICD
right if they don't have CACD because of app store bureaucracy they can still have
CI they can have CI and then deliver to to to some version of a master branch
that's just ready to to roll out the the thing is is the limitation is okay it
rolls out oops we screwed up now he also mentioned it rollbacks are our
painful and so to me this says okay you need to do something to protect master
branch you need to do something to make it a bit more preventative model but the
inability to just sort of do rollbacks which is why feature flags came to mind
right away you need a way to write if you could just that's the fastest way
because if there's a problem and simply restarting the app and getting it to
reread from the remote config it's fixed rollback is is that fast right it what I
would I would look at is how can we make architectural changes to support these
capabilities right a config rollback a like what we just talked about a
business logic like in my mind I've already sort of designed if I were
building an app like this how would I make it such that I could update it
with and a rollback from with it right again we're gonna look at the biggest
pain point which right now is the ability to roll back or handle a
regression in a timely manner for our customers and brainstorm on what are the
ways we can work around these bottlenecks and it's all the things we
just talked about it's like but it needs the team to brainstorm what's
feasible it could be architectural it could be adding a feature flag which is
semi architectural and definitely architectural for changing the nature of
the app where the guts of the app are actually separate from the Chrome that
goes through the app store but then there may be other options as well I'm
sure the internet and Stack Overflow and center are full of ideas but the
team needs to really brainstorm on how to work around the bottlenecks that are
out of there especially when they're out of their control yeah that's you
said it correctly I know what I'm doing I don't everyone knows is that on this
podcast Brent is a smart one but I'm the pretty and entertaining one agreed on
all points all right I hope that that was a good discussion that I hope
continues and I hope and again probably the three answered that better than you
and I did but I did want to call out the transition from agile to modern
testing because that's something we hadn't heard before and worth talking
about then just a sort of and we're not the right people to help brainstorm the
solution for this but we're the right people to through our wrong answers for
you to realize that brainstorming how to work around those bottlenecks is what
should be done the one last thing I'll call out before we sign off is if if
we were wrong and and actually app store isn't the primary cause of the
bottleneck then then one of the things that I have found is that actually
doing a shift to Kanban is really helpful here right because even though
you may not have a CD system Kanban's kind of kid gets that muscle going yeah
well Kanban the best thing about Kanban if you use it right it helps you find
where the bottlenecks are on your system it does but I'm thinking in in
terms of the benefit I gained from it right you essentially if you if you
singly release one ticket you don't have the this sort of this the scrub
impact where all of the bugs get introduced to the product at 11 p.m.
the night before and if you roll out one small batch chunk and everything's on
the floor right it should be easy to roll that back then to build on that yeah
one thing is that I think because of the bottleneck and deployment the team
could very well likely be encouraged to bundle up a bunch of changes so they only
have to submit it once to the app store so you're really as a mobile developer
you really got to find a way to work around that stuff all right all right we
got we got meetings to go to man I got a this is Friday's usually my light day
and it is today I only have six hours of meetings but counting this one this one's
fun though this one doesn't count yeah this one doesn't exhaust me like the rest
of them do all right hey thanks for you guys turning in as and again and and gals
folks y'all once again I promised next time we do a livecast to advertise it
in our slack group a little bit more ahead of time so that people can plan
around it but thanks for listening yeah I know I know and it's been fun
chatting with you burnt I got the name right see you next time
bye all right bye bye