Welcome to AV testing podcast your modern testing podcast your hosts Alan and Brent will be here to guide you through topics on testing
Leadership agile and anything else that comes to mind now on with the show
All right, that was we might leave that in the podcast. I feel good
Happy new year Brent. Happy new year. It is what year is it?
2020 Alan I'm gonna reach across the table
And I will kill you until you're dead
Hey public service announcement PSA. I don't know if you have
Seen this it's all over everything but in in the year
2020 yes, if you are dating anything official
It is advised
For you to
Spell out the entire year
Okay, you have not heard this
No
But I always spell out the whole year because I know people are dumb and we'll get confused or computers are dumb again
And the reason why please tell me why is because it is 2020. Yes, it if you just write 20
someone can play
18 18 or
49 or
Which could have
Depending on what you're dating could have negative consequences
To the date or date or date or the guy writing so is this only on dating apps?
like or everywhere like
like like plenty of fish
Tinder tinder, that's the one I was trying to load
No, so the the feedback is was was specifically first on checks or or contracts
You're who writes checks chronologically. I'm older than you but come on. It's 2020 stop writing checks. I
Wasn't my feedback. That's how I'm passing it on. I am the middleman
Yeah, anyway public service announcement for 2020 that don't write just 20
Okay, great. This is an educational podcast. I didn't get a lot of sleep last night
so either I'm going to have some wonderful rants or
I'm gonna have to edit everything I say because it will not make any sense
Let me see our first
Who was your how was your holiday who was your holiday my holiday was Brad Pitt how was your holiday?
We'll see my holiday was
Honestly fantastic it
The only problem with it. It was probably
three four months too short the
But my son from college came to visit. I learned a fantastic strategy
He's now
21 so it was kind of cool to be sitting
drinking with your oldest kid
but a new strategy was
When he came here, he didn't have an available car. So he had to hang out with his poor parents and
turns out
We did a lot of things that we as a family hadn't done in a long time
We had one day where we just went through our game closet and went board game after board game after board game
That sounds fun. It was fun. I
my
Family is now firmly
Readdicted to Katan. Oh we played that's the one game we played over break over the was it. We put Katan. Yeah, I
Won. Okay, that's it. I'm a winner
and the sea
So I now am out of single-digit children my daughter her birthday's on New Year's Eve
so she turned 10 and
I now have only one
minor aged
children
My my middle son turned 18 last night. God. Oh God God
Help us all. Yes
You I didn't I didn't do much it I just kind of hung out which was great
It was great to sleep in and not have meetings with Europe
I like my meetings with Europe, but it was good to take a break for a little bit
I have a whole crap ton of travel coming up. I'm leaving end of the month like
The week of delivery comp. Sorry Lisa. Sorry Abby. I'll be in
London for
Nine days I come back for like three days and I go to California for a week
And then I come back for a week or two and then I go skiing and whistler vacation
And then I come back for a couple weeks and then I go to Helsinki for a week
And then I come back and I try and keep it all together
Yeah, I may need to apologize to Lisa as well
I have to look at what the schedule is for that delivery comp because I think it's aligned with the three-day weekend
It is you. Oh does Microsoft get that day off? Yeah, okay
Yeah
One thing one difference in unity as I couldn't go whole podcast not talking about it a lot more like regular days off
But I can't imagine I have to look because I can't imagine that they scheduled the whole conference
Overlapping with that weekend. I think it's during the week. No, it's during the week. It's Monday Tuesday
When's I think it's I can't remember now. Okay
anyway, I'm not yet prepared to apologize to Lisa but
Definitely won't be available that Monday. All right, shall we try doing a podcast? No
113 you know at some point in time we should just give up. Yeah, remember you've only done 112. Oh
That's true
So maybe if I get to the next one, okay, you have proposed a topic that is very interesting
Can you please kick it off and let me know how I can help you?
Be successful in sharing this topic and your wonderful insights with our listeners
Yeah, you can start by
Lowering the expectation bar a great deal
So I
Discovered something last week you did and I
Found it surprising and I have this could go anywhere from here. Hold on to your seats folks
Yeah, let me
Before I announce what is in your my hands
Again, this could go anywhere from here
Let me let me read a conclusion paragraph
Very
Quickly, this is a large paper written by
someone that I think every one of our listeners knows at least by name
conclusions
Many members of the testing communities current vision of testing looks a lot like what I learned in school in the
1970s
For example, take a look at the ISE B practitioner syllabus
British community
Yeah citation the 1960s and 1970s were a different time
Programming was linear programs were shorter much shorter. Yeah, they were
1970s
But I remember when the time makes Sinclair with a total of 8k of memory came out
Development was often done by outside companies and even if programming was done in-house testing if it was done with any formality
Was often formed out ideas that worked well for that context don't necessarily stretch well to other contexts
Amen bros
Professional software development has become much more varied XP and test driven development offer a different vision of the relationship
between testers and programmers
Even more traditional projects demand better user interfaces better usability not just pretty screens
with better quarter in better quarter it
Coordination among the staff the larger programs make prioritization
Automation more even more urgent and component based development which allows programmers to sew together large products much more quickly
puts it this
proportionate burden on testing with the parrot
Dime demand her dramatic. Thank you changes in development. We need shifts in testing as well
This paper doesn't spell out all the important shifts, but it does open
Many of the established ideas up for consideration
The tone of this paper has been sharply critical of the traditional ideas
Please understand that I'm writing sharply to make a point
Most of these ideas apply perfectly well in some contexts
What I'm doing here is challenging you to think about the the context you are in
Set aside pre-existing assumptions and think through what craft and culture of testing will actually work best where you are
or
Where you want to become?
now
Alan knows who wrote this
Have you seen this before I?
Well, I mean not before last week, okay, I'll tell you what I think I remember when this paper was published
But based on the author and my experience both reading and interacting with the author of this I dismissed it without reading it
knowing the author and hearing the conclusions
Your thoughts initial thought well, I've your emotional. I've changed my opinion
I have such a sour experience with this person that
That it was hard to read and get past it, but but now that I've skimmed it and you've read
The conclusion to me. I do need to try and change my opinions
I'm not even sure what this person is doing today. I haven't heard from them in years
But this paper is paper is to be clear is from what year right 2004
16 years ago
Dispose a lot of myths definitely saw things like modern testing on the horizon
Definitely was able to see XP for what it was
For how it is an agile techniques agile approaches for how they can improve software quality
whereas some contemporary peers of this author have
made fun of and
Dismissed a lot of things from agile
I think I this is a paraphrase but I've even heard one of his peers
I'll give you the name in a minute
So don't give this away like the surprise of course our three listeners already have read they gave us the paper
So they've heard it. So this is all BS. No, I found the paper. Oh you didn't yeah
I'm the one who posted on select. Okay. Well, they've all they've all read it now
So this is all I can't remember the comment now something like like agile hates testing or something stupid like that
Anyway, my opinion has changed
Good paper interesting
It's hard for me as I read it and skim through it while you're talking
to imagine this author writing this paper, so
Do you want to give it away? Do you have more stuff?
What were your reactions when you read it before you talk about the author more succinctly? I was
pleasantly shocked
And on two fronts number one so my interaction with this with with this author
Has always been indirect right you and I are both
good friends with a
person who used to be a direct co-worker and
This guy's first book and I've talked about it on the podcast
I
Back when I was a traditional test test manager, I
Bought hordes of these books. See there's the difference between you and I even when I first read this book probably in
1999 I thought it was dated and and didn't make and was irrelevant then so I first read the book
95 96, okay, and I was
First moved into test management
You didn't hear the punchline. No the way I use this book is with new hires. I gave them two weeks
to read the book and
because
Testing still wasn't taught in school still really not today
And I what I wanted to do as we all agree testing is a
Critical thinking process. So what I wanted them to do is I wanted to first read the book and in two weeks
our 101
They're going to walk me through know what they picked up from it. Okay, and
When they did that I would give them a new assignment and I would say great now what I want you to do is
Read the book again
They would look at me like are you an ass?
Read the book again, and I want you to come back and tell me every place this book is wrong. So I used
testing computer software by Kim Caner to test
the book testing computer software
by Kim Caner
Because that book came out in 88 it did so in the 16 years
Since writing that book he even went back and the original edition of the book said
Purpose of testing is to find bugs who back and changed that in a later edition
No
He said even worse a test that does not find a bug is a waste of time literal
Edition he did change in later. She did change that but this is
He rebuts most of the points in the book in this paper
Uh, yeah, he calls out a lot of statements that he made that have been made about testing as
myths
He's got a long list of things that we've been still talking about like you and I have said over and over again
Modern testing is not very much about
Testing and is most definitely not modern
Right. This paper was written in 2004 and I see even before we were talking about modern testing even before we
Even before we had a part before we met time. Yeah
Like I didn't know there was a person named Alan Page in 2004
Right how your life has changed since then yes, I find this paper
Fascinating that he even has so I'm thinking we go through I
Just want to just comment further on this one of the the three
Were I may had made a comment around. Oh my god. I see a ton of
Modern testing stuff in here. All right is the primary reason of testifying bugs
No
Right, but then he lists out is it define
defects or maximize bug count or block
Premature product releases help managers ship. This is listed in the paper as things
that
Are typical reasons
but not primary
Maximize technical or minimize technical support costs the next section is something you want to say there
No
Make it make a point man. I'm trying to I know is the main reason
To test to prove the program works correctly
No, right. I find this paper
shocking as I mentioned because it's
Because of where it came from in how old it is
It is very interesting. So I'm gonna I'll give a few comments
But I think it's probably worthwhile to share my chem keener interaction story. Okay
Because despite the fact I like this paper
The way he read we had a we had an email interchange once and it was very interesting
This was probably around the time this paper was
Actually probably exactly around the time this paper was written. So it makes it interesting. It was the time when all
Bach talked about James Bach was
Exploratory testing and how is this special thing if you could do exploratory testing you were a special person
Which is actually called out in this paper says it's not just something experts can do. It's critical thinking
I forget the exact words. Yes, you're used
Anyway, it was it was
Bach was going off all the time about how special it was
so I wrote a blog post something about testing and
I said something to the effect of this could be the exact quote and our teams do exploratory testing and then in parentheses
As I do can I even use that term that way anymore?
Can I even use that term anymore without crediting people or something like that?
Just some just you know a little a little passive-aggressive blurb not
Shouldn't really cause offense
Kim caner emailed me and
Said I don't know. I don't know you or what I've ever done to anger you mr. Weasel
but I find this completely disrespectful and
Blah blah blah and just kind of went off on me and I I swear to God
It was the only phrase was am I allowed to use that word that phrase and he was pissed off
No end, but I think I understand why
this was
when did
Whitaker's tours book come out much later was it later? Yes
Are you sure positive because he and I talked about that book on the soccer field we used to
Place kick the ball around once a week for about an hour and just kind of BS. Okay for it and that
was in
God, you know what as I look back
No, it was later. It wasn't I was in I was
The director in engineering excellence, which I didn't start till 2007
So I think Whitaker's tours book came out in 2008 or 2009, right?
But you remember the name of that book exploratory testing? Yes
But it wasn't out yet. It wasn't even vinegar hadn't even thought of it yet
Yeah, so the thing I know from talking with Whitaker at that point in time. Oh
Oh
Did he piss off a whole bunch of people? I know he's publishing it under that title. He did that book just to piss off people
That was his thing. So anyway, can't it would so it was such an overreaction and
Then later to have our good friend James tell us all kinds of stories about cam
It soured my view of him
But this probably came out and I don't know if I saw when it came out, but it was definitely after
his
odd
Email rant to me. I might have that email somewhere. But so if you if you and I were
far more
Sensitive, I guess that's the best word I can think of if you and I were far more sensitive. I'm very sensitive and
someone
released a set of
Waterfall traditional testing principles under the name of modern testing
We would probably get pissed to you know what though the good the good news is we wouldn't have to because our community
Would go to bat for us because they're awesome
right, right, but if
If we didn't do something then the community may lose
Confidence right we had to lead by example on some of the I don't know. Honestly, I don't think I would
Chalk it. I mean I'm talking up is stupid. I think the thing is is that we're not
sensitive
And I obviously haven't spent enough time inside of your head but in my own
Right. I think a
better idea than modern testing should win
Yes, my whole goal is to continue and push forward
objective
Communication on the topic. I don't care if people disagree
Not not there's a lot of people particularly in a Twitter verse
That are very interested in amping the drama level on modern testing
To 13 and you're like we wanted to be one must win. This is sort of a Highlander and I'm like, yeah
You know what? There was somebody you probably remember this there was somebody this is
Six months ago, maybe longer. Yep someone like tagged Bach it said I'd love to hear your thoughts on the modern testing principles
yeah, and
and of course, I just replied and said to all including James because James and I have a
Is much as we disagree we have sort of a Twitter truce. Yeah, I was gonna say it's a it's an unwritten truce
We have we have sort of a truce going on. Someone just wanted anyway
I replied and said they're not that modern than on about testing, but you're welcome to take a look
I'm still pissed off about the automation paper. Anyway, go on
Yeah, that's one where you were misquoted if I recall correctly. Well, I was misattributed
Yeah
What we see in this paper are a lot of statements around what testers
maybe traditionally were thought of doing and then
Underneath that paragraphs and paragraphs talking about how this really isn't true
Anymore especially or how it really isn't true. Well, so not entirely but you can see
You can see the formation
of
even from from someone who I would say
I would honestly say was a contributor to
Maybe not the Bible but several chapters of the Bible of traditional testing. So for example here
under a section called testers and programmers have
conflicting interests blah blah blah blah blah words then he says
over the longer term
A better approach is often to refuse to play a test group can stick to and publicize its role as the
as the
technical information provider
Right something
Well, we're back to that information testing is information provider, which I don't write but this is dated 2004
I get it. I get it, right?
I don't know where he would be on that topic today and it's something that obviously you and I don't agree with
Should test group work independently of the programmers
No
How many it's interesting because in this section
The way I would interpret the first part of it is he's like maybe but then he closes the whole thing
Being heavily supportive of TDD I
Saw I'm gonna tangent off here because
We could look at how little
The test world has progressed since then in some ways
And we've talked about at least I've talked about looking at where testing is on a cost of innovation curve
There are probably things more modern than modern testing out there in the early adopters
Modern testing is some more out towards the front end of that
there's still people doing the old Microsoft thing of lots of s debts testing the crap out of the code and
There are still people who the independent test team doesn't connect to devs
they write bug reports against requirements and there's a whole bunch of the industry back there and
There are people trying to cross the chasm but doing it in odd ways
I saw a Twitter conversation. I think it was Twitter around
Should testers learn TDD and there are a lot of people are going absolutely
it's the best way for testers to write unit tests and
What what why why are the testers writing unit tests? So tangent reversal to come back to the paper
what I like and
What sets cam apart from his peers is he's non dismissive of new approaches
of software development
What I like is he's Lee looked at XP and looked at some things from agile and said, you know applied
Proper critical thinking and figured out how those could benefit testing and software quality, which is fantastic
Whereas some of his contemporaries
Have dismissed those things
So I give him full props for that for actually learning and growing and not digging his heels in on
the things that are
more relevant to him and I wonder if
You know, this was maybe some of the basis of the I can't remember when the bok and caner fallout happened
But it might have been around here. I don't know it doesn't matter. I could have been for completely different reasons
Go on what other things would like to highlight from this paper
I'm gonna need now remember to put a link to this paper
Damn show notes and I will most likely forget
Luckily, it's already in the selection or you can use your favorite search engine to look for it. What's it called?
Now the best way to do it the ongoing revolution in software testing. There we go. No link needed. I
Think there's a lot of interesting quotes in here. For example, the one I just highlighted
Remarkably many testers still push the traditional waterfall method. I don't understand why
Right they in a big part of this to me
Just quite honestly
Number one. I do not understand
how this paper has escaped my notice until literally just a few weeks ago and
Although when this paper came out
No, I think I was in Bing by that time. Yeah, I'm trying to judge which when this paper came out
Which side of the the agile fence I was on I was no that was early. I was still in Windows CE
I joined
engineering excellence in 2005 no, yes
2005 I did a little 10-year recap at the end of the year blog post and I realized that 10 years ago
I was still in engineering excellence
Holy crap times have changed
Don't want to go back to your statement because it reminds me
I'm gonna reiterate a rant that I've done before on this podcast is I
Don't understand there are testers that not only they may not say they embrace waterfall
But they love being isolated from development
They sit and they write their freakin selenium tests all day long and they feel like that's doing a good thing for the product
Holy crap, that's wrong. Anyway, go on. Here's another section. I enjoy
It's somewhat relevant
James Buck and I have been working with exploratory testing throughout our careers. I coined the phrase in 1984
published it in
His book with a strong recommendation that testers should run exploratory tests in every cycle of testing since then
I've come to realize that in practice
Good tests explore all the or good testers explore all of the time
more more more more more words
Be willing to change what you do to follow up what you're seeing as a test is the mark of a thoughtful
Tester and the thing I think is the most important
thing and I think this paper shows that cam was was
living by that mantra is
You have to be willing to learn have to be willing to a be thoughtful and evaluate the best way to go
to be from a and show a willingness to change and I think that's a
Also an underlying I don't want to take this and blow it up too big
But I think it's an important theme even in modern testing
the the whole point of of this is
is
times
change
value propositions change skill sets get automated hell I
Don't know if I've yet set it on the podcast
But I've already at a point where I truly believe
that we're at the beginning of the end of the of
the the the fad portion of data science
Where we get a big large book of people coming in
And everyone's trying to ramp up
my son
just finished an initial part of
Going through and applying to schools and he's keenly interested in
Pursuing data science. Can you guess why?
well
Probably not because his dad does data science, but there are lots of jobs for data scientists
No, it's actually you had that a hundred percent backwards. Oh
100% he wants to do what dad does because dad looks fun what he wants what he wants to do
It's even less thoughtless than that. It's what he wants is
To maintain his center to living and he knows
That if he gets a job with the same title as dad
He doesn't even know what the damn job is. Okay. Oh, yes. No dad makes coin
Yeah, maybe he knows where we're an upper middle-class family and
He he knows that that amount of money is enough to he's also very
analytically aligned
So he's very he's a very matic hit but I sat down with him. I'm like, you know what? I don't think you should do that
I think actually
computer science is a much better way to go and
and
Look for a school that will offer a minimum of a minor or at least a computer science curriculum is a data science one
Yesterday I had a mentee
Another mentee one of my employees
He came in
He has his PhD in operations research
and one of the
Things he brought up. He's only been here five months and he's
He realized that in this environment
He's not as autonomous as he'd like and that's because he doesn't have the coding background and he said hey as a PhD
I've already looked up at UW and I realize
I could get in
for a
Master's program in
Computer science with very little friction. He's already got his PhD. They're not gonna ask him for GMAT or GRE
or any of that crap and
He and I looked at the curriculum in the master's program at UW
I would say a good 40% are
Not only data science classes
but
specific ones
All right. They have a whole course on NLP
Which is not something you would tradition are do it traditionally see from a computer science course. No, that's interesting. Yeah
So I think actually the next set of developers
Coming out of college five years from now
They're gonna be the dominant workforce good and they're gonna be excellent at modern testing principle number five six
Yeah, yeah. Yeah. Hey, so there's one point
And just to show how this is
2004 just to show how relevant this is there's a section on
The statement is we can measure the individual effectiveness
Effectiveness of testers by counting how many bugs they enter which is interesting because he
He gives a example. We've probably given on this podcast before there's two testers one finds a hundred bugs one finds ten bugs
Which one is better? It says whoa, whoa slow down there
What if the person that finds ten bugs is working with developers to?
Make sure they're writing more testable code and finding and things as to get reported
Which is a statement we've made for probably since the second episode of this podcast. What's interesting is here we are
16 years later and
Ministry of tests had a post two weeks ago where they asked how do you measure?
How do you measure how well your test teams doing and someone I thought it was a troll but they were serious
Or maybe they were a really good troll. I can't remember now
Said well if I have two testers, I it should be like sales
I keep the one that finds the most bugs and show the other one the door and
luckily there were
there were and
way more people
Disagreeing with this person in this conversation then we're going. Yeah, that's the way it should be so we're kind of past that but
It's weird that those things come up and I bet
I
Bet there are teams where bug counts are bug quotas are the thing
I had a bug quota when I started at Microsoft 1995. I've told this story before I was expected to find ten bugs a week and
What I would do then the behavior that drove was I found I found always like 14 every week
Because I like to overachieve a little but some weeks I'd find 20
But I keep those extra six in my back pocket for the next week because I didn't know if my well was gonna dry up
You get what you measure, right?
Yeah, never a good idea, but oh my god does that bring back man
I was making 20 bucks an hour man. I was loving life. I did exactly the same strategy you did
except
Whatever their min bar goal. I made sure I always doubled it on a weekly basis and
Man, did they get bugs?
Right, I would one of the great ways for me to fulfill my quota is go look for grammar mistakes in the help documentation
Yeah, oh, yeah, you're missing a comma
You need a comma. I'm like, oh my god
Let's bring this forward to 2020 in the conversation I had last week with a non Microsoft non-unity employee. We're talking about
Metrics is what do you measure and I mentioned the accelerator metrics and the question was I forget it was a word
I haven't probably heard since I read Caner's book maybe before
He asked what's your defect?
Insertion rate or something creation rate defect creation rate you posted this later
I did because and I and my answer was I can create a bug in Jira and under five minutes. What do you mean?
Because you know how many bugs come in? I was like, oh, I don't know because we don't
We don't really track bugs
We just fix them as they happen. We have one we except for one exception
We have a slow trickle of bugs that comes in through our enterprise support
We have for our organization that we enter usually their SDK things and usually only a half dozen working out at once
And they're usually done within two weeks
So but that's it. So I don't know how to count
defect creation rate
But the fact that that was suggested made me think oh my god
This is still counting bugs as a metric is still a thing people care about
I don't honor even understand the
For quality even even in a lot of like you and I talked about it
I don't know recently and I even remember it was on the podcast. We it was a conversation around incident rate. I
and my board
Using Kanban, right? I I call bugs forms. I don't have a bug database
Right the the naming of the way they asked you what's your bug creation rate? Right in like
How fast do your devs create bugs?
Right, which is I believe where it's coming from not how fast do people file bugs and
The way I think of it now particularly with a Kanban system is I go, okay
What is my what's the rate of my inbound queue?
And am I burning that down am I making it harder to to?
Construct customer impacting issues that we call them swarm tickets in my team
Yep, I've I've I have seen your concept of Kanban boards know what the swarm swim lane is for. Yes
We hate that board. We hate that lane because it's the only thing that interrupts us
As it should as it should and so that puts a focus on
reducing the interruptions
It's interesting
That person's question if he had asked me I would have used it to shift it from the traditional
bullshit
Way of thinking to oh, I think you mean this and I probably would have even played dumb
In just
Conversation was around I was brainstorming outsource like here are the things I
Here's what I measure
accelerate metrics some of the
Server health metrics who thinks I watch and care about so what else to think I should do it this came up
And then they just started telling me a bunch of things. I should do not things I should measure which was weird
Anyway, but you know, that's common. It's kind of it's depressingly common actually
Yeah, I asked for one thing got another anyway in talking about this this paper will recommend and read
We should do our next book report or at least worth half a podcast and talking about is
Did you read the latest state of DevOps report? This is the one put together by Nicole Forsgren and gang
It's based on a large amount of survey and some interpretation
One of the interpretations they know I've read one. I don't know if it's the latest when it come out months ago
Two months ago, no probably not two months ago three months ago not that long ago
But anyway, I'll send you a link and I'll remember to put one in the damn show notes. I'm gonna suck
One of the things that was interesting is I use those a lot and I'm preparing
I'm at this presentation I put together and I'm presenting the accelerate metrics because I know they've been studied and I can use those
too I
Can use the research to make add some validity to the numbers
But you need you want to bootstrap with something that's credible and then you'll you'll add you and I have other flavored ad but anyway
One thing they've done in that paper Nicole and I don't I think she did most to work on it is
Sort of maturity modeled although Nicole hates maturity models. Maybe even more than I do
the metrics like the accelerate metrics like where you should be on things and
There's good news and bad news and I'll forget the number so I won't quote them is
My team my organization is at the elite level in everything
We're not good enough
that those
The elite level is very lenient
the one the one I thought would be close on is the
failure rate so I looked at
incidents or issues that happen in production per deployment and it says one to five percent and I look and we're
Way under one percent. So which I think is still a lot
If you're at one percent one of every hundred deployments causes something bad to happen. That's horrible
No, so therein lies an opportunity
We can have a whole podcast about I just I was just thinking about that because it's this
segue into
2019 set of DevOps so 20 sorry 2004 to the 2019 state of DevOps
So the first thing I want to I want to say regarding this paper is in some regard to caner paper the caner paper
it's
depressing and
Because because it's been 16 years and so much of the industry is still every paper is still
relevant
Well, no this paper can be shipped to people and they would go
It would still have the same argument, you know, what do you know how?
Do you know what do you mean? We shouldn't have a bug tracking system with by the way, he says no
So a couple years ago every year on 4th of July
For the US listeners at the Independence Day holiday everyone else. It's our opinion stay holiday
NPR our National Public Radio published it they tweet the Declaration of Independence
Okay, and
Not as much anymore because they caught themselves but the first year this happened a bunch of
Trump supporters were going off on Twitter because I thought this whole thing was just they didn't realize the question independence
I thought it was all jet NPR making jabs at the president. Okay, so I
Wonder if I were to take select quotes from this and tweet them
How many people would disagree and tell me I was full of shit I'm asking you this now because that's what I'm doing this weekend
Before this podcast
I am going to take some choice quotes from this and I'm going to troll the internet and see what happens the challenge here
Is that thing I really would want to see
There is a challenge and you can finish that the challenge is all the people that hate me for all my shit and going against
Your exploratory testing and oh my god. There is nothing better in life. They're writing selenium tests all day
They've already stopped following and or blocked me already, but I'll see who's left because there's always somebody
Oh like the person when I said when ministry testing tweeted testing is dot dot dot and I wrote
accelerating the achievement simple quality and so reply back testing does nothing to accelerate the team and
Fun happened from there, so we'll see what happens
Yeah, I'm actually yeah, what is Eric talk with you off the podcast
Cuz this is a lot of fun that you
Fun possibilities based on what you just said but going back to going back to Nicole thing and I and I this will be my
final thought on this one or on this
Like the state of DevOps and and the
The KPI that you're thinking of rolling out and how you're gonna do that, right? You mentioned by her standard
You're in the the
elite class, so great
Unfortunately as you called out
That means
You may not necessarily be able to
to leverage much from the coal
to move into the
Super elite I can define my own levels the metrics that are in accelerate are still highly valid
I still want to use them. I just have higher standards than the elite level know what I'm saying actually
Because you're you're now going into something that she hasn't documented. I think there's an opportunity there to create a collaboration
connection
with
Nicole I hope so
Alright, and actually I lied because there's one thing as I was looking at you and realizing where you work
There's something that I do also gonna be it could be because of my unity hoodie. I'm wearing my admin. Are you aware of?
The communication the the recent controversy with the communications workers union
No, I am NOT. Okay. I'm not aware of the recent controversies with the communications something union
in
California
They are working to unionize
Game developers. Oh, I have heard about this the game testers
game developers game developers
Interesting and I haven't heard about this. There's always some because of the way the game companies treat testers game QA
frequently I hear rumblings of
Testers game testers wanting to unionize but I had heard about developers anyway continue
I think it might be something worth discussing between the two of us on this because one of the things I realized is
Knowledge work is becoming a bigger and bigger thing. Yes, like a lot of the the blue-collar work is being automated away
and
I'm actually it's not the prediction episode, but I'm actually thinking there is a non-trivial chance that in
next 10 years
That could that could unionize. Oh well
Long as ever hits me. I'll retire if you ever have you ever worked in Union. I have I have also
The experience was not good. Yeah, I worked in Union. I think it would be a horrible thing long term for
The people in the society quite honestly. Yeah, but I think in the short term it might much like labor unions did in the short term
I think it might be a good thing
So here's one of the things that unions do
If nothing else if the unionized and this stuck and then we got rid of the union. I'd be for unionization
gets read of
This hyper competitive heroism bullshit a buddy of mine works at Salesforce
Everyone knows what their bonus is gonna be and it there's there's no
There's no
Behavior at Salesforce where you're trying to look I don't have to be good. I just have to be better than Alan
Because that relative stack system the the hyper competitiveness is
Very much a Microsoft thing. I think I mean that's my experience my experience at Microsoft is
man, when you get to may
People are sucking up and putting others down and trying to make themselves look good for
At the risk and pain to customers at the risk and pain to each other at the risk and pain of mental health
It is it's horrid. Did you read Whitaker's why I left Microsoft again, I
Know I didn't
Nutshell he says that culture is changing. It's the right direction not going fast enough
I'm gonna go someplace else. Oh, that's what I said when I left. Yeah
screw him
the
In all of that's true
but
What it was frustrated him further is he he knew why it wasn't going fast enough and that is because
All of the hippos at the company that have been here. Oh, you know what?
Maybe I did see that that that's all absolutely true. If you look at you know Windows, which is
Even though maybe it's getting better now that it's part of Azure, which is still weird, but that whole
It is whole it's just a just a old
It's a it's a frat Club for 50 year olds as the leadership of Windows
Yeah, and it's interesting. I'm trying to come up with a way to classify this
Because I am in the 50 year old Club and
next
maybe
episode
On February 6th, it's my 25th here
But yet I share no kinship with these folks these folks that have have
decided that
There is no reason to change right unless it's forced upon me
absolutely and
There were in the and we can go on a little bit here
But well what a tangent in the the 90s and the early 2000s. There was still so much turnover people
Weren't staying at Microsoft a long time, but some were in there
people start takes staying at Microsoft longer and longer and they stopped learning and
ten years ago
James and a friend of ours were at lunch and James takes credit for this but it was actually Dan who first said this he
Said everybody at a certain level and above should have to go out and every two years
they have to get a job offer from another company in order to keep their job here make sure they're staying relevant and
There is a reason they're staying here some of those
Partner level folks and many of those partner level folks and many of our executives the reason they're staying at Microsoft because they cannot
Get an equal paying job or an equal prestige job anywhere else in the industry because they're irrelevant to every other company besides Microsoft
well, that's part of it. The other thing too is
Microsoft has put into place for a long time strategies to retain
Those type of folks. Yeah, but maybe that's the wrong thing
But it's fine to retain them if they continue to learn and grow but you can look at them and I'll I'll call out names
Michael Fortin the stagnant of their like talk about someone stuck in
1990 and being totally happy with it. There's an example. I
Have not I don't know if he's still around anymore. He is. I'm Irish and his boss is same thing
Terry's not yeah, I know. I know. Yeah, God
I have you can't imagine and just the pain of being in a meeting like with Terry Meyers in there and just going
Oh my god, you're running this ship. Oh
Anyway, names dropped doesn't matter. I left three years ago almost exactly. I had an interaction. So
you mentioned Windows is is
part of Azure they are and
As you know because you were still here when they formed it I believe
Windows response to the removal of tests
was to put them all into a
an organization they called quality and then
Take what seemingly a random 50% of those same folks and change their title
You know, yeah, you get a title developer evens you get a title data scientist. Yep. Just rotate draw straws
I was there for that and and oh and by the way, this is gonna happen and we're gonna give you no direction
Go figure it out on your own. Yeah bad bad bad idea
the
However, even worse. It's a bad idea
Executed poorly poorly. However
That was many years ago
It was but was about six years ago. Yes, and five years
they have hired in
for example, there is a
one of those data science teams
They hired in a partner level data scientist manager
Who
Now has been at the company for a year
But before that he was at HP and he and I is funny
He and I went had coffee and he's like bring can I just talk to you?
He's German and Germans like to be blunt. I mean he's from Germany and he's like, can I just have a straight conversation?
I'm like sure, of course
and he's like
WTF
This company and I'm like dude, you're in the middle of Windows. It's not this company
Yeah, and that's one thing to be clear on my my rant is dedicated there
I do talk about there are some bright spots. There's bright spots, but but still a struggle to rewind it
It's just it's tough because it's tough to
Everyone's focused on getting promoted people are more focused on getting promoted than probably anything that benefits the customer
I remember that you remember the lesson of the the monkeys experiment. Yes, sometimes people are doing things
because that's how it's always been done and they don't know it a
Great example that same team. So I have
AI actually running in production and
Customers its customer-facing it's something I shipped about six months ago
They have a similar technology this this this one team I'm thinking of and I said, okay
Let's meet and let's run your model against my data and see which one's better
I still hosted if yours is better. I'll ship it. We started this about three months ago
They haven't finished writing the proposal
Document so that they could get the approval
to do a four-hour freaking experiment to see if they have something better and I'm like
Yes, so one one final final final thing that I really have to go fair enough is
Another thing we could potentially talk about in the future
But I'll bring it up shortly now is you know 15 years ago 10 years ago
At some point I was working a lot with 10 years ago with not cheating. I got the pun who you know, you know not
she I do and always did research on
Really relevant stuff and he's good with statistics really really fantastic human and there was some talk last week because someone wrote a bot at Microsoft
It's one of Microsoft wrote a bot based on his research to
Walk code and predict defects and one of the things they found
I had the highest correlation or the highest recall was
Organizational structure and the internet went. Oh my god. This is so cool
But the thing I would like to point out with that research and I think you'll head nod here is
at
Microsoft that makes complete sense because organizational structure and
Who you report to and what org you report to is something people often look at before they'll even talk to you
So of course it the challenges in software and complexity come from communication
And there are communication breakdowns dependent on org that are highly
Specific or at least intensify that Microsoft
so
And so
Yeah, there are that particular study to my to my knowledge it hasn't
So you're aware of the repeatability crisis right now, yes, okay that one
I think hasn't passed the repeatability it was intended to be sort of hey, this is what we've learned
I did I've actually had meetings with not she and
one of the things he struggled with was trying to find a
Variety of different right data sources right that had sufficient data
and at that point in time he
Shit ton of data and there was only two groups
The thing was and again granted not she used windows for the bulk of his research
Anyway, I would love to keep talking about it. We keep keep giving us your papers. We'll keep giving you bad book reports
So show notes caner paper sinner DevOps
Maybe even not cheese paper not his bot stuff if I get that far that's gonna be a lot of work for me
I'll see if I can get that done. I'm Alan. I'm brain and we're gonna see you next time. Happy New Year