Welcome to AV testing podcast your modern testing podcast your hosts Alan and Brent will be here to guide you through
Topics on testing leadership agile and anything else that comes to mind now on with the show
Hey everyone
Brett say something. Hi
All right
But you said hey everyone like that was for the list that was for the three people
Brit you're you remain the smartest idiot I've ever known but luckily we have someone even smarter joining us on our
our
Socially distanced podcast this morning. We have Julian Bucknell who is the CTO of test cafe? Hey Julian and
Good morning. It's well, it's morning for me. Yeah
Hello
Long-time listeners may know that we we record it 8 a.m
On Fridays usually so are welcome to have Julian get up early for us. Which part of the world are you in Julian?
I'm actually in Colorado. So it's it's not an early morning for me. It's it's pretty good. I mean I've got my
Starbucks coffee which I went to him, you know a
Drive-thru
To get and I'm ready
It's
Ready for the the morning's work
All right. Wait, you introduced me as the CTO of test cafe. I actually am the CTO of developer Express who
Create and market test. Thank you for the clarification. What else does dev express do we are mostly about
Kind of user interface controls for for developers across the gamut from Windows
to the web and
You know, I can get into why we created test cafe because you know
we have all these user interface controls for the web and
We need to test them and so on so forth. But yeah, we we basically target developers
creating applications
you know either for Windows or for the web or
It's getting more and more things like the Mac and and so on so forth. It's it's getting very interesting
Yes, indeed and I like that you said you cater towards developers
I don't I didn't mention this earlier in our pre-show talk, but I
My role is difficult to describe. I run engineering systems for an org of about 250 people and
We don't have any dedicated QA. In fact, we have a lot of people doing testing. They're also called developers and
many of our developers for the parts of our
Our product that are in UI are using test cafe and I have played with it in the past for some prototyping
And I have to say I'm a fan
so I am curious why in a world where
Selenium is ubiquitous. Did you like what was the
Where'd you where'd you come from here? Well, the thing was this is my word. This is probably about seven years ago now
Yes, we we developed
Web controls
controls for web applications
so, you know the boring things like menus and buttons and all that kind of stuff we have a
theming thing we have grids and spreadsheets and
Previews and dashboards now and all that kind of stuff and the big problem without this is yeah, we can write
our own
Tests or the developers can write their own tests
to a certain extent when you're talking about things like
unit tests or integration tests and so on a functional testing but
When you're talking about the web
as
I'm sure you both know and all everybody listening knows
You're not actually running the web app on its own. You're running it inside a browser and
We ran into the problem with Selenium
Which I'm sure a lot of people run into is in order to test an application say
test your user interface you've got to
Install something inside your browser. I think it's called web driver or something like that and
And that becomes a problem. You can't just you know start up a browser and say, okay
Let me test this particular piece of my application or this particular piece of the UI
Am I getting the right results from my back end and so on so forth?
and so we we started to run into these problems and
Pure JavaScript controls were originally written for the mobile market
so we talk about phones which were tablets and all that kind of stuff and
Selenium tablets the phones
No, so we had to basically come up with an idea
Some kind of tool that we could use to test our own user interface controls on mobile devices
Automatically and
You know put it inside our continuous integration
Service and all that kind of stuff. And so we started off in test cafe
I remember when we first launched it. I think was 2013
There was a big conference in San Francisco an HTML 5 conference or some description
and so we had a booth there and we were showing it off and
and I had my
my Kindle and
You know, we were showing everybody that oh it runs on this laptop that we have here and there's Julian with his Kindle
Look, then test cafe was working on the Kindle
Yes, we love doing stuff like that
And it kind of grew from there really people got enthusiastic about it
The thing is with test cafe, I'm sure you know is you write your tests in JavaScript
So not only you writing JavaScript for your web app
You're also writing JavaScript for your tests
You're not having to learn something new. You're not having to install something new. It's just
You know, it's no JS essentially a nice
framework for no JS
Can install it with NPM and you know, it's dead easy and as I say you don't have to install
Anything on the browser to make it from the test
The thing was that you know at that point
We realized there were a lot of people out there who would like it even
We just have a user interface which ran in the browser and
People saying yeah, but you're not doing this you're not doing that
So we basically stopped developing user interface and we decided to create an open source
framework for test cafe
And
Then once that was popular
create a better
dashboard style or studio style
Interface for recording tests and all that kind of stuff. So yeah, you can you can download it from
GitHub it's open source project. We get a lot of
Feedback from from people who are using it
and so on so forth it's
It's been a it's been a journey
Yeah, so I briefly my experience touched on this a little bit in our pre podcast talk, but
Many years ago when I was still at Microsoft as a Microsoft for a long time with Brent
That's where we met tonight. I've moved on from there about three years ago. I
My last job there. I ran a team where the developers were using
Slow down protractor for an angular website and
one of the things that
Bugged me was that the only browser we could get all of our tests to run on consistently was Chrome
There were various issues with Firefox more issues with ie and granted. This is now five or six years ago
Five well three four four or five years ago. I can do the math here
So when I got a chance to prototype test cafe just to let you know
My experience as a user it was NPM install test cafe
Open some you look at the docks write a little code go
Oh, wow, this just runs and then try a different browser and it just runs and I wrote more extensive tests
And not only did I write I just wrote a little
Basic test for one page to create some random project names for us. This was an angular set at the time and
It was pretty easy to get a basic test up and running
Ended up having to do a lot more and I'm gonna really anger the Selenium crowd
I'm not against Selenium as everybody knows we had Jason Huggins on the show last year to talk about it's a lot of value to it
But as far as quick
Getting things up and running it worked really well for me and those tests ran with only one
Air when someone pulled them out and dusted them off to build on them
Six or eight months after I wrote them. So I think that's a testament to
How well things work?
I'm a little bit removed from that but I remember in Selenium a lot of waiting for elements to appear which
You have to do a little bit of a test cafe
But it's a little smarter about not needing to write these massive nested
Weights and checks so a big fan. So this is all leading to a question. So when I first used test cafe, I
posted
Eventually Alan gets somewhere. I posted to Twitter and said hey because I haven't done a lot of web automation. I
Said I've used test cat facings to work pretty well and what am I missing? What's what?
Why isn't this a bigger deal and the feedback I get from my followers who use
And others who are forwarded. There's a lot of Selenium folks out there
We're really just two things and maybe watch you address these and kind of get rather than my opinion your opinion
One was which I will actually argue with first one was will it inject JavaScript into your website?
So it's not the real site customers are seeing
I thought that is and just I'll just dismiss that one is lame
but the second one is
But web it doesn't use webdriver and webdriver is w3c c standard w3c standard and
My answer to that was so and they said but it's a standard and I said so and they said but it's a standard
But you may have a better answer to that question. So I'll leave you with that to comment on
My my viewpoint
Just to go back. I mean we create these user interface controls written in JavaScript for web applications
And the thing is we don't just say
these controls only work in Chrome or Firefox or
Safari or whatever edge. Yeah, that was the other one edge. Ha
Yeah, we say it's you know, it's a
User interface control for the web and it should work in any browser and what we get is if we get it wrong
We get you know a support question or whatever it happens to be. Hey, I'm using this version of Safari and your web
Your user interface control doesn't work
And so we have to basically, you know
Boot up some Safari or other and check it out. The problem is
Once you fixed whatever issue it was in whatever particular browser it was
You've got to repeat that test forevermore
It's part of your test suite at that point because you don't want to revert to a buggy
Version and so on so forth
So that's you know
emphasizing the fact that
Yes, web driver may be
W3C
Compatible and all the rest of it, but it's not in every browser
It's not there if I download and install Firefox, it's not there you have to then install
something else and
And you know if I come my
I'm old-fashioned. I've got an iPhone 6
It's you know, the operating system is version 12 of iOS not version 13. It won't go up any further
so at some point, you know
I'm just saying
We're going to create a user interface control or some feature and other and it's just not going to work on my iPhone 6
And i'll be able to say okay guys, you know sort this out
but with selenium
until
If you like the web driver becomes like
um
The big thing everyone's talking about these days is wasm web assembly
Every browser now has web assembly built into the browser so you could now write applications
Which target web assembly fine?
web driver is not like that
and um, so
You know for us in particular
Uh emphasizes the fact that we needed
something which went beyond
Um what selenium could do because we have customers out there across the world
Using a wild variety of different browsers, so we cannot
Just say oh, sorry. You're using internet explorer 11
You would believe the number of people you still use internet explorer 11
Um, I would because i've run those
Because we had to when I when I had web apps
At microsoft I would look at browser percentage and at the time again four or five years ago
At I was surprised how many people were running ie8
Yeah, absolutely. I mean it is it can be absolutely crazy, but then you start thinking about okay
It's a legacy app and you know, we haven't upgraded all our users
So on so on so on I mean, I wonder how many people out there are using the new microsoft edge for example if they're using edge
Did they actually do the extra step to install this brand new chrome based edge?
Brand you you're probably using chrome edge
Uh not by purpose. No
Do you call it credge internally?
No, we do not we do not
I'm gonna offer that up for free
Just pass that along to satya or the ie team directly
If it goes that way it's already going to get translated to frames internally. Oh, i'm sorry. I'm sorry. I said microsoft
I'm sorry. Credge for business
No, so like the
the
uh
I do think going with the chrome
Architecture was a net positive for edge
Uh, I don't think there's much disagreement there not for me
No, no
but
Like to me, I think there's a bit of a branding problem right now because I think the majority
About if I were in the right position
Once I made the decision to go with the chrome back in I would have rebranded
Right because I think I think edge is synonymous with
pain
in in
the world market
That's just my opinion and satya listens to this and what's the question me on it?
Um, I'll still stand by that even though I have no data to prove it one way or the other
um
couple couple of things, uh
So i'm currently stocking
julian on linkedin
Oh and I see he actually has spent time at microsoft as well
Yes, that was a while back
I was at microsoft for about a year. Um
I was brought on um
because
The visual studio team were about to release visual studio
And if you know your visual studio history, there was no visual studio 2003 because there was a major cockup
And so it became visual studio 2005 and so I was brought into you know
in theory to
provide
I was program manager to provide ideas and thoughts about what the next version of visual studio would would have and
Would be doing and so on so forth except that
I was brought in and everything had been decided and
We were doing visual studio 2000, what's it called? Um codename whitby
It's kind of interesting. I remember these things. Wow. Yeah
C-sharp was getting um generics. That was the big thing about it
I remember when generics came out those were cool. Uh,
So you remember when wittaker was in dev dev
Was it around that time frame?
It might have been so barton barton was running their massive qa org
But when did I don't remember when wittaker's first stint at microsoft began and ended?
But yeah about that time he actually might have come a little bit later
Yeah, was was tfs a thing then julian?
Tfs was just starting
It hadn't the team foundation server
I I I
No, that was later i'm sure i'm trying to get back now
I mean i've i've been with dev express now 14 years. So it's like
you know
I forgot I forgot most of those days at microsoft. It was uh,
It was fun, but I just didn't fit in at that particular point. Unfortunately, so all right
I had to give your yearbook away. No, that makes that makes perfect sense like like um
You know, he started this question with sort of a web driver
Is the standard thing right in in the somewhat of a?
cyclical argument in my view standards change
right, uh, I
Just happened to be looking
uh
Uh in right now I found a page that talks about laws that have changed
Right there was a law apparently in washington in 1969 where it
Made it a felony and punishable by five years in prison if you um
Slayed bigfoot
Where are you going with this?
No, I I'm just
Which page you've got up?
So so that law that law was in 1969
In and in the context back then there was there
Either this was a complete joke or
Uh in in the people who passed that a lot had nothing else better to do or there was some evidence or a real strong belief
That bigfoot is a creature that needs to be protected. My my point is is that as time advances?
We create new tech new standards need to be
Uh
Standards need to be reconsidered
right, um
Qa certification
Right. There's still a lot of standards in in in the eu around qa certification
And and as an example i'd make a large argument
that those standards are
Contradictory, uh to to many marketplaces today
Not all but many
I I I
Alan you you sort of just immediately bit flip the javascript argument. Likewise. I bit flipped the web driver argument
um, alan
Well, actually i'll i'll ask one question that i'm very curious about so
Dev express targets deaths, right? We we talked about at the very beginning. It's very
fascinating
What about test cafe?
Specifically do you have any sort of sense of
If you can share this sort of your your customer segmentation
around
Uh a developer versus a a traditional
Uh ui tester or ui automator
Uh, so
So let me let me approach that in in a slightly
weird way
Originally, we wrote test cafe for developers because we as a company
market to developers essentially
um
As I said, we do user interface controls across the board
and so originally test cafe was targeted towards developers and those developers would be
Fairly proficient in javascript as I said we're talking about five six seven years ago
um
and
what we found was
that
The developers were saying
This is too simplistic
um
For us to use you've got to
broaden it and you've got to
Make it easier to program to
Um, and so on so forth. So that's why we split test cafe away from its user interface to
a pure
javascript framework essentially
And that was made open source and blah blah blah blah
And then we went back to the user interface to say
Okay
We know that developers
will um
I'm going to say the word enjoy using test cafe because
You know, they're writing web applications and writing some javascript and they know javascript and they can write javascript to do their tests
brilliant
Now we have to target those people who
Maybe don't know javascript as well
but are
Qa people testing people people who
basically
are
If you like away from that developer mentality and go
How is this application really going to work and how easy is it to use and how can we test the
usability of this application
Easily and quickly which is when we produced test cafe studio, which has
basically a visual
test recorder
So yeah a developer could go in with the studio and say all right
Here's my web page and i'm going to press this button i'm expecting this to happen and you know these
Elements to be updated and so on so forth and they could actually just record that using
the visual
Test recorder instead of actually, you know trying to write the javascript and
Oh, they're using or really and they need
You know an extra bit of code to actually access the elements and and so on so forth
so we originally started targeting developers, but with the
User interface either studio side or
It's going to migrate into a kind of dashboard type
application
um
You know, we're we're then
Basically saying okay developers you have a qa team
Um who may not be as proficient in javascript as you are
And you don't want them to come to you to say write me this test, please because i've got to run it
You know add infinitum every day
uh in my integrated test suite
um
that's
The whole point where we thought okay, we have to target
um
Uh the testing environment in these companies these uh corporations
and make it easier for them to
Create a suite of tests to run that suite of tests as part of some integration
um
and
So on so forth so it's um
We're not we're not saying
Oh developers you've been doing it wrong. Here's a great new studio, which will help you do it better
And we're not saying to the testers. Oh, i'm sorry. You don't know javascript that well
Here's something to make it easier for it. No, we're basically saying
Writing tests is
I mean, there's so many different types of tests you've got you know, as I said units integration tests functional testing
Which is very developer based
um performance testing
Hmm in usability testing the thing that fascinates me most and um,
uh as uh
Cto at dev express no
I'm very into usability
Unfortunately these days I don't do much development
Um, you know, I started off years ago as a developer, but I don't do much development nowadays. So I tend to look at things
from a
User standpoint more than a developer standpoint
so usability testing for me is is something that's
interesting and um
I I really want to get more into and um, you know to be able to look at our
particular controls and to say
Yes, they're usable if the user
Comes across an application written with our controls. They know how to use the application. They're not searching around
You know the window going well, what do I do to do this? It gets obvious
um, and you know test cafe is all about that it's uh, um,
especially the studio side of things it's the ability for
um
Qa testers to actually
Write tests which show that an application is usable and continues to be usable
so
I don't know the state of the art today on test recorders
when
When I started this this was back in oh my god ms test was when it started
Ooh
Are those who remember that? I I I was a beta user
um
and one of the traditional problems with this is they were
They were absolutely great for very quickly creating a bunch of repeatable tests
As long as your developers didn't check in any changes
Uh, then it very quickly then it very quickly became a maintenance nightmare often with people who didn't understand
Uh the code being produced
um
What's the what's the state of the art on?
that
that's
That's that's that kind of a broad question because if you like we suffer from that from our um, you know main
um thrust of our um our company is
Breaking changes, you know, we're we
So let's say we produce a control
Um people like it and they want some changes and they want this feature and that feature and all that kind of stuff
It's very easy at that point to say, you know
We thought about doing abc with this control at the beginning
but it turns out that c is not really required it really ought to be d and
We make the change and it's a breaking change and
Yes, we have to tell our
Customers that yet there is a breaking change
Uh, it won't work in the same way as it did in the previous version and all that kind of stuff and the one thing about test cafe
video
Test recorder is that it's actually writing the stuff as javascript in the background
So it's not some weird and wonderful
Database there and we're just doing some wacky sql to
Put the test into the database and all that kind of stuff. No, it's just a javascript file
so
In one sense, it's uh fairly easy to make changes
Yes, the developers can do something which will break a test
as the test broken because the change made was
Um bad or was the breaking change a good breaking change in this case you have to change the test for sure
and it's easier to change the test if it's just
You know language, you know and can just quickly change or re-record the test with the new
Um new outcome that you're expecting from this new feature
Yeah, so to build on what with what brent asked and as answer part of it myself in the old days of windows ui automation
People would change an id of a control or the tab or a tab order or something that would screw up all your automation
in the web world brent the
If people
Have auto generated or randomly named or or usually unnamed controls things get weird even in test cafe
I had one control in that little suite. I wrote that didn't have an easy way to access
so I had to make a constant with
with the
Totally ugly selector name and we went back and changed it later
But the way you get around those tests breaking is you you give your controls ids with sensible names
That makes them easier to access
So which is one of the reasons I think it's critical
Whether you're using selenium or test cafe or any of the other tools around this is that for that
Unit level that basic bvt of ui wouldn't be unit level test
But that basic bvt of ui like are my controls there and they do
I'm beginning not testing logic is the stuff where I want it to be
Have the devs write that because they're going to feel that pain right away and go fix
Yeah, and I mean
We don't have qa on our team, but if they if they go oh wait, this is stupid
Why am I doing it this way? That's such an efficiency boom rather than the if you have a like there are some
organizations where a tester writes test cases and an automation team goes to automate them and the back and
forth between those layers and the developer
Just it's it's an inefficient game of ping pong that drives me nuts
So let's take care of and maybe if you have that automation team, which i'm not a fan of
I'm not against having qa teams. I think it makes sense, especially in a in a ui centric application, but get that basic
Testing that that first level of testing done by the dev team have them own those tests
Because if not you're going to be playing a constant game of back and forth and back and forth the entire time you're building your product
And it's just a horrible way to make software
That's a that's a good point actually
And one of the things we discovered is yes
Uh test cafe will record a test saying is the 13th child of this particular parent because you haven't actually given it an id
And yeah, something will break pretty quickly at that particular point
Um, which is why we also have
Not only pure if you like css
um
Classes and ids that we can search for and use and all that kind of stuff. We also have
the ability to
um have
Format format framework specific
Um selectors, so if you're using react for example react is
If you like notorious for hiding things from you because it creates an old separate dom and you know
What do we do about that in test cafe? Well answer is we have a react
plugin if you like which knows about react and knows how to get
uh to a particular control or a particular element in the react dom tree to be able to
ascertain its
status and
What it's showing or whatever
But yeah, that's an excellent way of putting it if your developers can't write the test then
Nobody else could
Zen and the art of motorcycle maintenance a book on the philosophy of quality basically says quality and care are two sides of the same coin
If I look at my work, if I look at a string of random
Glued greater than signs and strings that that that is a thing in my test. I am not proud of that work
Right, and I want to be proud of what I make whether it's a test or production code or or even a project
I like to be proud of my work. Uh, I want to
Ask you a different question
And I think it's fair for because again a lot of people
I don't I don't think it's any mystery to you. There are more selenium users and there are test cafe users
I haven't looked up that number, but I'm pretty sure I can say that I feel I have a high confidence. That's correct
What are some for the selenium crowd maybe because i'll get questions about this maybe let's preempt some of those
What are some things you think selenium does better than test cafe or or or a reason you would use selenium in some instance over test cafe?
that's a question that I really could not answer because I
Personally have never used selenium. So I
I
I just don't know. I am to officially outsource that question then because I don't know either
I mean I get I get the point that selenium has been around
the longest
so
So actually I have one maybe we can talk through because I haven't thought about this
But I think I think I can talk through it. Maybe you can help me with it
is
One of the things that were built on top of selenium is selenium grid the ability to have a basically a server farm run a whole
bunch of things
you test across a whole bunch of browsers and a whole bunch of
permutations
I'm as I say that because I brought i'm just trying to think I think I could duplicate
All of that in a modern ci system
Is that something that's come up with you?
Has anybody ever asked like I want to run this across on every build across
16 different browser and os flavors
Would they just use test cafe on something like browser stack or like what will be your what would be your answer to that?
That question that's something that we are continuing to improve. Let's put it like that the ability to run
Test suites concurrently
and
it's
Quite unquite difficult, but it's still it works at the moment. We
The other thing is to go back is
We get an awful lot
these days
Of people are using sites like source labs
To run their application on multiple different mobile devices
And yes, we'll do that in quite parallel. Uh, unquote
Um
Which again, you know selenium is more geared towards your desktop browser
Experience and not necessarily. Oh i'm running it on a very smaller
Very smaller and a smaller screen and you know, these things disappear until you hit the hamburger menu
Icon and stuff like that
The way test cafe works is it uses a proxy server essentially
so
It's end-to-end testing and test cafes in the middle. So
If your browser asks for a particular, you know
HTTP request test cafe receives the HTTP request recognizes it sends it on to the actual back end
And then when the back end replies will then pass that reply over to the browser and um
Um
You know inject if you like it's uh its own test, uh information
Uh so that it can verify that test is running. Okay, and all the rest of it that server
proxy server will
work with multiple
browsers at the same time
So you can basically with test cafe set it up so that
You know it'll run
even on a desktop
Chrome and firefox and edge all at the same time running the same test for the same application and so on so forth
But I would guess that selenium if you like does it better because it's it's an actual application. It's uh, you know, it's
Giving the whole hog as it were
Yeah, I think in
So let me talk through this. I haven't thought through this completely but because the installation is just an npm install
Yeah, uh, it's it makes it fairly easy. Well, not fairly makes it extremely easy to add to my
My ci workflow. I just added I add a step that's
Uh, there's a setup step for npm install and then it runs the test results get reported and I can definitely
in parallel send that that that step to multiple locations whether it's on a farm or
Or I can specify where I want those to run. So that should work and i'm sure and again
I have used selenium protractor fairly extensively, but again, this is years ago. I I don't have the data
But uh, my experiences are similar, but i'm actually looking forward to hearing
Uh what our listeners have to say and if you're fairly new to the podcast if you go back to
About a year ago one of the early posts from 2019
I think that's what it was. We had jason huggins on the podcast
in response to a tweet
Actually, this was better brought up a minute ago. We're talking about ids
I had come across a blog post and someone talking about how they solved the problem in selenium
And they're very proud of this code
And I looked and talked about looking at code and saying am I proud of this?
They were very proud of code that I thought was
ugly
Unfarrassingly ugly. It was a long string of
Of the selector they had to choose to get it get access to the control
And I tweeted something crass like reason
438 why I hate selenium
And the community exploded against me and told me I I couldn't hate selenium and it's not I don't actually I I think selenium is great
Uh, it solves it solves a huge problem
What I didn't like is that it enabled that stuff. This is true also in test cafe
but it started a nice little war, uh, one of the
the contributors to web driver was extremely mad at me and and gave me uh,
I'll just say some grief over twitter
and I
We ended up having jason on the show to talk about it and he was actually he was super pleasant and he got it and
He asked he tried to bait brent and I with a uh, a question
Well, should should selenium just not support selector? So that make it easier said no
We should you've you've you have legacy of a million different tests. You can't just go break them
Uh, I think in a way he was acknowledging it that part kind of created a monster
But the point I wanted to make was not that I hate selenium
Uh, I hate hated the way it was being used the way people like again going back to my statement before
which is
Don't don't settle for having to access controls like that
And I got all kinds of well, we can't get developers to do that
Okay, if you if you're not collaborating with your development team if you're in a dedicated testing role and you're not collaborating with your dev team
That's the problem
Solve that problem. You'll solve all kinds of other things, too
so anyway, uh
We we support everyone if in fact I will put an open invitation out
If someone wants to come what else wants to come on the show and tell and tell me why?
uh
Why selenium is so much more awesome than test cafe?
We could do that too and I will offer that to you julian as free competitive analysis
I'll tell you I'll tell you if you if you want to do that
that's somebody on and uh have me be there as well and
You know have a big discussion about this versus why and i'm gonna even go more meta on this and say
uh
Don't use a tool because it's the one everyone else is using don't follow someone
Because that's the guy you think you want to follow form your own opinions
Whether it's around philosophy approach quality
Test automation tools do your research and form your own opinions. I can tell you i've formed mine and mine is that
uh test cafe is very easy to use and
Consistently runs my tests across every browser. I could throw at it
It does seem to me that intellectual laziness and
In the knowledge work business is a great way to limit your career
Um one million percent. Yes
The and then for those listeners who are curious
Alan's uh ui rant was episode 102
And the follow-up 103 was the one with
Jason
I I will look up those and um, um listen to them afterwards. I just like to say, um
I had a thought and it's gone. Um, it sounded like me
No, it's completely gone
Actually, I was looking at um angry weasel ab testing the website and um
You are responsive or the site is responsive. So it's a word. It's just a wordpress site. Yeah
Actually, I should bring this up
I used to give a workshop at conferences called tools you can use a bunch of different tools that any tester could use for testing
And I use test cafe as part of that i've since open sourced that I know one of our listeners chris kentz has
Given that workshop and anyone can but I used a quick little test cafe script
uh to do some automation of angry weasel.com and
And show that as a demo like this is this is how easy it is. It was not very much code
Yeah
The I I just remembered what I was talking about. Um
You were saying about, um developers
um
not being um
Exploratory enough if you like and just plumping for whatever everybody else is using
Um, this is something that we we come across with regard to our trial versions
Essentially the trial versions of our products are there so you can
Play around with them and see if they're actually going to suit your particular application your particular company and uh
Whether you should actually buy them and all the rest of it and I always say to developers when they're
When they're saying well, you know, why why should I buy yours and not?
Um, you know competitive be your competency
And I just say to be honest, you know writing user interface controls
You have two audiences you have the user and you have the developer
and
So play around with it use it as a developer
And show it to your users and see if they like it and the same thing with test cafe
essentially
Try it use it
You know do a
Contest if you like between selenium or cypress or one of the other big ones
Uh versus test cafe
How easy is it to use? Does it suit your particular application? Does it suit suit your particular?
environment
And
Go from there if you plump for one brilliant
I'm not going to argue with you if you say, you know, we did a test we checked, you know
You versus selenium versus cypress versus weber and we like selenium better
fine, brilliant you actually did the work to
say
that
Selenium was better and i'm not going to argue with that i'm not going to jump up and down and say well we use javascript
We use javascript
You know, you know, it's it's nothing nothing to do with that. I
Goes back to that whole, you know writing crappy code or whatever or writing
Code which you look at and go. Holy cow. Is there any way to make that simpler?
Uh, maybe if I switch my framework, it would be simpler to write and to maintain and to use and all that kind of stuff
but at that point it's
you and
your developer mindset
Whichever thing works best for you go for it
Yeah, same same advice for me
Yes, brandt. Sorry. Yeah, this is to julian
Julian has so are you familiar with the work of nicole forstman?
She recently published a book called accelerate
I just like to point out now for our listeners. This is the 37th podcast in a row. We've mentioned the book accelerate
Go on brandt. Yeah, we we
Um, so what she did is she went back and did
A research study around sort of typical agile practices
and
she concluded
many interesting things
um
one of them was that
Uh developers owning their testing
Owning the testing for a company was highly correlated with
Uh the company's success and productivity
uh, however
qa owning
the the tests
uh was not at all correlated with
highly valuable business results
and um
This is somewhat towards the salimian salimian comment and perhaps test cafe
But I wonder if if companies in your sorts of business
Shouldn't in some regards help your your customers?
um
I need those sort of goals. Uh, meaning
Right. Sure. If you don't have an id
Uh, if you don't have ids we're gonna fall back and we'll still succeed within test cafe
But now you're gonna have the high maintenance
Uh version of your recorded test rate. Um
I'm wondering if things like annoying warnings or or or something along those lines to sort of
Start changing the their engineering behavior towards
towards things that are that are known to produce positive business outcomes like it seems to me
Uh if test cafe was able to say
Hey, we not only just do tests, but we actually help you change
Uh the culture of your business
Right. We're an ally to your business as well as our own
anyway
That's an interesting viewpoint and i'll have a chat with the developers. We already produce a
Uh a product for c-sharp developers and javascript developers
called code rush which
Helps you analyze your code and suggest ways of improving your code
like it already
and
That seems to be or what you're saying there brent seems to be something that we could
do with test cafe whereby
as a
An example like the stupid example I gave earlier, you know instead of hey, you're selecting the 13th child of this parent
Why don't you give it a name?
And here's a name for you or something like that. Let me that's an interesting viewpoint
And I I've just bought it on amazon and it's coming tomorrow. So there you go. It's a great book
Um, okay, that was my turn to forget what I was going to say as a photo
Yeah, it's the end of the week
Mind you every day seems to be the end of the week
Oh, yeah. No, my my recurring comment there is every day is tuesday
Right. It's not monday. It's like the not the typical misery of monday. It's it's not oh wend's day
Hey, we're halfway through it is most certainly not friday
All right with with that I with us all being confused by the day of the week
but not being confused on uh
branch shut up
But not being confused on having a great and fun time talking to julian today
Uh, we need to close
Well, thank you very much. Alan and brent for invite me on to the uh, the podcast. I I must say I enjoyed it very much
We're super glad to have you here. And I uh, I say again if you uh invite somebody who wants to have a discussion
A versus b then I'll certainly come back
Yeah, sure. Let us know. Let us know. All right. Great. How do you hear?
Brent what were you saying? I said hear that hugs
We'll see if one of the listeners uh routes it to a
Yeah, we'll see what happens and again
I think it's I think again. I just want to close and say
critical thinking blind faith in anything
is
Whether it's ideology or tools or anything in between is going to get you in a heap mess of trouble
so
with that message, uh
Thanks again. Julian good talking with you brent
And we'll talk to
You too and our other three listeners sometime soon. Everyone say goodbye
Bye, bud