Welcome to A.B. Testing Podcast, your modern testing podcast.
Your hosts, Alan and Brent, will be here to guide you through topics on testing, leadership,
agile, and anything else that comes to mind.
Now, on with the show.
Hey, hey, Brent.
Hey, Alan.
It's time for another episode of A.B. Testing.
Do you know what number we are?
I do.
I looked it up this time.
Are we 130?
We are.
I mean, I have only one real job on the podcast.
And last time you just went forward without me.
I know.
And I think I got it wrong.
Was that last time or the time before I got it wrong?
It was last time.
What did I call it last time?
128?
Yeah, you were.
And it was 129?
Or are we just permanently off by one now?
No, no.
We're good?
You correctly corrected it in editing.
Wow.
Nice.
Yeah.
So on my little recording device, it's just called 130.
So I guessed well.
That was my guess.
I was going to double check with you.
So here we are recording on Friday.
This will come out on Monday, November 2,
which is one day before the US election.
And I have never in my life been so nervous over an election.
Over an election that 538 says currently Joe Biden,
well, anyone who's not Trump, has a 90% chance
of winning the election.
But I am still nervous because it comes down
to what three or four or five states decide to do,
which seems really fair.
That's what people wanted when they made up
electoral college for sure.
There's crap going on to stop people from voting.
There's crap going on to try and throw candidates under the bus
four years ago.
I wasn't the biggest Hillary fan either,
but I think Trump's a piece of crap.
But I was confident that he was going to go away and do
his talk show.
And then crap happened.
And I have not been happy.
And not because I don't like him.
It's not because I don't like him.
It's because of the things he's done that make me not like him.
Short story is, welcome to the AB testing political podcast.
I'm Alan and do my NPR voice.
And now over to Brian.
So you were mentioning, you were hinting
as we were talking, you have a prediction.
And you being the data scientist,
I hope it's not based on data.
And I hope it doesn't just, I have a knot in my chest
talking about this.
But what do you, what are you nervous about?
What are you thinking about?
So I will, I will share with you what my thought process is.
And then I will assure the three.
This is entirely based on non data sources.
It's, it's, it's more based on you remember back in the day,
when you and I were laughed at repeatedly because we saw
that within the next three years,
the whole of Microsoft was going to get rid of tests.
I do recall this.
Yes.
Well, I wasn't the data scientist then,
but, but my prediction kind of comes from that same space.
So you and I tend to pay attention to what's going on
in the world around us and not in an echo chamber
or even the bubble we live in.
So yeah.
First off, I'm pretty sure I've mentioned that on the,
the podcast, right?
I don't think Alan's ever mentioned it,
but he's, he, what party he's affiliated with,
but he definitely has Democrat leanies.
Well, I had never thought about it much
until the last four years.
My viewpoint is I think people should be allowed
to do what they want as long as it doesn't hurt other people.
And I think people should be treated fairly.
If that affiliates me with a party, then it go ahead.
I believe in the golden rule.
One party is closer to that, at least than the other.
It's interesting.
You say it that way.
Cause your first statement, I completely agree.
I haven't thought about your second statement enough
to decide how I feel.
The problem with deciding that whether or not people
are treated fair is fair as a subjective term,
but I do believe that people should be allowed
to live their lives as they see fit.
I'll just say I am a libertarian,
which means no matter who I talk to,
no matter who I talk to,
I can agree with them that the other guy is an idiot.
And in this case, like we keep hearing that,
that this is about to go into a two party system blows rant.
Oh, a two party system does blow.
Everyone knows that it's idiotic.
We keep hearing- I want rank choice voting
and no electoral college and term limits.
Oh, term limits for everyone.
I'm so with you.
Those are my, I'm gonna run for something.
Class president of the AB testing podcast.
And those are the three things I want.
I want rank choice voting
so we can get other parties involved.
Even if it takes a while to get them to grow,
I want to get rid of electoral college
because it doesn't make sense anymore.
I'm sorry.
Your arguments are invalid and I want term limits
because just turn on the news and you'll see why.
Let me, I'll just quickly glance through
sort of my philosophy and then give you my prediction.
Meanwhile, the listeners are like,
fast forward 30 seconds, still politics.
Fast forward 30 seconds, still politics.
All right, go on.
Up next on the AB testing podcast,
religions and which one's right.
I don't know if I can do anymore, man.
So, right now with the two party system,
I actually view the Democrats and the Republicans
as the opposite sides of one very stupid coin.
And the way I view that they differ is the Democrats
offer freedom and independence on social issues
but want control of fiscal issues.
The Republicans are the exact opposite.
Like the best thing the Republicans as an example
could do for their party is boot the religious right out.
And I think that would attract a large number of centrists
but I am not in a role for political advisement.
A libertarian kind of goes, no,
we want the freedom and independence
on both sides of that coin.
And for those who aren't aware,
the opposite side of a libertarian
is a socialist where as I was saying,
no, no, we want the government to sort of be a big part
and regulate both sides.
Now, that said, so at least on one of those pivots,
you and I agree, my prediction for this election,
I will state that it's a three-parter.
Sadly, I believe Trump will win.
I hope to God you're wrong.
I very strongly believe he will win.
I can even articulate why I think that.
I don't want you to because I don't believe you.
Okay, good.
The second thing I believe is he will be impotent.
I think the Democrats will control enough of Congress
that essentially the next four years will be a no-up.
The checks and balances haven't worked the last four years.
It's been a wreck.
It's been an absolute wreck.
Yes, completely agree.
The third thing, and this is the thing
that I am worried about, you asked what I'm worried about.
It's the third thing.
If I am right on the first one,
it doesn't matter if I'm right on the second one.
I do think the third thing will happen.
And that is literally America will burn.
Yep, I believe you are correct.
And there are signs of what I will call
political blackmail already occurring.
A buddy of mine, and now I haven't confirmed this,
but a buddy of mine was mentioning
that in his neighborhood, he had heard, right?
So this is now a three level indirection.
He had heard of pamphlets being distributed to houses
in suburbs saying if Trump wins,
this house will be damaged or destroyed
or something like that.
Right, Am.
So it's conspiracy land.
Yeah, I don't want to, look.
The thing I'm saying on this front,
the fact that rumors like that are even coming
is what worries me.
I don't care what the thing is.
All right, I'm gonna close this out
because the listeners are super, super bored.
You know, I could only hope that,
I don't believe you on point two.
If Trump wins, I think he's gonna continue to incite hate.
I do not affiliate myself with a political party
so I think the two party system is broken.
It doesn't help that you're being a libertarian,
just those are your political views,
doesn't give you a candidate to vote for
because you can only vote for one of the two.
I got a candidate to vote for.
Yeah, it's a wasted vote.
Yeah, and it's already been,
my wasted vote has already been sent.
If a fraction of the voters that voted
for the third party candidate in the swing states
where Trump barely won voted for Hillary instead,
we'd have a different crappy president right now.
Yes, that's absolutely true.
The data will tell you that.
So anyway, again, I don't like either party.
That's a concern this time too though, right?
Right, because there are actually a lot of left leaning folks
who are essentially.
Hopefully aren't so stupid
to know that their vote is wasted.
And again, because of our lovely electoral college,
your vote only counts if you live in one of 10 states.
Otherwise, nobody gives a crap
who your presidential vote is for
other than bragging rights for the popular vote,
which I guarantee, unfortunately again,
I guarantee Biden will win the popular vote.
I think it's a 0% chance.
Anyway, let's go on with the podcast.
There's your political commentary.
This is gonna come out Monday.
You can pontificate on this.
I took today off to build some furniture
and to putter around the house
because I, as I mentioned last time,
I wasn't earning any more vacation days.
I am taking Wednesday off as an election recovery day.
I plan to stay up late watching and either crying
or being relieved.
I don't know if I'll celebrate,
but I will be up late, gonna take Wednesday off,
try and recover, get my mindset for what,
based on whatever happens
and plow into the rest of the year.
So let's get into the podcast proper.
How many minutes have we gone by here?
Okay, about after editing,
maybe 12 minutes into the podcast.
We had a great conversation, a meeting this week.
So my manager, our VP of engineering,
has a weekly meeting with all the people managers
in his org once a week for 30 minutes,
which is actually really good.
It's a way to have the right conversations,
align on some things.
Sometimes it's business, sometimes it's just a,
what do you think?
And I had forgotten.
This is a question that maybe early on
in our relationship,
I remember sitting at that Vietnamese place
having a conversation about this topic
and you had changed your mind since then.
And I hadn't really talked about it much.
I have strong opinions about this.
Well, strong opinions about the ambiguity of this question,
but it generated a lot, a lot of discussion.
So I wanna throw it at you
and maybe for our listeners for comment.
And here's the question.
As a manager, how many people should you manage?
What's the limit?
What's the minimum?
Minimum?
Minimum, if you're gonna be a manager,
how many people can you effectively manage?
I don't think there, well, okay.
So minimum's actually easier than maximum.
No, minimum's one, right?
Minimum's one.
But if I were in an executive role, right?
Would I ever do that?
And of course the answer is no.
I can put constraints around it.
So I remember these days, like back in the day,
it was four or five and at Microsoft,
there was a phase where needed to be a minimum of 20.
This was when Microsoft was heavily laden on managers.
And now it is, I would say the policy
is a bit more laissez-faire.
It's, we don't see, you don't see too many small teams
and small teams, if they get constructed,
generally you'll see in the next budgetary cycle,
you know, a couple more heads.
Notice how Brent still hasn't answered the question.
Minimum, five.
Maximum?
There it's gonna depend on the person.
What is the answer to any sufficiently complex question?
42.
The answer is it depends.
The answer to any sufficiently complex question is it depends.
Yeah, on that one, but still I wanna come up with a number
and I'm gonna say somewhere around 20-ish is the maximum.
Yeah, and it depends on seniority,
what you're working on, et cetera.
I'm flat, flat, flat, flat, flat.
And I fully believe, yeah, you can manage,
I don't know if I go as high as 20.
I currently have 11 direct reports.
I feel pretty good about that.
People say, oh, it's so many.
And I think, no, I think I'm under control.
But there was a lot of pushback on the team
from having a high number of direct reports,
like more than eight.
So Brent, how do you manage a team of 20?
A standup with 20 people is untenable.
It's not the same topic.
Yeah, yes.
That was an area of pushback that made me go
from leaning back in my chair, going along with to,
whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, hold on.
Wait, wait, wait.
Let's talk about.
Look, I was just thinking through,
I had my data science head on
and one of the things I was thinking through
is essentially like an old econ supply and demand curve.
What would we look at to identify the ideal number?
And then it very quickly comes down to principles.
Now, in this entire discussion,
you've been asking me,
mid and max from managing a team.
I don't give a crap about managers.
What I want is leaders.
And the problem when you have a manager
is with a small team,
they have a tendency to micromanage,
overly focused on the product,
fail to encourage autonomy
and fail to come up with vision
or principles or rallying cry.
On the other side though,
I was just thinking,
what's the biggest issue you have with too large of a team?
And that's, you have to choose what you spend,
like for me,
I currently have a half hour one-on-one
with each of my directs.
At some point in time,
with 40 hours in a week,
that means I could have a max of 80 reports
and all I would be doing is one-on-ones.
Right?
Which doesn't scale at all.
There's other meetings you need to go to.
And by the way,
I also do weekly one-on-ones for a half hour
with all of my directs.
Any other leads in the org,
so if I have leads reporting to my managers,
I'll meet with them every other week.
And then I have another half dozen or so people
I meet with monthly,
maybe 10 people to meet with monthly.
So I spend a lot of time on one-on-ones,
I find it very valuable.
There's something else I was gonna mention, but go on.
Yeah, for me, one of the things that I did,
particularly as at a defense for COVID,
is I kept my one-on-ones,
but when it came down to specific project questions,
I found that my team kept on trying to set up
additional half hour meetings in a one-on-one context.
Right, you had mentioned that before.
Yeah, and so I actually just created
a daily one hour Brent's office hours
and say, that's where you come in
with your one-off three minute question or whatever.
And that's been effective, it's been effective.
I've gotten everyone to a degree of,
I'm able to spend time coaching them through the career,
coaching them through their development.
The team feels like they have a dedicated time
to come in and-
I'm gonna put us back on topic here.
Oh, I thought I was on topic.
Ish, I mean, it's great.
You have one-on-ones, they're effective, awesome.
The other bit of, so one was standups,
and of course, the team size doesn't mean standup,
we've got multiple projects.
One bit of feedback I gave though,
when you go the opposite, which is,
we, you and I have seen at Microsoft in these
where every single different feature area had its own lead,
even if they had one person or 10 people.
And you end up shipping your org structure.
The other thing I want your feedback on
is a lot of people push back on saying,
well, if I'm a line level lead,
now you just have ICEs reporting to me,
I can't manage more than six people
and still provide any tech leadership to my team.
I'm too far away from the tech
once I manage more than six people.
What do you say to that?
I would say that's a person
you should double the size of their team.
Because they're, and I'm serious,
because they're actually focused on managing and not leading.
I agree a million percent.
And it's a wacky solution, but I tell you it works.
It's like, no, what are you gonna do
to put this manager in a position
where he gives up micromanagement as a solution?
No, stop, guide, direct, measure.
It's only been in this position,
this is really the first time where I have not been able to,
managing managers of a team of about 60 people now,
where I can no longer contribute anything technically,
whether it's code, whether it's technical documentation.
I no longer have time for that.
However, even when I managed fairly large teams,
moderate teams of 20, 25,
I could still do non-critical, important tech work
if I wanted to stay sharp.
And I found that very easy to do.
I knew what people worked on,
I understood how it worked.
I just don't get the argument that,
because I'm, and again, I like the fact
that they are putting an emphasis on growing people.
And that does take time.
Recruiting for open positions takes time.
It's hard to fill a team,
but I just do not buy the statement
that once you manage more than six people,
even if they're all super junior,
because they'll take time,
they will take more time when they're junior,
but I just don't believe that stops you
from being able to contribute technically.
Again, lots of variants.
The answer is, my answer is eight, plus or minus five.
Eight plus or minus five is the-
I don't know.
I just made up a number.
Yeah, that would be eight minus five.
So that means, no, that's a bullshit number.
Yeah, of course it is.
Eight plus or minus two, maybe?
Like the Scrum one, that's an easy answer, right?
There's a lot of actual science.
There's actual science on this one,
where the ideal Scrum team is five to seven.
So if you have 20 directs, all right.
And they're probably not all working
on the exact same thing.
I actually prefer that, I don't even like seven.
So I'm going through a challenge related,
not a challenge, a shift in my org,
where a lot of folks have been,
org I inherited, I should say.
People worked a lot on their own.
Here's a project, one person worked on it.
Here's another project, one person worked on it.
A lot of stuff being worked on at once.
Not a lot of things, as you can imagine,
being finished.
What we're working on now is doing more of these projects
that are shared and worked on,
not only by multiple people, but wait for it,
self-organizing teams that span managers.
Now, how do you do a standup?
You do it with the damn people
who are working on the project.
Therein lies the solution, self-organizing teams.
I'm lucky I can do that,
given the nature of infrastructure and DevOps,
whatever you want to call it, work.
We're going to focus on finishing,
and even better, even better, one little plug for me,
and I have another topic to do, we can go more in here,
but in my self-organizing teams,
I love this that the people working on the teams
span different managers.
It's going to work great, I'm pretty excited about it.
But also, I'm giving all of the projects codenames
to end after Hanna Barbera cartoons.
That's pretty cool.
So last week I kicked off Project Grape Ape.
I was just going to ask, I was just going to ask.
I can't tell you what it is,
something came up that I had to set up.
I knew I wanted to do something about it.
I knew I wanted to get a bunch of people involved,
and I knew it was something that if it had,
there were key words I did not want to mention
in the channel title.
So on the spur of the moment, I made up Project Grape Ape.
Somebody asked me, are you talking about
the children's cartoon or the strain of marijuana?
And I said the children's cartoon.
What?
But very cool.
And so I'm kicking one off again.
I took the day off, I didn't send mail today,
but on Monday, I will be kicking off Project Yogi Bear.
Nice, is Boo Boo going to be your last one?
Do you know how many Hanna,
I mean, I have the whole Scooby Gang to go through.
I'm loading it up.
All right.
It is now the single most important thing.
Of course, because you're so ADD.
Snagglepuss.
Yeah, Project Snagglepuss.
Huckleberry Hound.
Oh, I always loved Captain Caveman.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Okay.
Anyway, that's how I handle team size.
It just let teams, well, don't let them,
help them organize.
And I know I've mentioned it before,
and I mentioned it to my team now,
the World of Warcraft guide to project management.
Get a team together.
It's like the end game in World of Warcraft.
Get a team together with varying skills.
Work together to solve a common problem
when you've reached your exit criteria.
Because even in a raid in World of Warcraft,
maybe you don't want to do the whole thing.
You just want to get to the one chest
because you want to help this one guy
get this one piece of armor or whatever.
Whatever the goal is, you accomplish it together,
and then you either take on other tasks together
or you disband.
It's one of the things,
there's a planning event from SAFE
that is very much aligned with what you're talking about,
as we've talked about here before.
Again, I don't like SAFE, so, half.
All right.
Shockingly, does not hurt my feelings.
But the planning event kind of solves that problem,
where basically a business leader comes in and says,
these are the scenarios we need accomplished.
The other aspect that really helps here
is when you do self-organizing teams
is that you have missions and not owners.
Right?
I kind of think of it like a military mission.
Hey, we need to go take out that artillery bunker.
Right?
Once it's done, it's done.
But when you have product teams with feature owners,
there's this general inclination to locally optimize.
Right?
Oh, yeah, Alan.
Look, we just nailed feature food for the United States.
And then Alan goes back, great.
What's it gonna take to go globally?
Oh, well, it's gonna cost the same amount for each country.
Yeah, but the rest of the countries
are only 10% of our usage.
Yeah, well, do you want globally or not?
Right?
It's one of those things where if you were in a more
dynamic scrum type organization,
you might be offered the opportunity to say, no,
actually it's not worth the price tag.
But when you have feature teams, they just,
okay, well, we'll do the next country and the next country.
And I mean, it's a bad metaphor,
but I see that feature teams are product teams
when they go down that model,
they have a tendency to sort of local optimize
instead of global optimize.
Short story is self-organizing teams,
let them figure it out,
give them the help and coaching they need
and Hanna-Barbera project names.
I wasn't planning on getting there
from the conversation about how many people should you
manage, but it reminded me of something.
And I think it depends.
I think I don't like managers
only one or two or three direct reports.
I think it's, I prefer flatter orgs.
It depends on the seniority of the manager,
lots of other things,
but I think it's perfectly capable of managing
well into the teens.
And as you said, 20, I think it's definitely possible.
It just depends on a lot of different things.
There's only one scenario where I like
a manager above a small team.
And that is they are a new manager.
That's it.
That's the only-
Sure, and I wouldn't put it,
I wouldn't give a new manager more than five.
Yeah, yeah, I agree.
Okay, so I have another topic.
Nice.
I don't know if you saw,
a while back in Twitter,
where should I start on this?
Of course we have, plug,
the Introduction to Modern Testing course
on Ministry of Test.
Still getting people going through it.
I think it's really done well.
I've also been thinking about what's next.
If that's the 101 for modern testing,
what's the 201?
Put some questions out on Twitter.
Didn't get a lot of good answers
until I think it was Lisa Crispin's answer.
And I forget what she said,
and I should have brought that up.
Let me see if I can find it in my replies.
No, I can't find it.
But it was something to the effect of,
what does it take to,
the principles are great,
what does it take to be a modern tester?
Or how do you do these things?
That got me thinking,
and sorry, Lisa, for messing that up,
but it got me thinking,
because other things were around the basics
of how do you get developers to test.
And I actually just did a talk on that,
an eight minute talk for Test Flix I recorded.
I don't know, I can't remember when the event is.
I'm sorry, maybe I'll put a link to it if I remember.
But there was that bit,
then it kind of hit me.
Because what I'd like to do is a workshop
for Ministry of Test,
just to promote the course
and to get some more ideas about that.
But the working title is,
so you want to be a modern tester?
We can start off with, well, of course,
DevOps is a culture,
modern testing is a culture.
We have DevOps people to help facilitate that culture.
Hence, we could have modern testers
help facilitate that culture.
So in that, is like,
one of the things,
if you're want to move the org in that direction,
what are the things that are difficult
in those first steps?
One is getting developers to test.
I feel like I have a good model for that
in pairing with them, asking them questions,
working on coaching,
which is getting people out of telling them what to do
versus asking them to think about what needs to get done,
get them to actually shift into that testers mindset.
I think that's one area.
Do you struggle with getting them
to take over accountability for testing?
No.
Because of the way you've described it in the past,
you kind of trick them into it.
It's not, we do trick them into it
by pairing with them or working with them.
And then it's as I've described,
a developer may ask a tester,
can you test this for me?
And instead of saying, sure, yes,
let me please test that for you.
You can ask, well, sure,
what have you tested so far?
Well, nothing.
Okay, let's do it together.
See, it'll be fine.
Maybe the next time it's,
well, I've tested A and B
and they pair together to test on C and D
and eventually gets to the point
where the developers actually done all the testing
and they say it looks pretty good.
Very shortened versions of how that works.
So what happens there is that's a way
to work with developers to get them to be accountable
and feel like they get them over the bridge
where they feel like they can own testing.
But then the next thing that happens
is they don't realize what testing they're missing.
I think continued pairing to get them to think about
after you ask them what testing is remaining
and they can say, I can't think of any.
And you can say, great, what still worries you?
What do you think is still risky?
And then you can probe for questions on perf
or reliability or latency and form hypotheses
that you can go form tests to prove or disprove.
I think there's a topic there.
I don't believe it's a whole 90 minute topic
for like for a workshop, but maybe it is.
Maybe it is, what do you think?
Is there, because the other option
is we could go deep diving in teaching developers to test.
It's not that different from teaching testers to test.
I feel like if we talk about the coaching,
that would cover that.
I think about the two ways
that I've been able to help teams transform.
Honestly, well, it's been the same way.
And I wrote it up in a very, very, very old blog post.
And that is essentially shaking the tree.
It's essentially by leveraging unified engineering
and at the same time sort of removing the QA role from this.
It's setting the expectation that from here on out,
every member of this team is a developer and a tester.
Now, I know for a lot of our community, right?
That's basically saying, oh,
but you're saying that if I want to be a monetization,
I have to learn the code.
I think we can nip that one in the bud,
but I like where you're going because we could address,
this is all principle seven, right?
This is maybe there's an exercise on,
and this may be in the core.
This is actually in the course already on,
what would it take for your team not to have dedicated QA?
What would have to happen?
This is my thinking of it.
In a world where let's say we had two disciplines
on the same product.
Let's say we had dev and P, not dev and PM, dev and test.
Well, towards that product in the prior vernacular,
we would refer to them as specialists.
And as we've mentioned a bajillion times before,
specialists are bottlenecks and modern testing
is anti-bottleneck.
Well, the easiest way to,
how do you take two sets of specialists
and turn them into generalizing specialists?
Well, you force them into an environment
where they have to essentially cross breed.
Now what makes them a specialist here is their knowledge.
So we're not actually asking them to cross breed,
but their knowledge to cross breed.
And you have to put them in a situation where those,
the only way for them to claim success
after say a period of six months,
is that that knowledge was successfully transferred
both ways.
I'll give you a very tight example.
Number one, one of the ways I see these type
of unified engineering orgs poorly implemented
is by putting the prior dev manager in charge.
Because one of the issues is management.
You have two managers often where you only need one now.
Well, no, what I would do is instead
is keep the same number of managers,
but swap, basically do team membership trades.
As an example, let's say you were a dev manager
and I was a test manager, okay?
What you and I are going to do,
we both manage 10 people, okay?
What you and I are going to do is you're gonna give me
your three best developers
and I'm gonna give you my three best testers.
Those three best developers,
they're going to be accountable for driving
whatever relevant knowledge to me, the manager,
as well as to the rest of my team.
But the tester side, right, when it comes down to votes,
because I have seven testers and three developers,
that test side is going to balance out those three folks.
So to be clear, this is your plan for we have a QA team,
we have a test, we have a dev team,
and we're going to just have a dev team,
one way to make that work, I agree.
Yeah.
So really, you wanna mix and match the talent
in a way that enables people to learn.
But we should also talk about, I mean,
again, this was your example comes from Microsoft,
where we experienced at Microsoft,
where at the time you did that,
we largely had test teams who were roughly even equal
in size to the dev teams they worked with.
I think what we'll find that a lot of companies today,
is that's not the case.
The number of QA folks is a much smaller percentage
of the overall staff.
Typically embedded in teams as an agile team,
they still do all the testing, gross.
The flavor of that though still works.
I think to answer the question,
I'm all you're telling me I have to code, no.
The folks that have formally been in QA for me,
some of them are coding,
some of them are quality coaching,
some of them are in DevOps where they do code,
but they're doing different,
it's a lot of infrastructure set up as well.
Some are doing program management or project management.
Anyway, there's a lot of different directions you can go.
Aside from the dev stuff,
let's talk about the other thing that I think is hard
for people who look at the principles.
And that's right up your alley, it's data.
Yes.
So there is something there.
So imagine you're somebody, QA person
or quality minded dev person on a team.
And you look at the principles and go,
yep, we care about the business, yep,
DevZone quality.
You go on down list, you go data.
Now we don't do data.
Or we can't do data because it's,
we're worried about collecting the wrong information.
I could tell you from experience,
a lot of people are afraid of collecting any usage data
because they think it's PII.
It's not.
Oh my God.
Does that drive you crazy too?
No, knowing which button they clicked,
that's okay, that's not PII.
Okay, there's nothing personal about it.
It's fine.
I actually, for a longest time,
that one would drive me nuts.
I still hear that too often.
And this is what I tell them.
Let's play a little game, Alan.
Alan, do you actually know what PII means?
It means personally identifiable information.
Right.
And almost every person I talked to
knows the answers to that, but they have forgotten it.
They don't understand the meaning.
They just use PII, okay?
And I say, okay, so here is a click stream
of a customer going through and clicking our UI.
Tell me how you are able to personally identify this person.
Who are they?
And anything you can tell me about that person is fine.
Like where they live, what their phone number is,
their name, their middle name,
any information that helps to triangulate who they are.
And they're like, well, I can't.
Guess what?
Not personally identifiable information.
Right.
So let's back out a level,
because that one pisses me off and annoys me.
It's not.
So how do we get someone started?
Like if your team does not collect any data,
any customer data, there are a couple challenges here.
There's a technical challenge of picking whatever
off the shelf solution there is to get some of that data,
whether it's Google Analytics for a webpage,
or I don't even know what exists
in the open source world for a desktop app.
But the technical part, what do you collect?
I know the answers to these,
but how do you get the team started?
You have a team who don't care about it
because they haven't collected it.
How do we take a team?
How do we lead a team towards no data
to collecting customer data
that affects decisions in the org?
So it's interesting.
Yesterday, I had a developer from a team
that I know very little about.
They had raised, I'll just cut to short.
One of the things that's very common,
maybe once a month and once every two months,
I will do a one-off mentorship session
with somebody I've never met before,
and I have no idea how they found me.
That happened yesterday.
And he is a developer, just graduated college
in May with a bachelor's in computer science.
And he took one stats and ML course.
And he came to me, wanted to know,
how do I become a data scientist when I grow up?
One of the things I told him,
I'm not gonna go through the whole thing
because the premise is slightly different
than what you're talking about,
but I actually think the implementation might be useful,
is I said, okay, so you're a new guy.
And as you know, well, I don't know if this is universal,
but at Microsoft, new guys in dev,
new people in dev.
Thank you.
Yep.
We'll spend probably the first six months
spending 80% of their time just fixing bugs.
That's how they get their feet wet.
And I said, all right, here is a thought process for you.
This is what I want you to think through.
For every one of your bug fixes,
once it goes to production,
how do you know whether or not
this added value to your customer and or your business
or just wasted your time?
That's it.
That's the question I laid on this plate.
And I said, how do you know that?
And then I followed up and I said,
you're probably gonna dive into it and realize
you don't have the right data,
which is gonna force you to have a conversation around
or at least a thought process around
what data do I need in order to make those two choices?
If you try to simplify,
did I waste my time on this bug fix
or did I add value?
But the key thing there is you have to be able to prove it.
Because a lot of the times dev goes,
oh, I'm sure we added value.
Look, it was a whatever.
And I said, once you do that and you do it repeatedly,
you'll learn from your mistakes.
You're like, crap,
I can't statistically prove that I did it now.
That would be probably less than three.
Great, the trend's looking better, but is it relevant?
What I did is I said,
I framed the mission in a way that resonated with him,
that the more he could proactively determine
without intuition or opinion in play,
whether or not he wasted his time,
that would play out well for him in the long-term.
Anyway, is that at all helpful
or is it me yet again blubiating?
I think there's some nuggets in there.
The question I asked,
the opposite version of the question,
which is how will you know customers
are being successful with this feature?
Well, it's not the opposite.
It's the same question except now on features.
Sure.
Right, you just spent six months doing this feature.
Are customers successful or did you waste your time?
I hope it's not six months.
That helps you figure out,
there's some brainstorming around that
that helps you figure out what you can measure.
There may be a topic in there.
I have a meta question.
So there's one is teaching developers to test.
One is really getting started with data
and maybe a little deeper
because I kind of covered that.
In fact, I use that question in the intro course as well.
But what else do you think is stopping teams
from moving to modern testing?
Tradition I think is the number one.
The fact that in general,
I don't think that the test org has ever
done a great job answering
the implied questions around principle number one
is way up there.
Yes, and I've pointed to it a few times
in one of the three dots, slack.com,
go to moderntesting.org to find an invitation link.
But I wrote an article last year,
year before I can't remember just fighting this.
We always hear about the cost of software testing,
which is the opposite of principle one.
So I forget the title of the article.
I will not probably forget to post a link to it
in the notes, but I wrote an article
for CIO Tech on the value add of good testing.
Didn't say testers, I say good testing.
It's not a cost, it's a value add.
Well, not by itself, it's not.
Just doing a bunch of, well, I guess, nevermind.
Because you qualified it by the word good testing
and more likely than not,
if we were to drill down that, you and I would agree on it.
I think there's something there.
I have to remember, I want four,
and this is not in the short term,
it's batting around in the back of my head.
I do wanna do something, a workshop that dives deeper
into how to make these things happen.
But as I talk through it,
the gusto's going away a little bit
because really what you need is leadership skills.
You need to be able to influence change
and get people to care about what you're doing
and think what you're saying and trying to do is valid.
That's probably the most important thing.
We didn't cover it in either of our two stories.
There are two things that really solidified
what we now call modern testing for me.
Number one is my own personal experience
of managing a dev team without any sort of testing.
Okay, but number two,
it's the agile principle around removing waste from the system
and how valuable that is.
And in order to be able to do that,
you have to be able to confidently identify waste.
And the thing that really resonated with me on that one
was the Eric Rhee story.
Yes.
He had his whole company.
They spent six months working 40 hour days
to produce this one value add system
that at that point in time, they all were true believers.
They all in that organization believed.
None of them had any data, but they all believed
that of course it must be true that this would be a hit.
And they got 20 downloads the day they shipped, right?
It was an abject failure.
They had misunderstood the problem
their customer needed solved.
And I happened to see a presentation.
Eric Rhee came here to Microsoft
and I happened to see him to present.
And he's like, you know, I replayed that whole six months
over and over and over again.
And I realized something,
that if on the day one that we started this,
if we had created a mock-up webpage that said,
hey, welcome to Eric Rhee's magic project,
click here to download.
They could have discovered that same day
just by putting that fake facade up
to see if there was any demand here.
And I remember like yesterday, the question he asked,
and by the way folks,
would I have had to implement that download page
or would a 404 just been fine?
We've told that story before.
I think it's good.
And maybe one of the things is to,
you have to wear a little bit
of that project management hat in order to get past,
of course there's the fallacy of now,
what I'm working on now has to be,
customers have to have it,
and failure to launch, which is this case
of spending too much time waiting for customer feedback.
We do not have time for a rebuttal.
We're gonna have to call, okay, go on.
No, I was just going to agree.
That's exactly right.
It's not even waiting for too much time.
No matter how much time you wait for feedback,
how do you make it faster?
Because that's how you eliminate waste from the system.
Yeah, it's speeding up the feedback cycle.
So maybe there's something there.
I would love to hear back from the three.
You can either reply to the Twitter post announcing this,
the LinkedIn post announcing this.
You can add comments.
You can send us mails.
You can poke us on Slack and let us know what you think
we should be doing for the community
to help them get even further with modern testing.
And I'll try and coagulate that
into some sort of workshop.
That's my plan.
Thanks for a workshop and that with me a little bit, Brett.
Sure.
We will chat again in a couple of weeks.
Is that right?
Post election?
Yeah, well, that's the plan, right?
We'll see if we're both still here.
We both live in the hated suburbia.
So, right, we'll see what happens.
Okay, thanks everyone for listening this far.
I'm Alan.
I'm Brett.
See you next time.