Welcome to AV testing podcast, your modern testing podcast. Your hosts, Alan and Brent
will be here to guide you through topics on testing, leadership, agile, and anything else
that comes to mind. Now on with the show. Hey, Brent, how's it going?
Going good, Alan. All right. That's enough of that small talk. We are not alone today.
We have an old colleague of mine, not old in age, but someone who I worked with.
Let me finish. I'm going to let you finish, Brent. Someone I work with, I think last time
we crossed paths, we'll do a little catch up here about 15 years ago. I'd like to welcome
Sue Lowe to the AB testing podcast. Hi, Sue.
Thank you. Hi, nice to talk to you.
It's been a while, right? I'm going to see if I can recollect. I think I left CE in 2005
and we worked a Windows CE for those of you that were for the millennials there. It was
an old embedded version of Windows. It was fun.
It was IoT before IoT was a thing.
It was ahead of its time. It was ahead of its time. We used to build like entire operating
systems and web services with device drivers that booted off of a floppy disk. Once again
for the millennials, a floppy disk was a little thing you shoved into your computer that had
data on it. Kind of like a USB key.
It wasn't floppy.
No. Well, if you tore it apart, it was, but then you couldn't use it anymore.
I'm not going to try and remember everything. Maybe you, did you move away while working
on CE? Didn't you move to Atlanta or something?
Yeah, I was working remotely.
I remember. But then you came back.
Yeah, my husband had, he wanted to do an academic job and there's only one university here in
Seattle and if you don't get a job there, you have to choose other things. So he went
to Georgia Tech and I went with him and luckily the team let me stay working remotely.
That's cool. And then you decided to come back. So I'm not going to walk through your
whole career because I'm not, well, I do want to catch up a little bit on what
you've been up to since then. There's another bigger topic that you know I want to get to.
But first, let's just, I am curious, both for, mostly for me, but I think the listeners
find it interesting. So what have you been up to the last 15 years?
Well, working on Windows CE turned into working on Windows Mobile and Windows Phone. And I
had a great time working on Windows Phone. I loved that product with all my heart and
it slowly died. As that product disappeared, we all got organized into the Windows team and
I worked on the Windows team for a while until one day I decided I wanted to get back to
devices again and looked around and found a friend on the HoloLens team and managed
to finagle my way into working on HoloLens. So I've been doing that for the last, almost
the year now. And what do you do on the HoloLens team? What's your specialty?
I work with our telemetry data. Part of my work is just watching our reliability and
making sure we fix all the crashes, including some stuff on Unity, by the way. But mostly
a lot in our own code. And then also actually building out the pipeline for our government
product that we have. I want to ask, but I'm probably not allowed
to government product. Well, it's publicly announced. There's a military HoloLens product where
you could imagine augmented reality things you might do with Soldier.
So what's the biggest bug you're worried about with that product?
Leaking data onto the public internet.
Oh, yeah, that's one hack away from everyone being a Soldier.
Right. Which might be fun.
When we work together on Windows CE, you're working on performance, but it was file system
stuff as well. I know in Windows you're on doing performance, looking at low level
performance fixes. What keeps you, you like working in the guts of things.
So what keeps you excited about that? What's interesting about that for you?
I love the chase, you know, investigating really tough things where you've got a sniff of
what's going on and you have to dig and try to figure it out.
You know, when you finally figure it out, it was always a story, you know.
That's a good parallel into the real reason you're here.
I'm seeing some parallels between our main topic of the day and the story you just told.
I always like the debugging, too.
Yeah, I could tell stories, but it's your podcast today, so I'm going to stop.
But I love debugging.
And someone today, I just helped them find a clue.
They said this is like Colombo where we're under where we're uncovering clues to find things.
It's really fun. So I'll stop there.
But let me move on to the real reason you're here and we could talk.
We could do a whole podcast talking about what you've done and the interesting things
you found. And I think it's all really cool.
I love that kind of work.
But what's more important is you have an evil plan to save the world.
Yes. And that is fantastic.
And I want to hear more about it.
Tell me about your evil plan to say.
Actually, don't tell me. I know it.
Tell everyone listening about your evil plan to save the world.
Sure. It started several years ago when I was listening to an NPR story about how
the Hunger Games after the Hunger Games came out,
the number of girls taking archery skyrocketed.
And I said, wow, you know, if big companies like Microsoft and Amazon and Google
were really interested in improving the diversity of people doing software,
they should hire people to make best selling novels and movies about kids
saving the world with software and get more girls and more diverse people
interested in working with software by making it as cool as the Hunger Games made archery.
So I was mostly just kind of talking about this and wishing I could make something happen.
And a friend of mine said, you know, ghost writers exist.
Let's go. Let's make it happen.
And I told them to go away because he was scaring me.
But that, you know, started me on the journey where I said, OK,
if I were to really do this, you know, like, do I have a story?
What would I have as as the basis of this thing?
And it took me probably about a year to come up with the list of characters and a plot.
And so I started looking up ghost writers and realized how much it was going to cost.
So I decided to run a kickstarter to pay for the ghost writing.
And so it does help that having been in the software industry for 20 years,
I knew a lot of people.
I basically emailed everyone I had connected to me on LinkedIn,
which was like 800 people at the time.
And that, you know, since it was something a lot of people in software care about,
trying to improve the diversity of the people in the software industry,
a lot of people helped out.
And so I managed to fund this through a kickstarter.
And it took the author and me together about a year to put it together.
And then, um, me more time to get it published.
And it was just published about a month ago on May 20th.
And it, to be clear, is a book called Raven.
Yes. Which I've read and enjoyed very much.
Thank you.
I'm not afraid to read a young adult thriller.
Yeah, it's targeted at middle schoolers.
And it is funny.
I asked my mom what she thought and her answer was, well,
you could tell it's not written for me.
There's a lot of, you know, like kids talking to each other and lingo and stuff.
And, um, so that's okay.
The, but it's aimed at the middle school, young high school age folks.
Uh, just trying to give my maturity.
I like it.
I honestly, I read that book with a huge smile on my face.
Cause it's just fun.
It's aimed at that age group.
Uh, and it's really just a fun story.
You know, at the end of the day, kids aren't going to read it if it's not a fun story.
So, uh, we did our best to make it something that folks in that age group would enjoy.
And it's, uh, the premise of the book is what if software companies got tired of
waiting for, you know, the ability to hire more people.
Cause it's, it's so hard to find people.
They start running their own academies where you go to the school for free, uh,
spend time there earning the equivalent of a bachelor's degree in computer science.
And when you're done, you work at the company to pay off the cost of your
schooling, and then you're free to go and do whatever you want.
So, and the students are working on this team for the university and the
university, well, the, the academy and the company are hired to
investigate a hack at a bank.
I actually came up with this plot before Experian got hacked.
And then when that came into the news, I was like, I got to publish this
book before more things come true.
Uh, so yeah, they, they are investigating a hack at a bank and, uh, it turns out
to be, you know, a mystery of what's going on earlier.
And with no intention at all on asking like what kept you interested in tech, I
saw a parallel between the story you told me, like the, the, uh, investigation
and the discovery and the detective work and what happens in Raven.
So obviously intentional.
And the book, the book has a lot of, a lot of really cool tech ideas
in it too, which were fun.
So I'm just curious.
How did that work between you and the ghost writer?
Cause I assume the ghost writer maybe didn't have that tech background.
What's that relationship like?
So, uh, I don't have the right to give away my ghost writer's name, but
I'm not asking that.
Yeah.
But she had actually worked in the tech industry.
She was actually a, uh, involved in, uh, the production of windows 95.
And so, um, it, that was,
It narrows it down.
Yeah.
Well, a woman,
but it still won't tell you who it was, but, uh, yeah.
And she had actually even had problems with being, uh, mistreated as a person
in the tech industry at the time.
So it was, you know, she turned out to be a great partner on this last year.
And Brett, you don't know this.
Um, one thing I know, so I've, I can write technical stuff all day.
I did the Howie test software at Microsoft book and articles here and there.
Last year for a nano Rimo, I wrote about 10,000 words of a, maybe 20,000 words
of a, of a business fiction novel about this modern testing thing.
And it's all it's no, but it's awful.
So I'm picking your brain.
So that was, that was part of the intent also of hiring a ghost
writer was to get an actual professional to do it so that it would be a good book.
Yeah.
The stories in my head that I think about when I'm walking, or I go to write them
down and I better just stick to writing a technical descriptions of things, but
it's just really cool.
So in Raven, I really enjoyed how the plot, I don't want to give away any
spoilers, you've done well, how the plot, uh, the problems that we're solving and
even getting to know more about the characters all kind of happened in
parallel.
I think that made it a page turner for me.
I don't know.
I, I don't know if there's a question there or not, but it just, you know, even
reading a book targeted for someone slightly younger than me, uh, it all
kind of fell together.
I, I, you know, as the person I mentioned before, oh, I love debugging.
That's the part that really, that really got me was just watching them
discover the problem and the problem unfold.
And then then the, the students who are, you're talking about, they get their
equivalent of their, their, their BA in computer science, they're all in high
school and smarter than any BA I ever interviewed in my life.
So it's fun.
It's fun.
And anyway, just to comment there.
I, I was kind of proud to sort of get them in there looking at performance
logs and things, uh, you know, as a performance person, having some of the
problems in the story involved performance and similar investigations, the
things I would have done.
Uh, I was happy to get that in there.
Yeah.
And you also covered, uh, some of the Jerry Weinberg says in software,
eventually it's always a people problem.
And the book also covers in the character development, how much the
relationships and conflicts and, and even teamwork among the team members.
Uh, it felt very real to me.
Yeah.
Uh, you know, one of the other things I wanted to portray was the fact that,
uh, software is not necessarily just writing code, you know, there are a lot
of different things that, uh, you can go into and software, it's a pretty broad,
you know, you, you've worked in testing, I've worked in performance, you know,
um, you sure, you have to know how to write code, but it's not necessarily
the thing that you love about it.
And one of the characters, it didn't entirely come out, but it was specific to
her, but like, uh, the character, um, Wiz was intended to be somebody who was
actually really good with people and understanding people and figuring
out what people needed.
And, um, other people were intended to have different kind of focuses
on what they were good at.
Uh, so I wanted to show that you didn't have to love writing code in
order to love working on software.
Yeah.
And that definitely comes out.
And, and as you know, like I've mentioned, I've been in more infrastructure
and, and DevOps roles, which are a lot about there's use code to solve some
problems, but it's more about just kind of making things work, making
things easier to solve.
And of course, working in performance, it's, you mentioned earlier, it's
looking at a lot of data than figuring out what to do.
And then maybe writing code to help you in some ways to help you understand
what you're looking at.
And then of course, looking at the code to figure out how does this relate
into what's happening here and what can we fix here?
And that thinking part is a lot of fun.
Right.
Brent,
I wonder if it's just a maturity model.
Like I was just thinking through, it has been a long time, uh, since I've
cared about the code I write, it's more around taking an idea and giving it birth.
Right.
It's solving a problem that wasn't solved before.
Like, um, Pete, my, my, so I have a 10 year old daughter.
Um, I, I've started sort of walking her through Python and it's interesting.
And I'm learning very, uh, a bunch of different things.
Both of my boys, uh, have learned Java.
They were older.
She's very different for her.
It's interesting because coding needs to be a social event.
Right.
Unlike me sitting down and writing code, uh, very introspective for her.
It's, it's, she's having fun.
If I'm sitting there with my laptop next to her writing code too.
Right.
It's if I, if I, if I close my laptop to start making dinner, her interest just
plummets, but I saw her doing some of the things this last time.
I don't know why I got on this topic, but I saw her doing things this last time.
Um, oh, I remember knowing where eventually, but not always gets to a point.
This is, um, I, I, I, I deserve the reputation of, I say in 20 words,
what takes three, I saw her going up on stack exchange and doing searches and
trying to find Python code that she could, she could copy paste.
And I'm like, wow, she's, she's, she's almost an actual professional.
Anyway, she asked me, you know, what languages do I know?
And, uh, and, uh, and I, I listed them off, but then I told her, I'm like,
what the reality is in my humble opinion, uh, I know them all now.
Uh, it's just, uh, it's because the patterns of coding languages are
all essentially the same, uh, they just have different approaches, like a
functional language, uh, sure.
I could code in it.
Don't want to.
It hurts my head.
Um, uh, in with one link, uh, link paradigm, I just can't get my head
wrapped around that one, but anyway, that was the aspect is the coding
language is not at all interesting anymore to me.
And I'm wondering if it's, if that's just because we're all, uh, experienced
and in, uh, you know, have, have time behind our belts on in this industry,
like the glamor of a new language and whatever.
I would like to point out that over the last week, I've been learning rust
and, and I like it.
I don't even know what I I've heard of it, but I don't know what
you would use it for.
It's actually for anything.
It's a, it's actually a lot like C and C plus plus with better
memory management.
So, uh, yeah, I've, I've enjoyed it so far.
Um, I don't know what I'd use it for.
Anything I write these days is in, actually, I don't write much code
anymore, but probably Python is the most you after writing C forever, uh,
Python, probably what I use the most.
So anyway, uh, Brent, the good story, uh, the, um, that nobody can see
my eyes roll in the podcast.
I have some more book questions, but before I forget, I do want to, I
know I'm pretty sure you do some other things for like English,
like extracurriculars to also get more people involved in tech.
And one of them is a thing that.
Another old colleague of ours, a former employee of mine still at
Microsoft did for a while.
I know you're heavily involved in now is hunt the wampus.
So I'm sure, which I want to hear about, but what else are you doing?
What's going on?
You're doing, you're doing stuff for people and I want to hear about it.
Wampus is one of the major other things I do.
Yeah.
Uh, before we go into that, I guess I don't, I'm trying to think of what
other I organized for my hockey team, but that's not particularly related to
software, um, I'm kind of a sucker and get involved in lots of things
because people can just sense that I can get involved and organized.
So, uh, it's a challenge to say no.
Um, so hunt the wampus.
Yeah.
I doubt other than you and I, maybe nobody knows what that is.
So tell me about it.
I would love to hear who it was that you worked with, but before we do that,
um, hunt the wampus is a program to get more students into computer
science by, uh, taking the students in a class, um, a computer class and
forming them into teams and then having mentors go help them, uh, through
a project, building a hunt them up this game.
So we give them a spec for how the game should be played and then help
them figure out how to turn that into objects and each student owns an object
and they work together to make this game.
And the really cool thing is, you know, they start out excited.
They have all these grand ideas for how they're going to make their game.
Uh, and then they get all bogged down in confusion because they don't actually
know how to turn that into something.
And we help them through all that confusion.
And then at the end, they've produced something that isn't quite what they
had dreamed up, but is at the end more than what they kind of expected
out of themselves and feel really proud about it.
So it's, it's really fun to mentor students through it.
And one of the cool things also is that the schools that we work with, we
end up growing their computer science program.
So I've been working with Redmond high school for about a decade.
When I started, we had one class, the computer science that we were working
with and this past year we had five.
And in fact, every year he keeps coming back and saying, yeah, I have more.
So that's cool.
It was, um, Evan Goldring was doing some of that many years ago.
He, he, uh, was involved in that.
It's a super cool program.
And I think it it's, it's across multiple.
I don't remember anymore, but it's across multiple high schools, right?
Yeah.
We work with, I think it was six area high schools this past year.
Um, the, and even it's been, we've had little sprinklings of things outside
of the, uh, Seattle area as well.
But the truth is, you know, we organize Microsoft mentors.
And so it tends to be here in the local Seattle area.
When I was in Atlanta, that's when I got involved.
I brought it to one of the high schools in Atlanta.
I was going to ask if it's spread out and, and now that the workforce of
every company is spread out amongst the whole world.
Uh, it's, it, maybe it could spread even wider this, this year.
Did you do hunt the wampus virtually or did it happen or what happened?
Uh, we, yeah, we work each spring.
Uh, we start in the schools around the end of January and then go through
the spring semester and end at the end of the school year where we
bring them all to Microsoft.
We, so we, not much of that happened.
Yeah.
So we, we did get started.
Um, most of our schools got about a month into it and then, uh, yeah,
the mentors weren't allowed at first.
It was no, no visitors.
The mentors weren't allowed to go to the schools and then eventually
all the students were sent home.
And, uh, for the most part, we just ended up shutting down the program.
We had two teams of students continue.
Um, one was a group of students who just self-organized at Redmond high
school and one was, there was a private school that we brought in for the
first time this year, uh, East side prep.
And those students, uh, the school was very, very well prepared to do things online.
They already had classes going on teams.
Uh, and they actually sent their students home earlier than the rest of
the public schools around here.
And so they just continued with business as usual and their mentors would help
them through the project over teams and, uh, everything was working great for them.
So they continued and this one group of determined students at Redmond high
school continued, and so we got two projects.
That's given the circumstances.
That's still very cool.
Hey, Brent, have you heard of hunt the wampus before?
I played it back back, uh, when I was seven, eight, the program, uh, that,
that sugus described, I had not, and I'm extremely interested, right?
Um, uh, one of the things that, that it is very possible, like, uh, my middle
someone, when he was coding, he'd never mentioned the term hunt the wampus,
but he had a similar thing where it ended with a field trip at Microsoft.
Right.
He might've been wampus.
He spent the, the entire day in a building 33.
Um, the, uh, I'll have to, I'll have to ask him the, but for my daughter, one of the
things, um, so have you gone into the lower age range I've gone through and.
She's, she's more advanced than, uh, what's that beginning thing that starts the
beginning programming thing that starts with an S scratch.
That's it.
Thank you.
Um, yeah.
Um, so she's more advanced than that, but, um, certain coding constructs confuses her.
And, and originally I had started with, um, uh, headfirst, uh, learning the code.
And love the headfirst series, but even that's too advanced.
So now what I've been looking for is, is, um, uh, little, little, very simple
projects where it's very clear the outcome.
It would be fun to do and now sort of reverse, reverse teaching her coding.
Instead of like sort of teaching her, this is what a for loop does.
And this is how to use it.
So instead of teaching the widget seats would begin to end and then go back
and explain the widgets, but what I'm looking for is sort of a open source, uh,
listing of little projects like that, that she can select from, um, doesn't
seem like that aspect has been well enough organized yet.
They like, like code kata for teens and tweens.
Right.
Exactly.
But yeah, my kids have lots of fun on code.org making little things.
That's basically scratch though.
And it's not, it's probably too boring for a, uh, someone your daughter's age.
Yeah.
She, she has this dream.
Um, her heroes right now are the female developers at, uh, Roblox.
She can list them off.
Sadly I can't, um, and she kind of wants to follow in the, in, in those shoes.
I love that.
She's got some role models.
Yeah.
Are these, are these, um, the people building Roblox or people
building cool stuff on Roblox?
Yes.
Both.
Yeah.
Yes.
Um, and so she comes in and, uh, she comes in.
But some of the systems there, it gets her the ability to sort of
design things and she can sell things.
I haven't, I haven't dove enough into it to, to go, what exactly is she doing?
Um, I probably should.
Cause I think I can tie that to her coding adventure.
Anyway, Roblox, I've not takored a lot with it, but I did show my 11 year old
how to install their dev kit and get started.
And she was making her own platformer games within 15 minutes.
I was very impressed.
It's a great way to get some kids started.
That's impressive.
Yeah.
That's way easier than unity.
And I can say that,
yeah.
Uh, having spent, so when I got started on the HoloLens team, I, you know, it's
not my job to write HoloLens apps, but I wanted to see what it was like.
So I set aside a day and said, I'm going to spend this whole day learning how to
write HoloLens apps.
And four hours later, I was still trying to get unity and visual studio and
everything that we needed installed correctly in order to get started.
And that was enormously frustrating.
And that's something that we definitely need to fix for our product.
And, uh, I was impressed that Roblox just had an instant, you know,
download and you're done.
Yeah.
Both of my kids have gone through a programming and unity course for teens.
Uh, they're 16 and 14.
Uh, they did this a couple of years ago, maybe two summers ago.
Anyway, they can, they both, uh, learned some of the basics of it, but, uh, the,
the learning curve is it's there.
You can do some basics pretty well.
Uh, but yeah, getting it once you start trying to get to work with a
bunch of other things, it's a little bit of a, huh, what?
Yeah.
So yep.
Room for improvement there.
Uh, we can work together on that.
Yes.
Yeah.
So, um, for better, for worse, I don't work on that part of unity.
I just work in, in the ads business.
I make sure that game developers can make money off of their games.
Also important.
It is, it is.
Uh, so let's go back to the book a little bit.
I just have a couple more questions.
So maybe you can, I don't know if we can do this or not, but without any
spoilers and you mentioned earlier, you read the book with a smile on your face.
Do you have a favorite part of the book or a favorite?
And again, maybe you can't answer this without spoiling, but I'm curious, uh, did
like, was there a part of the book that turned out even better than you
expected, maybe I'll put it that way.
Uh, I can answer that without spoiling.
Uh, the spoilers are some of my favorite parts, but, uh, the, um, one of the
things that kind of happened as I and the writer went along was, uh, we ended up
kind of modeling a software development environment that is a lot more wholesome
than many, you know, uh, there's this character mom who's, you know, trying
to take care of the kids and like making them eat their vegetables and stuff,
you know, and always making sure that if they're up late working on something
that they get a sandwich, you know,
mom is awesome.
And it, you know, even, yeah, I'll just say that throughout the book, mom is awesome.
Yeah.
And, and so I was really proud, but it's more than just that, you know, like
there's Carver who's running the school, the academy, uh, and kind of, uh, I
don't know, quarterbacking their team also.
Uh, and between the two of them, they're watching out for the welfare of
the students involved, not just, um, you know, working them to death and, and
focusing on the goals, but also focusing on them as people.
And that is something that I was kind of proud of modeling in the book was a more,
you know, people centric development environment.
Yeah.
Very cool.
Like it definitely came across.
So, uh, you missed it before you logged in.
Uh, as you know, I've read the book, but Brent, uh, you
say you have, you have a copy for your daughter.
She hasn't read yet.
Is that correct?
Oh yeah.
Uh, yesterday I went up and looked up, um, uh, and, uh, downloaded it to my daughter's
Kindle.
She, she's awake yet.
Uh, so, or she's awake now.
Um, but so she hasn't looked at her Kindle because the first thing she does
is breakfast and then she goes, um, goes on the roadblocks.
Yeah.
I, I, I will, we won't have it for today, but I look forward to hearing her reaction.
Uh, I'll share it.
I'll share it.
Um, and it's nothing else.
Uh, I'll, I'll send whatever feedback to you directly soon.
Yeah.
It's a fun read.
And also I see from your website, there's some positive reviews coming in.
Uh, I won't ask you to say to share your sales information, but I hope the
book is going well because well, actually, let me ask.
It this way.
We'll where are we at right now with the, the concept of maybe having a book too?
Um, I would, I would love to make a book to happen.
Uh, at the moment I'm spending my time focusing on trying to, uh, do a
good job with book one, you know, uh, I sent out feelers to get help from all
from people and all sorts of things like libraries I should talk to about
carrying the book and youth organizations.
I should donate copies to things like that.
And I haven't followed up on all of those things yet.
So I'm trying to complete my mission on book one before getting started on book two.
Understood.
Yeah.
I would love to.
Um, I just have to, uh, I don't know, convince myself that it's worth it.
And the number of people that I'll reach, but you know, the funny thing is like
the best way to market book one is to have a book two, right?
Uh, the best way to get more readers is to keep writing.
And so we'll see.
I would love to make it happen.
I just have to justify the expense.
You know, I have to be asking people to donate to another Kickstarter.
And, um, the time wasn't really that bad on my part.
So.
Do you have plenty more ideas?
Do you have more ideas?
Do you have, do you have additional plots and technical problem solving things?
I actually have another plot that I like even better than the first book.
So, so exciting.
I like it enough that I kind of want it to be book three, but I have to come up
with another idea for you have to find your empire strikes back to go in the
middle.
Yeah.
You should lead with, uh, uh, that last statement, um, as you try to succeed
in your mission on with Raven, right?
And that might be enough to say, to inspire your audience.
Oh, if we could just push Sue over that boundary, we'll, we'll get that paper.
Yeah.
Well, um, yeah, if you want to help support it, then buy books
for the young folks in your life.
So, you know, just kind of encourage them to think about themselves in a software
career, how have you been, uh, how have you been surviving during COVID quarantine?
How's the big going for you Sue?
It's been good.
Actually.
So, uh, we've had a nanny watching our kids ever since we had kids and, uh, our
nanny has still been coming every day to watch them.
So unlike many parents with young kids, it hasn't been that hard on us, uh,
during the day we can, uh, have a pretty normal work day.
So overall, if anything, I'm working too much and need to find
better ways to set boundaries.
I've heard that before too.
Yeah.
It's, it's definitely, you know, I was working from home most days before
because none of the teams, none of my team is in the Seattle area.
They're all in San Francisco and, uh, UK and Helsinki and maybe, and maybe
a few other places, so it's just been getting used to, uh, just getting used
to them all being home to Brent.
On the other hand is, have you just blown up yet or, or what's, are you
survive, are you getting any better at handling this Brent?
No, no, it is.
It, it is absolutely thankfully it's slow, but it is absolutely a steady,
consistent decline.
I can't predict when I'm going to go crazy, but I can, I can feel it every
single day getting closer and closer and closer.
Uh, however, I think I understand now the primary cause, um, uh, last week
we had a meeting free day and I was completely recharged.
I'm like, ah, a day where no fricking PM can spontaneously set up a 30
minute meeting on my calendar.
Oh, fantastic.
Uh, and that's all I got things done.
Um, so the, the, the, I don't think it's the working from home so much as
working from home is, is inspiring far too much time on my calendar spent
talking and not enough doing in that, that, that lack of balance is, is
driving me insane today.
In fact, unfortunately I overslept, but today my half hour meetings
were supposed to start at six, six in the morning.
Uh, they don't end till 5 PM and it literally is back to back to back to
back all the way through lunch, half hour meetings.
Uh, everyone asked me for status.
So bad plot ideas for the Raven series, a whole book where they can't
save the world because they're too busy in meetings all day.
No, no, no.
But you know, if you want your villain, you know, that could be the, the,
um, the origination story for the village.
Crazy because of it.
Oh my well, Sue, it's, uh, it's been really fun having you on the podcast.
Thanks for doing this.
I, I, I saw the, I missed the kick and I, if there's another kickstarter
for book two, I will be part of the support for that.
I, I missed seeing a kickstarter the first time, but I did see on LinkedIn,
I said, wait, I know this person and that was like a cool idea.
And I got the book right away and it's a good read.
And so for anyone listening, I read it for yourself, read it for your family or
get it for your family, get it for your kids, get it for your friends, kids.
Uh, let's get the word out because not only is it, is the premise behind
your evil plan to save the world.
Really, really cool.
Uh, but you ended up with a really nice product.
You, you solve the problem very well.
You saw a problem.
You said, I'm going to do this.
And your solution for that problem was just, it's, I think it's fantastic.
So, uh, I will put when I post this on Monday, I'll have links to both your
evil plan to save the world and, uh, links to, I don't know.
I can't, I can't decide if we're hating Amazon or not right now.
I can do an Amazon link, but, uh, whatever, whatever other link to everything.
Yeah.
I will, I will look at your site and see whatever links you have to whatever
bookstores are around, but definitely worth checking out.
And, uh, any, any final words from you, uh, Brent or Sue before we close for today?
Well, one thing I want to call out is, uh, with, with this, with Sue, I
don't know that we went into her evil plan sufficiently enough, but she's
trying to spread the word, uh, like we talked a great deal around getting
girls to code, um, that's a big part of it up on Kindle right now.
Uh, it's 99 cents.
It's she's, she's not just like with this podcast.
Sue is not doing this, uh, to, to get rich.
It's just, it's to share and spread a message and, and to try to change how we,
uh, impact interest into the tech and sciences.
Um, I believe, tell me where I'm going.
Yeah.
No, I, I priced it absolutely as low as I could.
Um, any money I make off of it, I'm going to donate.
So, um, it's, it's all about trying to, uh, change people's perceptions about
jobs and software, and in fact, I've put in enough money.
I'm never going to break even.
And that's fine.
Uh, the other thing I'm doing, uh, lately, uh, since the social
unrest that's been happening is I started to try supporting black authors.
There's a community amount around the self publishing industry that I got
in involved in, and I volunteered there that I would read and review
books by black authors.
And I've been posting book reviews on my evil plan to save the world.
So another way people can help is just go look at the book reviews.
And if there are any books that look good, go buy them from these authors.
So.
I would love to continue with that, by the way, as I keep going, when I
finished this first round of books that I've committed to read and review, I'm
going to keep going with books, uh, any books that promote diversity in STEM
and tech, so just keep a look there.
It's beginning to sound like your evil plan to save the world.
Isn't actually so evil,
but it makes it more fun to call it that.
It does.
Uh, I'm, I'm massively impressed.
Thank you.
Thank you for having me.
Yeah.
Our pleasure again.
It's good to catch up with you.
It's only been 15 years, but, uh, uh, it's, it's great to talk to you
again and hear you've been up to and just congratulations on, on doing such a.
I'm doing what you've been doing.
It's it's, it's, it's just really impressive for me.
I'm, I'm, I'm really in awe.
So thank you.
Thank you.
It's been fun.
Okay.
Well, thanks.
Uh, please everyone check, check out everything Sue talked about and, uh, and
let's do this support more diversity in tech, uh, more actually, I shouldn't say
in tech, let's just support diversity everywhere.
All right.
Gosh, seems so easy.
Uh, thank you again, Sue.
Uh, thanks Brent.
Thanks for hanging out and we'll see everyone next time.
Thank you.
Bye.