Welcome to AB testing podcast your modern testing podcast your hosts Alan and
Brent will be here to guide you through topics on testing leadership agile and
anything else that comes to mind now on with the show it's day 1000 of the
pandemic and I'm Alan and I'm Brent maybe it's not day one thousand what it
is is episode 147 of the AB testing podcast right Brent right if you divide
it by pie and round up and then square it I'm sure that's close to a number and
then if you speak that number and then play it backward it will be a secret
message from Brent and I to you all three of our listeners right yeah I'm
staring at a Dave Grohl quote are you a fan of the Foo Fighters I'm a fan of Dave
Grohl I like a lot of Foo Fighters songs I think Dave Grohl is really really
cool at it he is really cool like I'm a big fan on YouTube just as a very quick
tangent no we don't do tangents on this podcast come on he he he has this thing
where he goes and does gigs and then pulls random people yeah yeah I've seen
those YouTube videos that's why I'm a Dave Grohl fan he's a cool guy he is
and I'm addicted to those videos the ones where he pulls random people yeah
yeah these kids that come up and shred and makes him think of firing his band
members anyway I'm staring at a David Grohl quote right now that's relevant to
your last comment right if you if you play a Nickelback song backwards you'll
hear messages from the devil but even worse if you play it forward you'll hear
Nickelback you know man Nickelback are just the band everyone loves to hate
and really for good reason yeah we should do a podcast of music reviews we
should review music sure I'm I'm I'm I'm down for that let me see what's good what
have I listened to recently I know I have some deep tangents we could get into but
we won't I don't think no let's do a podcast what is I gotta think there is
well let me stop it not from our list able to lead with is it is this this
thing that we're dealing with ongoing pandemic and the ongoing work from home
madness it's not madness I don't mind I don't mind it it's actually good for me
but it's getting what I've been thinking about is there's it's been a lot more
monotonous than the first 25 years of my career there's nothing to break it up
I come to my desk I do a bunch of meetings all day do a little bit of
work and typing and then I do the same thing the next day which is different
then maybe the way most of my career is gone there's things to break it up
there's whether it's travel or an event at work or some social stuff there aren't
enough things in between it's just the same thing every day so I'm doing fine
but I worry on the impact of that on in fact I worry about the impact of that
far more than like I just just before we were on here I was watching yet
another anti-mask protest just it's not harming children they're back in school
if they were still being remote there is some harm in that in the long term I'm
I'm seeing it with my workers I'm seeing it with me we have a big rat hole I'm
gonna go down that I don't want to get to but how are you and your team feeling
like are you feeling burnt out feeling good and energized how's it going I'd
say there's a diversity right I am coming into work there's no one here but
then I am on constantly on slotted with new and interesting things I guess one
one difference between us is so early on when you and I first met you were sort
of anti-manager I will never be a manager something yeah I'm paraphrasing
well and I'll remind listeners why in a moment but I'll let you finish yeah and
so now not only are you a manager right you're you're you're one of those you're
the man right you're one of those hippos that suppress the rest of us you're way
up there and one thing I guess I have learned that you either haven't learned
or have definitely avoided needing to learn it right I have learned that I will
never again in my career man I say this with with a knock on wood be a middle
manager because that I am just not wired for that job front the frontline
management is where it's at for me it's the right balance between keeping my hands
dirty and and providing strong leadership and I'm able to do that at a high-scope
because of the type of job I do like I'm going to senior executives and and
having cogent conversations around strategies to me it's sort of an ideal
thing whereas a middle manager job and I wouldn't like are you you're do you
have managers of managers of managers underneath you know that's a lot of
managers to count I have some of my direct reports have leads okay one of
their leads has a lead himself so that's as deep as it goes but we're not very
deep either my skip level is our CEO right right yeah so I'm trying to decide
if you're if you're upper management or middle management I don't know but the
there may be a tag on my underwear that tells me let me check in a second yeah
we're pausing anything no my pants are off but so far I'm not sure what I am
okay yeah there's a quote out of context could be really bad yeah sure so while
you're thinking I'll go ahead and address the the pin from a moment ago
and you're right I did not want to be a manager at micro at the time I
realized took another realize out Microsoft what we had managers do at
Microsoft was it wasn't fun managers would pride themselves on being in
meetings all the time thought it made them feel important and then you got to
be forced to stack rank your team twice a year once a year whatever it was and
that just didn't seem very fun to me I wanted to be able to get stuff done and
the managers that were around me didn't actually get anything done
eventually I learned how to find a role where I could be a manager who could get
stuff done and that worked out much better for me so I like being a manager
now it's working out very well especially in my older age but I get
stuff done and my team gets a whole bunch of stuff done so it's different
than the managers I was exposed to at the time when I was telling you that
because I did truly mean it at the time and there are plenty of reasons to not
want to be a manager at Microsoft in those times yeah in in that case it
wasn't it wasn't so much then that you didn't want to be a manager I didn't want
I didn't want to have a job where I was supposed to be a dick all day yeah no
and that's one thing that's one thing that's nice with the the Satya error
error it's not how he rolls right it so he he's he's basically starting the train
where if you're a dick you're gone good good I think that would be good to see
I think I knew a lot of folks we talked about this for who could be dicks and
be aggressive or harassing and it would take Microsoft years to get rid of them
so I love the idea if you're a dick you're gone one thing I really loved
you know as part of the train that's just under Satya as well it used to be
Microsoft you poaching was illegal frowned upon you could not go to another
team and try and recruit someone eventually someone on HR got smart and
said you know what if they want to do that that's fine and I remember HR I
don't praise HR a lot that Microsoft but they had the sassiest little comment
on their fact and basically said something like hey if poaching is allowed
what happens if my whole team goes to work for other managers and the answer
was well that I guess you're not a manager anymore it allows a team to vote
with their feet yeah no I mean I haven't seen that comment but the one
where HR came out with the guidance of proactively saying there is now no
longer an anti-pooching rule yeah that was right that was a bit of a turning
point to that made stuff a lot easier and one of the comments that they had in
that is we want to make it clear the only way to ensure your employees stay
with you is to make a better environment where they are at than alternatives
yeah and I'm like that is fantastic fantastic it sort of sets the stage now
that doesn't that doesn't prevent people using fear-based tactics or I didn't
prevent it but the the DNI initiatives have then prevented that tactic so a
fear-based tactic was the case where like let's say you reported to me Alan
and I was a complete dick and and I get the hint that you're leaving and I just
point out blank and say hey Alan I'm just gonna be super clear you leave before
this date I am going to completely screw you in your in your connect and make
sure HR is involved and probably get you fired you know whatever that was
that was unfortunately common it was a less uncommon at least it's far less
common like now it's the the needle has kind of swung the other way it's it's
kind of really hard to fire somebody now the latest one I have heard of just
just completed last week and it was two years in the process yeah yeah I don't
like that at all one thing to bring up along that is you know one of the the
straws that broke that mixed metaphor there leading to me leaving Microsoft I
I was in a job I liked the culture wasn't great there was a lot of sucking up my
manager was a complete jerk and Brent mentioned connect earlier that's
Microsoft's version of a perf check-in over review yeah yeah yeah and is the
first time I managed to make it through and I got lucky I made it through 22
years at Microsoft before I had a manager literally make stuff up in my
connect that I didn't do stuff I had never heard of because we didn't even
deliver on this and just nice little WTF and also huh wonder what else is out
there moment and he has he has since lit left the company so I can't exactly
you know check in and see what's happening with that level of dignity
because he left on his own accord he got a VP job at some financial place yeah
I'm those type of people good riddance no kidding no kidding hey I want to use
this topic to segue and we can always bounce around because we do we had a
question to talk a little bit more about being quality coach and maybe a
day in the life of a quality coach and what it's like and I want to talk about
it a little bit also have a proposition I'll make to you here but it's a segue
because you mentioned to me an episode or two ago when I gave the book called
the coaching habit a big plug yeah that it is there's like a course or required
reading or something around that can you maybe talk a little bit about that
in a moment because I think what that book teaches you is that coaching is
different than consulting and often as a quality coach end up doing both you
end up both giving advice and and helping me a bootstrapping some work
getting people on the right board just telling them what to do I would see that
as the consulting hat but the coaching hat is where the long-term stickiness
comes from yes getting people to reflect on what it is they're doing and and why
it's important and why quality is important for customers etc so I want to
hear the story about what how how that's going at Microsoft coaching habit
and tie that in we'll talk a little bit about maybe what I've done in my roles
as a quality coach but what I want to propose to you is you know I haven't done
an AB T AB T 343 in a while I will take volunteers if you want to be just you
and me doing a little interview for 20 25 minutes let me know we'll get you
set up and Melissa Eden who's on my team very everyone knows Melissa was on an
AB T 343 but her whole role I mean it's expanding well beyond quality coach now
but it may be good to have her on to talk about her experience doing that
sometime in the near future as well doing quality coach yeah yeah okay cool so
yeah no no I definitely think our audience would love to hear from someone
on the the ground floor of quality coaching right in ideally would be
someone outside of your org right yeah it'd be great so for somebody else doing
it don't contact me too I just right yeah you get a little bit of the unity bubble
when I bring Melissa in well yeah and just to be clear the questions that I
want her to be comfortable answering is like okay what are the difficulties that
she didn't she didn't inform you of for you know whatever reason I don't think
anything like that will come up when you go back to maybe our previous
conversation in whatever label you decide to call me one thing I've trained
my team very well on is to know that I I have ideas all the time very very few
to none of them are good ideas and they're not afraid to call me out on it
we have a pretty high level of transparency so I don't think there's
gonna be any secret sir that would come out I have a similar philosophy with my
team I'm like look my a big portion of my job is to make decisions a big
portion of your job is to make sure I'm making good ones yeah what you're gonna
find I'll guess a little bit what she'll talk about and what will we can I do
want to hear the whole coaching a Microsoft story but what I think we'll
find is that the difficulty is getting people to care what you have to say you
can't just I can go point at my dog back here and say hey your quality coach now
but the challenge is to build that credibility you know Maxwell talks about
these five levels of leadership first you're put in a position of
leadership been appointed quality coach but second people have to give you
permission to lead them so you have to there's work to build that credibility
and and show results and all the things to do that that have to happen before
you can really be successful in that role it's not something you just take a
you're not gonna hire a college grad like the old look at the old Microsoft
s-debt we get some college folks who are programmers and had a good mindset
for or skills for debugging or analysis and we make them testers you're not
gonna be able to hire someone out of college to be a quality coach you need
experience on the front lines either in probably in testing at this stage but
maybe in agile coaching or working with another quality coach for years it's
not a job for a junior or even slightly less than junior employee no no and the
thing is like you even you even talked about it right the I would say the
single most important job of any coach period is it's this will be generic
statement but it's to make it stick for a for whatever is the important it in
that context is make it stick and so I don't see I don't see how you make it
stick in a world where where you don't have the experience around around either
the topic or interacting with with with other knowledgeable people on the topic
yeah I could even to build on your make it stick it's to sustainably improve
performance does that work for the yes coach as well as the quality coach yes
actually that that I like and if you if you underline the term sustainably then
then I'm I'm a hundred percent of board yeah I like that definition yeah you
got to teach people to fish yeah tell me I want to hear the story but keep I
keep on sidetracking you but tell me the story about what's happening with the
coaching habit and coaching at Microsoft um well I would say right now the story
is is is nascent we'll see so so Microsoft has in this this started up
officially last year they did a study that that essentially showed that there's
a lot of crappy managers and yeah and the the the problem is is that there's a
diversity around the definition of what is a good or a crappy manager so the one
thing that Microsoft is doing is they're they're aligning with essentially the
the statement that that you just said right my job as a manager right back in
back in the day we would have conversations around what's the job of a
manager right and some people would go oh it's purely people group some people
like well it's no no no they need to manage the project and then of course
just some place in between and as an aside for leads in my org it's they know
they are responsible for three things people project and tech they have to
manage the people they have to do the project management estimation delivery
for their team and they have to be the technical leader for their team of course
they can if as the team grows they can delegate a little bit of that they can
have if they have a senior IC on their team to do some mentoring and coaching
or just technical leadership that's fine too but they're ultimately
responsible for people product and tech people project and tech right so so so
project and tech would fall into the would be two subcategories of the the
prior category I mentioned the people project in tech I'm in alignment with that
so what Microsoft is doing is you could essentially say is no actually we need
all three very similar to what you're saying although on the project side or
there's multiple different ways to to skin that cat so they are putting in what
they've identified is of course the greatest weakness is around the people
side because a lot most managers that Microsoft in my view were were promoted
were the best I see at whatever the task at hand is and so there's a struggle
often whenever I get a new mentee that just got promoted to a lead job right one
of the first and most valuable lessons I teach them is what got you here ain't
gonna get you there right that the now that you've accepted this this lead job
be aware that even though you are probably still the best IC on your team
you need to view that skill set is completely useless otherwise you're gonna
burn out just completely fast but you can't be a lead and the number one IC on
the project that you just don't have that ability you have to now learn how to
scale it so one thing we do in my org just to and that anti-pattern of taking
the IC oh you're the best IC you're gonna be the manager we say we saw that
a lot and there are some definite traps there some of those people grew
into good managers so that's okay and I mentioned so unfortunately we've gone
the other direction in my org where I I need more leads and I have a bunch of
people who go no I want to be an IC they don't want to be a lead and it's
good and then when we do have someone who wants to be a lead we put them in a
provisional lead rule so we don't move the headcount change we have them begin
to we usually take three to sometimes six months of having them we add them
to my leadership meetings they they manage the folks they do everything
except for the the basic accounting you have to do in in workday or your or or
head tracks at Microsoft and they get a chance to try it like it's a try before
you buy on both sides they get an opportunity to see if it's what they
want to do if they like it and if they're good at it and I get an
opportunity to see how well they do that so that helps out a lot we never
just put someone into a lead position and say okay you're a lead now good luck
it's they they get a chance to test it out which has been very successful so
far okay so they get a chance remembering that we're talking about
coaching now but anyway right there a be testing in their tangents yeah no no
the the issue I see I guess my question is what's the common reason why they
don't want to be a lead they want to focus on keeping their hands dirty as
mint in the product as many hours a day as they can also because of the I tell
people this too because we rely on the leads you're responsible for delivery
project people management and tech leadership it's being that first-level
lead in my org is probably the hardest job we have in my org you have to want
to do it it's a challenge and I think it's so much of a challenge I think it
it's a lot of it's daunting for a lot of folks to go that's I know that's a lot of
change I don't want to do all that I know I don't want to try to fix it now
but that to me if I were in your role that would be something I would want to
look into is is do we have the right amount of friction in place for those on
our on our bench to to to little friction and too much friction both are
bad yeah it's not we don't have to be clear it's not like we're trying to hire
for a lead and have open heads we have a couple of teams are a little flatter
than we'd like in the long run but also what we have at the same time is a set
of leads and managers across the org who are all really really good at being a
leader a manager well that's that's a good problem yeah so it's not horrible I
think long-term they're looking at when I'm looking at two to three to five year
growth and what's happening assuming I live that long which is you know fairly
likely I do need to look at capacity and growth and where we'll need to add
people so it's just something I think about I don't have I have a pretty good
I'm getting to a bench for me but that long-term bench there's some holes it
just a problem for me to address I don't think it's a given what we have I'm not
going to change the principles of what that baseline for what leads to do
because that's working in the long run I can hire strategically to take care of
that I'm not I'm not worried about it but it's something I want I'll need to
take care of at some point all right so going back to the coaching story oh yeah
yeah yeah all right going back to the coaching story right so there's a bunch of
required training that's that's being pushed pushed down and so they created a
synchronous gamified training around the coaching habit I think this is the this
is one of the things that the author of the coaching habit has done although so
he produced a lot of videos and in those videos he mentions Microsoft quite a bit
so I think I've never I've read the book I've never watched the videos so I'll
trust you well so no so I think I think the content he built was for Microsoft
but he's definitely put together like I wouldn't be surprised if he's if he's
turning what he's done into more of a self-serve business because by doing the
right set of videos and then they added gamification in automatic requirements
like the training is very self-serve and you're kind of forced to to learn as
you go through it if you can't you can't proceed until you have enough
points and you can't get points unless you you know answer the questions and
things like that it was six weeks long I would say one of the problems is that
they they set it up with pairs so I was in a cohort that had four four members
and in week one I was to pair with one person and week two a different person
etc in my particular cohort I was only able to have one of those meetings because
one of the one of the problems with with how how it was set up is it was very easy
for it there's a new culture shift on managers and a lot of the managers were
like oh crap this is started and there's not really a sense of the time
commitment they say oh it's gonna cost you like an hour a week no no no no it
does not cost you an hour it costs you significantly more than and the meeting
starts showing up and it's it was on it was unusual because it was self-serve
whereas a lot of these training meetings like you have to go to the tenant
conference and there's a moderator or a conference call and there's a moderator
this was different I've gone through the training I have right here like lots
of my notes you can't see it because I have a background and and also the
people in our podcast can't see it either that's oh yeah there's that but I
actually have the one page bookmarked because I have found that that going
through the enumeration of questions is so friggin useful so he talks about the
seven powerful questions and I find that doing that and find the structure is
absolutely useful it allows you to very readily avoid what he calls the advice
monster right that's remember I think consultants give advice and coaches ask
questions so I'm gonna interrupt I'll let you go on in a second but I want to
tie this a little bit into quality coaching because these questions are
they lead off with something like the old how's it going what's on your mind yep
I forget I get the kickstart question yep it's like just get it started kind of
kind of see what's going on there and he goes a big escalation on why it works
and why it's important and then there's the the the and what else so this is
great for one-on-ones too but for coaching I may come to go to Brent and
say hey Brent what's on your mind I'm trying to get this release I'm
just listing this point where I'm not giving advice and what else oh and that
it makes you stop they pull what else is on my mind oh crap we have I yeah I have
a team X is asking me for something and trying to figure out how I can do that
so now you've gotten a little bit into what's going on and then the one I
use them one-on-ones a lot I use it today and it almost every time I ask it
even though my directs have heard this question a lot of times for me doesn't
matter if they've heard it from me once twice ten times before when I pull this
one out which isn't every week I spread it up but they all go that's a great
question and I ask what's the real challenge for you here they go oh good
question well and that's why I start again I'm just gathering information but
it's getting them to think about it well the real challenge is probably
dealing with team X who wants that thing for me it wasn't the first thing on
their mind but because you asked and what else you got them thinking about what's
going on and then when you asked what's the real challenge this thing's actually
taking a lot of my time getting this thing to happen so then the foundation
question you ask well well what do you want I want team X to be satisfied so
they could leave me like a focus on this delivery I'm confident we can get
the delivery and the quality built in place but my team and I are distracted
though a lot all kinds of notes go with that and then the lazy question how can I
help and there might be even a flippant answer like well you can go tell team X
to f off but maybe an answer of maybe nothing I don't know of anything okay and
you don't have to try again don't be tempted to give that advice you're
trying to get them to figure it out themselves coaching is you get them to
figure it out themselves but there may be something they think you can do well
actually do you know this lead of team X maybe maybe that connection will help
those things happen all the time and then the strategic question is is like
this is digging a little bit deeper it's almost advice I think but you're
asking questions like do you have anybody in your team already working on
this who else have you talked to about this that may be able to help
things like that you're trying to get them to are there things you could
things that I can take off your plate that would give you time to do this and
then the learning question at the end is again imagine I've coached you I'm trying
to help you get your delivery done which as far as I'm concerned as part of
quality at least it is for this example we finished that conversation I haven't
given you advice I've asked you questions to make you think about how to solve it
and at the end and I'll do this someone-on-one sometimes as well I
don't do them every week because I don't like to be predictable but I'll
ask what was most useful for you what comes out of that is some feedback to
you as a coach on well I found that just actually until I talked to you I didn't
realize that the thing on team X was such a big deal for so thank you for
that it reinforces it helps so that's that's it that's the seven the flavors
of the seven questions but they work in a freaking multitude infinite not
infinite but yeah infinite numbers of scenarios and they're fantastic and
remember remembering to do that and not as I forget the office name Ryan somebody
not falling into the the clutches of the advice monster is huge huge and getting
people to get stuff done okay back to you Brett so it's interesting because
you literally in order read off everything I had listed here except you skipped
over what I had as question number five and you you you skipped over my question
number five you did how can I help this questions five then you added a new
question six so I'm wondering if he's changed his content because I'm pretty
sure you got that from the book but what I have is question number five so this
piggybacks after you ask what do you want then then the follow-up question to
that is what are you going to say yes to and if you do what then will you have
to say no to oh that's a that's a good coaching question by itself right it's
sort of a it's sort of for this forces them to understand okay what are the
trade-offs yeah so I actually love questions like that when people come to
me and say I am so busy I have too much to do yeah and then we have that that
question followed by some advice or consulting on prioritization everybody
gets the same number of hours in a day right how you choose to prioritize that
time the selects what you can say yes to and what you can say no to and no this
is not I'm not knocking anybody all the time I can't I have never in my history
of not just managing but mentoring I have never in never gone very long
without encountering people who did not know how to say no to things and not
because they wanted to be nice they just like well that's cool I'll do that
that's cool too I'll do that well I want to do that too and all of a sudden they're
going I can't get all my work done because I'm deadlocked oh so I I'm
afflicted by that same problem but for me it's I evaluate I go oh that sounds
really freaking cool and and I think I could get that done in like two hours
yeah right so but then it isn't until I'm working on my fourth straight day on the
same thing that I am reminded of how bad I am at estimation yeah the bulk of my and
related the bulk of my growth as a manager and leader has been learning how
to be a ruthless delegator and I have now empowered like I had a situation today
where there was a thing that I was going to do that one of my employees took off
my plate they delegated it to themselves and in my head for a second I
thought but but I want to do it I thought oh my god they are a genius yeah
yeah actually so I have a couple of people that will will do that and they
come to me and they they they come to me and they they're so polite and they're so
diplomatic and as they as they're like kind of they they all have the same
story they first walked through the why hey I was doing this and then this and
then this and the strong-out story because they want they want me to have
all their facts but the end story is Brent I'm taking this from you you're too
busy you you're you know whatever they're variant of you suck which almost
ninety ninety five percent of the time whatever it is that they're explaining
that they don't want to say around Brent sucks I I mean I will be the first to
agree so that was a worthwhile tangent but I want you to go back and repeat
that question and then back into the other differences between the questions
from the ones oh I'm sorry no sorry this is fun well so the close-out what
I roll man close out what I was saying is that when they finally got to to
their ass and I'm like oh my god what a rollercoaster yeah George like they
they they do not understand how hungry I am for them to step up and take things
from me absolutely being the answer is yes every single time today I handed off of
one small project that I was owning to one of my ICs it was like I gave him
candy it so it was a net win and for me I have learned that one-offs I can do I
can be on but but things that are gonna last longer than a month in terms of
being useful the business I have no business being on it then I need I need
to have a need to plan for that to be delegated if not up front very quickly
after there's a lot of things around my job that honestly I am the the the best of
my team so I do a lot of bootstrapping stuff but that so anyway back to the
question there we go yeah what are you going to say yes to and if you do what
are you going to say no to I like that question all right and then what else
was different so you had some question in between how can I help and what was most
useful here that I don't have so does he talk about the strategic question what
did you call this strategic question actually this strategic question is the
yes no one the flavor I use there is I guess there's a version that there's a
question there that in his strategic questions the version it's a little
where I said who else have you talked to about this what what have you tried or
what do you what can we take off your plate to make this work your question I
think is better there but that's the strategic question from his number when
you gave me is actually number that's if it's strategic which is how you
described it it fits in that bucket but that's the original question number
six is I have it as as question five and then how can I help his number is
question six okay maybe he flipped those around because I had how can I help
as the one before it those two are just flipped in our in our in our renditions
so yeah just do your little goog everyone do a little Google searchy
searchy thing check out the coaching habit you know there's a chance not a
good chance there's a chance there'll be a link in the show notes but people
don't look at those anyway it's way faster just to bring up a search engine
like Google or Duck Duck Go what's the one does Microsoft make still make a
search engine yeah you can use bong go to ball is it something like that and you
can type in the coaching habit and you'll find this website and the book
and it's really good so Brent screen-sharing actually and I like so
it's interesting your your search so maybe it's updated from the book because
you're or maybe I just wrote it down wrong I'm wondering that right but I also
like this question even better if you're saying yes to this what are you saying
no to I think that's more succinct yeah and by this it's the Brent in oh it's
cool he used Google he typed co he searched for coaching habit seven
questions and the very top list is very similar to the questions he and I
just talked through so you can use those to help with it's really a day in the
life let me we got like nine minutes left here eight might be five minutes left here
oh next episode no I think we'll do the other topic so next time I'll go ahead
and tease for it next time Brent's gonna tell me why safe isn't as bad as I
think it is and also why it may not be needed anymore something like that do
you want me to clarify the cliffhanger no what I want it's it's something like
that just listen to 148 and you'll find out if we remember to talk about it you
never know so let me talk a little bit about what when I've been in a quality
coaching role or part-time role what that's like so some of it is because
you usually it's it's kind of like if you look at the embedded tester on an
agile team that is kind of a coach but now imagine you are the embedded tester
for 10 teams or 20 teams you are probably not going to go in there and do
their testing when you're like how agile testing is described everyone on the
team does testing everyone has a priority around quality that embedded tester
who's typically part of an agile team in the worst case they're doing all the
testing for the team they're not coaching but in a case we're actually
following agile principles and doing what the teams who are good at this do the
person in that role is helping that team understand what are the quality
challenges what testing do we need to do and eventually those folks are getting
better at that now as you expand that and you say okay now I'm the the
embedded tester or the quality coach for 10 teams the time you spend with those
teams is less do you spend exactly one tenth of your time with each team no you
spend time I may spend all of my time with one team because they have
particular challenges you use context to figure out where you should spend your
time to use things like the quality culture transition guide to help teams
figure out where they are what improvements you may want to want to
make and help them figure out how to do them you're doing coaching asking
questions to get them realize what they need to do get them focused on solving
customer problems if they're not all kinds of stuff like that there was
something else really important oh one super cool thing it's great to have a
quality coach or have that quality coaching hat on and sit in on the team
retros because it's a great place to offer advice I and other quality coaches
have pulled out that quality culture transition guide during a retro and say
well here this may help here or talk about how you can this problem could
have been solved if we would have built quality in a little bit better in this
particular way you know should we add a linter here or how can we why don't we
add memory monitoring to this this cluster so we can keep an eye on that in
the future how do we prevent these things whatever the typical stuff that
comes up that brainstorming that comes up in a retro helping teams think about
things from a quality perspective when they may want to do it from a perspective
of someone who doesn't have the experience and breadth and testing you do
so those sorts of things there's my little bit of a nutshell of it's not a
whole day and we'll get a quality coach or two on here in the coming weeks and
months to help us walk through it and give some more ideas I think it is
worth it especially it starts to give a picture of what principle seven is like
when you don't have a debt you don't have dedicated quality specialist you may
have a quality coach that quality coach could be the agile coach could be a hat
someone wears it's worth talking about I think that captures it at a high level
yes Brent no I completely agree
all right so that's a start we definitely get back into that we'll
talk about safe that ended up being a much cooler conversation than I thought I
can't congratulations to Microsoft do you see on doing coaching do you see these
coaching habits actually a bit of this way books called the coaching habit do you
see these questions becoming a habit among leaders and managers at Microsoft
you see them doing more coaching yet as a result of this training or is it yet
no so the answer to your first question is is no I don't see it but the second
question I guess the first question is as well why and I think a big part of it
is goes back to your initial of the podcast right everyone's kind of working
from home teams are kind of isolated right it's I don't know that Microsoft has
really sort of I don't know that too many teams have really come up with a good way
to figure out sort of the random coaching opportunities that would be
publicly visible right the the so when in person thing like somebody comes to my
office randomly I can use that as a coaching moment is something that they
they talk about like coaching should take 10 minutes or less so says the
author so in order to really see that you really need to have like I would
need to be in like public meetings where coaching events could occur with other
management peers now I will say I do see it it's just not brought yeah so that's
something to work on one thing one maybe last thing is we have grassroots
kicked off some coaching clubs kind of like your your group so I have a group
and they listen to the podcast so hey everyone a group of folks I've been
meeting with regularly for a while now and we just it grew out of some my old
team but we've been giving each other coaching practicing giving and receiving
coaching in a group of four or five people I would have done it long enough
that we wanted to split it up so we've now broken into three groups and added
more people to see if we can organically spin up these coaching clubs
across more and more people at the company so phase two multiple coaching
clubs just starting but that'll help I think getting the chance to practice
giving and receiving feedback is time well invested all right yeah yeah okay man
I got a run but this was fun time flew by I know we started a little late
because I had some technical difficulties here on the A's side of the EB testing
podcast if you read my five for Friday I got a new desk and because I have a
new desk I had to move where my microphone was it's a long story and I
didn't quite get it done as fast as I wanted to and then Brant made me change
levels and blah blah blah and yeah and we're done so thank you for listening to
episode 147 of the AB testing podcast where we don't talk about AB and we
sometimes talk about testing but we always talk about things that we think
may be relevant may be interesting if you have other ideas please let us know
one of the three dot slack comm you can go to modern testing dot org get an
invitation you can go to iTunes and leave us lots of five-star reviews if you
want or with a blog the other blog the podcasting host of your choice okay man
that's it for me I'm Alan I'm Brit or the floor mizami all right you too