Welcome to A.B.
Testing Podcast, your modern testing podcast.
Your hosts, Alan and Brent, will be here to guide you through topics on testing, leadership,
agile, and anything else that comes to mind.
Now on with the show.
Today on the A.B.
Testing Podcast, Brent will eat food.
Hey everyone, I'm Alan.
I'm Brent.
And Brent is eating and crinkling already.
It's good, good fun.
Everyone will pay $5 to the first of the three that can guess what I'm eating today.
It's a new segment on the A.B.
Testing Podcast.
Is this like what's in my pocket?
It's like that, but the audio version of it.
Oh my God.
I think it's episode 138.
Still season one, because we don't do seasons because that's a thing that other podcasts
do and we're not like other podcasts.
Our season never ends.
It does.
A lot of things never end.
Kind of like pandemic.
Yeah.
A real quick rant that didn't post this.
Last weekend I got excited.
I logged into one of the, I'm not going to throw anybody under the bus, a local hospital
and got an appointment set up for May 2nd to get my first shot.
And I got an email back the next day saying, hey, we made a mistake.
None of those slots are actually available.
You're out of luck.
And then there was rage and apparently people, other people must have raged more than I did
because then the next day got another email saying, uh, hey, we're going to call you and
reschedule those things so you don't hate us as much.
That was the good news.
And then they called today, but, uh, I was out on a hike and my phone dropped right
after I picked it up and they didn't call back.
And I don't know if that lost my place on the list or what.
So right now I have no appointment to get a vaccine, but I'm hoping I do someday.
Um, I am in this similar place.
Although, um, are you, are you currently picky?
Uh, not yet.
I, I was excited cause I, you, I think it was you that told me Moderna is the, is the
best one in your opinion.
Uh, actually if I did tell you that I am now reversing that cause I literally, I now
have a whole bunch of friends who are going through shot number two and literally a hundred
percent of them are reporting life is hell after shot two.
I heard that from, uh, the teams, the teams on my folk, the folks on my team who had Pfizer
as well.
Yeah, it could just be a thing.
It could just be, uh, crawl under the covers and suffer for the day or so till it's over.
Yeah, I don't, I don't know.
I'm currently favoring Pfizer.
Okay.
I'm going to take what I can get.
That's my plan.
Yeah.
The, the, the J and J one is probably the one I'm least likely.
All right then.
So we have a podcast today.
We got stuff to talk about.
Um, and we should probably get going.
I don't know.
What do you want to talk about?
Uh, stuff.
Okay.
I got stuff to talk about.
Newest one.
I might not even have five for Friday at this, but I mentioned it to you as we're logging
in today, I have a brand new Mac book.
My last one, um, it still works, but I just wanted to get the battery replaced and they
won't do it.
It's out of warranty.
So it says just your, you're due for a refresh anyway, cause your computer is four years
old.
So I got a new Mac book M one.
It is lickety split fast and I've never heard the fans turn on yet.
I can't make it work hard enough to actually try and spin up fans.
So I need to this weekend to try and do something a little bit more strenuous to it.
Start advent for coding early.
Maybe, maybe those things don't let you do the brute force solution.
Those things don't really compute a lot, but anyway, I like it so far.
Uh, totally irrelevant to the podcast.
Uh, I'm in the, I'm in the market for a new laptop piece of crap laptops that
I've been using.
Like I think, I think my laptop now is at eight years old.
You know, you work for a company with a lot of money.
They'll probably get you a new one.
Yeah.
The issue is I need, I'm picky now on which one the, so it's eight years old.
Like I can plug it in.
It still works as long as I don't, like it's now got like 15 minutes of battery,
even on the full charge.
All right.
For the listeners at home, Brent, uh, actually slid his chair back, opened his
laptop bag, got his laptop out.
He opened it.
He like, they flipped it around, looked at the bottom a little bit, looked at the
top, opened it up, and now he's typing a letter from his laptop.
No, I'm not.
Cause the battery's already dead.
All right.
Um, the battery life lasts just a little long.
I'm trying to just trying to find on here when I got the damn thing.
I don't see a date anywhere.
Oh, there's one.
Uh, I believe that says 2014.
All right.
Damn.
Yeah.
Anyway, the issue so much for me, it isn't, it's the screen size now.
It's, it's an order because I'm old.
And, um, it's essentially when I blow up the screen so I can actually read what
it's saying, I now have essentially two inches of real estate and therefore I
can't do anything with the stupid thing.
So I actually went with, I, this topic is not very exciting, but I went
with a smaller computer this time.
Uh, I had a choice of getting a 16 inch MacBook or a 13 inch MacBook
with the new MacBook and I went 13 because there'll, there'll be a world
at the end of this where I'll go back to traveling often and it is impossible
to open a 16 inch laptop on an airplane.
So I thought ahead, hold the smaller one.
Okay.
So, all right, then.
All right.
Let's, let's get on with the podcast.
Hey everyone.
I'm still Alan.
I'm great.
We did that part.
I, um, I mentioned, I did a teaser on one of the three dot slack.com, which
you can join just go to modern testing.org and find the link.
And there are several of the three there.
In fact, if you count up all the three, there's only, only ever three listeners.
They take turns listening, but we have 633 members of our one of the three.com,
one of the three dot slack.com slack community.
You're welcome to join that.
And yesterday I teased a little bit because yesterday or the day before was
the exact two year anniversary of me joining the organization that I'm in.
The bi-annual Alan changes jobs event.
It is, it is.
And, and bring his tease about this and I was told, no, no, no,
but then it always happens.
And in this case though, it's not as dramatic as the other ones.
Uh, what has happened is my org largely supports the division that I'm in
because the division that I'm in, well, my org does internet infrastructure,
cloud CDN, uh, C C I CD, uh, et cetera, et cetera, et cetera.
You name a tool used in deployment infrastructure is probably supported by my
team while our largest customer is the division Maria and we do work company
wide, which has been fine.
Unity is very flat.
We don't have a lot of hierarchy.
It makes it easy to do.
However, uh, that was out of convenience and it was out of convenience of my
management chain to fund that, uh, central org within their org, but
recently unity has formed a org, especially for central stuff like this.
There's a labs group there and labs is like lot like Microsoft research,
much smaller scale.
There are a similar team to mine supporting a lot of the desktop developers.
And we tend to overlap and not optimize as well as we should being in different
orgs and some other things that I won't go into,
but, uh, we, I'm just, it's just a drag and drop reorg.
I, my, and my org are being drug over to another part of unity with a new manager.
Well, we will continue with our mission, but also, uh, work on.
There's a couple other things we're doing there.
One is just keep doing what we're doing to is to fix that alignment or not.
I shouldn't say fix.
It's not broken.
It's to increase the collaboration between our team and the other team at unity
who have similar goals for different developers.
And also to bring our culture with us.
Uh, we have a reputation for the way we work with, uh, things we've talked
about here, uh, transparency, accountability, collaboration, psychological
safety, all that stuff.
Uh, we're going to bring all that with us and shove it down their throat.
No, we're going to, but safely.
So, uh, yeah, so it's going to be fun.
That's effective Monday.
Just wrapping all that stuff up by the time this hits, it'll all be
announced across the company.
And I didn't, I don't think I revealed any trade secrets, just to, just
to drag and drop, reorg gives me a little different perspective.
So it counts as my migration because I have different people I'm working
with, even though I'm generally doing many of the same things.
Um, doesn't feel like, unlike last few, it doesn't feel like you're anxious
in any way, shape or form, but what, what, what, um, in terms of your
team's missions, oh, this would be a good opportunity to load up the unity.
Three questions, if I could, uh, which I can't, our mission doesn't change.
Where do you see an advantage for you executing your mission, your mission?
Uh, and where do you see a disadvantage?
Well, I think it's obvious this is good questions.
Nice interviewing Brent.
The advantage is working from a central organization will increase
discoverability from the other parts of unity that we, that we work with,
but sort of ad hoc, uh, it makes it a little easy for them to discover.
Okay.
This central org has the ha is the place for us to go ask questions.
The disadvantage of course, is anytime that the team you work with the most,
uh, we're being not in the same org as them.
Uh, there's always a little bit of a fear or a challenge there, but again,
we are transparent and flat enough.
I don't think it'll make a difference, but, uh, it would be silly of me not to at
least consider that it could be an issue, but I'm not worried.
I mean, your culture is different than here.
So that's what's going on with me.
Not the, not a big change.
Sorry for the cliffhanger in slack and then the not that exciting of a change,
but we'll hear more stories cause you get to work with different people,
a whole different set of folks get to be my peers or as I should say,
a whole different set of people have to suffer through my questioning and, uh,
discernment,
interrogation,
Oh, discernment. Sorry.
All right. So, um, that is what's going on with me.
I actually have a question for actually have two topics for today.
Would you like to start with data or test automation?
Oh, I want to start with, uh,
uh, automated checking for sure.
I would like to start by punching you in the throat.
So, uh, a little bit of a soapbox leading to a question.
You've all heard me see, say and discuss and write about that developers should
be doing the vast majority of the testing, testing,
and that they're definitely the best suited.
Not only can they test to the best,
definitely the best suited for test automation.
Also realize, well, before I even get there,
I will repeat a rant from, uh, maybe it was last episode,
more and more. I'm thinking that nobody should be writing any web automation.
Given, given how many of those tests it should be writing, not very many.
And given the massive improvements in reliability in the just recorded tests,
and there was a time when we hated those,
but for the web stuff with the AI they have in there,
which can detect changes and the massive amount saved and the fact that you're
well handcrafted tests are going to be flaky anyway, because, because reasons,
I would just have everyone use,
oddify Mabel test and test project, whatever,
something that lets you quickly create some tests for the main things you'd to
check in the, in the web, web UI, but that's not the rant.
I want to get out. It's not my question for you. Uh,
the question is despite the little bubble I live in,
where developers do write tests, many testers,
checkers, no testers insist that the majority of the industry doesn't and can't
work that way.
And that just because of the way things are and because changing things is,
is harder that they have to write the automation.
So, um, so despite all that, okay,
that isn't even my question yet. My question is I'm going somewhere.
I forgot where it was a couple of times, but I'll get there. Okay.
Let me just ask you this. So if I'm a tester,
and now you don't talk to any testers,
but if I'm a tester on your team and I say to you,
I would like to get into automation because that's what they say on the
internet. They say, I'm a manual tester and I want to get into automation.
And I face Palm twice, but if I say that to you,
I'm a manual tester and I want to get into automation. What do you tell me?
I, I, I'm like, what the hell have you been doing?
What do you mean you're an automated tester? I said, I'm a manual tester.
I want to get into automation.
I feebly responded because I'm like, uh,
the idea of a manual tester and on my team are
okay. All right. So you didn't play the part as I wished. Oh,
we should do,
we need a follow up to the modern testing manager versus traditional test manager
where we talk about automation or something like that. It'll be fun.
Uh, didn't plan ahead well enough on that, but no,
that would be a good idea though.
I am thinking more and more and more that the answer like I'm drinking some
tea right now. I usually have some water here,
but I think the answer to any injury or ailment is to drink more water.
If you, if you're feel horrible after the second modern shop, just drink water.
You'll be fine. Break a leg, drink more water. You'll be fine. Uh,
but for the automate for any problems in testing and quality,
my answer is getting to be more and more again and again, time after time,
pair with the developer.
Uh, I was actually going along the same line that I was thinking, you know what,
uh, let's find a bug for you to go fix or something,
something that's a lightweight coding exercise.
But I need to automate the UI, man. That's, that's,
that's what the cool kids do in this case. Also,
I is also a broken problem where these people writing web automation,
they're automating a bunch of BS.
I'm going to automate these user scenarios because I can.
So I wonder if imagine today we did,
imagine this today when someone wants to get into automation,
they take a class or they there's no books, they read some blogs,
they watch a whole bunch of crap about selenium.
I don't think that's right because then they end up automating like these,
they don't automate the right things. They're,
they don't know how to design automated tests. I don't know what to automate.
If you go talk to the dev and you say, Hey,
I want to get into automation and instead of this as great,
what do you want to automate? And they say,
I want to make sure that I can put things in the shopping cart and check out,
blah, blah, blah, and do it in all these permutations. That's great.
But we can do all that at the logic layer or just having that
conversation with the person who actually knows how it's implemented.
And some people are going to say, but Alan, but Mr. Weasel,
when, when the developer, they, they,
they can't think about testing. They only care about the code and not the
customer and I bullshit and crap. Uh, and I,
if that accent defended anybody, I meant that to be, uh, just, uh,
me as a young, young tester. So, uh, I did not mean to, um,
insight that anybody that actually sounds like that person,
I just made with anyone other but me.
My, my, my, I wish my middle son were here.
He has mastered the art of the, the,
the know it all bratty kid with.
Yeah. That's so the, the point is, I think if you have a discussion, uh,
and when you get over the fact that developers aren't going to be skewed or
tainted by the fact that know how it works,
you'll actually have a discussion on what the right things are to test and what
the right things are to automate.
It goes back to the anger Weasel's tautology of you should automate 100% of
all the tests that should be automated. A lot of people today,
especially in this web UI automation world are automating stuff that shouldn't
be automated.
Yeah. Actually, I want to go back to a basic question. Yes.
Like if you're a manual tester, somebody right now is going,
there's no such thing as manual testing. Do you call it manual programming?
But anyway, go on. No one's we're using the term to differentiate,
but no, uh, people who are creating test automation. So it's fine. No, no.
So you have a manual tester and, and no one would say it's,
there's no such thing. I do think there's a large number of people would say
it's redundant. Yeah. Okay. Yeah. And so like for me,
why is it that they're saying,
I want to get into automation versus saying I want to get into
coding through automation.
Like that, that to me is the thing that I think is the important sort of
perspective. Like I don't care. Like automation,
as you just called out, um, from a testing standpoint,
like we got accelerate that's that absolutely tells the businesses,
your team,
your software company is going to have a
stronger performance when your devs own the
automation. That is true. That is true. I don't think, and again,
most of these people don't read book like accelerate.
They don't read books. They don't want to program.
They just want to make sure. Remember we started AB testing way back when,
to help people transition as, as jobs are changing.
These people for the most part want to get into automation because they're
worried their job will go away if they don't.
And what this, in my opinion,
what happens because of this is a bunch of people learn to crapily use
some crappy tools to create some crappy automation.
And I want that to stop. Well, yeah,
I don't have any data that says to what degree that happens.
I know that it does happen cause I've,
I've had to manage several of those transitions
and it's a, it's a journey,
but it's one that doubles down on things that I just don't
agree with anymore. Right. It's, it's, it's so,
if a, if a manual tester on my team came to me and said, Hey,
I want to do that. My first question is going to be why, why,
why, why are you doubling down on harming your career?
If that's where you want to go, you need to go in a different direction.
And for our world and for, and actually, and as you and I see,
the bubble that we live in is getting bigger and bigger and affect huger and
huger. That's what you're doing is actually, yes,
it's true and more and more of the world. And you're right.
My answer would be, well, if I had, I would never have, I mean,
I may have a tester,
but they would never want to get into automation because it understands that
automation is the developer's job. So this can't happen in our world,
but in a world where a tester asks you this,
yeah, I think getting into motivation and understanding why is really important.
But if they just want to do it, learn more about it,
the paths that we give people today,
the paths that we give people today who want to get into automation are the
wrong ones. Cause they, they lead them down a path,
which is not productive for their career. I think, yeah, no.
So what I, I want, because they don't design good tests.
They don't use the power of the computer to make some aspects of testing
easier. It said, or they just want to automate a bunch of clicky,
clicky, clicky user tasks and ask trivia questions about X path that I see on
LinkedIn all the time. I think by talking to the developer,
how should we test this? Cause the tester, they're going to have,
and despite the fact that the arguments people have with me,
when I said developers could test the expertise of the tester is if they're a
dedicated testing specialist,
they're going to have better testing ideas for a lot of things.
So talk about all those ideas with the person who should be writing the
automation in the first place.
And maybe they'll take you under their wing and have you write some of the more
simpler ones to start or pair a program with them and get an idea of how to write
test automation from someone who understands code design and test design,
automated test design, probably far better than you do.
That is a much better path to long-term success for your career.
Then reading a bunch of blogs on Selenium and getting excited because you can
make some archaic stuff, click a button on a screen.
Again, it comes back to their motivation.
If their motivation is saving their career, then,
then I would absolutely guide them in an entirely different direction. Right.
It's, it's, I'm like, yeah, that's,
obviously if they're coming to me, right, if they want to go to,
let's say one of the other thought leaders in this space,
that has a polar opposite opinion, right? Maybe that's the answer.
I send them to there because look,
I can't, from where I'm coming from,
I can't even see you from, from, from where I'm at. Right. I, that's,
that's now an entirely foreign idea to me. And to me, it's harmful.
But the,
but if that's their motivation, then their motivation,
my answer would be to redirect to something that I felt was far more
productive. Right. The,
if their other motivation might be to,
hey,
we're lacking coverage and I want to,
I want to accelerate the coverage. Hey,
I'm supportive of that. Right. That would be, again,
what you're saying is, Hey,
pair program with the developer who should be the one accountable for that
automation,
work through their template and, and,
and learn from that as you add additional coverage. Right.
But also throw in, right.
The,
the developer should not be allowing coverage into their suite,
unreviewed and do put them through at least the,
the code review and,
and those others are the processes.
So that person gets familiarity with how code is produced.
Design constructs,
that might pop out of that.
Right. Um,
it might not. Uh,
I would hope it did,
but in a way that didn't blow the person's mind.
I don't know.
I just typed into duck duck go. I'll, I'll,
you won't hear me type in the edited version,
but I typed in literally I'm a manual tester and I want to get into
automation. So let me lead you, read you a few of the, uh,
I'm not going to go into the pages,
just the part that shows up in the search page. Um,
many manual testers wish to land an automation job with qualifications of
manual testing.
The process of learning coding is tedious and for a person working as a manual
tester for so long, this means going back to square one,
never what other one it requires dedication, hard work, motivation,
lots of time and money to train for a test automation job.
You do not start with the test automation libraries to selenium.
No, you start with something considering the market situation.
Many manual testers are now becoming more interested in test automation.
Some want to expand their skills by including programming,
test automation framework in their testing toolbox.
Others are contemplating switching direction completely. It goes on. I'm, I'm,
it's making me sad. So the, the point there is, and tell me if I'm wrong,
I think one, you want to get motivation.
Is the point there that our bubble is still too small or I mean,
I don't, I acknowledge I live in a bubble on this, on this front.
We both do. I think the more we talk to people,
the more I find out our bubble is bigger than we think it is sometimes.
Maybe at least I think it is because a lot of people go, oh yeah,
we already do that.
Given these answers and given some of the folks who doubled down and freak out
when we do make some of our, uh, what our outlet,
what are not outlandish points, uh, there are people out there with this,
this is a, that's a thing they do.
And I think the thing they should do when they want to get into automation is for
whatever reasons, the part that drives me crazy.
They think I want to get into test automation.
So I'm going to learn how to click around a webpage with this shiny new
framework. I think that's the wrong place to start. And I think I could just,
do you want to think about test design? You want to make,
you want to do this one and I've done, I've,
I've talked about that before long in the past,
how to think about test design.
I've given talks on test design that help you think like which tests should be
automated and not, and what you can use the power of the computer for.
But I'm tired of doing that. It's not what I do anymore.
I'd rather just, I think some good generic devices,
if you want to get into automation or get into programming,
go talk to the developers on your team,
find opportunities to pair with them on bug fixing or automation ideas,
et cetera. And if, if,
if it comes back that every single absolutely no developers on the team want to
work with you on that, well one, I hope that's not the case, but two,
it's a different problem than it's a different problem. Exactly.
And as you know, there's, there's part of this bubble is I listened to,
and I, I ranted a little bit about this on, on our Slack group,
but I listened to a panel of people who do exploratory testing and,
which I have nothing against exploratory testing. Although once I,
I made a joke about whether I could use the word exploratory testing.
If I wasn't in the special club,
this was 15 years ago when a certain group of people on the internet were
talking about it a lot and correcting people that they didn't use it right.
And one of them wrote me an email just bitching the hell out of me for,
for referring to it that way. And like, there's no club,
you're just being a jerk. And well,
there is a club and I was being a jerk.
The folks on this panel talking about exploratory testing,
their ideas around ET were all fine.
But the scenarios they described on why it was valuable for them are right out of
1992. They get a new,
they're excited cause they get a new build from a development team they never
see. And they, and with no instructions and no notes,
and they get to figure out how it works and give them feedback. And well,
I guess maybe that could have been fun for me one time in my career.
That sounds like a living hell to me today.
Yeah. Yeah. Uh, completely hell. Uh, the,
yeah, I don't know what else to add to that one. The,
in fact, I will,
what other rant do we get back to the other question here?
Cause we only have like 15,
18 minutes left is some people on the other side of the bubble.
Like again, I'll go back to the one that really triggered people.
I talked about developers being able to do testing.
Still see post people saying, well, I'm in the developer's mindset.
I have to shift gears and change in order to find, to critique my own work.
And yeah, I get that.
But what is missing from a lot of these stories is that creating
good software is a highly collaborative process.
And yeah, it is a little harder maybe to do your own testing when you're just by
yourself. But if you make something by yourself, you're probably not,
probably don't have a lot of customers. Uh,
when you're trying to do something significant,
it's a collaborative process and that collaboration is, uh,
where you get the benefit from.
And there's so much in what you said. I want to,
I want to just go on a rant on the very first statement is I have to shift
to the, the, the, the tester mindset to move forward. That's to me,
like, why is it phrase that way?
When I sit down to write a new chunk of code, okay,
I go through, uh, the TDD process and I say, okay,
now before I begin, it's, it, to me,
it's more like a Steven Covey. Have you ever read, ever read Steven Covey?
Oh yeah.
Okay. Begin with the end in mind. What is the end?
How can I sit down before even get colored by how the code was written and be,
you know, no, uh,
run the risk of not being able to discern the forest from the trees.
According to this, um, this theory is, is, okay, well,
how do I know if I got there? What's the sunny day scenarios?
What's the rainy day scenarios?
What are the tests that I'm going to, to write up first?
Uh, and then I'm going to write my code to,
to the point where they pass those tests. Okay.
I can get a long ways there. Will I forget about things?
Will I neglect something on my own? Damn straight.
But that's not because I'm going to developer versus tester mindset.
That whole thing is, is, is bull. And we've,
I think our listeners get that. I don't want to go too far in the echo chamber,
but it's still out there. I wanted to mention it. Did you want to rant some more?
No, no. So in this one, I'm just like, how much of this,
of this point of view is being solidified because the,
the language choice and,
and how they're presenting it in the first place is just bullshit. Like to me,
actually you represent this all the time on the podcast. So, and you, you go,
Hey, here's a problem. Here's my definition of done.
This is how far I've gotten. Brent,
do you have any, any additional thoughts on this?
Like you've probably done it five or six times on this podcast. It's like,
no, it's,
it's the value of collaborating and recognizing,
and maybe that's it, maybe that's it.
Maybe that's my problem with specialists in some of this regards.
Like you and I have encountered this in the, in the old school days.
Like there were teams when I was a test manager that I would go talk to the dev
lead and he would just say, all right, if we have a bug,
it's test fault because my devs are,
are five star devs just ask them, right?
And there's this sort of specialization ego that gets
involved. And, and, and I'm wondering now,
because I am very much a generalizing specialist or a specialized,
and generalists, one of those things now. And I'm wondering,
am I a lot more collaborative now because I no longer even
pretend to believe that I frigging know everything,
right? I'm not trying to know everything.
I'm trying to accomplish a goal and I know quite a bit about it,
but I also know the things I don't know. And you know what?
I'm going to go ask Alan what his thoughts on this topic is,
or I'm going to go ask Sally what her thoughts are on this one.
Because we're better together. Yep. Whole team quality, baby. Yeah.
Maybe you saw this. I saw this on LinkedIn.
Someone was was ranting against whole team quality. Oh, I saw that. And I,
do you have whole team design? Uh, yeah. Yeah, you should.
Do you have whole team performance? Uh, yeah,
it was, uh, awkwardly, it was just awkward to watch.
It was, it was, it was a little cringy. Okay. Um, I have a question for you.
Different subject, different subject. You promised me something about data. I did.
I did because I ran into an interesting question recently,
which again, it comes down to framing and the question you and I often ask a
lot, a lot of people do is, okay, what's the outcome you want?
Imagine you had this, what are you going to do? The question,
what was, what was actual question? Uh, Hey, Alan,
do you have any tips for us? We want to build a data org. Okay. Okay.
What do you want to do? Well,
we want to be able to make a data driven decisions about our business.
Oh, you just,
you just immediately changed it to shit.
I deal with all of the time. Okay.
So what I want to know is because I'm here today for advice.
Cause the answer I gave him was that I need to think about,
this a little bit more. If you can give me some more context,
I'll get back to you hoping I could just chat to you about this, uh,
about this. So the stage I got them in,
they asked me those questions literally. That's what they want to do.
They want to be more data driven and building a data org is the answer they
decided on. And right now the,
this team is trying to understand, okay, what will this data or do?
What questions will they help us answer?
And I feel like I can't put a finger on it,
but I feel like they're starting at the wrong end of the question. Um, yeah,
I was going to say, uh,
though just with the questions that you asked me, uh,
that is absolutely a sign of the tail wagging the dog.
Yeah, I felt that way. I'm checking with you. So, so what do you do?
Imagine just came to you like,
what are the questions you asked to get the tape to get the,
to get to the front of the dog?
I have better metaphor is the underwear norms, right? On this one, right?
We got data where we're missing step two,
but once we find finished that up, massive profit. Yeah.
Okay. So the first thing they have to unwind is what is a data culture and
hold on a second. I just rolled over my goddamn headphones.
The, I can imagine I got his pause for a second here. Let me come back is, uh,
I got to imagine it's like Brent's on a rolly chair rolling around.
I've been sitting on a ball the last month or two. So I can bounce. All right,
go on to tell me, tell me what, what to tell this team. Um,
they want to improve the, the, the data culture of the org. Okay.
Correct. So what is, so in my mind,
I would say, okay, what are the principles that are going to find that?
And, uh, again, what are the actions? Cause improving,
like even improving the data culture of the org, that is a,
like I did that presentation. It's basically, right?
It's essentially how do we transform? Right. And it's essentially,
what you're trying to do is make quantification a stronger influence than
intuition on decision-making. Sure.
So that like the first thing I would say is they have so much to learn before
they would even begin doing that. Like it,
if someone came to me, I would with that question now,
and I would immediately go and say, uh, this needs to stop. Like, um,
but, but you can't say this needs to stop. They have a,
they have the right to do it.
They can't say this needs to stop. They have,
they have the right desire in place. Let's go back to the beginning. Right. They,
they want to be more data driven. They want to quantify over intuition.
Those are all good things. We want those things.
So I can't just tell them to go away. I think they're solving that, that they,
they define their end state. We always have current state. We don't have,
we were data oblivious desired state want to be data driven. Uh,
what are the next, what are the right next steps for a team like that?
So begin with the end of mind, you know,
what is the single most important in,
and you want me to wind this to the head count. So you're going to need,
like from this, you're going to need a lot of PMS.
You're going to need a lot of data engineers.
You're going to need developers to buy off on, um,
telemetry. Am I not going to the right director?
I think so. I, a little bit,
something I've noticed for years and years and years,
even going back to my time at Microsoft in the early days of a data science,
some of you may recall,
I actually briefly led one of Microsoft's first data science engineering teams,
that a science teams when I worked for Chris on the stupid, the stupid thing,
I ended up giving that I ended up hiring, uh, uh,
Gigi and given him and given him that role. Oh, right.
But I did it to hold, to hold things down, but there was an idea.
And I see this notion. I hear it a little bit between the lines from this team.
And I've seen it before where teams think, okay,
we just get a bunch of data and then we'll get a data scientist and they'll
just make cool things happen in there. Magic, magical happen.
When, when someone comes to me along these lines, it's,
it's essentially a belief that all we need to do is hire a bunch of dead
engineers, right? It's essentially build it, and they will come.
Okay. And that's when you came to me, that's what raised in my mind. Oh my God,
this is a building. They will come exercise. Yeah.
I think they're starting with what are the questions we can answer with data.
We'll make a big list of those and then we'll hire a team to go make sure we can
answer them, which seems it doesn't, it, I know it's wrong.
What's the alternative? What I can't just tell them, I don't think this is
wrong. Don't do it this way. Cause then the next question is,
how should we do it? You gotta do, you gotta do a journey, right?
The, the first thing everybody wants is, uh, I,
and I don't know what unity uses, but, um,
first thing everybody wants is their pretty little dashboards, right? So it's,
it's having the dashboards there gives proof that the data is there, right?
Um, and, but it doesn't advance the data culture per se.
It creates a new bottlenecking team. You'll end up having, uh, you know, five,
depending on the size of the team, five or six vendor, uh,
power BI developers,
then you'll end up having your unfair share of data engineers,
uh, who are spending 50% of their time. I call it data hurting.
It's sort of data, the data version of cat hurting.
It's essentially a going through and figuring out where the hell the data is,
because of course there's no, there's no, um,
formal data engineering structure in play. Like the first thing I would,
I would hire would be a,
a business analyst who would come in and absolutely figure out what are the
actual important business questions to answer.
I would almost start that way. Just hiring a business analyst,
biz, biz dev kind of person to figure out,
figure out those questions cause they're going to know better.
They're going to know better what they want to solve. So,
but the thing to keep in mind here also is that I'll bring up is,
is if they know the questions they want to answer already,
then they can go add the instrumentation so they can answer those questions
where I've seen value from data engineering or data science teams is helping me
figure out what questions I want to answer.
There are two approaches there, right? It's like,
you're far from a data science space right now. If,
right, maybe I don't know.
Well in my current org got a crap ton of data scientists cause they do all the
modeling and prediction algorithms for our, for our, our advertisement placements.
All right. So that team should be approached.
That team should be approached and say, Hey, we want to do this broader.
What's the unity gaps?
Cause that team's going to understand where the pain points are.
Yeah. For again, this is actually the team. I'm,
this is the team asking about this, not a unity team. Um,
so making that connection isn't as easy. Uh,
and it would be a little bit different. Gotcha. Gotcha. No, no,
it's not a unity team that, that, that puts it into a different context.
I have gotten, uh, questions before around, um,
if you hire two people, you want to hire, um, you want to hire,
um, number one, a business analyst who will,
who's experienced in this and will, we'll go through first and foremost,
what are the questions that the business is trying to answer?
The second thing you need is a data engineering architect.
Cause, um,
the biggest slowdown in this space is cleaning the data and even discovering the
data, putting something in place where that data can be curated up front without
turning it into a month.
I've seen huge pain points from that when people have gone crazy,
crazy, where people have gone wild, uh,
excessive with the data collection with poor schemas in place and just things
are broken forever.
They're broken forever, but then the,
the solution is not to go the other way either. Right?
Cause I've also see, uh, people propose monthly, um,
multi milestone, uh, big design up front. Oh,
we're going to,
we're not even going to write the first line of code until we have, you know,
figured out the entire perfect snowflake schema for the entirety of the
company. And I'm like, okay. Um, you know, 10 years when you,
when you failed to achieve that circle back with me,
because basically then where data science comes into play,
you're right. There are two places for, for data science here.
Number one is the simpler one, which is hypothesis testing.
It are deductive reasoning. And in their earlier phases,
that's the more in the earlier phases of the company towards this.
That's actually the one I would suggest doing.
It's basically the intuitionists have a belief and you use deductive reasoning
to, to prove or disprove it.
It helps to get that moving forward. Then when that gets tiresome,
because you know, after every hundred hypotheses,
only two to become validated,
then you want to go into inductive reasoning.
We're using AI and ML to learn the patterns within the data.
And push them up so that someone can, can go, okay,
is this interesting or uninteresting? Um,
but it all starts on that,
that journey starts on in my mind very clearly with the two bookends.
How do we create a solid curation culture of the data and treat the data as if
it's a product that's that's prob for my experience.
That is probably the single hardest challenge is,
is that the, the, the PM, the dev team, they'll have data,
but they're not viewing that as a challenge.
And so people are trending stuff or on trying to understand what happened here.
And there's a lot of gaps and holes. And it's not,
from a dev point of view is like, look,
I'm just sharing my diagnostic feed. If I don't, right,
don't ask me to turn it into a product. And then I'm like, no,
that's exactly what I'm doing. It's great that you can,
you can use my data for other things, Brent, um, but it's not a product.
And I'm like, uh, actually it is now.
There's a, we need to wrap up. There's a meta point here, which is, uh,
I think, you know, you and I both get this a lot.
I'm sure a lot of the three do as well. Uh,
people will ask you how to get started on something they've set up
fundamentally wrong. In fact,
this question is actually at the meta level is very similar to, Hey,
I want to get into automation. What do you really want to do?
I want to build a data team. What do you really want to do?
And even then, and so the five whys is a fantastic tool here.
Like, okay, great. You advance the data culture of the organization.
Why does the business care? Yeah. And that's definitely a line of questioning.
I'll get into, um, when I discuss this with these folks that asked me,
I think they'll say, well, we want to improve our business. Why? How? Yeah.
It'll be fun. Uh, okay. Well,
thank you for helping with that and need a little bit of framing on that.
I think it's really just one of those coaching consulting,
asking a bunch of questions to get people to reflect on what they're really
trying to do. Uh, but a little bit of context helps me out. All right.
I am late for another meeting. I'm going to get going, but Brent,
as usual, it's been good talking with you on our AB testing podcast.
And, and you as well,
I will talk to you and the three next time.
Awesome. See ya.