Welcome to AB testing podcast your modern testing podcast your hosts Alan and
Brent will be here to guide you through topics on testing leadership agile and
anything else that comes to mind now on with the show welcome to dance party you
know it's the AB testing podcast hey everyone I'm Alan I'm Brent and this is
144 yes episode 144 not just a random number which is a perfect score of 12
by the way I tend to prefer our prime number podcasts when's the next one I
don't know what no 20 no 147 49 might be how's it how's the the new gig well it's
the same gig with the new boss and my org is growing I have yeah there's a
unannounced reargue coming so I won't give the details on that but that'll put my
org at about including open headcount about 130 140 somewhere in there Wow so
my dog is joining the podcast everyone say hi to Tara Tara say hello hi Tara
she can't hear you you're in there my headphones but it should make her
wookiee sound here in a second it's going pretty well I like it works fun
it's just an easy place to do good work as I've said many times so yeah
work is good how are things going on your end work is work where we're in a phase
where I don't know so right now there's a high urgency thing asked from the
senior VP and it results in me spending a lot of my time building yet another
dashboard and as you know that type of work really excites me yep yeah yeah yeah
yeah I am I tried I play the hands when somebody's told me to build a dashboard
I play the hands over my ears la la la la can't hear you game that works well
for me I'm not sure what happens you know well for you yeah no so in this
particular case I actually so the last time I said yes to this ask it was a
big massive learning lesson I told my manager no I am NOT doing this again and
this time around I had I had my staff come in and have them work on it but one
of my peers is going on paternity leave and one of the things that I do pride
myself on is I am good at training up people to be on the bench and so the
person that I had targeted to to basically be the leader for this project
that is not me was also on the bench and so she is now going to be while he's
out on paternity she is going to be the acting manager of that team which I
think is a fantastic opportunity and experience for her but it now puts me in
the position of oh I have to be the IC for the stupid dashboard so you bring up
one thing I was gonna push us along to the topic but this idea as a leader in
building a bench and it's a term that's not every company uses it but I've heard
it enough to know it's used pretty often it's this who is the level of
leadership that is gonna take over for you when you leave move on to something
else etc right and I've been working a lot on that I have a fairly junior team
where I now have with a recent promotion I have one manager within two
levels of me right now and working on getting everyone else where they need to
be with the way you have one manager in an organization of a hundred no no no
I have one that's within most both all of the rest of them are three levels
below me latter level wise one is two levels below me I am trying to grow my
org so right now there's no one if I disappear if I decide I want to go farm
clams in would be island there is no one in my org that can take over for me
as my org is planned to continue to grow throughout this year I have now
one person who can take on a lot more leadership and some that are getting
there but I'm spending a lot of time trying to groom my bench going back to
the term of the bench again to get more people on my team capable and ready to
take on larger more strategic roles yeah yeah I forgot I there was a reorg we
had a lot of reorgues I actually have two two of my managers are within two
levels of me but I don't I don't I'm not I put it this way I'm I do not have a
good bench right now it's on my mind it's something I work on with my HR
business partner as far as planning goes quite a bit to make sure we're moving in
that direction when you say in within two levels of you do you mean lateral
or yeah hierarchical I mean latter levels okay got it got it and and those I just
want to I'll keep them abstract but it's you know similar to Microsoft is a
level of scope and responsibility that people typically can cover as they grow
through latter levels and you know I could solve the problem I'll just promote
them but they're not already to handle the scope of that work so I'm working on
that right right that's that's one thing that I I view very seriously with with
promoting folks one cool anecdote to share I don't spend long talking about but we
could actually if I could change the topic we could do a whole podcast on
growing your team when I left Microsoft and we're gonna have a longer topic on
this a little bit I recall my last several years there as teams began to
flatten there were far fewer lead positions and there were people who had
been leads or wanted to be leads it was very difficult to get into a lead
position I don't know if that's still the case or not no it's not it's not in
some regards and I forget the chronology but you were you were there for both
events and one was right when we got when we we moved tests to different
disciplines and then there was another where and not all teams did this but
it was in general with them within Microsoft like a general flattening of
organizations yeah what I recall I'm just finished my thought and you go on
with yours but whatever call is that when that flattening happened there are a lot
of leads who either moved to I see positions or what remember when there was
an opening for a lead position there would be a hundred applicants and just
the thought I was gonna say is right where I'm at now I actually have lead
positions that I can't get anyone to want to I was I am short a few leads
on my team across across the organization and I am going to have to
probably internal transfer or higher externally which is I hate I don't hate
doing for a lead it's difficult to do for a lead I think but I have to figure
something out because I'm short a couple leads and all of my IC's are like no man
I don't want to be a lead I love being an IC but go ahead and continue your
chronology sir about Microsoft well I was gonna say there was a time where we
kind of flattened the the organization as a whole within Microsoft I remember not
all teams did this but it was still sort of a general practice and I would
say things are sort of naturally kind of going back to the way it was like they're
heading back so in other words we probably over over flattened and in the
in the do-ness of time things have become a little bit more hierarchical as things
happen I don't think it's problematic at this point in time like back in the day
right a manager with two directs was super freakin common yeah it's it's it
happens it's but it's not common now back in the day someone in the senior
band might be a manager or that was super common it's not common today but it does
happen the 20 20 years ago someone far from senior could be a lead yeah yeah
actually is the wild wild west all right so anyway that's interesting grow your
bench and find good leads and take care of them because they're good people I
have two topics for the day one was a cliffhanger from our last episode if you
want to go back and check it out you can do that but the story was I was asked
to give an AMA at test bash home if you are a Ministry of testing pro subscriber
you can go watch that recording right now and the wonderful Tristan asked me
questions about the feature of test automation I think they asked me to
give this talk knowing I would be at least somewhat controversial and I came
up with three bullet points that we discussed and each designed to it in
combination the three of them together the van was designed to piss off the
most possible people unfortunately because the audience was so mature and
had actual proper critical thinking it just made him think about stuff and ask
good questions but the idea was there so I don't know if I should give you
them to you one at a time or go through all three maybe I'll do one at
a time because knowing you you'll want to comment and off the real you back
in so the first one is I have forgotten no the first one is in the future
developers will do the vast majority of all test automation okay and I was
trying to find in looking I was trying to see if someone wrote down what these
were because I I just scribbled it on a piece of paper somewhere as test bash
was approaching but I can actually find myself saying this as far back as 2016
so I don't think anything super controversial or something you hadn't
heard before actually none of these are things you hadn't heard before so that's
number one any worries about that as a prediction like the only thing I could
say that would cause it to fall apart is perhaps underestimating the the
strength of test automators white knuckles holding on to the past this
is actually my worry because there are leagues and leagues of teams who do our
test automation specialists yeah and that's what they do they don't want to
do anything else they make their money making so but I think it's right I think
it's in and for all the reasons we talked about in modern testing on this
podcast it's inefficient once developers write the code write the test for the
code they end up writing better design code because they end up writing more
testable code all these things happen lots of good things happen developers
own test automation they end up automating a lot of the right things and
they do a good job yeah I think actually one of the one of the things that is
sort of what's the opposite of a prediction the one of the things that
benefiting the opposite of your prediction is that literally everyone
that I have talked to and we even when we had that conversation with those folks
a couple of podcasts ago right I'm forgetting their name the the company
name at the moment where where they're providing test automation services reflect
on run thank you reflect that run right one of the things that is I think
slowing this down is the fact that not a lot of people are still currently aware
around around the the current studies and science on this one no no because they
like to just you know we live in our bubble they live in their bubble yeah a
so anyway I'm not surprising you there too but you can imagine you can
imagine that would push some buttons the second one again is nothing you
picking a reflect dot run nothing you haven't heard before I think record and
playback low code whatever you want to call them tools like reflect dot run
test and Mabel etc they will be the de facto standard for test automation I
think in the future handcrafted tests in Selenium sorry Jason I love you but
you're not the future handcrafted tests go away and record and playback was a
de facto for UA automation there's still actually you will use Selenium for some
special cases when you want to do a special maybe it's a stress scenario
maybe it's a smart monkey test there are some things that it will probably do
better when you want to handcraft your test but this idea of armies of sorry
not armies this idea of a mass of web tests written in Selenium running as
your product is going away those two together mean that developers will be
using these record they know how to code which is great they also know how to be
efficient and I would say in the future a developer quickly creates a record and
playback test for the UI they've done game over that's that's the way UI
testing is done and the way test wait UI test automation I'm sorry is done in the
future yeah yeah and I think it's influenced once business leaders
recognize the outcomes that we're recognizing and I think they'll shift
over right it's essentially what so what holds it back number one developers don't
want to do it number two test you know small armies of test automation
engineers obviously don't want to have their job at risk right number three
business leaders aren't actually really aware of the benefits so if business
leader once they're aware of the benefits right whether it be dev or test they're
both gonna kind of both dev and test and a lot of businesses are gonna push back
on this that's that's what's gonna slow it down at least from my experience you
need to have leaders that I don't know the way I would never mind I'm all right
I'm blocking my own tangent so the last one can try this one a little bit
because I know one way to trigger a lot of people is bring up the test
automation pyramid because I don't know why I like to push buttons and what I
said was because of the first two when the when we have a world where
developers are doing the vast majority of automation and the UI automation is done
via record and playback the benefits from that actually make the test
automation distribution just test automation pyramid true in nearly every
case wait wait wait so that's automation pyramid because of one and two test
automation pyramid becomes true yes where I think a lot of people this was back to
my comment I've said many times where people look at the test automation
pyramid and they think it's dumb to try and make their tests fit that ratio and
they're right and my viewpoint has always been that the test automation
pyramid is a reflection of what happens when you have well-designed code and I
think you'll get more of that as developers own more stuff and have an
easy way to do their UA automation you're gonna you're gonna see the
pyramid actually happen and nobody will care and this is the problem right now
people care too much about the pyramid no but it's not always right and
sometimes you want the ice cream cone and sometimes shut up stop your warning
it's a model all models are wrong some are useful everything about it makes
sense just stop getting your arms all caught up there slim buckety so let me
first thing when we're talking about when we're talking about the test
automation pyramid correct we're talking about one where there's edb
number of tests at the UI layer there's you know right more at the business layer
and then way way way way more of the unit test layer right that's what we're
talking about right so if Dev owns everything and record and playback is
done through the UI you then think unit tests will become dominant and the UI
will be I think you're overthinking this Brent and no no I'm trying to decide if
I agree with your thing and what I'm you're right I may be overthinking but
obviously what we see so if if record and playback becomes wildly successful
because of well let me phrase it differently I think those who argue with
the test automation pyramid most of the stem of their arguments come from the
fact that test rather than dev attempts to own the vast majority of test
automation I think if and when developers own automation regardless of
the children regardless of a second one when developers own automation it is much
more apt and I would say almost guaranteed that the tests fall into a
distribution as described by the test pyramid yeah I'm just wondering to what
degree the service layer like I actually wonder in your thing if you know
the quote-unquote middle class disappears because it's really the thing there's
there's not if the pyramid puts those nice lines between things it's test get
more granular less granular depending on where you're going there's a fuzzy line
between things you call unit tests and things you call functional tests and even
things you call UI tests or end-to-end tests yeah the the only issue is is that
I actually see you know UI tests you know taking over if it ends up being that
easy and you know fixing shit through through ML supported methods right ends up
being that easy then I could easily see the the business rule automation sort of
disappearing unit tests thing because of how fast it is and things along those
lines I kind of I feel like I agree with you that that would be at the bottom but
I'm wondering if the pyramid becomes a square I don't think so I think and
I'll say this again for those who have heard me say this I think today due to
ownership and the popularity and nothing again love you Jason nothing against
Selenium I think the industry has an unhealthy infatuation with UI automation
and I think the in the future that goes away explain that in the context of
your principle number two today with test owning writing the UI automation and
loving loving loving Selenium and having it being a separate team often not even
connected or talking with the dev team agree right thousands and hundreds of
thousands of lines of Selenium code to execute the UI of their application it
takes a long time those tests are can be flaky when selectors changes lots of
stuff you can do around that to make those more resilient but still they are
flaky and it takes a lot of time to build and maintain those tests I'm saying
in the future it's going to be much more efficient to just record and
playback that test and if the test ever can't handle those tests again
with the right tools those record and playback tests will automatically adapt
to changes in your underlying selectors layout etc if it ever gets to a point
where your test just the tool can't keep up with the overall you made to your
website I think it's still faster just to go rerecord that test than it
would ever have been to continue to handcraft and maintain those tests over
time I now understand where we we where you and I where I was having
difficulty getting to the same page in your book and it was essentially because
you talk about UI automation and in all of that discussion that synonymous with
with handcrafted UI automation right to me recording playback is still UI
automation it is I did not mean to imply otherwise right but the value proposition
of having a whole team whose job it is to spend 50% of their time taking
yesterday's flaky tests and turning them into tomorrow's different flaky tests
right that shit goes away I think that the tools today are very resilient to
change in underlying code and that's what's been missing and again we came
from a world you and I hear record and playback we automatically think nope way
too flaky for use the world's changed in the web world at least stuff got
better anyway that's it I do want to get to the other topic today which I think
is gonna require some discussion so that's sort of a recap I encourage you
who are pro members to go to the ministry testing site and check out that
talk it's very I had a good time lots of good feedback and I'm surprised given
the at my attempt at controversy which kind of failed that it was still fun I
at least got some people to think which is always what we strive for and
maybe testing and so I try and take that stuff elsewhere so did you get any push
back on not really not really there are some tangential questions around well
should testers still learn to code and of course I think yes and I think it's a
lot of things that could do that aren't writing test automation there's
lots of tooling and even doing some testing that isn't necessarily driving
the UI but no real pushback no real pushback people there's stuff like
people didn't really believe me like oh yeah I could see why you think that but
that won't work in my world a lot of the snowflake stuff you overtime what
happens I could be wrong but it's a world where I think it's a better world the
future I described is it is it is achievable it's what Steven Johnson
calls the adjacent possible it's right there we just need teams to start
doing it and I have found I also discovered not just teams I've worked
with here at Unity but I have now found other team for the development
teams are more and more like when we first talked about modern testing team say oh
hey we're doing that I am finding development teams who are using record
and playback tools for the UI automation so it's it's happening just not
widespread yet I think it's gonna be big we had a subject change not really a
mailbag question but a good inquisitive question on the slack
channel today it's something I've been asked before and worth talking about if
you can recall way back remember the you don't remember it but the listeners
are three listeners may remember we did a podcast once without Brent I invited I
invited all three to join me in this small room kind of off behind the seats
in the room where we had a test bash Philly in 2016 I was at Microsoft
working on Microsoft Teams and I gave a talk on testing without testers sort of
the beginning of how I have been working with teams to on quality coaching we
took we have previous podcast or talked about that will rehash a little bit of
that but they asked a very good question they say Alan I'm gonna I'm gonna for
Raghu on it's like I'm gonna summarize this whole thing to something I've heard
before so you're pretty passionate about modern testing and not having dedicated
testers and test coaching and you worked on teams but with all that said
you worked on teams Microsoft Teams and Brett don't say anything you'd stop in
trouble but they say but Microsoft Teams really really sucks so what happened is
it did you really are you are you not walking the talk or whatever again I'll
do most of talking to your Brett in case you know your boss is ever listening I
like like honestly I can't imagine Microsoft you can't badmouth our
product every single Microsoft product is excellent and you need to tout our
awesomeness no so there will be no teams bashing for me today I I do think it has
I mean it has it has wads but generally generally a lot of those wads can be
traced that sometimes can be traced back to two things that I have a very
particular interest there will be none of that today but as it relates to what
the hell Alan you you hypocrite I'm all aboard on that conversation okay so let
me talk let me just rehash a little bit those haven't been on the podcast for a
long time we talked about it when I was there on the podcast I don't
remember numbers back in the 60s or 70s it's been a while not episode
numbers not years so I joined teams as an individual contributor to they were
very early on they were about 75 developers maybe all up at the time maybe
less maybe 50 I can't quite remember but they wanted someone to come in and
help the team think more about quality they did not having dedicated testers they
had some former testers working on infrastructure here and there but they
didn't really have anyone helping the team think about testing I joined the
team and they had a pretty good suite of unit tests in place and some other tests
which weren't very good they did as I've described elsewhere all the testing they
knew how to do and they put some effort into it it wasn't great but it
wasn't horrible so that's where I started and I joined the team and I did
some stuff kind of like a test manager would for the team I just I made sure
bug tracking was in place and we had some bug metrics boring but worth
tracking for tech debt I did some communication around quality and just kind
of set the team up a little bit with the quality culture maybe some of my first
thinking that in develop the quality culture guide till a couple years later
but at least stuff that was in my head way more years later yeah so one
thing I realized there so I did a couple times I did a bug bash kind of
thing let's take two hours today or a half a day today and we'll all do a bunch
of testing on the project and I would they mostly did it in teams like small
little teams getting together to work on things and I would roam fairly small
team and give them ideas and help them and I of course I have been coaching
them and giving them ideas on quality little tidbits here and there before
then and this was the first time I discovered that given the freedom and
permission to do so developers can do very excellent testing not checking God
okay I'm gonna avoid that very deep good test they dug in they found bugs that
only the very some of them some of them just found very surface level things but
a good number of them found bugs that only the best testers I know may have
found very deep important bugs and they just they looked at how the system fit
together and found some flaws that were worth fixing definitely your P0 type
bugs so that was a revelation like yes they actually can do great testing
wasn't really revelation I expected it would happen but it sort of provided
some proof so in the early days we were trying to get we're trying to get
product market fit trying to prove viability trying to figure out if we're
making something that could be sold and as typical for many projects at Microsoft
there were several teams at the time originally working on similar things
they wanted something that was sort of compete in that slack space and over
time they we built in the the conferencing stuff too but we we kind of
won out along the Microsoft teams among the Microsoft organizations building
communication and collaboration type tools so at that stage all pretty good
we're still pretty small trying to find the right product we did and it was
working I over time I took over to have the most influence over quality I took
over running all of our infrastructure teams as well as kind of putting on a
release manager hat for our beta and I left right after the beta to just have
as much control as I could as I could over what we were releasing quality
understanding understanding where risk was also in the modern testing world
helping the team get to a stage where they could comfortably release every
week and not worry about it's for the we actually release all the back-end
services all the time but the front end once a week and getting a team used
to that that was hard believe it or not because they were so used to your
typical waterfall ship every year projects a lot of these folks that they
would even for a once a week release they try and shove stuff in at the end
they say look the next trains coming by and I at the time when I was there I
really wanted to get them to continuous delivery on the front end right but we
just didn't have they didn't have the quality cultures to do it talk about
why in a minute I wanted to get there I ended up hiring a team in India to help
with testing because the develop I'll get to the crux of this the developers
were too busy doing other stuff to get to to get to doing the testing that it
needed to do and what it came down to was really the culture of the team
which is eventually why I left Microsoft Teams was I can say in my 22 years
at Microsoft hands down the most toxic culture I ever worked in there was
nothing about the customer it was all about pleasing your boss and pleasing
their boss I had never worked with such a huge group of suck-ups in my life
you know I said earlier I said it a million times you know unity it's easy to
do good work because the egos don't get in the way best ideas win the things
you want to see but at teams it was so hard to do good work because if you
did the right thing for the customer doesn't matter if you didn't matter if
it's a huge win for the customer if it wasn't done in a way that sufficiently
sucked up to your manager or to their manager it was gaffod so we had a
program manager which is a Microsoft or like a product manager in the rest of the
world who was I remember the time I remember the time I knew the end was
near I was in a we used to call a war room meetings and then became something
else a ship room a ship room meeting and we had just put the the Alpha out or the
first beta some early release before the beta maybe it was the beta that went out
I can't remember what the order was and he had went and you know got feedback
from some other teams at Microsoft and some customers and came up with a list
of things that had to be fixed in fact I didn't know if it was customer-based I
think it was made money been from our VP but he's like ten things we gotta do and
we have to do these and we have to do them by this date and he went he got up
a little bit of a soapbox and said every priority is getting these things
done in time for in time for this whatever this date was we'll take
shortcuts where we need to we have to have these done and I chimed it said
yeah but we can't sacrifice quality we have a good quality release we can't
sacrifice it he got mad he is like yeah he says quality is one of the shortcuts
we'll take to get these done and at that point I knew I was in a losing battle
because he was fairly new to the org but he had joined the org because he was a
previous suck up of our VP and he had our VP's ear and once he knew that I
was against getting these features done over the favor of quality it was
basically impossible for me to get my job done so combination of that my boss
calling me at home to ask why I approved something for release just all kinds of
micromanaging and toxicity kind of caused me to leave but I think those things
this prioritization of features over quality this inability or unwillingness
to understand the value that CD brings to quality after I left they went to a
point where their changes and bugs were so jarring in their big weekly releases
that it's like my reaction be okay we just ship you know continuous delivery
ship our often puts FBI and feature flight theater right their immediate
reaction was to go ship that front end monthly instead of weekly and I have
told you a thousand times I'm sure you agree I would rather ship a hundred
times a day than once a month and I and I believe those things led to gaps
in quality I could say I can say that from a data perspective as advances as
you would expect any Microsoft team to be we could debug we knew exactly where
customers were getting failures and what was going on there the problem was there
were so many failures that we had a hard time prioritizing them sometimes it
wasn't it wasn't tractable because it was so frequent that's more into why I
left than the quality issues but I'm going from what I heard from immediately
after I left I talked to some people for a little while in fact I hired one of
my previous managers to take over my job when I left and he's much more of the
traditional test manager which I thought would be good for that org but
maybe it wasn't because he was all too happy to drop back to shipping once a
month and doing a full test pass with the even an even bigger team of
offshore testers in India and I think a lot of those things just trying there
was still trying when I left or at least in that first six months after I left
they were still trying to test quality in via outsource team and I just don't
think that's a good recipe for long-term quality success so that's where
I think happened there but I didn't even make fun of team as much as I want
except for the fact that I can tell you that it at least they have a
Linux client now which I have installed and uninstalled occasionally what I have
to do a Teams meeting but honestly zoom and slack I have to say whether I worked
on teams before or not I love so much more I would say teams is to its credit
teams being part of office 365 is genius because it's the collaboration app for
companies that don't know the need a collaboration app nobody's switching
from slack to teams released willingly but teams that don't use a collaboration
app they can they'll use teams and it's it's kind of okay it's not great there
are some bugs and not to say zoom doesn't have bugs and slack doesn't have
bugs these things all have bugs and I'm not gonna go list them all out and see
which one is buggier but for me the zoom slack combination has been pretty
awesome so anyway that that's the story of why I think quality remember do you
work with Ronnie Calabi yeah so he has that term he came up with the term he
coined the term the hippo the highest paid person's opinion and you want to
avoid that and be data-driven this team very much and they have a new VP in
place since I since in the last year or so but teams was very much at the
every feature every decision was at the whim of the VP running the org I
think that's what led to the quality where it was the story I think you just
told I mean it happened there were there were some things that I'm not
gonna talk about on the podcast that I think were unique to your situation
but in general I think 80 to 90 percent of your situation was essentially a team
and transformation right it's essentially you had you had a lot of old
schoolers in the business leadership folks that would say hey I've been shipping
product for 20 years I know how to do it blah blah blah yeah at the same time you
had those folks building a what is essentially a service and not really
adapting well and what happened in this particular case I think your story is is
one around how agile transformations can go wrong right so I have talked about it
on the podcast as well you and I had different experiences and being the in
the Xbox right my experience on the Xbox org I will I'll just quite honestly say
very very aligned with the story you just told right they were not an agile
team they were a fragile team and they and it was during that period of time in
Microsoft where they were where again agile principles were being weaponized
instead of being used for the the benefit of the customer and there weren't
a whole lot of people that really understood how to do it even me at that
point in time like I left Xbox to to go to Bing at that point in time because
they were a service and I went to Bing to learn how to do this right and I did
and I don't know too much about the internal structure I have a few contacts
in teams I don't talk to them all that often but to me I think actually the
story to tell there right the difference between zoom and in slack in teams might
very well be I'll frame it as a hypothesis my very well be you know how
long it took teams to to realize that they needed to shift to it to some form
a CICD model yeah I don't know if they're there yet I don't I I would hope
so but I don't know it doesn't matter I have some evidence that they might be but
I can't say one way or the other I don't actually know but this is teams is where I
learned how to do safe deployments I'm we would do originally I got there we
had a both a dev environment and a test environment and the regular environment
the typical environments you have and the dev environment was always crappy and
I remember this is funny it's reminding me I remember that nobody on team is
before we ship but nobody used the prod everyone used dev go after use dev
loading get the new features but oh god this is bad but eventually we had one
environment with with ring deployment so we when we did our weekly release we
always like released on Friday but we did the snapshot on Monday and that
snapshot on Monday immediately went to prod but that version was only available
for first my team and then we roll it out to usually if it passed initial
sort of smoke testing would go to all of the Microsoft Teams team and then to
all of Microsoft and then eventually on Friday release it to customers which
was you know my first experience doing that kind of staged rollout which was
really powerful way to do that and that was fun and I loved it but hopefully
that got even faster but I totally forgot that yeah and I went back and
looked back in time the one thing I'll say is to the best of my knowledge teams
was the first time where you were taking a very direct hand in trying to
ship the waterfall team to to an agile team it was worse it was a it was a
edge it was a waterfall team who thought they were agile right yeah it yeah go
back to that's exactly my experience the back box and and for the listeners like
I left before Alan joined and any overlap at all there I don't think so
when did you do you remember when you left it linked in would show it I'm not
gonna go look at LinkedIn so I remember I joined Xbox on Halloween in 2013 yeah I
was in being so I think there was a gap of months there so no no overlap because
I I joined being in pretty certain 2012 I either joined Bing in 2012 or a left
thing in 2012 I don't remember the point of the story I think here and if
I go back in time as well I went back in into our podcast and look for what
was the date of the episode titled the conception of modern testing right that
was in 2018 which I believe you were already in unity oh yeah yeah for sure
I was well but right yeah we've been talking about we just didn't have a name
for it maybe we've been talking about modern testing for a long time right like
but it's the beginning right the my point is in terms of hey Alan did this
you know Alan keeps talking about all these principles and all these things
so how come teams is all screwed up the the one thing I'll say on that front is
you don't learn from success true only learn from failure and what I will say
is a lot of Alan's Alan and I have never had this good discussion but I am so
confident in what I'm about to say I'm gonna say it anyway you're wrong a lot
of Alan's thought process around supportive of modern testing when he was
thinking through it he absolutely was considering what he views as personal
failures from his experience with teams right yeah I agree and there's there's
two things maybe to highlight there one is that definitely the modern testing
principles were nowhere near being formed at that point it took me going
back to managing a test team for a while at Unity to kind of think through
that as well as building that quality culture transition guide at Unity with
reflection on time I spent on Xbox and on teams doing coaching yeah those ideas
came primarily like even when I joined Unity back in a test manager role it
made me go back and think about what actually mattered and how testers should
work it's that's what I began to think about using it when you have dedicated
testers using them to accelerate accelerate the achievable quality or to
accelerate the team versus be a bottleneck and then building that
quality culture and then and then maybe that last principle came from my time at
Unity when you have dedicated testers you can use them to help expand the
testing abilities and know-how across the org and all that came from a lot of
reflection and in fact when I first gave the talk in 2017 let me think whenever I
gave that talk at test bash in Brighton the first time I give a public talk
about modern testing it started with the history all the things I had learned
from Xbox and then from teams and then from Unity and how those all came
together into the principles so back on teams I had a lot of good ideas I
learned how coaching worked I learned how to teach I began to realize that yes
developers can be very very good testers but my full thoughts on how to
achieve quality even though I gave a talk on testing without testers my full
thoughts on how to achieve quality without dedicated testing specialists
didn't fully come to fruition for a few years after that based on what I
learned there and if both you and I have multiple different experiences around
attempting the principles trying things out and going well that didn't
work that that that that not only didn't work like one of the things I think we've
talked about in the past in my view agile principles will far out produce not
only slightly it will far out produce waterfalls based mentality okay it far
but the one thing that is the Achilles heel to agile do you want to make a
singular guess before I drop the bomb nope go ahead the Achilles heel to agile
is command and control absolutely right there is that I have yet to find anything
with with agile that that successfully survives a hierarchical structure where
the hierarchy is is against it right or or or even either against it directly or
indirectly even micro management might instead of using quantification or other
other means a customer usage to to sort of drive decision-making so that's
something that I think is is it's actually one of the reasons why you make
fun of me all the time on this one but it's one of the reasons why I actually
still do favor the safe methods because safe actually tries to make the
management part of the agile process instead of say scrum that's another
conversation on their slack channel right now around sort of the failings of
scrum and scrum scrum has had the sort of history of of enforced autonomy
management's the man and scrum is anti the man right and I think that actually
holds it down or holds it back and creates limits yeah that's my philosophy
yeah I'm with you man okay so that's kind of the story you know we can go
deeper if there are more questions but that was way easier to talk about it
here cuz I think it's interesting to everybody else and I like I like where we
got with that then trying to have an answer in slack again if you want to see
these slack conversations or ask your own questions in slack you can go to
modern testing org and join our slack group there is no cost for that it is
absolutely free of course you get what you pay for which is me and Brent being
smart asses in slack but it's fun we have we have we have taco emoji so it
would give away yeah one one additional thing that I at least want to say is
despite what you feel about teams I will say teams has actually been in a
important asset to the globe during the pandemic times I totally agree and I
think it goes back to the fact that the vast majority of people who are using
office 365 or office subscriptions to their enterprise they're not using any
other collaboration tool and it just it just gives it to them in a way that's
comfortable and it integrates with the way they work and then one thing worth
sharing it so I totally get that but I'll mention a name the old VP he really
wanted to compete with slack I want to take out slack and and Stuart Butterfield
was worried for a while he's put out that that full page ad the day teams
came out which was kind of cool but it says welcome to the welcome to the game
but it really fits the niche because those office 365 companies that use that
and there are hundreds of thousands if not millions of users in that camp
they're not going out and getting slack licenses they they just get teams as
part of the package they already have it's very convenient works very well I'm
all it it fits there very well something else I was gonna say there but I forgot
and we're out of time anyway all right okay everybody thanks for being part of
our podcast today all three of you you and you and you I'll see you next time
I'm Alan I'm brain bye bye