Welcome to AV testing podcast your modern testing podcast your hosts Alan and Brent will be here to guide you through topics on testing
Leadership agile and anything else that comes to mind now on with the show
This is the AV testing podcast and I'm
Brent and yay is this episode 133 is that correct that is and by now everyone should be finding our podcast
I change hosts for a couple reasons and it didn't go as smoothly as I wanted because I realized that
One I thought it was bad that a lot of a lot of
Podcast hosts make their own feeds which actually I can see what they do that
So I'm not mad at them
But it turns out a lot of them base their feed purely on the iTunes feed which is weird versus the source feed
But that's okay, but it just took longer to get the Apple iTunes feed updated, but it looks like it's all set
So now you should be hearing this. This is our second podcast of 2020
We love all of you. And hey, do you know how you find out more about the podcast Brent you go to?
AB testing calm you do not go to a B testing calm
What are we talking about on here a thing that's not really modern and a thing that's not really testing
You know the answer to that question Brent. Yes
Yes, I do you can go to modern testing org
You oh, oh, I guess I didn't which is the site a domain
We got a couple years ago for start talking about this that used to direct to a B testing
On my angry weasel site, but now it goes to actual modern testing org
I've set it up as a real website
Nice. Yeah
It's not super pretty but happy to take volunteer web developers and the way to get involved with anything you want
Behind the scenes on the podcast is to go to modern testing org and in the sparse amount of text there
Find the link to join our slack group one of the three dot slack comm
How's that for an intro and get everybody hooked? I'll give you a minute to go find that website and log in and say hi
Right the clone the github repro and yeah, we got we got
Typing while he's talking again
Which I don't like well, I can't remember we were recording when I said that the hard time thing is I can't punch you
We were weren't me. Okay?
The first things first before we get starting with a couple topics today is Brent wanted to talk about balls. I did
And you can't see this on the podcast, but right behind me in my
luxurious office here in East Seattle otherwise known as Issaquah Washington is
some balls is a mighty fine stack of some big balls
soccer balls except for one rugby ball the rugby balls the outlier I got that on a trip to
New Zealand that Australia that's an Australian
Replica rug just a souvenir rugby ball. I got in Australia the rest are ever since
For many years. I don't have all of them up there, but for the past
But for the past
2024 years or so I
Have procured myself every year they design it every four years when there's a World Cup
That's a tournament for soccer or football. It's a game
It's the most populous one in the world but popular but anyway, Oh Super Bowl. That's like in two weeks. Oh god
I don't even know who I lost interest
Although the funny tangent is here, but I'll finish the story first
No tangent is I every World Cup
They make a specific ball and I get a ball from that World Cup and save it never play it
I just kind of I have brand new
soccer balls footballs from every World Cup back to
Before Korea so it must have been it maybe back to the US run the first US run anyway
What was I gonna tangent on I don't remember doesn't matter the Olympics?
the Olympics no
Wrong. Oh
guess again
All right, so okay one thing I'm curious though so one of the soccer balls
Looks like it's impaled by a frisbee
That is purely an optical illusion. There's actually some other crap laying up there. It's not a soccer ball
It's just balls and a couple of things they threw up there
Gotcha. All right, cuz I was wondering what the hell that was but it's an optical illusion it all right
Thanks for coming to our podcast everyone
We can skip the politics session for this week up. There's stuff happening and there's still idiots just like always they're just more prominent now
Don't you want to do the the podcast podcast or is it too early in the episode for that?
It I mean, it's uncharacteristic early. We're like five minutes in
I feel like we should just like wait for five minutes and then start but why don't maybe maybe ten minutes in
No
Why don't we do this?
Cuz this is because sometimes we talk about like what's been going on and and why don't we talk about the article?
I posted two weeks ago. Maybe it's
Tuesday of last week and
We talked let's talk about that so yeah last time on the podcast
Insert clip here. No, I'm too lazy
We were talking about this idea of mindsets and skill sets and how it never quite sat right and I was working on an article on it
And I went that weekend after the podcast and finished the article. I just needed to get some ideas going and
posted to
Exactly the reaction I expected and the gist of the article if you haven't read it you can
Find it in my five for Friday last week or in my Twitter feed. I don't have the URL memorized
But it's on the the blog test project IO and the gist of it was that I
argued the fact that folks like
Michael Bolton James Bock have posted that
Shifting from a creator's mindset to a testers mindset requires a massive and difficult mind shift. I I poo pooed that and
Gave some examples. I said those are really skill sets and
There's no block that developers can't do very very good testing and as expected
90% of the replies were duh. Yeah. Thank you. It's it's funny how I can get this happens a lot
because I'd like to try and tow the line a little bit is
For as many people as I get I get people agreeing, but I also get people saying this is old news
Why are people still talking about this? This is dumb and other people thinking like I'm killing a cat
I'm on the the old news camp, right? There's a reason why we call what we've done
modern testing
the other thing to point out that I always want to point out is you're probably gonna get to but I'm on a roll and
I'm riled up is that sorry go for it
Didn't invent anything with modern testing and we've been accused
I've been accused of inventing something that's harming the craft and Brent. Did we invent anything at all?
Um that answer is no we we invented a name
Yeah, we put a name to something that we were seeing if you go back to our very very first podcast
Don't listen to it. Trust me. We're much better now as bad as it is. We're better now
We would we just wanted to talk about what we were seeing to help people who may be going through the same thing not freak out
and
What we see is people putting their heads in the sand and freaking out if people want to give us
Credit for this obviously it's wrong and inappropriate
It's it's interesting because I actually
As you know
We are not harming the craft the craft
has
long since been under threat and
What we are doing
For those who listen are
protecting
the craftsmen
Right. It's essentially
God normally I can load a metaphor here
Right, but there's a long biscuit in a wood shredder
Right. No, no, I'm thinking of
Normally I go back to
Cobalt right or or cobalt not cobalt. That's cobalt is an element cobalt is a programming language
While I am chronologically older that you are a dimension old man go on
Yeah, I definitely resemble that fact like Alan to me in some regard like continuing this discussion on
Is test dying blah blah blah. I
Won't even play that game anymore. No, it's it's like I'm already starting conversations and starting to bring up
That my view we are right now
at the beginning of the end of the data science
Specialist there there will be people holding on to that specialty for decades as well. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah for sure
It's especially I went to school for this I studied this I've put a lot of heart and soul into it
Please don't take it away. I'm unwilling to adapt
There will be that
Maybe maybe the problem is right now
there's a glut of folks coming out of school with that and
They're not able to to sort of land the job in the career
And that would be true even if we weren't in a in the midst of a covid nightmare
So what one point I want to make and of course I I have Bolton and Bach muted
Not blocked but muted on Twitter. So sometimes they can show up. I don't sure how the meeting algorithm works actually
but it was pointed out to me that the response to
Bach on my article was that I thought it was interesting. I see exactly where he's coming from but I think it's bullshit as well
he said something to the effect of
Unless Alan you've studied social sciences, you really don't get testing
Which says two things to me one is for the testing
one
first answer, huh
to I don't know how I mean sure if you want to
I'm not gonna deny some applicability. Maybe and I'm giving in the benefit of the doubt on number two, but number three is
Huh again, so for number three, it's just I don't care
Repeat the quote it was I'm paraphrasing
It was people do is if they're not quite sure how to engage me on something
They know that Bolton and Bach will be pissed about they just tag him they tag him in a Twitter and
Apparently Bach came in I just glanced at it cuz again cuz how meat works but something to the effect of
Unless you've been studying social sciences is the art
This isn't really what they're doing isn't really testing and that's what I wanted to get to is
historically
historically, if you look what Bach has done to
Elizabeth Hendrickson and
Lisa Crispin where he's I've seen him say like because he hasn't seen them test. They're not good testers and
it's like he has the
Authority to decide what good testing is and what good testing isn't and he doesn't not in a million years, you know who gets to decide
Nobody actually cut customers closely. They get to value a quality and here's the trick. Here's the thing you and I
Agree on which comes out to be the crux of all these these people who get stuck in
Celebrating the craft is they care
1000% more about testing than they do about quality
Yes
Slaps me in the face. I suck. I just do not get how you can
So I love the craft and I was deep in the man. I'll learn a lot about testing
I know a lot about testing. I'm gonna talk about testing
I'm gonna write a book about testing
But which I did as you know, and I don't like it anymore because I care about now is quality customers
Don't care what testing we did. They don't care if I'm a skilled practitioner of the arts and social scientists and testing
They don't care if I could ask a hundred and one
Totally dumb straw man argument questions about testing. They care if the product solves their problem in a way that they enjoy
Just say true. Hallelujah. Amen
True. Hallelujah and
Amen
Part of the I mean, there's so many things that came out and what you were just saying like number one
I don't know what you're doing, but get to the point we talked about this last time. So let's let's get get to it, man
Number one
Yeah, there is a good deal of
Ivory Tower ism in his statement there, right? It's
Unless you have studied
Sociology
I'll find the quote and again coming from where he's coming from and again
Every behavior has a motivation. Oh
Sure, and I'll look up the tweets here a second
I'll stop trying to type while I or type on my phone while I talk but
from his view
Testing is the most important thing doing good testing his client
his only stakeholder is the person who's made that software and
First so for that angle. Yeah, he wants to do the very best job find the best report
give the give the stakeholder all the information because
From that school they're not decision makers or information providers and for a lot of people it's all about the customer
So the focus is different. So we think about things differently. I get where he's coming from. I vehemently disagree with it
But he's not spouting nonsense as much as I really kind of don't like the guy. I think he's smart
What he's essentially saying like you and I have talked about many a times
That the activity of testing is important. Number one, huh?
No argument. No argument number two and in the end
I guess number three the thing that so that's one place. I think we're in VM an agreement
The the thing that I guess continues to be fuddle me is
Given the this amounting evidence
On your side on on on the mindset discussion
All right, it being a skill set versus a might say let me let me give you the exact
exchange
When you're when you're ready, let me get I'm gonna give you the exact exchange. I don't want to go too deep into this
I don't feel it's fair regardless of my opinions
I don't want to go into rank on somebody on the podcast when I wouldn't engage him on Twitter
But I went and looked it up because I only glanced at it
Uh when it was pointed out to me responding to my post with my article someone replied and of course tagged in michael and james
And said oh they brought up the idea of the problem of critical distance
Which is a nice term that I could find very little information on to define it and try and rebut it but the idea is
That because I wrote it. I can't test it which again. My reply was I found this theory to be largely false in my experience
Which is absolutely true. I'm not not trying to be provoking
I have found people that I have found critical distance to be not just false but a flat out falsehood
Which is the same thing?
So then uh james jumped in and said in my experience
You've never studied this stuff or did you start reading the literature on cognitive biases boundary objects social forms of life and sense making
While we weren't looking which I thought was kind of a passive aggressive dick move
Oh, I didn't look at the replies, but there's more after that but the thing is
We're coming from different places and and I like to believe i'm coming from a place
That's going to help people who are in test rules be not just keep their jobs
Which some people are worried about and worried about the right testing happening
What we're talking about on the podcast. I want to help people freaking thrive as software changes in a day
And figure out how they can take all of this
I already closed the tweet cognitive social stuff and apply it to all this stuff if you do it, right?
It applies to building an entire learning organization like peter singe talks about which I that's a that's a what I try and strive for
I use everything I learned in the critical thinking and systems thinking that I used as a tester to build an organization
that is capable of
Delivering predictably and with high quality. I use the same skills. I just don't use them to do one aspect of software delivery
uh, agree
agreed
but the other thing I was going to say on this one because I have the thread loaded up and
And bach was coming in with all sorts of
You know
How social creatures work?
Right, and that's actually one of the things I think is brilliant around like we've talked about it repeatedly on on tvd
the one of the things that's brilliant about tdd
is
The the person's writing the test before the code. Yes. It does it does it solve cognitive bias? No
But damn alan, it sure helps mitigate it
Right it just just in the fact that it creates a much better code base for for testing
In general it it reduces the that risk and in terms of cognitive bias
Right, i'll just be quite honest
even if test were
That the assumption there is test is able to maintain objectivity
And and not be biased as they go through their testing
and
That that by itself is fundamentally false
Right, even if their statements were true, I would argue that that that it that occurs even amongst the craftsmen
today
so
in my mind that that that
That statement is true on both sides and therefore can be safely ignored
The one thing that puzzles me here, right and this is the thing and we can go on to another topic if you want. Um
After this but the one thing I just don't understand
If they view your
Article and we don't have evidence here
But if if your article is viewed as a as a direct threat to sort of, you know
the dogma that that they're talking
in the face of
Of the by not the bias in the face of the the evidence that we that we're seeing
that contradicts this
Contradicts their point of view
Like I I just don't understand like I I completely agree that that
testing is is important
But why are they so reluctant?
to
Encourage and invite and market amongst developers
Well, why are they so reluctant?
Why now why this you already stole my next topic, but yeah, and this is why maybe
I can't get in their heads. I don't want to actually insert myself into other feeds they've had
Many of our listeners have heard those but
I want to skip that but if you look at one of the things I love about elizabeth hendrickson's exploratory testing book
Is it specifically talks about teaching developers exploratory testing?
And what i've noticed in my everything, you know, I I don't just make this stuff up
We watch stuff. I read I read books and articles and try and put it all together
I want to look for a full system's view of what's happened
Not just what you and I are seeing what's happening across the industry
And I got to tell you what I find more and more and more is when we go to highlight stuff
Like think of everything we've highlighted
Chances are I can find an example of elizabeth hendrickson highlighting it eight to ten years before we did
Yeah, well, she is pretty awesome listening to
Uh the ideal cast by jean kim and i've tweeted a couple times about this so worth calling up here and I listened to her episodes
Specifically there's one that's an interview and one there's some outtakes of a conference talk she gave in 2014 and 2015
That kind of backed up the point. She was talking for a while around
This article that she wrote with some other folks and chem caner what they did. There's like 17 of these tests
This is like 2001
This is a ways back. This is when you and I still thought testing was the schnitzel
Yeah, and she was meeting with these folks and they're trying to answer the age-old question. What's the right ratio of developers to testers?
And as you know, microsoft used to be almost one to one and windows was almost two to one in some groups
And they want to answer when I started when I started it was two to one
So the way they did it yeah
And what my answer has always been even very early on I what I was in
I didn't really care about it
I was in ee and had to think about engineering excellence group at microsoft and I realized the only
When did I join that group about 2005? So i'm still behind
The only right answer for that question is it depends
Or as I learned to put it shortly after if you're asking about ratios you're asking the wrong question
so
What they did as a thought experiment a good little affinity exercise was they asked people to think of
What was the ratio on the team that had the best project ever as far as delivery and quality?
What was the ratio of devs to test and what was the worst quality?
What was the biggest on the biggest train wreck you ever worked on? What was the ratio?
And they didn't find a lot of correlation on the high quality products, but they found massive correlation on
The low quality train wreck products. They all had a very high tester to developer ratio
You and I are not surprised
2001 you and I may have been surprised. I gotta tell you that
So in passing there one of the things she said this is
She just gets it but she like you and I we try and stir the water. She just knows she's like the
She's like the obi-wan Kenobi waiting for us to learn this stuff. I think
she
Said just in passing was talking about a test team like I can't even fathom the idea of a dedicated test team
Like I don't even get why that would even be a thing anymore
And you know, it is a thing and people are proud of their dedicated test teams
Anyway, the point you got to on ownership is interesting and I want to use that or or actually the point you made that I just totally
Screwed the pooch on the point you made was why aren't they talking to developers about doing better testing?
And
I have an answer but it's flippant even though I think it's right
So i'm going to skip it
But I want to talk about developer testing and it's sort of a piggyback on that last article. I wrote
Let me go back to 2015 when I went to google test automation conference in kirkland
Uh, it was the second or third one. I went to and a whole bunch of talks. I wasn't presenting. I was just watching
It was in kirkland
You know
Humans are good at pattern matching
And very quickly I noticed a pattern that if I would have turned into a drinking contest would have killed me
This is how many times each talk
Said the two-word phrase
Flaky tests
I wanted to call it the flaky test conference
It's a problem that you and I have dealt with for years and years and years
Developers write about and this is especially true, especially true today in the world of selenium
and
Lots of automation teams not only is a dedicated team dedicated test automation team
And they write a bunch of tests and
They're proud of the fact they have a hundred thousand tests
But 5 000 of them are weird and flaky and they do things like run them again or run them 10 times or they pass once
That's good. I'll just delete them because they don't want to run the flaky test only ones. Don't tell us any information
And that bugged me and there's a solution for this. I want to get to
but
the other thing I was going to mention is
Accelerate
In you've heard us mention this book called accelerate written by nicole forest green and some other people
We love that book
People love the dora metrics. The um, the the four devops metrics that tell you if you're going to be high quality
Well a lot of reviews of the book leave out some other important
Indicators of quality and there's one you've highlighted on the podcast before
I want to highlight for you then i'm going to ask you a question and stop talking that you answer and ponder for me
Okay, she's talking about automated testing
In the book. Yes, and she says
First the code becomes more testable when developers write tests
Second when developers are responsible for the automated tests
They care more about them and will invest more effort into maintaining and fixing them
And what she's found here is the thing she's underlying is that
When developers own the automated testing those tests are higher quality in the products higher quality is a correlation between developers owning the tests
and product quality
So let me give you a rant with a setup statement and i've talked i've been on my soapbox almost long enough here
so given that there's scientific correlation proving this
And given that in my experience writing especially ui end-to-end automation is one of the most difficult programming tasks
you can do properly and non-flaky and
Given the fact that almost every time I talk to folks who write these sort of end-to-end
Ui automation tests they're doing it because it's the only level that the code is testable at
Given all this data
Why don't?
I see a given developers should write every single automated test
ever always
And that'll even piss off some of our listeners
I know we have avid listeners who love what we do who still spend a lot of their day writing test automation
I don't think it works. I think it's we've fallen into this weird rut where it's work that the developers don't want to do
But all according to studies here and according to everything i've seen it results in lower quality
If you want to raise the quality of your team
Everyone if you're not developing the code don't write automated tests for it
Number one, I mean do you want I mean I completely agree with everything that you're saying like what what well agree with it in
An elegant way that will allow our listeners to get a second point of view and be less mad at me and while I can ever
Yeah
Like I i'm still thinking around the prior conversation in the cognitive bias issue. Okay, um
one of the issues he even if
test had
uh
perfect ability to
To look at the code and be objective and and do the right thing which which again they don't
Uh, because they turned out to be just as human as the developers who wrote the code. Okay
It is very rare in my experience
that test has
sufficient power
For action to be taken
Okay, um
And of course the rst model will will address that because that's not their job. Their job is to provide information
okay
And information provided that no one takes action on
has um
I would imagine
a remarkably low impact to quality
Now even even further one of the things that that they called out
So that study that that that nicole did in in accelerate it calls out two things. It's essentially
they found
that
automation
Only correlated to a high functioning software. I forget their actual definition
But to good software
When the dev owned the automation
right
In other words when test owned it they found no correlation to that automation
Improving the software no and an anecdotal I can tell you why and there are only people that will dismiss this. Let me explain
I don't think this is going to be made up. Let me tell you why this works
I find it funny that the only I'm going to start with the test pyramid and I find it funny that the only people who
gripe about it and try and uh dismiss it as as useless are testers
So all the test automation pyramid says people get freaked out about the model
Of course, all models are useful and some are wrong. The reason why it works is today
Developers write code most developers
We're getting to a point where I think the vast majority of developers at least write unit tests and i'm on the record saying
That's a minimum job requirement
Which is great. They write nice little happy path test to make sure things work as expected
But then they throw stuff over the wall
So the the the shit they're throwing over the wall is just less smelly than it was 20 years ago in many cases
so what happens is
with
Poorly architected code we get these testers trying to test all these end-to-end scenarios almost black box like
I see questions all over the internet all over forums all over twitter on
What do I do to make selenium find this element? I it's really hard
I have to use an x-path and even though it's ugly sometimes it changes and my tests are really flaky
Yeah, absolutely true
The big answer to those is get your devs to add ids to your elements, which is great, but
They go how do I get my devs to do that?
If it doesn't help it's like a it just is a sad sad story to watch
so
Let's flip that around and watch what happens when a developer owns those tests because developers like
And maybe I think it's fair to say that most developers are lazy
The good ones are the best developers. I know are also lazy
And if they get to the point they have to write this this automated test in selenium and they go well, this sucks
I don't want to write this test. This is a stupid waste of my time
So then they go fix their code and they fix their architecture
So they can test for things that need to be tested at the lowest possible level
only in the environment where they don't have a tester because as you call out developers are lazy if they have a tester
And came with a with a five-word email
The second they own the automation they will fix their architecture to make the code more testable and
guaranteed
What they end up creating will look a lot more like the test pyramid because they're only going to write those big flaky ugly tests
For things that can absolutely only be tested there
and it doesn't mean there's not a role for people with
Critical thinking and actually that's a I don't like that because I think a lot of developers have those skills. They aren't like
Special things that only people who've been blessed with a special testers mindset can have
Nicole does go on to say it's the point I wanted to talk about in that same paragraph
She does say none of this means that we should be getting rid of testers
Testers serve an essential role in the software delivery cycle. I disagree with her slightly
I
in
There's a lot of caveats there. I think she's trying to I think she's weaseling out a little bit. Love you. Nicole. Sorry
I think she did wanted to avoid any backlash there, but you and I both know it can now
I think the point here she wants to avoid is the cult of oh, I've heard teams don't need testers
Let's get rid of them all it's ripping off the band-aid when it's a tourniquet
It's getting rid of the net without first lowering the rope
That's I think
There are caveats there, but uh, so I can see where she's coming from but yeah, you can absolutely make world-class high-quality software
Without any dedicated testers on the team
Conversely and as I tweeted
You can you and I won't pick will it some a self-proclaimed testing expert of their own choice pick
The top five testers in the world if you put them on a dysfunctional product team
There's no way they're ever going to ship anything that customers like
Well with the typical with the typical
Process to use that i'm used to
Right because when you have that then
The the dev team optimizes for hey, it's fun time. I get to write more code
and
When when we ship shit?
Uh, I get to be blameless
And that doesn't help the business. It doesn't help the customer
Right. Um, so we have data from nicole that says that developer owned automation is better for your product
Yeah, so given that
and
how much
There's this
I'll say it there is a industry
infatuation with end-to-end tests that's that's unhealthy
Agreed to me. The solution is obvious have the devs own it the right architecture will happen both in the testing test automation architecture
And in the dev architecture, it's it's it couldn't if it was painted in pink paint actually i'm red color blind
If it was painted in yellow paint
a thousand feet high
It couldn't be more clear to me
Why is it that?
industry wise we uh
We're not there. What am I seeing or what's wrong with my view because it's so obvious to me
How come as an industry we're still infatuated with having people who aren't the developers of the code
Try it and write end-to-end tests for it as the primary means of testing. Uh, please
Because
No
You know the answer to it. It's because it's seductive
Like you can get a really low trained
a low skilled person
Uh to try it out again
Why take the thing that look i've written shipping software in operating systems used by millions and millions of people and i'm telling you
Writing non flaky end-to-end automation is harder. I would rather go fix kernel bugs
I'd be more confident about changing the windows kernel or the xbox kernel same thing
Than I would about trying to write an end-to-end test. That was always going to be value and non flaky
Yeah, and we're going to put newbies on that here
Go for it. No, it it's again because well and you've seen it right? It's it's ui. It's newbies
Right. You just hook up
You just hook up to a recorder script and just click around and look you got a kick-ass
uh automation suite and actually I want to say because
Reproduces that continuously will reproduce the results until the next build. Here's the thing
I want to interrupt you because yeah, go ahead. I think these click and record things
I used to hate them and think they were stupid because I was thinking about them as a
Trying to create a test suite
But it gives me a way to do some exploratory automation
Like I just here I want to go do this set of actions a thousand times and I don't care if it fails
I'm just going to do the clicky clicky clicky record and then wrap it in a loop and go home for the night
That's valuable. It's not a test. I'm going to run on every build, but it gives me an opportunity to do what I call exploratory test automation
Let me link together some actions. Let me make a monkey test
The other thing right so because it's a monkey test
Right. That's what attracts the that's why it's attractive to assign these two sort of low-scale people
Right because because well, let's not let's hire a better monkey in some regards
Right, but the problem is these low-skilled people don't have the experience around what's going to take to maintain it
what it's going to take to actually get it to work and
I think in some regard like at the end of the day here is one place where I will say
I won't use our typical answer of it depends
Because here like I don't have an answer, but I know where the answer is
And the answer is going to be let's follow the incentive model
Let's let's go follow
How people are reviewed?
Let's go follow
That part of the process of developing a software and in there. I think we're going to discover
um
the cause
While you were talking I thought of something else because I thought about clicky clicky clicky monkey monkey monkey
and then
what I find in the reports from some of the folks who
Who love the craft and again?
I love I I don't mean to make fun of anybody just just just pointing out where I disagree and and not just that I disagree
But why?
uh
There was a time when we didn't know what customers did didn't know how they used our software
We tried to find what we thought were the bugs that they would find but we were just guessing
We heard things like no customer would ever do that. But then they did
and
I still think today with some of these folks. I have seen examples of them
I talked about infatuation with the end-to-end automation, but they're infatuated with the edge case bug
And the difference today is I think edge cases given millions and millions of requests for users
The edge cases are much more likely to happen
But the difference is today is we have the data to go see we see say I run this
Weird made-up test I make and it finds a crash
Yay, I found a crash go fix this bug and in the old days someone may say
No, this will never happen in the real world
But what we can do now is we can go to our data and see is it's actually the cool thing is maybe we found something that
A hundred two hundred a thousand users have seen never been able to never been able to reproduce
And now at least we have a path to reproduce it. So that's better. I'm off on a tangent
I just don't get it. I I
I'm not particularly smart. I'm not particularly dumb either
But to me, it's just so obvious that we shouldn't have people who aren't the developers of the code writing automation
I don't get it like I i'm again thinking back on the the cognitive bias discussion
right, I'm
I am
I'm trying to puzzle through
On this one. I have not
As you know, i'm a data scientist I have not seen I do not have access to nicole's data
But I have no reason to believe
That she and her team are anything other than highly competent in this craft
Yeah, I am I am competent. She's yeah, she's not only smarter than I am. She has done this stuff for you
She knows exactly what she's doing. In fact, the methods of their research are documented heavily in the second half of that book
Yes, and i've gone through that
Let's assert then that that fact is true
Right when devs own the automation
There is a correlation
Okay
Now she did not say causation. She said correlation
which then generally means
either a high quality product
is causing
devs to own it
Or that devs owning it is causing the high quality product and actually both could be true. Yeah, and i'd say
She focused on devops metrics and their correlation, which is good
But I would say on teams where developers own all of the automation. I'm guessing they probably have some other
Modern practices in place as well leading to that quality. I think my hunch is that practice
Is an indicator that they have a as we put in modern testing land a
Mature quality culture. Oh, I I completely agree, but let's talk about let's assume that they don't right? Let's say
You and I are going to start up a startup
Okay, and we're going to explicitly only hire
Like the old schooliest of the old school developers. Yeah, because they can't get jobs anywhere else. Sure
These these are ones that have been
For decades brainwashed that they are incapable of doing their own testing. Yep
And and they've been told that by their best friends the testers
And so when you're in my fictitious company, that's who we're gonna hire
We're gonna hire only those folks and we're gonna hire exactly zero testers
And we're gonna say you are accountable for for this automation
I do think we will eventually see
Uh, I can't predict the amount of time, but we will eventually see that quality dramatically improves
I believe so also and some of that via attrition when some of them just give up and quit
But but I get what you're talking about. They well, no, so I want to cover three cases here. Okay. Okay number one
Uh, they suddenly see the light and
And they build up a great test suite
two
Well, actually i'm just going to skip ahead to the thing I wanted to talk about so
Let's say these old schoolers, right? They they all gonna put in one or two unit tests
uh that are craptastic, okay, and
Uh
Then they have fulfilled the the our requirement on them. They own their automation suite
We we will put no requirements on the number of test cases. We will put no requirements on whether or not they pass or fail
We'll put no requirements
Uh other than they own it and it is run regularly, uh daily maybe I don't know
It's my metaphor i'm making things up
now
We though will make one strong stance
right
your
your review
will be heavily weighted
off of
uh the customer experience or
Customer retention actually, there we go. Your review is weighted off of customer retention
That's it
It's a microsoft review heavy for uh thing i'll i'll just say they get a bonus target based on customer retention
Um, which I think is separate from the review, but I I get I get where you're going. Sure. Sure. I mean we can modify it i'm just tying
Customer retention to their incentive model. All right
I predict that with that incentive model change
those oldest of the old school
people
Will either leave to a company with a incentive model that they understand
Or will suddenly become kick ass automation. Yeah writers
What all let me actually give you a different ground there because as you know from dan pink people are motivated by
Buy enough money where it's not an issue. So they might not be the thing
purpose mastery autonomy
Yes, and what i've seen actually supports that model because i've coached i've taught
old school never written a test developers to write tests and
They've been told so long that testing is this dark art and yes, i'm talking about real testing
I've seen developers find bugs that that my biggest biggest opponents would never find they're good, but
they
They can learn to test and once they get over that hump because they've been told for so long that they can't test they believe it
Great and once you get them over that hump and you stop
Lying to them
And show them what real testing is and how to do it and how to evaluate risk and how to not just test the happy path
And again, I got somebody replied and said you can have developers test but the only test the happy path
I said jesus help them. That's the whole point help them because they haven't done it before they're not stupid
It just drives me crazy back to the original topic. But anyway, what i've seen is
They actually don't need that money. They need expectations
They need autonomy and mastery and a little bit of coaching and purpose. They know it's important
What i've seen is they get motivated just by them figuring out. They know what to do as you were talking one last thing I wanted to say is
When I see folks harp on the test automation pyramid
They look at it as a model. They have to fit
And they don't like it because they well, it's contextual. It may be different from my product and of course
But really the way to think of the model is
If your software is well architected and well testable
It'll nat your test automation will naturally look like that
So that's my point
Hey, if you're a tester and you're writing a much automated test just stop it
If you have to do it to stay employed do that but
I believe higher quality software comes from developer-owned test automation
Well, it's and it's not a belief
Well the belief the belief is the cause you know
It's correlated and it goes right back to the point we made towards the beginning of the podcast
We're not trying to preach some new idea. I am telling you this is happening
People have been doing this and it's working arguing with me that i'm wrong
Doesn't make these facts go away
I'm just I'm just highlighting some things that are happening
the only
point of doing that argument
honestly is to
Is to make an emotional plea
Yeah
Right. That's all right. And again, I I get where they're coming from these opponents. So I I
Again largely largely positive response on
the the first article i'll write a follow-up soon and
See if I can anger a different crowd of people which again, I don't i'm not doing the stuff to be controversial
I want people to understand what's going on around them
That's my soapbox for the day. Anything else before we call it a call it an afternoon there brent?
Yeah, there was something else. I wanted to say but no, we're good. You can save it for
That's our next episode, right? Oh, yeah, i'm like, yeah
So the what that reminds me is I was watching a listening to a radio show. I for some reason I thought you added
three days to january
There's this new meme that I had to say I find appealing and and that is uh
to keep counting adding days to december such that
Uh, this is still considered part of 2020 because everyone wants 2020 to be over
Yep, i've seen that thank you everyone for listening for those who
Are you brent? I am I must be alan. We'll see you next time. Bye