Welcome to AB testing podcast your modern testing podcast
Your hosts Alan and Brent will be here to guide you through topics on testing
Leadership agile and anything else that comes to mind now on with the show
live
From our my house and Brent's office. It's the AB testing podcast. Hey Brent. Hey, yeah
The same place we've been for the last
14 months actually several of those you were in your house
I don't remember the last a B testing we did together, but maybe it'll happen again Sunday. I am
half
Vaccinated as am I I got my first shot. I got a Moderna shot on a Monday
I felt a little foggy a little tired on Tuesday
But other than that I was good except for feeling like someone hit me in the arm with a two by four. I
beat you by
one working day
Got my Pfizer shot
last Friday no
No symptoms except for again the two by four thing it basically
Massive soreness at the injection shot just like any other vaccine I've ever had
although a couple days ago, I started experiencing
Stiffness. Oh, I thought it's gonna be superpowers because I can fly now. Oh
Dude, not very far. I can fly about four feet
But you know, I'm not sure I'm not sure I could do that before I was expecting
Your your superpower to be to communicate with wildlife particularly grizzly bears
Oh, yes, you missed it in the pre show
Which you don't get to hear because it costs money. No nothing costs money here. But in the pre show Brent compared me to
Grizzly Adams which much of our demo some of our demographic may remember some may wonder what that is
But we'll let you Google that
Yes, and I will tell you
For those who aren't able to see the live stream. I will tell you. Oh
My god, is it similar?
the the the the
We a couple episodes ago. I don't know
Several episodes ago. We started talking about that the B in a B testing is about to refer to Alan's beard
And if you go to our slack group at one of the three dot slack comm there's a link to sign up on modern testing
org you can go to the Alan's beard channel there and
Occasionally get an update on the state of Alan's beard and I am I am
Claiming that is just just a short term amount of time before
Alan's beard asserts itself and makes that happen of its own
We are maybe a month or two away from the beard reaching a sentient
Proper. Yeah
You are one of the three if they get to it before you should post a picture of Grizzly Adams in the Alan's beard channel
just to see if like
separated at birth
I remember watch that show when I was kids so vaccines good
We've all heard that like basically 90 plus percent of the time that second shot is gonna kick your ass to some extent
Yeah, I've heard that that's especially true with Moderna
I will have my fingers crossed for you Alan and anyone else on Moderna
I have I have preemptively marked two days off after my shot just in case
And then there will be so my second shot is is
essentially
conflicts
With our podcast next time around so we'll we'll have to do some schedule
You can move it we can push that a week we can do other times
I'm usually free in the afternoons because I
work I
Most of my team is in another continent, which reminds me
I've been reading a book called the culture map just FYI for any of you that works with a global team
you know, I've been doing it for a long time but still some insights from that book and
understanding the difference across a whole bunch of attributes of
Different cultures and just maybe a quick little book report what it does is it takes these eight or so attributes of communication and
Then puts different countries on a scale
whereas
What seems really strict and rigid in one country may seem like chaos in another country
Just so it all depends on your point of view of how you how you communicate for example
You're probably aware of this but English being the
Hodgepodge cesspool of a language it is has like two or three times as many words as a lot of other languages and
What that means is we can be very in English. We are very explicit usually in our communication
Whereas in languages with fewer words
The subtleties are between the lines communication is much more prevalent and just being aware of that and how you communicate
With people from different cultures is very important. So very insightful wasn't even on my list of things to bring up
But that's what happens on the AB testing podcast
Yeah
In case there's a new listener
I'll let you answer that but no I won't
Alright, fair enough. I was gonna say you could answer that in a moment
But just for any potential new listeners and we had a listener by the way who started from episode one and listened all the way
Kudos to that guy. I think it was a guy now now I know I
Mean I I offer my deep
D
I'm impressed on the other hand. Yeah, some of those it took us a while to figure it out
But why is our podcast called a B testing?
Well because the officially I think the checking meme started after we did the the podcast
Should have been a B checking
Yeah, just think of it ABC. I mean the t-shirt writes itself a is for Alan B is for Brent
We don't know what testing is
checking is for
No
You know what?
Let's change it because a B checking is ABC
Dude, I literally like 30 seconds ago said that like no, but I I did that thing where I what's it called when?
See if you were a woman and I did that there's a term for that
It's called he peed in no mansplaining is when I explained something to you that you already know
Heeding is when I repeat it from you know being oh anyway
I'm just it's not that I'm I don't have respect for you. Well, that's actually it. Never mind
Yeah, ABC so and we're really not about testing which
The only thing I worry about and in fact if you're listening
I don't even know if getting more reviews or we have a lot of reviews and in the stores and we're very well rated
Here's what I worry about. You know, we do this not for the fame and fortune we do this actually
It's still to help testers and people from tests understand how to navigate the new world that is
Unveiling quicker than some people like in front of them
but I feel like there's a whole world of
People in software development and agile team struggling to figure things out and all over the place who would benefit
from our
podcast
but
Maybe don't listen to it because it has the word testing in the title
I'm not sure if that's true or not, but what do you think how do so my question is?
We have we have a solid pretty consistent thousand ish listeners per podcast
So thank you all of you
It's really only three of you at a time and thank you for logging in for different IP addresses and and fixing our stats
but I
Feel like we've finally gotten to a point as we begin our 139th episode
where
we can
Recognize that we provide value to a maybe a larger audience. So I'm gonna shut up and get your thoughts. Yeah
I'll tell you the the thought process for why it was a B testing. It was rather
Alan and I
Were thinking through names. I
Don't remember any of the other candidates we had
Right, but I was thinking through. Okay, what is our desired audience?
What is our expected audience? What is our desired audience and where Alan and are my interests am?
for me a B testing
Really resonated because number one, right it it
Covered are you and me and sort of the expected audience?
but number two
It covered kind of where I thought at that point in time we would go
Go really deeper in then we really really have
It opened the door to sort of bringing in data science topics
as well as
Just sort of a B testing by itself is a really great
modern testing
tool
So to me it was just sort of all the different check boxes got marked off with that
The only the only flaw we've seen so far is
In order for Alan to get rid of me. He has to find a good
Co-partnered with a letter B
But then the one of three even stepped up and you know
That people can change to name
right
they pseudonym is is
Is very cheap to advertise on right right burzy?
Okay
Okay, just curious on thoughts are that wasn't again also not on my intended topics one thing
I wanted to mention and I should have put this in my five for Friday. I was stupid. I
as mentioned before I have a new Mac M1 total subject change and
As maybe I mentioned at least in five for Friday. I have a brand new big-ass monitor
34-inch ultra wide
They're actually from this century my last monitors only had VGA and DVI inputs
So without an adapter, I couldn't connect my Mac and it wouldn't be great refresher resolution
So now that I have a proper monitor from the right decade
I can have both my Mac and my Linux machine plugged in and they both can run 4k on this monitor
Which is great, so I'm using my Mac more and I thought about getting a KVM
I had a separate keyboard for my Mac which I was using me adjust my little bouncy ball
I said on quite a bit, but then someone on slack again. I forget names, so I sorry
Recommended this product called synergy, which is a software solution
Do you write at Microsoft remember do you still have what was the thing called with all the tools toolbox or yeah?
Code is that called toolbox toolbox interestingly without any input at all for me or anyone from Microsoft at Unity
We now have a site called toolbox with similar things
But anyway, there was a thing on toolbox called magic mouse which lets you share a mouse between
Between systems which is really cool
But this is keyboard and mouse you can share between systems via a little teeny little TCP server
And it works really really well you can even cut and paste between
operating systems
The two machines you're using are your laptop in your home computer yeah
Yeah, as I mentioned last time I'm not spending a whole lot of time on my laptop
Yeah, my laptop kicks butt the new MacBook Pro M ones they completely rule
from my middle son for graduating high school as well as to sort of prep him for going to
your alma mater actually
We bought him a Dell
XPS 17 and it's so it's a
17-inch screen and I'm like why didn't I buy two of those that thing is sweet
It's so big it's so big okay, yeah, that was that list although honestly the answer to that is at this point in time
Like it I'm so trained. I'm like no I don't buy myself a laptop. That's works problem
Exactly exactly you know I feel like we could almost do tech recommendations
But I I feel like the kids out there know more about the new tech coming out sometimes
So I rely on my Twitter followers to make it like I had them give me monitor recommendations
I had to help me figure out if I should get the the 15-inch
Intel MacBook Pro or go with 13 inch M1 and I'm super happy with the M1 things like that
Anything else going on we should cover we have a mailbag and something else. I forget. Oh yeah anything else
I had two topics. You know what they are anything else you want to cover before we dive into those
15 minutes into the podcast
No, I'm good. I think it's important that our listeners get to know us and what's going on in our world
Before we start talking about stuff that they probably don't care about as much which but which is occasionally informative
Wow
so those
Like I'm staring at Alan and he suddenly shifted to like full-blown empathy mode in his body language, so
So I'm not accustomed to it normally I the the face I look into is filled with anger around
They don't call me angry weasel for nothing so okay. Where's this going?
It's a trap. I've seen see the trap coming always a trap always yeah, okay?
Hey, I wanted to follow up so a couple episodes ago. We talked about personality types
and by the way
Ray Dalio the author of principles one of my favorite books his company, and I forget the link
But I just they have yet another
Personality test which I did
It's fine
But I'm discovering of all of them as I dig into it and pay attention to this stuff
And not all personality, but these little tests the working genius is
is
Giving me more and more value
I'll tell you why in a minute
But can you remind me of what your top two and bottom two are if you have those rent?
That would be the two working genius and the two working frustration that is correct
Thank you for digging out the right nomenclature for me
Yeah, okay
my two
working genius our
invention and discernment oh
Yes, I could see that and frustrations
Enablement and tenacity
Okay, so that's good to know so let me as I dug into this more and thought about how this works
And I had some licenses that I had some of my team go through it's been a little
Enlightening if you think about how these work so the geniuses are they spell widget wonder and invention
discernment and galvanizing and
enablement and tenacity
the cool way with the way these work which I didn't mention last time because I didn't actually realize it is
When you think about how we make things
Whether it's software
Processes or whatever you start with wonder and invention
You ponder things you figure out. I wonder if we could do it this way
I wonder the way you come up with a good idea is come up with a lot of ideas or the bad ones out
Wonder is are great at that
They just throw stuff out there with the full idea that we're gonna get some stuff torn apart and then invention is what are these new?
ideas, but we don't go straight from there to
actually implementation
there's
That there's these middle steps of discernment of breaking down the idea making sure we're solving the right problem for the right people
You are a discerner
you enjoy
Figuring out if what people think they want to do is the right thing and and making sure it's solving the right problem for the customer
This this brings you joy. It does
Very common phrase
That I now use because as you know, I talked to lots of executives here at the company
I will go to them and say I hear what you want, but it's my job to bring you what you need
Yeah, I say that all the time too because I am also a discerner and sometimes they're the same thing sometimes
So in the middle there is discernment and galvanizing and I sit right in the middle
I just I'm able to break stuff apart like you do and I like to get people what they need versus what they want and
It brings all that I can't do all of it
Anyone can do all of this stuff
But if you do the stuff that are in your frustrations, what I'll get to in a minute
Eventually those kind of wear you out if that's all you do. So I live in the middle
I rely on other people to
In wonder and invent not that I can't wonder an event not that I don't but the things that give me the most joy are
Making sure we're solving the right problem and then getting everybody rallied around solving the problem making making the team
Understand what's important about what they do. I like when you go to Dan Pink's autonomy mastery and purpose
I love bringing purpose to the work. It gives me joy
If I feel like I can connect people with the work they're doing in the project we need to get done
That's that's the kind of stuff. I like doing are you saying that your?
To you didn't remind us of your I did I snuck it in there. It's it's the middle to discernment and galvanizing
So discernment we just go galvanizing is getting everyone together on solving the right problem and your bottom
my bottom two I believe are
not one oh, it's a
invention and
tenacity and
What it means is I can get people rallied around the project and again
I've had tenacity before I can just I'm just gonna go crank this workout. So enablement is
Giving you the support you need while you're doing the work and it could just you know
I can do that and I've done that a lot. It doesn't bring me as much. It doesn't bring me joy
if all I had to do is
Get in the trenches and do the work and it could be just how I've changed over time
But doing that enabling sorry not enablement in task of the enablement in my yeah enablement Sarah tenacity is in my middle
So it's enablement and I was looking at yours
enablement and invention I don't
I
Don't invent things often, but I love to jump in as things are invented and do the discernment
so with you with
Enablement and tenacity at the bottom
Those are the both the things at the end of the building stuff
So you start with one dimension you go to discernment and galvanizing and then there's enablement and tenacity
So it sounds like you know, I know I've seen you do those things but what this says is that
Those things don't bring you joy
Gettin yeah, it's it's
The thing with working genius here right they're talking about so you use the term joy
for other folks
Sort of derive energy from
Would be another way of expressing it. It's not a negative thing. It's not that I suck at enablement or tenacity
right
absolutely, right it's
Which doesn't mean I don't suck at those two as well, right?
It's not making a comment on those on those statements is basically saying it's it's far more likely to be a
energy drainer than a
energy
Refiller correct and the so the addendum I want to add it on today add on today
And if this is all new to you, please go back and listen to a couple episodes ago
We talked about this but what I didn't get before I thought was worth bringing up
Is that the way these fit together around getting a project from inception to customers?
Is this working genius? So you start with one dimension you go to discernment and galvanizing
Is that these are leadership attributes of course and then enablement and tenacity is just getting that work done
So I wanted to bring that up because one I learned that and thought it would add a nice cap on to our previous discussion
but two
It leads directly into a question from our mailbag
Insert grab insert sound here if I can find it crap. I have a new computer
I may have lost it just a second just in case I have to do this again
All right, so the question from Sean
It's been a while it's been a while welcome back welcome back
Sean says topic I think might be interesting and Sean we think it's interesting too
So you're you're right is walking through the life of a feature from inception to production whether in a fictional or real process to illustrate
how
collaboration works how you see roles on a team and what a team without
Dedicated testers look like a lot of details here Alan mentioned in last episode that development is collaborative
Of course and on a team without dedicated testers other developers may test the code sure everyone everyone tests
It doesn't need to be the person to develop doing it all the testing. I agree. I agree
I remember Brent saying previously that he asks about test process and data proving a feature works
Yes, that's part of it that whole everything is a hypothesis. Everything is an experiment approach
Yes, and then I'm sorry
I'm adding too much stuff here all makes me curious how you might see a feature from beginning to end who might work on it
Handoffs or whoever might be described from story writing to design to engineering release and monitoring
I know every situation could be different, but what is an example of a process?
Do you think works well maybe with comments and other ways I could work well
Or what wouldn't work well any sort of handoffs never work well tell you that right now
But let's talk through this we have I think we can make it we have like a half hour
I think handoffs don't work. Well, I think handoffs are often often cause bottlenecks
Yeah, it's it's interesting and I'm wondering if what I my team does
right because
We do a lot of I don't even know what the term is
So intermittent pair programming
Where it's essentially there will be?
Folks working together then they'll separate then they'll come back and they'll separate right? It's essentially it's spontaneous
V team of two I maybe that's another way of calling it. Oh cool
Handoffs don't generally work. Well
When it's a situation where you're also
You're also hand in handing off out of the blue an unknown context
Right. It's essentially
Alright Alan. I have this spreadsheet that I just finished doing I need you to
Successfully cluster the data together, you know, I'm making crap up because I'm looking at my other screen with this spreadsheet loaded
Okay, I could see that I was thinking more of what I thought hand I thought
Throwing stuff over the wall kind of handoffs versus that's a collaborative handoff really right. So let's
Okay, so
It's the nuance of the handoff non collaboration
Is a bottleneck that all agree with?
Okay, so let's start and I can pick it probably both have several stories here
But let's kind of walk through a fictitious example. So
But oh boy my first my first inclination before we wreck it is
a suggestion to Sean to go read the lean startup because it probably I imagine where we'll be stealing liberally from
Rees as we talked through this scenario. Yeah, there's there's actually
another book I read
And I forget the name of it. Oh, yeah. Yeah, that one's really good. I read that a couple times
Actually, you might have it's very old
But it had to do with what do you say a man you saying I'm old
Well, yeah, you are. Okay. I mean
Yeah, you you know that
But I'm still kind of
I'm still kind of dealing with the segue from the last topic because I as you rightly call it out
It's not much of a segue. It's more of a tightening of the focus
I'll bring up that that I'll use that as a teaser and if I can tell that story later
In context, I will you'll completely forget the story in the next two minutes. It's alright
All right. So let's start from idea
Let's say I have an idea for a new product or I wonder or something or a new feature
So, oh, let me start here. There's a better way to frame that
How do you figure out what the next feature is you're going to deliver?
Well, you start with
start with a
Need gaps in some fashion. No, no, no you start with
Things you think that would be cool to do I'm kidding. I'm kidding. Do you?
Well, we both know sadly some people do that's
some people do and that's wrong it's
Ideally you understand or have a way to understand what the biggest problems are your customers or potential customers are facing
Yeah, or like you said you just you just fully own the fact that you are the second coming of Steve Jobs
And then you do whatever the hell you feel like did I tell you about the time at Microsoft when one of?
Someone who is no longer there was a partner test manager who is known as a buffoon
He reminds me of Mike Pence actually, but he compared himself to Steve Jobs and meeting I was in
Like literally said well, I Steve Jobs has ideas and I have ideas are the same
So what so in reality? I like to start with what's the customer problem?
We're trying to solve and hopefully it's a big one or one of the biggest ones
I like to start with the problem versus the feature idea and then I refer to
Weinberg which is until you can think of at least three different solutions to your problem. You don't understand your problem well enough yet
that I agree with the
And
In even further I'll tell you the three I'll tell you what the three different solutions should be
the one that is
the low cost
high risk
the one that should be low risk high cost and
The one that is right in between I get that I get that
Do you actually I mean you're laughing but do you get the?
The wisdom behind no I do it's it's it's a flavor of the
Quadrant used often effort versus impact
Yeah, I use that frequently, okay
But it but they may not all be that way they all they all may have different trade-offs that may not be that may be
More subtle than the impact versus effort
But the important thing is is you don't as you know, just don't fall in love with your first solution
So who's involved in figuring that stuff out who's involved in effort and impact and problem solving in the generic sensor in a
Modern in a modern sense in a modern sense in a world where we live. So it's it's I
was gonna say the whole team, but that's that doesn't even cover it because
The the problem statement could come from user research as part of UX. It could come from marketing
It could be product management
Could come directly from customers through a series of forum posts or scathing articles. There are lots of ways for you to
understand that problem, but you you won't understand the
effort impact
Quadrant until you get your development team involved understand because a lot of times you really can't understand
Which solution is most feasible and viable until you can get people brainstorming about the different solutions
Well, yeah, but I think you're you're not at
That phase yet. It's right. The very first thing is is how do you know?
when
To even bring it that idea to that forum. I
Guess I'll be the first to bring up the the Eric Ries story, right? It's essentially
In lean startup. One of the things that he talks about is how they very deeply
Began to invest in
What Eric Ries now will proclaim it was a just a fundamentally stupid idea
right, um
But it's very easy to get spun up and believing that you have found a an important gap and
Work through that right if we do if we use your
system the widget ordering like
Wondering is hey, where is their great potential? So they got to that phase they basically said hey
We think it's gonna be absolutely
Fantastic to do blah blah blah blah blah blah and there's a lot of people who are doing that and and you know
you just have to watch, you know three episodes of shark tank to get a good sense of the diversity of
of
How people will come up with with new potential
and and even
Stand behind it
now the question is in my mind in in them and that's always happened in in throughout history like you and I have talked through
Like how many times in the old-school Microsoft did we go and see a requirements document?
that
You know was was either
unfounded by any sort of customer statement
Or or very loosely founded. Oh
Darn often. Oh my god. It just drove me crazy. Even when I didn't know what was better. I knew it was wrong
right
Right. Yeah, and back then one of the challenges were
Was we really didn't have the ability to
To do anything differently
right, so this this this person did two-hour call with a customer and
That entire deck came from that call right from one
Customer right, but we didn't have the ability to scale customer feedback back in those days, right? Right. Okay, because we didn't ship anything
told
True again, so okay, so we're vetting
We're figuring we're doing a bunch of work up front to make sure we're building the right thing
Let me fast forward a little bit and say we feel like we have what's called product market fit
Okay, what happens next and who's involved?
So are we to the are we now to the let's figure out exactly what we're gonna build to solve this problem?
So if we found product market fit is it let's say we've selected the best what we think is the best solution
Actually, we see we see even experiment solutions
Yeah, have we already discerned solutions because I think the first thing like wonder is the exploration of opportunity
That's how I view it. Yeah. Yeah, so you're right. We need to discern the solutions
It can't like I said, it's more it's usually more subtle than just effort and impact if there's like a
There's a low effort high impact. It's just we could probably just go forward and try it, but it doesn't always work that way
I just realized my dog is laying on my foot didn't know she was there great back on back. Look a squirrel
Okay, so I like the idea of discerning solutions again
A lot of companies fall in love with their first solution a lot of feature teams
We're as discerners especially and as disciples of the lean startup we say BS to that
So we want to discern the solution. Let's talk about how that happens. Who's involved in that?
Discern we got we skipped over invention. I think invention. I mean
No, no, so the very first thing so wonder so this is actually really cool
I did not play I knew there was a segue
But you are actually tying this phase of working genius directly in here, which I kind of love some let you keep going
And I'll remind you
My working genius is invention and discernment. Okay, so I in some regards. Yeah
Because I don't really care about about about that first part I want to get to discernment and galvanize
But anyway, go on so wonder I go back wonder is is around
The the gift of seeing an opportunity and a need
And it's a gift. I I wish I could load an example
But have you ever sat down and briefly thought hey, you know this particular something or other
Sucks, how come they don't make it this way?
In I wish I could come up with a really good example here. It's something actually my wife does quite often
She she will go why why doesn't yeah, anyway
I can't even let any of her examples at the moment the closest example I can think of is back in the day
Do you remember magic cards with did you ever get sucked into magic cards like magic the gathering? Yeah. No, I never played. Oh
so
Literally 90% of my spare income in college went to magic cards. Okay, and
What I would do is I turned it into business. I actually created this whole
Offline auction system where people would send in bids and I did it on
Got news groups like this was before the internet and I had generalized it
But you know what? I I was thinking of I
had a need
Okay, I had a need I had a full end-to-end bidding system and in different types of bids
But I don't have that gift of wonder so it never it never
immediately
inherently
Registered that hey if I generalize like the the money I'm selling off of these magic cards is
Less valuable than if I found a way to generalize this whole auction site
Yep, right and that was the thing that
Amongst other things the the other thing is it's not on here. I have the vice of being completely lazy
But that was one key thing which is why you're not currently talking to the CEO of eBay because I
Didn't think broader around that potential
Okay, so it never occurred to me that there was a global need on that one
Once you I've identified a potential need then then how do you generate ideas?
How do you generate solutions to that question is you bring in domain experts and you have a
Brainstorming session you do not and ideally the customer is part of your domain experts yet that yes
right now
In in in in some models they call this feasibility analysis opportunity analysis
That's where you going through and you say, okay
How do you take this thing and understand the pros and cons?
What would be the constraints out of the solution?
There's many a times where I'll come to you Alan on certain things
You can you go I don't know the solution and then with a few precision questions
I can really understand that well at least you know the constraints on on that solution
So if there is a solution, it's now not this big grab bag of thing
It's got to be in a much much smaller space
Right. For example, you may say hey, I need a solution for something
But I need it in the next two weeks. So anything that's gonna take longer than that is not going to be a solution
Now now with that constraint you can bring in people and say okay, what can we do?
within this time period on discernment
intuitively and instinctively
Evaluating ideas and situations that is one of mine
And I don't know that if I say so there certainly I don't I do it intuitively. I'm gonna in
I'm I'm an end
But instinctive I don't so this one
I
I'll say for me. I am very able to sort of very quickly
I think of it in terms of the strength finder. I'm an ideater
Okay, I see how I see all the dots and I see how they're all connected
Let's tie all this to how a team does their stuff
So you need to you need to vet the ideas discern the ideas and figure out
I'm gonna fast forward a little bit because we do need to take time to figure out which is the best solution I can
Bend on time it can depend on customers and market and other pressures
Lots of things can influence
Which decision you choose?
in in terms of
Modern testing and in tying it to that the process of discernment I'll be super tactical on this
You get the right group of people together you identify what are the three MVP things?
You then prune those down because no one really fully understands what an MVP is
They always turn it into a friggin beta. Yeah, absolutely. That's true and they go
Well, all we want to do is what is the cheapest thing that we can do to sort of test these things out?
Yes, and that's that's a 100%
Yes
That's what you have to vet it down to is what is the least amount of effort we can do in order to get
Feedback that will tell us whether or not we're going in the right direction
Right and yeah, I totally echo your people
Bastardized the MVP term into something much much bigger and it drives me freaking nuts
They just don't get it and makes me angry when it really shouldn't so no it's because they overload
What the point is?
Right it it's not an MVP's goal is not
To generate customer happiness
No, no, it's it's getting to generate
Learning right generate learning. So now
We figure those things out
Let me know if I fast forward too much
But yes, absolutely part of discernment should be breaking it down and then part of that if we go through the working genius stuff is
Getting the team aligned and I'm gonna repeat something
I've unfortunately had to say in several different conversations this week is that alignment is not consensus and
Get the team aligned on
What what they're doing what they're trying to learn they get it
Intel you this goes with the rallying cry and tell the team under team 100% asked to fully understand the problem of solving and
Be aligned on the solutions are putting in place and what the plan is in order to do that. So that is
Everyone on the team if you have a dedicated tester testers are generally people with that testing background
I'm not gonna say mindset, but that testing background are very good at discernment generally
They're good at asking those questions and figuring things out. Maybe not as good as getting everyone aligned, which is galvanizing
Probably why maybe it's cuz I'm a galvanizer that I work on alignment so much now. I have to go ponder that later
Okay, so anything else to talk about there before we get into
Really the nitty-gritty in the last 10 minutes here, which is all of the implementation of this stuff and who's involved
How do handoffs work those sorts of things?
Well, so I kind of go old-school
Agile on this is that you
You sort of create an assembly line of the work and
Part of part of that work advancing forward or are essentially spot quality checks
If you think about acceptance reviews
Generally in scrum you have an acceptance criteria
either generated or
negotiated with the product owner
When the scenario is complete there should be some form of an acceptance review, which is
Essentially, okay. I now have implemented what I thought we had agreed to let me validate that
It was what we agreed to yeah, I would go back one step. I think yes, you do those things
But it's important also
This is where if you have a dedicated tester they'll help but if not it has to happen
Anyway, is you need to think about all of that validation and testing as part of planning
We make our teams think about a test plan and you can make them think about testing
How are you gonna know this is gonna work in production up front? This actually goes going back to Reese. It's
What asking that question? How will we know this is successful in production?
Right, it's essentially it's essentially asking
Before we begin
How do we know if it's if it's working or failing? Yeah, and what and ties into I mean, there's this really old-school thing
failure modes
FMEA but the idea was to think about all the ways your application could fail before you shipped that that FMEA is
Super old-school and super heavyweight, but there's a flavor of that you need to do in addition to
Success metrics is how are we gonna know like just thinking about say I'm shipping a new
Website that's a good generic thing before I go live
I want to get an idea of how I'm gonna scale for load just in case people actually go there
Things like that just being able to think about those things upfront as part of planning
That's a new thing for a lot of developers who haven't
Been in a team where they didn't have dedicated testers before
So that's where if you have one you can help out but over time and I've seen this in many many many teams
It's not too hard to get a development team to think about those things, but you can't forget about it either
Yeah, the other thing with handoffs like in terms of handoffs that the I mean it's essentially
It kind of goes back to the sort of the stakeholder thing. Are you handing off because?
Hey in terms of what needs the additional polish that needs to be added is best suited by a
different set of experts or
Is it is the handoff really lightweight and it's more of an inform or an improve much like the story?
mentioned around product owners the I'm thinking through I'm reading through Sean's question again and
We've kind of touched on answering so sorry Sean, but you know, this is what we do here
Well, we got five minutes left. So I'm wondering maybe we can go succinctly through like the thing that I this all makes me curious
How you might see a feature from beginning to end who might work on it
Maybe handoffs or however it may describe from story writing to design to engineering to release some monitoring
Okay, we've talked we've talked maybe a little about some of this but not maybe not the best
Yeah, we kind of did a piecemeal
We did we covered some good stuff the a B testing podcast
Come to us for a tangential talk. We got that one nailed
from story writing right in
Initially that once that to me is it's very customer-focused. It's
And this is one of my challenges that I constantly see is it's no it's not about the work
The story needs to be about the outcome
How do we know we got there and who cares what's the context so completely agree with story writing then from the story
It says as Alan and I just just sort of I'll say detailed with double quotes
Okay. How do we decompose that? How do we generate? What are the alternatives? What and
with a heavy focus on on
lightweight in my humble opinion because the one thing that's
The one thing that's missing from Sean's
Discussion because he talks about story writing to design to engineering to release some monitoring in my humble opinion
There is a bunch of sort of the the loops through the system. I
Mission accelerate the achievement of shipable quality
Shipable quality may not be achieved in the first time the code goes to prod right? It could just be a a
an MVP that's missing a lot of things a lot of
Solidification because you're really just trying to determine is this idea something anyone freaking cares about?
But then you'll you'll go back to the drawing board add add additional hardening or or pivot entirely
to sort of
Submit the direction that the the idea came from
Obviously monitoring needs to be in place
That I think is another tool for answering the questions that that we just talked about is this is this anything cares about?
Hey, we we operate under certain assumptions that
So, for example, maybe we didn't test if it can scale beyond a thousand concurrent callers and
We're suddenly way more popular than we expected
Right. Obviously, I would want monitoring in place and I would have a discussion around
Hey, if for some as an example if for some reason
This exceeds what we tested for
I want to monitor in the system that comes and tells me that I need to be observing this near real time because we
May have made a decision to ship it too soon
Right if if we tested it for for a thousand and it's a million callers
Right. We may want to roll back
True true
One last thing to touch on I think and maybe we have to take some questions on this and answer more detailed questions
These open-ended questions aren't are not good for a be testing, but we do get some we do generate more questions from those which is good
I've been thinking like ever since I first brought up I but I questioned handoffs
I think it's worth just doing a quick recap on those because we do believe in teams of
specializing generalists or generalizing specialists and
Often whether it's a testing special or some testing background or performance or database or any other specialty
Which may live in just a few people on the team
Avoid the throw of the wall handoff. I think what we try and do on our team. We do a lot of pairing
when we have expertise
Because we want a collaborative handoff and I don't even think of it as a handoff when we need a bunch of
We need to make sure that networking is set up correctly for a new GCP cluster
Jesus Christ
Welcome to crazy world
Collaborating with a network engineer on the team who has some expertise there
It's a quick and easy way to do that versus and generate some learning on both sides versus just
Giving it to a network engineer and saying hey
I need this do this for me because I don't like handoffs like that they when I think a handoff should be a
collaboration between the hander and the handy
There may be places so there was guidance that I learned and I'm trying to figure out
I'm looking at my bookshelf. I don't see anything there. But one of them
One of the places that I learned around there is a role for specialists, right?
as the name might
State it needs to be something special
like security
Deep security is a specialization and if you're in a business where you need that
Right, but the one thing to be cautious about is by its nature
Handoff to a specialist is a bottleneck, right?
That's that was my the moment of my cringe earlier fully agree. We're on the same page, which is weird
But you know sometimes unavoidable, but it might be necessary and the way you account for that is
Is essentially you look at?
You you then have to figure out how to optimize
that particular bottleneck
And in terms of your end-to-end plan, you're gonna have to think through okay. How quickly is that bottleneck?
Getting through it sort of independent queue
All right. What does that mean for our timing? How do we how do we change our scope?
How do we go with a different solution in order for me to make sure that the end-to-end thing?
Reaches market while there's still a viable window off of opportunity
Anyway, yep, so anyway lean startup regurgitated. We'll call it that fan test ago
With some nuance in there. All right, we should we should call it a day it is or call it a Friday
Or wait call it another lonely day. You can go your own way, Brett
All right fantastic
Again showing my age
Yeah, all right. Well, I'm Alan's beard and
I am Alan's
beard's
predecessor
The wit on you is amazing. All right. We'll see you next time
Bye