Welcome to AB Testing Podcast, your modern testing podcast.
Your hosts, Alan and Brent, will be here to guide you through topics on testing, leadership,
agile, and anything else that comes to mind.
Now, on with the show.
Hey everybody.
Howdy.
It's Alan.
Hi Alan.
And we're here for episode 148 of the PBS Sponsor AB Testing Podcast.
I'd like you to all just get out your donor cards.
Now, this is the AB Testing Podcast and you never know what kind of intro you're going to
get.
And I guess most of you listen past the first, most of you fast forward past this part anyway.
So whatever, whatever.
Episode 148.
Yay.
To be clear, because I don't want lawyers contacting us later.
We are not actually sponsored by PBS.
We are not.
We are sponsored by no one.
Occasionally, occasionally we will do a sponsorship, but somebody would believe in.
Although I guess we could have just hidden behind.
No, no, no, not that PBS.
The other PBS.
Oh.
Yeah.
I'm so confused.
So PBS is just an acronym, right?
And we could have just made it up.
Anyway, nevermind.
Let's move forward.
Hey, what's on the agenda, Alan?
Hey, I don't know.
Let's figure it out as we go.
We're going to do a very agile and virgin adaptive agenda that I just paid up.
Yay.
Let's do this.
So what, let's start with what's new with you.
Wouldn't it be cool if I had a theme song for like, like a segment, but this is the what's
new with you segment.
Yeah.
We used to, when did we give it up?
Oh, right.
COVID probably.
Right.
Cause remember we used to have sort of a made up segment on where in the world is
Oh yeah.
Cause I don't go anywhere anymore.
I don't, well, actually, yeah, I don't do conferences, but I have the most massively globally distributed
team right now.
We just, I can talk about it now because we're going to make the announcement by the
time this goes out, but we are moving another large part of unity into my org, my org.
Let me see if I can remember here.
Cause we have some one-offs.
So right now my org is Sia Bellevue, of course, San Francisco, Austin, Texas, Montreal, Boston.
I also have some remote folks in Vermont and Colorado and Denver and Pittsburgh in the
US.
I think that covers the US.
Once we get to Europe, I have Brighton, England and a home of the ministry test.
Hey everybody.
And also in Edinburgh, Scotland.
I need to make a map on my wall.
So I remember, let me go elsewhere in Europe.
Of course Helsinki, Copenhagen, as I mentioned, anybody else, I have a one-off person in Belgium.
I feel like I, oh, Lithuania, Vin Vildnius.
All places I haven't been in a very long time.
And a few places like Lithuania have never been to.
I think maybe that's it for my team.
I think maybe that's it.
But there may be a few other places.
Anyway, that's it.
Your team, I believe, well, no, I know this to be true, is larger than mine and I believe
significantly so.
Yeah.
With this new reorg, it's about 200.
So you're only one order of magnitude larger than me.
But I have, my team of 10 is now in four distinct locations.
So one bit of growing pain worth mentioning as part of that is just to a thing, because
a lot of this growth has happened in the last six months.
And for the first time in my, since I've realized how important one-on-ones are, I
am now unable to do, you know, up until six months ago, I had regular one-on-ones with
every single person in my org.
I cannot do that with 200 people, not even close.
My schedule will be busy enough just meeting with the leads, the people managers across
the yard, which I find, which I will do that.
Those are important.
But yeah, it's a lot of peeps, a lot of things for me to learn and do.
Not, I mean, you won't be able to do it at all.
No, all.
Because your org is pretty flat.
I can't meet with everyone.
I can't do skip level one-on-ones with everyone on a regular basis, but I will spot check in
and there's some people I'll meet with.
I'll figure it out.
Wow.
Yeah, that's, that's to me, that's meaningful.
I don't know if it's good or bad.
I mean, it is what it is, right?
It is.
And I can do some things like some, we have a pretty, we do some things to promote transparency.
We have every other week, we have a team, all hands.
I just call it my team biweekly.
It's all about just transparency.
How decisions are being made.
Just let them know what's going on.
But I could also do some smaller group sort of roundtables just to have a chance to chat
with people, listen to them, see what's on their mind, take questions.
There's some things I'll do.
I do find a lot of value in having a personal connection with everyone in the org.
It's just going to take a while with this rapid growth.
Anyway, that's where, that's the org stuff.
There's some other stuff that's really cool to share that I can't quite share on the podcast
yet, but wait till next week.
That's the way we get listeners to come back.
I will have a really cool announcement next week about modern testing.
Yeah.
The cliffhanger is supposed to happen at the end of the show.
Good.
Now you told them, yeah.
We don't have a plan already mentioned it.
Oh, you know what?
In the, we're in the world thing.
I did agree to do a webinar coming up in January.
So I have time to prepare for it with our buddies over at practice test.
Oh, so I'm going to do that.
I don't know what on yet, but I'm going to figure it out and we're going to figure it
out.
Like we always do on this show, but not today.
I do.
I think that's it.
Any other cool stuff?
It's getting cold out.
All that stuff.
I want to talk about Twitter.
No, what I want to talk about.
I want to get the Twitter first.
For those of you that are still addicted to Facebook, it was probably nice having it gone
for a day last week.
That was cool.
And then not cool having it come back.
Somebody wrote up, I read an article.
It's in my five for Friday.
Someone wrote a plugin, a Chrome plugin that deleted that unfollowed everyone by default.
And I don't, I deleted my Facebook account quite a while back.
Their newsfeed by people just scrolling through that doom, scrolling through Facebook and
micropayments makes billions of dollars, but it's all filled with crap.
So he wrote a plugin that unfollowed everyone.
So your newsfeed was blank.
You could still find your, you could still go to your friend's page and see what they
posted.
You just wouldn't go up in your newsfeeds.
He just didn't have a newsfeed and Facebook not only made him delete the plugin with a
cease and desist.
They banned him from Facebook and Instagram for life, which seems like an asshole move.
Does this plugin still work?
Like can I go?
Yeah, his plugin is gone, but it still works.
The zip files are available.
If you know how to look for archives of things.
Gotcha.
So you can, you can still install it.
Just have to do it manually.
You can't do it from the Chrome store.
And you know, some people go, oh, I need my, I need to see my, my memes telling me why
I don't need the vaccine.
Well, for you folks, just, I don't want to go there.
So anyway, that happened.
And then the Twitch Twitch, uh, we're actually having an account, but I, I think I created
it when I was drunk.
So it was a username and never used anywhere with a password.
I didn't even know.
Thank God for password managers, but did you hear what happened to Twitch?
No, I did not.
Oh my God.
Everything got dumped.
Source code, payouts, everything as was hackers got the entire like, oh, drag, they drag and
drop everything.
All of Twitch's internal shit onto the internet, all kinds of badness.
I assume at least the passwords were hash, but yeah, bad, bad day to be a Twitch employee.
And I was going somewhere with that, but I don't remember when, but I do want to talk
about Twitter now.
So I said Twitter.
I thought of Twitch, then it went back to Facebook, all kinds of stuff.
There's this agile consultant.
I follow on Twitter.
His name is Alan Holub.
And he is a no nonsense sort of guy.
And I, a lot of this stuff is very modern testing.
I don't think he, some people even bring out modern testing and replies to his tweets.
I don't think he really knows what it is.
And that's okay.
Because again, we're not trying to sell or make a new thing that people can think about.
We're just trying to find a way to describe some things that are already happening.
So he had one today.
No, no, two days ago, the notion of testers not being devs is odd to me.
Testing must be automated.
Can you see the triggers for people?
Isn't writing an automated test coding?
Somebody who can't code can't create tests at all.
If they can code up a test, they can code up anything.
There are no testers, just devs who understand testing.
Okay.
That's that stirs it up better than we do.
Right?
Yeah.
I mean, well, so we want to inspire a conversation.
Like there's, there's nothing to what he said to me.
I'll put it this way.
No, uh, cause we're recording.
So I can't put it that way.
There is a element that we constantly look in terms of traditional testing that is
still holding on with white knuckles.
A little bit, a little bit.
Yeah.
I mean, there is a lot bit.
There is a, I'll say a hype, a hyperbole, written, highly vocal element of
leadership in the traditional mentality.
Alan kinda in terms of what you just read, it kind of reads like that same sort of
assertiveness on an in a modern testing site as well.
Yeah.
And I want to read a couple of their replies because they reek of these are
what I like about it is it reeks of modern testing without these people
knowing what modern testing is and more and more again, back at test bash me
first finished the principles.
I talked about them.
I was worried.
People said, Oh my God, you have a name for what we're already doing.
I had a feeling we just didn't know.
But more and more it's happening.
And unfortunately people needed to hear that to listen to our podcast.
But one of the first replies on that was someone saying, I literally had this
conversation yesterday asking to replace the expected test timer in our headcount
estimate in a for a project team with a dev with automated test experience, which
is what I would rather hire anyway.
Anyway, a bunch of, a bunch of nuggets since I found the thread like he's, I
don't read my people probably know that or I've noticed I'm not on Twitter as
much these days, but someone tagged me into one of into this thread somewhere,
some other thread and bringing up modern testing and it's worth checking out.
And of course, as you imagine, someone jumped in and talked about checks
and his answer, I was about to ask.
And his answers, as you'd expect from anyone experienced in the industry who
didn't go, isn't part of that doctor nation.
He said WTF for those that doesn't make any sense.
Yeah.
What?
You're enough on that subject.
I get why are the distinctions there?
I think people are using it as a weird weapon to gatekeeping.
That's stupid.
I like seeing modern testing in the wild.
I didn't find his exact thread.
I found the comment that your talks talk about, but yeah, there's a lot of,
I'll just say it the last, for lack of a better word, just glancing through his
Twitter feed, there's a lot of, um, me too isms that are, that are rising for me.
Overreliance on manual testing is the symptom of culture smell.
I totally agree with that.
I totally do too.
I am part of a org where despite having dedicated Estettes, the entire org,
uh, which you remember when we thought that was a good idea.
At the time, I guess in the context of our ship cycle and the way we made software,
it was, cause we had the test quality in, but to see it today, it just doesn't make
any sense to me.
It doesn't to me.
Orgs, this person who wrote this tweet today say that a term I haven't thought
of in years, like their whole org of 190 people, including a dedicated team of
Estettes will do a test bash.
And I'm like, wow, it doesn't mention what industry they're in.
There are certainly places where, uh, oh, it's funny.
So one person came back.
He's like, thanks dude.
It replied to that tweet.
Thanks.
I'm now having PTSD flashbacks.
Like, yeah, that that's an alignment to what I'm, to what I'm thinking of.
Yeah.
This guy, this guy seems in alignment.
They completely agree.
Yeah.
But there's a lot of people.
He's, he's like the meaner version of me.
I'm going to read you one more.
Then I want to talk about why I think this is important.
This is happening.
Just realize that there is a point of misunderstanding regarding testing.
I am not talking about UI automation, but I talk about automated testing.
Selenium is a disaster.
I'm talking about tests run automatically by the CICD system run
without human intervention.
And again, this is the whole me saying something like that is what got
Jason on our podcast.
And I think we actually reached a weird place of agreement where.
Selenium is a, it's a blessing and a curse.
It works.
And the reason we need to use it is because reason, not we, the
reason teams often need to use it is because one and most importantly,
their application, their web app, their testing has been architected and
designed so poorly that UI automation is the only place they have to test it.
The developers are working so fast and are counting on a test team to
test their stuff.
So people have to use selectors from hell trademark in order to
make their goofy automation work.
So the tool is fine.
The work is that I, I commend Jason and everybody that's worked on web
driver to make it work over time.
As I've said before, I think the no code, you, a automation tools are much
better for that because it just doesn't, I wouldn't put as much effort into that.
We've rehashing stuff.
I've said before, I try and say it nicely.
He just gets right to the point and I kind of like it.
Yeah, I, I do too.
The one thing like that you were just talking about that reminded me of
systems theory, something we're fond of, right?
The, one of the problems though with systems theory is that there's actually
a theory within systems theory and that as you change the system to, to
actually solve a problem and then forgetting, I'm paraphrasing of course.
But that the, the number of problems stays constant.
So, so for example, I'll give you a favorite example, email, right?
When, when email first got constructed, it solved the problem of
communication between in or reducing the calendar time between communication
on individuals, right?
That was fantastic.
But now everybody and their brother send me communication.
So previously, previously it was a snail mail and the stamp was a good
filter to prevent people from trying to contact me.
You know, certain people I don't really care to or, or right now I'm
thinking about all the slews of people that keep trying to come and
bring me more work.
Email solved a problem, but then it constructed a whole new problem because
email was successful in solving the problem it was intended to solve.
And to me, like the example that we were just talking about is related to that.
I am reading one of his tweets now.
I'm, I'm gonna change the topic.
The, well, kinda.
Well, I have, I have a tangential topic after this as well, but you can, go ahead.
Good.
Did you do you.
So here's a question I'm thinking of it that he asked.
He asked the question, is there an adjective to put in front of the word test
that describes all testing except exploratory and usability testing?
And I'm guessing he's in response to like the.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
You know, what's going on there.
So yeah, the word test evidently doesn't mean test anymore.
Well, it, unfortunately it doesn't in a, in a small part of the community and whatever,
but my big realization, I followed him for a while, but just as these threads of
the last couple of days, like, Oh my God, he is, he is modern testing incarnate.
And he doesn't know anything about modern testing, which is great.
Which again, gets me to the fact that if, and when I'm doing, of course,
I'm doing a webinar for practice test.
I'm trying to figure out the right way to talk about modern testing
with a non testing audience.
Example, he speaks of some arc, a lot of architecture conferences, but I'm
going to architecture conference or a, uh, DevOps conference or an
infrastructure conference, pardon me.
Thinks it like there'll be such does like, why'd you put a name on something?
We already know if we talk about modern testing, that it would
be the wrong topic, that maybe it's an aside.
I'm just trying to figure out how to.
When I read his tweets and see tweets like this, what I think is, and what
I always think it's not like I want to have 10,000 listeners for the podcast,
but I think there are people that do not know about our podcasts.
I could listen to it.
So let's do this.
I don't know the answer listeners do this talk about the podcast with
people who aren't testers and see what they think, see if they want to check
it out, give us reviews and blah, blah, blah.
Uh, that's, that's the sort of thing I'm realizing that with modern testing,
that there's just more and more things that are happening that are modern
testing without knowing about modern testing, which is really, really cool.
And I want to see more of that.
Oh, I love this guy.
Right.
So there, he has a tweet a while back where he takes a nice dig on safe.
So, uh, just, just keep that in mind too.
So they will, we'll talk about that in a future episode.
And I just tweaked my cable.
Yeah.
I was leaning back and my camera cable.
This should have been a YouTube broadcast, but oh well.
Yeah.
So tell me what you think of this phrase.
He says, knowing already upfront manual testing for final released is usually
a band aid over bad architecture.
I have yet to see a situation where people claim that manual testing was
indispensable where you couldn't change the architect to support automated
testing inside the CI CD pipeline.
So going back to your other things, going back to your last thing, you
know, how would you, how would you, how would you reach the, the dev
audience with this modern testing console?
What I'm trying to decide is whether they need, you know what the devs that
need to hear this or not this guy, it's the devs that think they need
a test team in order to deliver.
It's the developers who do not think they have the knowledge or the
permission to test their product.
Yeah.
I'm, I'm remembering back to the episode we did several years ago.
Oh yeah.
Good old episode 30, 70 something.
Are you being snarky or do you actually know totally snarky.
All right.
The one at Evans company.
Oh, at redfin.
Yeah.
Thank you.
Uh, I knew it was red something, but I kept on going.
You'd be testing live from the redfin auditorium.
Right.
And for some reason, my head couldn't let go that the name of the
company was red Zillow, even though I knew like there's no company called red
Zillow.
Okay.
There is revzilla who sells motorcycle equipment, but anyway, go on redfin.
Right.
Evan, the audience, the audience, the audience you would need to reach
is exactly that it.
And we like, that was that company at that time, they had separate Dev and
tests and what we wanted to do was speak to the Dev because, and I actually, I
think that's a really smart idea.
Cause if there is a way that we could reach that crowd and convert them.
Cause a lot of the times we hear that a lot of that a lot, like modern testing
resonates with a lot of testers, right?
A lot of them.
The reality is most from my experience, most test teams as an organization is,
is low man on the discipline pole.
Yeah.
Right.
It, they, they, they often do not have, it's not entirely the case, but they
often do not have the political clout to initiate change.
Dev is at the top of it.
How do you influence those folks?
I've come up with a lot of techniques as have you around basically
forcing functions to do this.
But my techniques have, have relied on me knowing full well, what power I have.
For example, I know I own that.
I own the resource allocation of the people on my team.
All right.
You don't want to play ball with modern testing.
Guess who just, who just lost all of their testers.
Right.
So let me, I have a, I have a thought exercise.
It's going to take a little bit of time here.
There's a good segue here.
So when we wrote the modern testing principles and honestly, it's still
kind of blows me away that one.
I was inspired to do so in the first place to make the draft in the first place,
but how little they've changed.
We thought maybe we'd modify more, but also how often they're referred to.
But we wrote them for testers.
The audience of the modern testing principles were testers.
Yep.
And I want to look at these one by one.
And I'm curious if there's a rewording we would do for developers.
So for number one, I think it stays the same.
Our priority is improving the business.
Yes.
That's good.
That's good for anyone.
That's not tester centric.
The next one is we accelerate the team and use models, blah, blah, blah,
to identify our prioritize and mitigate bottlenecks in the system.
Who's we in this case?
Is it everyone who's who's the we in that sentence?
We were when we wrote it, we were targeting testers.
That's what I just said.
Yes.
But as written, does it, does it target the whole team now?
Or would we tweak?
We're not saying we're going to change these, but it will be tweak.
Where is this?
If these were for developers?
Yeah.
So, so I put my, my old dev hat on.
Right.
And, and then that was like my, my, what I drew from to help craft these.
And I would say, oh yeah, that's exactly what we did.
Yeah.
My, my team did that accelerate in principle to came from accelerate the
shipment of the really simple quality, right?
Achievement of quality.
So I wonder if I'm not going to try and get these perfect, but if we just
said we use models like lean thinking, blah, blah, blah, then that can
become the whole team a little easier.
Let me look at them.
No, no, but, but that statement, that statement is true.
Period.
Whole team dev test PM that that team, maybe you're right.
I think let me look at the next one.
I think you're right.
We are a force for continuous improvement, helping the team adapt and
optimize in order to succeed.
This one's a little interesting.
There's a we, then there's helping the team.
So we are helping the team.
So if the team is we that reads weird.
Well, maybe because I don't think it's a separation.
I think, no, I think what if we change the, to our, we're a force for continuous
improvement, helping our team adapt and optimize order to succeed rather than
providing a safety net to catch pillars.
Again, that clause at the end, that's about testers.
Yes.
So if we said something like we are a force for continuous improvement, helping
the helping our team adapt and optimize in order to succeed rather than relying
on safety notes to catch features.
Uh, I would even say even more proactively something along the lines
of actively removing safety nets.
Oh yeah.
And right now people are freaking out.
Don't change the principles.
And we're not going to right away, but there's something I thought about
for a while to dove tails in here.
I want it to be, I'm going to be like, I've gone on these adventures with
Alan in the past, just be absolutely clear.
We are on path to change the principles.
This is, it's an unavoidable path.
It is going to happen.
I cannot tell you when, but the three will speak.
And I got to say, if you're on my team listening to this, this is the way I do
things I, I don't dictate change.
I put the wheels in motion for change to happen.
And I'll do that a lot.
I don't like, I don't make very many decisions for my team has a discussion
before, but I make sure we have the right discussion so they figure out
what change needs to happen.
So, okay.
So let me tell you putting my dev head on reading and rereading this again.
Like previously I was, I was doing modern test manager versus traditional
test manager when we did this.
Yes, of course.
Now putting on, you know, manager of a dev team where I did not have a test
team that was successful.
What did we do?
Right.
And this one was about number one, the lean principle known as optimize the whole.
Yes.
In other words, you don't try to optimize what does it take to get to, to
co-complete and then what is it?
What does it take to get the test complete?
You optimize the whole system in that, which is how do we release this whole
thing in the end, the fastest?
Cause that that's what, that's how you get the trade-off discussions between things.
Yeah.
So the safety net is to catch failures, right?
This is the old school mentality around everything must be that if you're not
trying to prevent things, you're doing things wrong.
Right.
As a lot of the times, as we've discussed, CICD or, uh,
flighting systems with, uh, an appropriate, uh, flight controller that evaluates
risk before going out more and more broadly, these are actually better
systems that to help you avoid waste.
Now I'm looking at, so when I look at this, the other thing I see that's
in this is, is an element of learning slash scaling.
If there's a focus on the end goal KPIs, not the intermediary ones,
that's what we're trying to improve.
And then there's a focus on helping the whole team learn what
the whole team needs to learn.
Right.
So to me, it also kind of kills siloism.
Yeah.
As written, there's a little bit of us and them in the principles,
which I don't think is the right thing for the long-term.
I want to read the next one to you in the new form in a potential.
There's a draft.
We care deeply about the quality culture of our team and we coach lead
and nurture each other towards a more mature quality culture.
I replaced the team with each other.
No, I like, I like that algorithm already.
Cause again, that's around, there's two aspects of that now.
It's around, I don't know if you, if I've ever walked you through
when I'm doing a kickoff for agile, right?
When I'm, when a team's asked me to come and teach them agile,
it hasn't happened in years.
But one of the things I describe is actually agile is a team sport.
It's closer to soccer.
Galah though.
Right.
It's closer to soccer in my mind than it is rugby.
In, in soccer.
And I think I've told you this, I don't know about this.
Yeah.
I'm, I'm huge on the whole soccer strategy thing.
We've talked about this.
Yeah.
Well, but not on air, maybe go ahead.
I'll just say years ago, I had an employee that was in a, a
competitive corporate league.
Okay.
And they got to play at what was then called Century Link field.
And it's now called Loomin field.
Yeah.
It's Seahawks stadium, whatever.
Um, Loomin field sounders play there too.
Anyway, go on.
Um, it was interesting cause that was the first time I had ever been in
the been in that stadium where you get actually here.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
Okay.
And I could hear the chatter on the field and what I really walked away with.
And I paid attention to this even like when I watch TV games, I'm like, okay,
are they, can I tell that the players are talking?
Answers?
Yes.
And in the soccer, the teams are very clear on the goals.
And when they need to be defensive, they all shift to defense.
When they, when they have an advantage and they can get to the goal on
appropriate number, you know, shifted towards offense while still doing
risk mitigation, like I could look at a soccer game and watch the game and
describe it in terms of software development.
Sure.
And actually I would say, I mean, one thing is very true is a
soccer team is made up of a group of specializing generalists or
generalizing specialists.
Yes.
They have some things they're good at and people are put in a position
where they can be most effective, but some players, there are some
utility players on every team in the world who can play multiple
positions.
Well, it's about knowing the role you're supposed to play and applying
the skills you have towards the success of that role.
The other parallel I like in this is if you watch, I've played a
goalkeeper quite a bit, even though I'm not very tall and old, but
one thing I like about that is you see everything in front of you and
you do, you do a lot of directing.
You do a lot of eyes for everybody.
And that's where a lot of the defensive communication starts.
Yeah.
Uh, the, the, the thing I found just most notable is how audible
the team players were when I was younger, you know, whatever it
was fifth grade or whatever played soccer in a league, like there
wasn't anywhere like this type of talking.
Whereas at that level, the teams are covering each other.
They, they say they know exactly when to hand off.
They tell they, they are looking out for each other when they're
under threat.
Like, you know, someone is coming up from behind and about to
try to take the ball.
Right.
That is what I see, what I think about when I read your, or when
I think about your replacement for principal four, the only thing
I'm thinking about though, is when we go and talk to a dev team,
is quality the right term?
I think so.
It's, I only, I can't think of a better one.
I think of, you know, this is all around the quality
cultural transition guide.
The, so the one, I can't, I don't think of a better word there.
Well, if I were to, we deeply care about the culture of our team.
We care, lead and mature each other towards a mature culture.
Now, the way I just said it, I'm sure you have no doubt will
agree with it.
The difference between the two is whether or not it's important.
Cause if you remove, if you remove quality, then you're kind of
talking about how well people work together.
Let me, let me phrase it differently and see it and totally
change the meaning.
We care deeply about the quality of our product and we coach lead
and nurture each other towards a more mature culture.
That doesn't make sense that way.
Do we focus on the quality product or the quality of the way we make it?
What is as written originally, it's about the way we make it with an,
assuming that I'll get to an output that's high quality.
No, I like how you, I like, I like where you're going with that rephrasing,
but if we were to do that, then I would want to swap principle four and five.
Okay.
Uh, I want to move on cause we're going to talk a lot about seven, five
and six ship them as is.
We believe the customer is the only one capable of judging, evaluate
the quality of our product.
That's actually perfect already as much as it pisses people off who are,
they don't get it.
And number six, we use data extensively to deeply understand customer usage.
And then close the gaps between product hypothesis and business impact,
ship it as is no need for a change.
And then the next one is definitely a we, us, and them thing that I
can have to think here for a minute on how to, how we rephrase this.
We expand testing abilities and know how across the team, understanding
that this may reduce or eliminate the need for a dedicated testing specialist.
This one's all for, we wrote it for the testers.
What would this, how would we rephrase this written
for a more generic team audience?
Well, so, uh, cause this is all, what does it say in a nutshell is that
everyone knows how to test and gets, it gets better at it all the time.
What is your, give a shit about testing.
What is your simple, cause I know we had different versions.
Uh, you, what is your like two or three word, um,
encapsulation of principle seven.
Do you remember what I'm talking about?
Everybody tasks.
Every, okay.
That doesn't work.
Sorry, man.
And so, so, okay.
Number one, we can fix the first part of, of this by just getting rid of the word
testing, is this really just without the word testing in there?
Is that, is it about being a learning organization?
This is yeah.
How about we expand abilities and know how across the team,
understand this may reduce or eliminate the need for specialists.
For, for a dedicated specialist.
That may work.
Yeah.
That was much, much easier than I thought it would be.
The wheels are spinning.
And again, the audience going, no change the principles, but, uh, yeah,
it's worth talking about.
And I think, well, so that, what do we call it?
I don't know.
The podcast.
Pretty soon.
It's like, I don't know what's going on, but I, yeah, I didn't know we were going
to talk about this till we started, but it's something that I've been thinking
about subconsciously, apparently for a while and cause I can tell just by
talking through it, I go, Oh, now it's these words.
Like, how do we get to more of the people that need to hear us?
And we've preached to testers for a long time, but having the
realization that we need to, I would like to find a way to get this
information in front of the developers that know that they get, if I said
before, it's not just telling developers, they have to test often that approach.
They just get mad and say, I need to test.
I don't want to test, but what I've learned more and more is again,
this is extrapolated and I'll get to my point.
It's extrapolated by the exact aspirated.
Sorry.
By the fact that people still insist that testing is a very special thing
that only specialists can do.
And to be clear, some, there is room for, anyway, I'm not going to go on the tangent.
No.
And, and, and we talked about it here and I, yeah, I think, I think it was,
it was my second to last blog post where, where I talk about essentially
except in a very rare situation, I'm now the view that specialization
does not make sense in software development.
Yeah, I totally agree.
And the point that I failed to get to, that's all my fault, not yours.
So I'll take, I'll take the blame on that one is that we just need to tell
developers they need to give, we need to give them permission to test and tell
them that they can actually do it.
That's something that's within their realm.
They've been told for so long that we need testing specialists to do testing.
And we've created that codependency that it's those folks that feel like that,
that I think need to see this potentially up and coming slight revision of the
modern testing principles.
Let me, we have a few minutes.
Yeah.
And I have one other quick story to share at the end about a podcast I listened
to today, but so go ahead and go on and do your few minute thing.
Okay.
So I am now going to share with you the safe principles.
Oh God.
Yeah.
Be prepared.
Oh, these are actually similar and they're shaped.
Look at, yeah, I think it's kind of nerdy that they did that.
But number one, take an economic view.
Uh, our priority is the business.
Cool.
Got it.
Yep.
Number two, apply systems thinking.
Yeah.
I've, I've heard of that one before.
Okay.
Now, Hey, when did these come out?
Did they steal our shit?
The article, I don't know.
Okay.
Anyway.
Yeah.
They obviously have more assume variability preserve options.
That's an agile thing that we didn't cover, but yeah.
Okay.
I'm going to go with that.
Build incrementally with fast integrated learning cycles.
All right.
Base milestones on objective evaluation of working systems.
Okay.
Whatever I would, I would, I would nix that one, but whatever I would have so far,
I would probably cut number three and number five, the two that don't match up
to empty principal school, gotcha.
Go on.
Well, yeah.
Although I think this one, I don't think we covered number six, visualize
and limit with reduced, reduced batch sizes and manage queue links.
Yeah.
But our intention was that, and I totally agree with, I don't disagree with that at
all, but our intention was not to talk about the basics of agile.
So it's more of the approach, but yeah, I get, I get why it's there.
I think we, I think we've collapsed that like in the principle.
What is it to this?
There is a construct on that.
Right.
Apply cadence and synchronized with cross-domain planning.
Um, that cut.
That would be cut.
It's important to be cut.
Okay.
Unlock the intrinsic motivation of knowledge workers.
Oh my God.
Do I love that one?
And we, we have things that touch on it, but not exactly what that is saying.
Decentralized decision-making, right?
We don't, we don't even touch that.
Right.
And then organize around value.
Now I'll tell you, organize around value is, is it specifically talking
around literally a reorganization, uh, but having gone through it, I will tell
you that that principle is starting off with principle five, it's starting off
with principle five and going even further saying you should also
organize your teams around that.
Yeah.
Okay.
Tell your story.
Quick story.
And then when I got to go out of time here, actually I got two minutes.
So I was listening to the knowledge project podcast and this time it's
Walter Isaacson who's written a bunch of stuff.
He's super, super smart, but he was talking about Steve Jobs and Steve Jobs
started using this word impute.
You know what impute means?
Of course I do.
I'm a data scientist.
Okay.
He started using it a lot and he wanted like the reason when the iPod first
came out, it had, it wasn't just the iPod.
That was this thing you wanted in your dreams.
It was the packaging and Apple products, even going back to the max.
I just got a new Mac a while back.
They spent a lot of time in their packaging and money on the packaging
because they want to impute on you that this whole thing is high quality
awesomeness and he talked about a couple of other examples and he goes,
and he says, and then when you look at something like Microsoft Teams,
they also impute and they impute that you want a horrible user experience
where you can't figure out how to do anything.
And it just cracked me up.
He totally in his eloquent way, just totally dug on teams.
So I thought that was, thought that was just fun.
I like a little bashes on, on the old team.
Okay.
So that was my little story there.
So if you want to find out more about this podcast, you can join
one of the three dot slack.com.
Just go to modern testing.org and you get an invitation.
We have about 750 members of the three there right now.
Maybe a few more.
I tell your friends about the podcast.
You can find me on Twitter at Alan Page.
Brent is Brent M Jensen.
Uh, we look forward to seeing you all soon.
So anything else, Brent?
Nope.
We're good.
Till next time.
All right.
Say goodbye to everyone.
Bye.