Will you still feed me?
Will you still need me when I'm 64?
Welcome to AB testing podcast, your modern testing podcast.
Your hosts, Alan and Brent will be here to guide you through topics on testing,
leadership, agile, and anything else that comes to mind.
Now on with the show.
Hey everyone.
It's Alan and welcome to episode one 51 of the AB testing podcast.
I'm Alan.
And that silence is Brent who is not here yet, but let's go ahead and start with Adam.
It'll be fun.
He'll show up and jump right in.
This show is also our end of year extravaganza.
I don't know what to call it, but every year, our last recording of the year,
we talk about, you know, things, things that we have reflected onto the year,
predictions for the next year, that kind of stuff.
So, um, I don't know if Brent's prepared, but I certainly have not, but probably
worth reflecting a little bit on what's happened in 2021 and what's, it's been
a long year, right?
With the pandemic and everybody working from home and we have more of it in
front of us, it's been hard, but a year ago, I went back and listened briefly to
not all that part of our year end extravaganza from 2020, uh, we talked
about, we were still talking about the election and it wasn't certified yet.
And, and Brent was still fairly worried.
Oh, Hey, Brent, I started without you.
Everybody say hi to Brent.
Brent is working on getting his microphone to work.
He is muted right now in zoom.
That could be part of it, but a welcome to the podcast, Brent.
Are you excited to join us here today?
Join us?
Yes.
Yeah.
I was just letting everyone know this is the year end extravaganza.
I'll catch just hold on everybody.
Just fast forward for a second.
It's the last podcast of the year.
And a year ago we were talking about, uh, would the election be certified?
That's kind of where I was when you joined us.
So welcome.
I'm happy to have you here.
I was talking about last year.
I told, I already told them I'm not prepared at all for this, but, uh, I
do want to now tangentatize, um, did you, have you watched get back?
Okay.
Apparently not.
It is so good.
It is so, so good.
It's all I'll say.
So.
I did watch a Sergeant peppers, lonely heart club band.
Yeah, that's different.
So, uh, yeah, it's one of the high points of the year for me.
And there was a lot of, you know, one thing if I were to reflect on the
year, as we bounced through, we felt probably have an order I'll get to in a
moment, but one thing I could reflect on for the year is the streaming
services really stepped it up to make being at home all the time work.
Having some first releases get to HBO or, or Disney has been really nice.
I have earned my money's worth.
You know, I've gone over my Comcast limit almost every month and why we have
limits on internet, I do not know.
I hate you Comcast, but we have gone over our limits about every month.
So there's no,
I thought you were off Comcast.
No, unfortunately, no, there's nothing else I can get here.
Just as of recently, we can get T-Mobile 5g, but everything I hear about it
tells me I'm not going to like it just for spotty-ness.
Oh, okay.
So you, you just, um, you cut the coax cord, but right.
I've got the coax cord.
I still pay for internet access.
I would love to live someplace where I can get fiber or have anything else, but
instead we have a monopoly.
Yeah.
So streaming services.
So you said you've, um, so what streaming services are you, uh, currently invested in?
Oh my God.
It's a little embarrassing, right?
So I have the.
Is the answer.
Yes.
The answer is almost yes.
So I don't have any live TV services.
I do have, uh, I have the package from Disney, which gives me Disney plus Hulu.
Plus ESPN plus, and that gets me a lot of soccer.
So that's very nice.
I watch a lot of soccer games on ESPN plus or Hulu.
I thought there was live things on Hulu.
You can get live Hulu, but it's like, it's again, it's, it's the same price
as cable and I don't watch enough live TV.
Gotcha.
I watch, in fact, I usually, uh, anything like any sport event, and I don't
watch a lot of sports, the only sport I watch is soccer.
And if there is a match that's not on ESPN, uh, the internet is full of
streams for those and I'll watch there.
Um, I don't feel bad for taking your money.
In fact, uh, if you go to Fox sports for American people, uh, just
log in incognito, uh, watch for an hour till the time limit goes up and
then relaunch your incognito window and log onto the event again.
It's very handy.
I really, I really enjoy, uh, that Fox makes it not very difficult
to watch their live events.
And I also have Netflix, of course, and Amazon prime.
Uh, anything else?
Oh, I just, yes, because T-Mobile for my phone, uh, has given me Apple TV for free.
I've only watched Ted Lasso on there.
It's excellent.
But I got to tell you the Apple TV app.
On, on my Mac that I watched it stuff on is by far the worst streaming
control experience of any of the streaming experiences made by anyone.
I it's, it's awful.
So I am, I am on T-Mobile and I did not know that they will do Apple TV.
They also gave just, I just signed up for yesterday, a free year of paramount plus.
So I can catch up on Star Trek.
It's CBS.
Oh.
Awesome.
Like I, so what was it?
Amazon prime just did the one episode of Picard, uh, which I watched the
second it came out and I'm like, yeah, I'm not.
Yeah.
They're all on paramount plus, man.
So I think that's it for my streaming services.
Uh, it's not too horrible.
Oh, also HBO max.
Nevermind.
HBO max.
Yeah.
Now I'm just so, so I'm probably paying more for streaming per month
than I used to pay for cable.
But much more value out of it.
Cause I can watch what I want, what I want.
And there's, and you, and you feel better about it.
Yeah.
Get apple TV on us.
Interesting.
Check it out.
So I, I actually want to watch Ted Lasso and I want to watch foundation,
which are only there.
Oh, it's foundation based on the, the, the, and ran stuff or something.
No, no foundations.
I'm thinking fountainhead got, I'm dumb.
No.
And Rand.
I was thinking fountainhead and Atlas Shrugged, but that's thinking fountain.
Yeah.
Atlas Atlas Shrugged is what I was thinking of.
No.
Uh, foundation is Isaac Asimov.
Oh yes.
Yes.
It's like the crux of science fiction.
I should watch that.
I should get back to that.
So what was I saying?
Oh, I should probably, well I'm on this rant and not rant, soapbox, whatever.
Maybe it's worth talking about last year.
You recommended the masked singer to me, which I still hate, but it's all right.
Ted Lasso.
Good recommendation.
The new season of the expanse, uh, kicked off.
I'm super happy about that.
A new season of lost in space on Netflix.
You haven't watched it.
I think it's a really good show.
It's great.
Canceled Netflix.
I forgot lost in spaces on there.
Some space was fantastic.
Yeah.
New season just, just showed up.
So I've been pretty happy.
What else have I watched?
A lot of stuff.
Um, those, those stand out from recent memory, but Ted lastly, you're like,
what are you been watching?
What did, what did, what did you stream in 2021?
Oh, uh, and of course all the Marvel stuff on Disney as a given.
I know.
Yeah.
I, I, I would say anything Marvel DC is what I've been watching like the, but
not, how do I put this like doom patrol or have you been watching doom
patrol on HBO?
No, no, not yet.
Oh, oh my God.
Like that is a fantastic show.
All right.
I'm going to check it out.
And they've gotten, they've gotten, I think multiple Emmy nominations.
Uh, they're just completely irrelevant or not irrelevant.
They're relevant.
Probably not the word you're looking for here.
Irreverent.
Um, which is as a data scientist, irrelevant is, is a word that they use far
more often.
And then, uh, even, even the, the live action team Titans knock off that
they just called Titans.
Yeah.
I, I've, I thought that wasn't bad.
I didn't have time to get back.
I've watched like two or three episodes and I got sidetracked.
Like there's more than enough stuff.
I want to watch to occupy the relatively small amount of time
that I give to watching videos.
One of the one to call out is on Amazon prime is invincible.
Have you seen this?
Uh, I watched the first episode of it.
Okay.
I think it's, if you get into it, it is fantastic.
And where it goes in the end, it is dark.
I'll leave it there.
Well, the first episode, it ended very dark.
Yeah, it gets darker.
And I'm like, yeah, I'm not certain this one's for me.
All right.
Fair enough.
Uh, although like last night, last night, what, where was it?
Uh, HBO max.
Uh, somebody had made a cartoon version of the, the Mortal Kombat story.
And I'm like, I was just so, I'm like, why would anyone build this?
Like no one knows Mortal Kombat anymore.
Uh, so I was fascinated, watched it.
And I can, I can tell you, I didn't actually get the answer to my
question, uh, but I can absolutely save you an hour of your life.
All right.
Noted.
What are you gonna make my list?
And of course, I think I mentioned this in our last podcast, uh, from the podcast
before then, but my video watching time has also been greatly reduced because
I've been playing through fallout four again.
Yeah.
Uh, I, I saw that.
Uh, I think we talked about it in the last podcast.
And then I saw you posted on that.
And then I'm like, you know, that's an interesting idea.
Um, yeah.
Cause I forgot how, cause it's a good, it's a different experience.
So there's two things and there's no spoilers on a game.
It's five years old, but you can play a completely different build.
Like I played pretty much a tank the first time I beefed up on
strength and, and punching and those things.
And now I just sneak and nobody can ever see me.
Cause I maxed out and I'm maybe not maxed out, but I can, I just.
One shot all the bad guys.
Oh, see when I play a fallout and pretty much all the time is I'm, I'm
a generalizing specialist.
Okay.
Sometimes we're going to get to, uh, the fallout four guide to modern testing.
Oh, did you see it?
You saw it in Slack, right?
That's so, uh, well, yeah, yeah, yeah.
No, I was, I was waiting for a segue.
I guess.
Well, let's segue.
Because we have no plan.
I do want to talk about, you know, have a little bit more reflection on what we
like from things we enjoyed in 2021.
But there's a nice article from the people at Monoma.
No, Mono, Mono, Mono, Mono.
I'm not sure.
A lot of references to modern testing.
And, uh, and if you want to see this stuff, like when it comes up, you know,
we didn't tell them to write it.
We didn't pay them to write it, but they just talked about, uh, uh, what
they do and the inspiration.
And they made it their own.
It's fantastic.
But, uh, we, I found out about this from our Slack group.
You can go to modern testing.org and to get the invitation link and join.
And there are 745, minus Brett and I 743 of the three are in that group.
Uh, lots of collaboration, very good self-sustaining community.
One of the, one of the things that I continue to be proud of and thankful
for, but you were going to make some other comments on that article.
Just say like, if you are, if you were a new listener, obviously in this
particular format, it's very difficult for us to determine that if you are a
new user, a listener, Jesus Christ.
And you find that what we are saying resonates, I can't encourage you
enough to join the channel.
There are people there that, uh, have actually taken modern testing
principles, uh, even further than, than Alan and I ever even thought it's.
It's fantastic.
It is definitely a community that if these things resonate with you, you should
join, uh, cause there's a strong community there.
Indeed.
You're exactly right.
People there, there's people in that channel that actually know more about
modern testing than we do.
Yeah, that's true.
Yeah, because they're actually, they're practicing the transition and
Brent, you know, I did the transition with my team here at unity four years ago now.
So it's not something I'm actively doing.
There's, I, you know, we, I don't have, I got a couple testers, but anyway,
it's not something I'm actively doing, but anyway, very cool to see that stuff.
So I'm going to ask you, we got onto videos for a moment, but what else did you
do of note in 2021 or things that kind of made, I say, affected your time other
than the pandemic and streaming affected my time.
Like, I don't know what I'm asking here.
Like what do you want to reflect on for 2021?
What's interesting to share with me?
What was interesting to share?
Uh, I don't know that we've ever actually talked about the podcast, but
you already have visibility to it in that, in that I have begun the discovery
of my inner artist.
Yes, you have.
Yeah.
So I have, uh, started and, and, uh, down the path of learning to paint with,
uh, watercolors, but, uh, as an adult, not, not, uh,
fingerprints, uh, we may have, we may have all done as children.
Um, and I'm pretty proud of like, I can, I've tested it with Alex on that.
Alex is my oldest son.
And every now and again, I call him Alan and I call Alan Alex.
I tested it with Alan and it has, uh, repeatedly achieved my bar, which is Alan.
Can you tell what it is?
I attempted to paint.
It looks like a turkey eating a seal.
And then I go, yes.
Awesome.
Nailed it.
Like my bar is, is quite low.
I'm reading this book right now on how to paint with this, this person
that far exceeds my ability.
And she was talking about how in her book, she's talking about how, um, to her,
it's really important to have a set of principles if you're an artist, because
everything, everything then shapes around those principles.
And one of her principles, uh, was the viewer can't see the brushstrokes.
And as a result, what she's noticed with that principle is that the, the
viewer gets lost in the scene, forgets that it's a painting, right?
But the second you can see the brushstrokes you're, you're reminded of,
oh, this is something somebody did.
Right.
Is there, is there any equivalent of that?
Uh, I know your artistry is, is in the music side.
Isn't there equivalent of that?
Maybe you don't see the practice that went into something.
It's a little different though.
I think it's a little different because maybe it's the same.
I don't know.
You can watch a musician and play.
Wow.
That's, that's effortless.
It must be easy to do that or, and it's not cause it's, it's easy for them to do
because they've done it a hundred thousand times, but I think it's a little different.
That's the repetition versus the building of the art through brushstrokes.
Don't know, man.
Yeah.
But that's cool.
That's cool.
I think that's to be commended because a lot of people thought, okay, I'm stuck
at home all this extra time.
I have all these projects I'm going to do.
I'm going to, and everybody at first like, I'm going to make bread.
I did.
I did that.
I've seen, I've seen these dolphins or some sort of fish before top view.
Yeah.
No, so for the listeners or orange, because the image doesn't really come across
where when, when zoom blows it up, but those are essentially koi fish.
Oh, okay.
They're big.
That's why they're orange.
Okay.
Great.
Yeah.
What was I talking about, man?
I don't know.
I was pretty loaded up by I could coat a koi fish.
No, I think the point is I think that a lot of people attempted to do something
new and creative in their, their time, you know, in our time or spending more
time at home and most people did not actually try anything drastically new or
get better at something they haven't worked on in a while or come up with
the actual sustainable hobby, but now kudos to you, you did.
You said, you know, I want to do this.
I'm going to do this.
And you practice at it and got pretty good and you're getting,
you're good and getting better.
The rest of us are like, yeah, maybe I'll become a professional pizza eater.
A pizza critic that would, that might, that would be a decent, you know,
upon the fifth piece, I begin to notice the tang of tartness against my upper pallet.
And I find creating things really helps to balance out the sort of the destruction
of the melancholy that comes from like this persistent COVID bullshit.
Honestly, the right.
It's, it's not going to end anytime soon.
Although it was interesting.
I don't know if you saw the article, Bill Gates is claiming pandemic over 2022.
So how's that going to happen?
So actually I had a thought about this this week in a conversation.
I don't know what you think, but what we really need is a variant that is,
has mild, mild effects, but is massively contagious.
So everybody can just get it and get herd mentality, that herd mentality,
herd immunity that way.
That's my plan.
Cause otherwise it's not going to happen because people won't the same people
that won't get vaccinated also won't get tested and they won't stay home and
they won't wear a mask and they won't be conscious of spreading it to others,
even if they don't know they have it.
So it's not, and there's too many people that way.
It's not the contagion is not going to go away.
I am curious and maybe I'm being pessimistic, but Mr.
Former boss, Bill G, how the hell do we get there, Brent?
I only read the first couple of paragraphs and then honestly,
I kind of bit flipped and then said, you know,
I wonder if the next Doom patrol is out.
Our listeners are tapered off because they don't want to have a discussion.
But I think we just have to make sure we have the medicines and it's not
Ivermectin you jerks to treat it.
So it's not such a big deal.
People have it because it's not going away.
Just, we're just going to have to learn to deal with it better than we have.
One thing that will, I mean, there's some things that'll change.
Let's, let's talk about, uh, maybe a little bit about what this means
for the future of work.
Like, you know, I'm not sure what the latest is a Microsoft on you.
You're going to the office.
No, people don't have to.
Is there a date when people are expected to go?
Everyone goes back or, or is the expectation of Microsoft that
everyone's going to go back or is it a hybrid where you're back a couple
days a week or is it really up to every team or individual to figure out
how much they want to work in the office?
And this is all new.
And one thing, one thing new is when people are sick, they're going to stay
home, which they, we didn't always do before.
So Microsoft's policy is the, is the third one that you mentioned.
So we are at, uh, internally, they call it stage four or no, I'm sorry.
Stage five, which is Microsoft officially recommends that you,
you still work remotely.
Uh, however, uh, you no longer are required to have management approval.
If you do so choose to come into facilities.
Okay.
We're in a similar place.
We don't require a manager approval from much, but we're called, we're at yellow
two, which means you can go to the office if you want.
And some people usually have between two and maybe at most 15 people on a
really hectic day at the office.
Oh yeah.
I'll say, so I don't see people too often.
There's a couple of people I see all the time.
Um, but just at glancing at my, my parking lot, uh, I'll say there's maybe
20 cars here on an average basis.
If I were to, and that building you're in is probably is bigger or holds
more people than our unity office.
So, you know, we have the same thing, which I think is common where we, in
fact, we just changed this.
There was originally going to be a requirement that everybody had to
go in at least two days a week.
And I fought back on that.
I didn't think it seemed like people should go in when they felt like it
or when it made sense.
And that's finally kind of where we're at now.
People, we want people to live in general.
We don't hire fully remote people, even though a huge percentage of my team,
like 13% of my team is fully remote.
They're not near an office.
Our general guidance is we want people to live somewhere near enough, a unity
office that they could come to the office if needed, you know, it's
helpful for it and things also for tax stuff.
Cause we don't have an entity in every state in the U S nor in every
country like Microsoft probably does.
So I think it's a good, fair thing.
I'm going to push back on hiring more fully remote people.
And I think I can get away with it.
You're going to push back on that.
I want to hire more fully remote people.
The policy is they're an exception, not a, and if I want to get the best people,
some people live in a place and they like living in a place where we
don't have an office and I want to make, I want to make sure I can
do that when it's strategic.
Uh, but yeah, same thing.
Um, and I've told people throughout this thing for the last, ever since we've been
talking about the idea of maybe going back to an office that I would go
in at most once a week and it isn't the reason I like our office and they have
snacks there and seeing people as fun.
But as I mentioned before on the podcast, I start my day at six or six
30 every day because of the overlap with my teams in Europe.
I am usually in meetings solid from that time till late morning usually.
And at that point I'm five hours into my day.
And unless there's a reason for me to go to the office, then I'm not going
to go into the office for the last part of my day.
So I'm trying to work out my schedule in the long run where I can have,
actually I'm trying to move our org to a no meeting Friday as a
proxy for a four day a week.
And if we do that, then at least I can go to the office on Friday.
So when I have meetings to be in, in the morning and, uh, use that time
to catch up with folks and other parts of the company, do, do some
office socialization and stuff, but we'll see 2022 is a new year.
Um, we're going to get that to happen, but, uh, anything else from 2021, we
should talk about before we talk about the future and what we think
is going to happen in 2022.
Uh, 2021, what was interesting?
Yeah.
I think, I think the adaptations to COVID are interesting.
I've been fast.
I am more than a little bit.
Okay.
With, with Microsoft taking a, a good long while to do full, a full open,
which is what they call stage six.
Yeah.
We call that green.
It's nice knowing that I, that, uh, I get the same parking spot that I have every day.
Uh, I, um, uh, I think meetings, honestly, I feel like meetings online are a little
bit easier than in person, right?
And you just things like, all right, you're hungry, right?
Uh, social decorum.
Right nowadays, you just like, all right, I'm hungry.
I'm going to turn off my camera and I'm going to eat something.
That's not viewed as rude, right?
If it's a meeting where, um, I'm there for just getting the status for five minutes.
Right.
I get my status and I get off the meeting.
It's, uh, whereas previously you might've stayed longer because you didn't
want to disturb the next topic as you got up and tried to leave the room.
There are some nice things about it.
Uh, my team has, has well, so we still have a daily standup at the same time.
I had to make some accommodations on that one a little bit because of time zones.
I didn't, I wanted every one of my employees to, uh, normally I will do standup
in the, in the morning and I wanted every one of my employees to not have a
religiously attend standup at their lunchtime as an example, but at the same
time, I didn't want to require like those of us in the PST or the Pacific time
zone to, to, you know, start our day at five 30, even though I do.
Yeah.
But I think we've well adapted to that one.
See what else on 2021?
So that into art, obviously I did more in data science, but I think you
and the audience expects that.
So let's talk about let's, you know, I missed a segue opportunity.
We're talking about COVID and COVID going away or just becoming endemic.
Yep.
What else is going to happen?
That one we can, I don't think when we first went home in March of 2020, we
thought that we'd still be at home in December and longer of 2021, but it's,
it's, it's what happened, but what else let's talk about what in respect to
AB testing, modern testing, software development, or interesting things in
the world, what do you think is going to happen in 2022?
What's going to be interesting?
So I'll tell you the thing I'm, I'm currently most afraid of is in this waxes
political, but I'm currently most afraid of world war three beginning.
And that sounds, uh, hopefully that doesn't sound like hyperbole, but, uh,
I think I'll just say it on the podcast.
I think Taiwan needs to be left the hell alone.
Uh, I think worried about, uh, Ukraine as well at the moment.
Um, and something like that happens and all of our predictions are completely.
Off base.
Yeah.
That's all we need on the tail end of a pandemic.
Like, Hey, we're all going back to work and now there's a real world war.
Yeah.
That's let's just, uh, stay in dark land and you thought
invincible was too dark to watch.
Yeah.
I did the first, I'll just say the first, the first episode, absolutely.
I'm like, what the hell just happened?
Yeah.
Um, and I assume as you keep watching, you understand why the, uh, I
forget you obviously know his name, but the father, why the father's
doing what the father's doing.
Yeah.
Um, find out, you'll find out.
If you want more.
Yeah.
I'll just honestly say probably not gonna, um, and the world is soft.
Where like I actually see, I honestly see the trend continuing, right.
Um, and probably even solidifying, cause I don't know if you've gotten this feedback.
Um, I've already started to receive feedback from certain people around.
Hey, they actually want to stay full remote as this thing ends.
Um, yeah.
Uh, and, and the most common, the common reason, do you, do you have a guess on that one?
They hate commuting to work.
That's 100% commuting, commuting is like, I don't have to do the community anymore.
So, all right.
It's depending on, you know, where you stand, um, that's either an hour between
an hour or two, uh, additional work time or between an hour or two additional
free time every, right.
And that goes back to the reason I'm only, I'm only going to go into work when the
commute, and I don't have a long commute.
Some people have a very long commute.
You're obviously not prepared for this part, Brent, I didn't do your homework,
but I do want to talk about one prediction I had that I failed on, but
I'm going to make, I'm going to predict it again in 2022.
I wanted to have Nicole Forsgren on the podcast 2021.
Uh, not only did I not do it, I blew a golden opportunity somewhere in my
Twitter feed inbox, I saw a talk, a fireside chat with Nicole Forsgren.
It was in a pack.
It was so in Eastern Asian time, I thought this is my Monday night.
I'm going to do this thing.
It'll be, I just want to hear what you say.
This is great.
I actually have, I doesn't overlap any meetings.
So I sat down on my kitchen counter with my laptop and poured myself a glass
of wine and I log into this thing and it's only like 25 people.
And she's, she's being interviewed by the folks at shoot, launched darkly.
And then I'm kind of half paying attention, half taking care of a couple
of work things and all of a sudden we get shoved into breakout room.
So now I'm in a breakout room with five other people and Nicole Forsgren.
Cause I got in the group with Nicole Forsgren.
Oh, uh, I had a chance to ask her questions and I did.
And, uh, she gave great answers.
A perfect opportunity to do tooth.
So here's my, my dilemma.
It's like, I was thinking like, should I actually use this time
to ask her to be on the podcast?
So that's, that doesn't seem right right now.
And then I wanted to, one of the things I know, it isn't very stalker-y.
It doesn't, it's not as stalker-y as it sounds, but I know Nicole Forsgren's
birthday only because it's the same day as mine, it was like three days
ahead of my birthday.
And I also thought about wishing her a happy birthday in that call, but
it didn't want to be, you know how stalker-y that would sound?
Some old bearded guy goes, Hey, it's your birthday fry.
I just, it's like, there was just no way.
I think there is no way to not make this completely awkward.
And I will, yeah, I don't want to make people feel awkward or uncomfortable.
And I was afraid of that.
I figured I'd keep my mouth shut and she gave great answer.
She's wonderfully smart.
It made me go reread her article on space, which is a, what's your
already get lab, but I forget what space stands for, but it's a lot of
things about developer productivity, which is what my questions were about.
And what I'm highly concerned about in my current role.
So anyway, I absolutely blew, but at least Nicole Forsgren may remember me
as the person who didn't freak her out by asking awkward questions
during a breakout room in zoom.
So this year I'm going to try again and see if I can get Nicole to
be on the podcast.
You know what I've never asked.
Maybe Marit.
I asked to be on the podcast.
She may have asked us to be on.
I can't remember how that happened, but most guests we get on the podcast, they
ask me and then I check with Brent.
What do you think?
Yeah, it sounds good.
Let's do it.
So, uh, I'm not very good at it.
I need, uh, lately that's been a, no, we should pass on that.
I need a producer.
I need, we need a producer who goes out and finds our guests for us and
actually maybe even gives us topics or less of a haphazard crap show here of,
of random bits of information, but it's a story worth telling.
Uh, someday, someday.
And when, when, if not, if, but when we have Nicole on, I do think Dr.
Forsgren Chicago, I should call her Dr.
Forsgren when we have Dr.
Forsgren on the show, we should actually get our act together and have our
questions thought of like in advance.
So we don't get all weirded out and, and make her think we're like unorganized
because we are unorganized, completely unorganized, but I think we should
hide it from the pros.
I would say, say, I know.
Unorganized, right?
Come on, Brent.
Don't argue that point.
No, I'm going to argue that point.
I'm going to say, yeah, I don't, I don't, I don't agree with that.
I would say we're not organized and that is not a synonym.
Oh, I see.
I see what you're saying.
We're not organized by design.
We don't choose to be organized.
We choose to be not organized.
It's part of our charm.
Right.
Yes.
That charm.
But that's who said that someone so long ago.
Okay.
I rapid fire questions for a makeup on the spot.
So this is episode one 51.
I forget what the episode was the end of last year, but how many episodes
we're going to do next year?
What's our year end show number for 2022?
You have five seconds.
Uh, one 75.
Ooh, good.
24.
That that's, that's going to, that's a stretch, but I'd love to go for it.
That'd be so close to 200.
That means we'll get to 200 in 2023, which we're going for.
Uh, so we can get that done before I go on the PCT.
Yeah, but that's still not going to be till April, 2024.
Okay.
Uh, vanity metric time.
We currently have 742, three members of the three in our Slack channel.
Uh, do you think we go over a thousand this year?
No, cause we're, we're, uh, no, I don't, I don't know what the rate at which
we are growing actually.
I don't know either.
And, uh, I didn't even know if there's a, any analytics to show me that.
So, but I actually think our Slack channel blows up once we get to a thousand.
You think, you think a thousand's a tipping point?
I think, no, no, I think, um, I think we had to like start paying
for it or something that, uh, a thousand.
Oh, no, no, we don't.
Um, the way, and again, I was having a conversation, uh, with somebody that's
one of my team members, my team members this morning around, I'll put it this way.
This is a long story and I'll make it short, but it's good.
So I can fit the tangent back in a lot of service providers don't know how to sell.
Their pricing models are screwed up.
Their pricing models don't scale with usage.
We had a vendor we wanted to use.
We liked their product.
The way they wanted to price us made zero charges made zero cents.
So we couldn't use them.
It just could be too expensive because they were charging us for stuff that
we would never use because of the size.
This is probably at that tipping point a little bit like a Microsoft, you know,
build versus buy, it's almost always build.
Almost always.
Yeah.
And we've been at by by versus build and we're at a weird tipping point where we
have to consider buying a chunk of, we have actually use a lot of open source
and a lot of, uh, external tools, but we need to figure out what we can build
versus buy.
So the slack model is I would love, in fact, I would pay for it.
If there was a model in between the free, what we have and the corporate model,
like the prices jumped from like free to unaffordable.
And I would gladly pay like a per member fee or a per message fee.
If it was, you know, reasonable, or they just need a middle tier.
Cause the pricing is, and what we get for zero is a limit to how many
messages can be archived.
So if you go back into some of our channels and scroll up, eventually you
don't see the full history and that makes sense.
They, they giving the services is fairly, you know, a storage is expensive.
So we don't pay for much storage.
You know, they don't want to pay too much storage for us.
So jumping up, uh, like the next level up from free is pro and pro is $8 a
member, so multiply eight times 750.
And that would be our monthly cost.
Dude.
Yeah.
Where I just noticed we're on a pro trial right now that ends in January.
So something is going to disappear in January, I'm guessing.
Cause $8 a person, right?
That that's a limit on how many plugins we could do.
But again, that price is just not affordable for a community like ours.
And I wish they had a community cost where you could not associated with
the company and I don't know how they want to do it, but if they had a, a
model in the middle, they would make money off of me off of us.
Maybe at least for some period of time, right?
We would.
So we have, we have the podcast account, right?
But, uh, it can't drain that that quickly.
Right.
It'd be gone a month, right?
Not even, no, not even, I got to think what's in there.
Yeah.
It would be gone in less than a month.
We just can't do it.
I don't want people to be able to come up.
So again, they're missing out and I've talked to other vendors who also charged
that per, I don't want to give names away, but the pricing models don't work.
We talked to a vendor who made a tool that was fantastic.
They wanted to charge a hundred dollars a seat at a seat was anyone at all who
access the website, the services running on a month.
And it just said, no, we can't, that model doesn't work.
That model may work for a 10 person company.
Yeah.
We'll pay you a hundred dollars a month to, for everybody can access this.
But once you have 2,500 developers, we just, that price no longer makes sense.
And I think I'm just coming across a lot of companies.
I deal a lot with vendor relations here.
Well, when you, a lot of times they just blow when you do a hundred dollars a seat,
a hundred dollars a seat per month.
I mean, honestly, I don't think, I don't think I, uh, I would even
subscribe to, to get at that rate.
No, right.
Right.
Which is just absolutely critical to business.
Uh, and that may not been exactly, but it was something outrageous like that.
It may have been a thousand dollars a year, but same thing.
It was some round number that was incredibly huge and it just, yeah, it doesn't work.
So anyway, slack reminded me of that because, uh, they have, I, I wanted to
find a pricing model where I could pay them because it's a great, it's a great
app, a great service.
I like it a lot, but I can't pay $8 a user.
So what do you think, what do you think is a head for the test community?
And, and here you accused me of not preparing the, was I, was I wrong?
No, uh, you were wrong.
Okay.
Great.
The thing is, tell me what you prepared.
The thing is, is that in this case, I realized that in order for me to develop a
prediction, right, this is one of the struggles as it relates to me in terms of
our podcasts at this point in time, right?
I'm, I'm not really attached to the test community and most of my prediction
power in the past has actually come from the right that I'm living it.
And in that.
So,
and we talked about this early a little bit.
I'm in the same boat.
Yeah.
So yeah, I liked the idea of, uh, we, we started the podcast, uh, with, with, or
somewhere in the store, we, we talked about, right.
The thing on the Slack channel where the one team just completely shifted and they
created, they made it their own and I just absolutely adore everything about that.
Right.
And then I don't know how I missed it.
Uh, you, you circled back, you circled back later and posted their vision statement.
But when I read it, I had completely missed it.
I think, I think I had just, my brain just said, Oh, random add, ignore, keep reading.
But I'm like, Oh my God.
Right.
Uh, just, I don't even know how many random words it is, but that the, the
random words I posted in a, in a blog post so many years ago really does
resonate with people.
And it, it's still, I chalk it up to self-esteem issues, but it still surprises
me even today that that's a, it's an excellent rallying cry to accelerate
the delivery of shippable software.
And that, that, that they just bolted on in industry.
Um, oh, that's fantastic.
You know, they turned it into a design pattern.
The other thing I liked though, what did they call it?
They called it craft, but they started it with a Q, something like that.
Uh, the yeah, yeah.
Like a quality craft.
Right.
And then they changed QA from quality assurance to quality assistance.
And that's something I actually, a last thing gets credit for, for doing about
the same time, maybe even before, but sometime back years ago, maybe even
before we did modern testing, they ended up calling quality assistance.
I don't think I would.
Like if I were, if I were in the process of informing a, another
company's transformation on that front, I don't think I would go with that.
Right.
Because it, if you still go in and say, Hey, we're part of the QA team,
but QA has changed, I think that complicates the story.
I think,
well, yeah, but what's, what's important to what we're seeing is there's
two different, there's this bubble of people that are, that are moving the
role of QA or a test forward by making it an accelerant and not a, not
the other school, which is purely an information provider.
Yeah.
And on a separate team, we have people seeing the value of collaboration
and the value of bringing that test frame of thinking, that tester
frame of thinking to a development team and development team, seeing
the value in that via collaboration.
Uh, yeah.
And I think, I think a lot of teams are moving on like that.
I, I really do wonder if we're already living in the post modern testing
principles.
That's exactly what I was.
So I'm giving a webinar next month and I forgot about it till I got the
reminder to give them a title and abstract.
And I don't know what it's going to be about yet, but that one of the
idea in my head was I want to talk about postmodern testing.
I don't know what, I don't know, I don't know what that is, but that's the
first idea for a title that came to me, even though I have no idea what
that talk is about because I don't, I don't feel right giving another
talk on modern, I think I've beaten modern testing down.
People can see talks on the internet, me talking about it.
So what's next?
And it's for a test audience.
So I have to, even though I'm not doing testing, it's something about
life after modern testing, or I haven't quite figured it out, but maybe
you have some ideas.
So I do just high level, like we've talked about multiple times, right?
That there's always the early adopters, right?
And what happens is the early adopters find what works and what
doesn't work. When we came out with modern testing principles, we
were part of, we were part of the entail of the early adopters.
There's always a role, I'm forgetting the name of it.
Al Shalloway actually recommended this book to me where they talk about
the names, I'm forgetting at the moment, but where the benefit is,
is by paying attention to early doctors, seeing what works and then
proactively trying to pull the lagers forward, right?
And what we are now seeing right now, I truly believe is that modern
testing principles can safely die to some degree, because anyone
else, because I think the majority of the world is actually doing it
already.
Yeah. So maybe as I think about this talk in my head, you know, when I
first talked about modern testing at Test Bash 2016, I showed the
cost of innovation curve or the innovation curve from crossing the
chasm, which shows that kind of showed that modern testing isn't all
the way out of the front.
It's kind of on the front, but maybe what we're talking about with
modern testing has shifted back and there will always be leg rates.
I'm not going to pull them along.
Some people are going to stay in their test last information provider
world forever, and I'm not going to worry about them anymore.
I'm again, I'm far enough removed.
I don't worry about those bubbles anymore.
I forget that they're there and tell people with their claws dug in
deeply and feet planted in that world.
Tell me they're never leaving, but it's fine.
But maybe what I could talk about is that curve and how it's moved.
And then maybe even the updated principles we talked about, which are not
as a tester, but as a team member on an agile or a software delivery team.
Like we went over in the podcast about four episodes.
Yeah, what I'm what I'm actually thinking through is in this might actually
be a consequence of COVID it I'm thinking through is it a consequence of COVID
is a consequence to like when we started down this path, you and I that
eventually led to modern testing principles.
Like there was, there was you and I had a lot of commonalities.
We could, we could sort of share individual division culture.
We were both still within Microsoft, right?
You actually set up community meetings.
And so you could see sort of the common patterns throughout the company
and then kind of get a sense of what where the industry is going.
Now, as part of COVID, I'm not not only am I not really doing that
across the board throughout the company, definitely not doing that cross company.
And so what I find myself right now is if our let's say you're in our role
is to sort of lead people to the next best thing, right?
But without being early adopters ourselves, like what I'm trying to think through is
who are the early adopters of the next best thing today?
Like I'm arguing, I'm arguing post-partum testing is already
occurring in this world right now, just you and I aren't aware of it.
Yeah, and that's maybe something to talk about, too.
We're we're yeah, out of the loop there.
But I get it. And software is evolving and people are doing great things all the time.
It's been something to explore in 2022 in our podcast.
It's been a lot we've talked about and things varied from it, explaining bits of it,
which we can still do.
But the practitioner side, well, on one hand, it's far away,
but it's still a lot of what I mean, I have people on my team who are
modern testing evangelists.
Just a couple of making sure we're doing things the right way as far as quality goes.
But just a few for a fairly large organization.
So think about.
But I think that should set us up well for, you know,
what we want to talk about in 2022.
I don't know what that is.
I am going to actually see if I can put together a title, an abstract
and if maybe a little idea of what this talk is about and post it for feedback
in our Slack group. So so, hey, another reason to join.
If you want to help me figure out what this is.
Postmodern. No, I I'm actually I may spend some time over the holiday
thinking through this because I every single time, like I said,
I'm absolutely convinced the early doctors are out there and are publishing.
They're just they're they're small and their voice is small.
Yeah. Yeah.
I agree to where we can find them.
Well, look for maybe I can find them.
I won't. I probably won't find them at this webinar, but we'll give it a shot.
But we'll look for them.
All right. We should get going.
But this has been fun.
Not our novel prediction episode.
Nothing too wild, but good to talk a little bit about the past,
a little bit about the future, a little bit about covid.
Sounds like a good Friday afternoon or Monday morning when this podcast comes out.
Yep. All right, everyone.
He's Brad. I am.
We'll see you later. Bye.
Happy holidays, everyone.