Welcome to AB testing podcast your modern testing podcast your hosts Alan and Brent will be here to guide you through
Topics on testing leadership agile and anything else that comes to mind now on with the show
Hello everyone and welcome to another morning edition of the AB testing podcast
Yeah, how about that for or like getting back to the old days?
Yeah, I had a conflict this afternoon with which has been our new time for the last several months or so, but as
Some of you longtime listeners may recall by the way
I'm Alan he's Brent and he's the one whose microphone still is picking up his no sounds and
We'll figure out what to do there, but we are recording in the morning now
You listen to this whenever you want to it could be the midnight show, but we're recording in the morning
So what that means is I haven't finished my second cup of coffee yet
Brent probably has he looks like he's been up. He has his
McDonald's coffee the big one
the cafe
How you doing, man? How I think our listeners want to know most of all
How did that second shot and the aftermath go?
I'm pleased to report. I think I was one of the lucky few
That literally got nothing
That's fantastic. I'm hoping I'm one of those two
Yeah, I have I have blocked off my schedule for the following day just in case
Yeah, I
both times for the shot I
Went in for it in the afternoon and took the rest of the day off went straight home and I'd scheduled it on Friday
just in case
The only thing I could say every so I
Physiologically react negatively to strong
Pressure changes in the environment. So this last weekend it went from like super sunny to really crappy
so on
Monday, I was
feeling like complete
crap
But that's close to three days after the shot and there was a huge pressure change. So I'm
I'm far more likely to attribute it to to that aspect of my bad genetics than to the shot
Cool enough. Cool enough. Well, I'm glad to hear that. I don't know if I have much else
To share tonight. I mentioned last time that I'm I did I will be giving an AMA
Oh, this will go good into our some of our topics today, but I'm giving an AMA ask me anything
For those who don't like it when I speak in acronyms
The future of test automation, it should be a lot of fun
Yeah
Because I of course I have I have a different view of the future than a lot of folks do
it's
It's interesting because to my perception you've actually done that talk
I don't know feels like three or four times in the I've done a future of testing and you know pretty
Predicting things is hard, especially about the future
I think this is just a chance they know
That given this topic in my opinions people and given
the
How many people I've pissed off on the internet?
About my opinions that this will bring I think this is to bring in lots of questions and viewers
So we'll see it might might be might be just the three our three listeners there in the AMA
Saying yeah, you're right. Now you go. This is boring, but we'll find out anyway
That's the only upcoming a thing. I have coming up. There's another conference
this summer
Someone just asked me over LinkedIn and and in this day of these days of pandemic and everyone's at home
I'm saying yes to a lot more of these than I
Probably would if we were in a different global situation, but I'm doing another one this summer
I'll talk more about that when we get closer
Nice. Okay. All right, man. You want to get into our
Our A B testing podcast topics. Sure. Yes. And by the way, this is episode 141
Counting down to 150. Should we do something special for 150 when we get there? Sure. Okay. Yeah, that's
Up to our three listeners if you would like to want maybe to segue into our first topic
We have a slacker group one of the three dot slack calm
You go to modern testing org and find a sign up link
where you can join our slack and drop in and ask us questions or
Ask questions to the the other two listeners who are there this week
We had someone drop into the slack and ask us some questions about some of our stances which we can get into or not
I'll leave that up to bread. The thing I want to call out is
We welcome everybody if you're listening to this podcast and you think we are crazy
Create maybe crazy. It's not the right word. If you think we are our ideas are
invalid or if you think
That we're just dumb old guys who don't know anything. You're partially right all questions are welcome
You don't have to just come in and be a be a fan. You can come in and challenge us. We like it
we
Stand by the fact that we're we believe that we aren't inventing anything new that was never our intent
But that we are just trying to identify
And explain what's already happening happening happening happening in many parts of the industry
So those are the discussions we have and if you don't get it
Or if you don't get how it works
Or if you don't get how it works for you or again, if you think that you need to explain to us
Where we're right and where we're wrong all that's cool and welcome. The community is there
For the open
Objective
Conversation on these on this front like in in my view and I'm fairly certain
Alan shares this view
There's a lot of places in what we talk about where
Honestly, we kind of know we're right
Science backs it up a good portion of it experience backs up the rest
But it is context sensitive
The we want that conversation
To be happening within the test community. That is the absolute
Even if we're wrong in your context
We think the single most important thing is
to
Get the conversation going it one of the things that a term that I don't
It was a term that I'm fighting against this sort of intellectual laziness within the test community this prevailing belief that
It ain't broke. But Brent we're the only ones with critical thinking
Yeah
Walk that talk buddy. Yeah, I don't think we can make that statement because and I forget
Because we're we're we're lacking serious study and something I forget. Yeah
social sciences
Yeah, oh
Can we um, maybe one topic not on the list of yours?
Can we do one thing I wanted to talk to you about that isn't on our list? I'm gonna do it
Actually, I'll do it now cuz I already brought it up along those lines something
This wasn't in that now moving on from the one of the three you can discuss this more with me explain it to me
You're welcome to come to our slack community talk to me there or just message me on Twitter
So you've heard us rant about checking versus testing how we don't really care. There's another
Pair a false dichotomy coming around that I'm seeing more and more in tweets and articles
This is an idea of shallow versus deep testing
Okay
It's from the look on your face and the sound of your voice you haven't seen this argument before no
It goes back to my developer mindset thing
Which a lot of people versus a tester mindset versus BS which a lot of people disagree with my stance on that and that's fun
I I call it like I see it and if I see it differently from you, that's a discussion we can have
I'm not trying to prescribe anything just trying to describe what I see so the shallow versus deep
The idea is yeah sure developers contest think Oh compromise
But they can only do shallow testing because they don't care about deep testing and you need to do deep testing to have high quality
That's the statement
What's the evidence of that?
Study of the social sciences and
Sure because the study of the social sciences is going to address the question or rather around whether
Software products are better with or without deep testing. I would like to understand that
Well deep touch Brent we could do devil's advocate on this and I yeah, maybe there's a whole
Modern versus we still have to do a rehash of a modern versus traditional on some of these topics
but the argument is that
deep testing
Defends the customer against risk or those are words
I made up not not the actual words
But deep testing is where we find the issues that that impact the customer all these edge cases and things like that
Part of me when I when I hear this around shallow versus deep
Right part of me feels like it's code words for the checking versus testing conversation. Well, it's not I mean
It's a different it's a different conversation
But my arg I don't want to go deeply into this but it's often described as shallow versus deep and I think
There is no dichotomy there
You do deep enough testing for the context of the software that you're shipping if I'm shipping 50 times a day
I'm my deep testing is
my analytics and monitoring
The dichotomy of shallow versus deep I think it's
Constructing and a needless argument
Its purpose to me it feels is to sort of create a
Foundation for an argument
or a debate
That's that is
So purpose is to say only test can do it right? So if if you agree to that point
Then to me, it's a debate argument. It's not really much to do with with
technicality because
the reality is
You should test
Exactly the amount of things that you should test
And it doesn't actually it in my in my experience. It doesn't actually split around deep versus shallow
right it more
splits around
customers
Customers need customers value that doesn't mean you should be intellectually lazy when you go through it. Obviously
Deep versus shallow is something
that you should
Think about but when I think about deep I
tend to think of it more along the lines of
Systems thinking type of things that we've been talking about before
You gotta know how the dots are connected together and and how it may
Have those integration points. Yeah, maybe again
Have to let the context dictate the depth of your testing
I think there's an argument that all and
Well, it's not stated correctly. So someone will correct me and say that's not what they're saying
I will say that there's an assumption that I've read about it and maybe you're right
I think it's there as a point of controversy and to justify
kicking your heels in and saying the way we've always done it is the way we are and
one way I've described it recently is
If you want to compare
Proponents of people in checking versus testing and shallow versus deep versus what Brent and I I think our intent is the same
We want to help testers cope with the changes going on around them
Our approach is to help people navigate the change and be successful in flowing forward with the change
Whereas I feel like a lot of these
Discussions around deep versus shallow and checking versus testing and tester mindset, etc. Are a lot about
helping testers
Continue to justify the need not to change while the world changes around them. Yeah the
Completely agree the one thing I was thinking of piggybacking and I don't know if this is something that you find interesting to
think about
how
might
the modern testing principles
In your view Alan be used for evil
Let's imagine. Let's imagine some some
executive
Happens upon it and says oh my god
These guys are completely
Justifying me doing this and the this is bad
Like what's your thought? I I love that question, especially since
You know some of the crowd likes to blame the challenges in testing on
Management and executive management. So let's go ahead and assume that all managers don't know what they're doing
I think very easily you look at number seven and go. Okay, let's get rid of our test team
We look at number six and we use that to collect a whole crap ton of data
We don't know what to do with this not strategically planned
That's what says we use data extensively
So you have a so you now you have no testers and a crap ton of data
With no one who knows how to look at it
And even if they did they would go this is crap data in believing the customer is the only one capable judge quality
I'm working backward that is you don't do any testing. You don't ask your developers to do testing
You just ship stuff trade out to customers
No matter what regardless of the context and you hope that this massive dump of data that no one knows how to look at
Will help you solve your quality problems
So how's that for a start? Yes so far though the path you're going
If a company I don't think a company would do that strategy for too long because I think that that company would fail
Oh, of course they would they would massively fail. So you know, so you're asking like
How could an executive use what we're proposing?
To do evil but still succeed. Oh, I don't I don't know. I don't I I don't see a way to do evil without success here
You could you can be dumb and implement them and egg and this is the my last statements
We're all about the continuous barrage of straw man's that come up in the world and especially software development
Agile doesn't work because I tried it. I did a really poor job and it didn't work
X does it work for anyone because we tried it and used everything did everything wrong about didn't work
You could you could straw man through you can find straw man arguments against all these but there's no
As far as I can tell unless you are thinking it's something I can't I don't know how you use these force
For evil and success at the same time you can be dumb and dumb can be evil, but you can't I
Don't see a way to use these and be evil. Am I missing something? No, I was I
I struggle with that as well. Right? It's it's the like the the one argument I've seen
waged against us on this one is
essentially
an executive could use it to justify the removal of their test departments
it sort of the
Sort of we're feeding the automation argument, right? We're encouraging the industry to kill this
Discipline, but that falls into the dumb and not evil though, right?
Well, it depends it depends right it depends on where you stand
right if you're if if if you view testing
or being a tester as
As essentially you're a member of an important craft
Towards the software development lifecycle like you and I both were in in in
strong in testing back in the day, we both
had many arguments around
Defensive I would argue defensive arguments around the importance of our role, right? We were always kind of defending
the the value of
of tests through a variety of means like actually back in the day
You when you were running the big
The big tlt meeting, uh, it was a test leadership team test leaders and execs from around the company
right definition overdub
Alan Alan played a a
central role
in sort of
Evaluating salary equivalency between tests and in development as an example. Yeah, we had
a lot of
Yeah, a lot of emphasis was put on
protecting and value and valuing test as a discipline across the company and this is
You know, there was a time microsoft had just short or just just right around 10,000
dedicated testing specialists
right
and even as we we made
We we gained wins
Around sort of salary equivalency like the the defensiveness of the arguments that we would make defending how important we were
In my view, maybe your experience was different never really stopped
Right, and that was because part of part of it
It's still i've made a statement before like the number one
value proposition of a test team
from those not within the test team and again defined by actions not by verbiage is uh
Where the organization scapegoat when when shit goes out the door
So I think part of what modern testing is trying to do is say hey
Look, there's a these are a set of people with with very strong critical thinking skills
And they can bring way more value
Than just simply the team to blame when when the sky falls
and a lot of the activities that that
We see that that we're honestly very important in
In the world where with on-prem products or shrink wrap products
And that world is not yet dead
There are lots of products going out the door that aren't aren't updated or shipped
via
via the cloud or or you know app updates
But in the service world, there are are better techniques and and again
pivoting off of accelerate
Which is one of my favorite content sources, but you combine ryan
Of everyone i've spoken to and i'm not aware of any formal study on this but literally a hundred percent of those folks
who who claim
agile doesn't work
It doesn't take much to realize that
that team
Never got to a point where agile was adaptive
Adaptive right right. It was still iterative. So they never
They never actually got to yeah, of course, of course, and I think
Rewind the stack here a little bit a lot of the arguments against what we're doing
are
Based on I just don't get what you're talking about. We don't do it that way or
But the arguments are based on just
That hasn't worked for me. I haven't tried that even I do want to
Rewind that stack so shallow versus deep and the whole
Set of tangents they're worth talking about but that makes me in real time because we are an adaptive
Not predictive podcast
I'm gonna change the order because I think that makes me want to go into
You're talking about traditional testing
Let's talk about this link
You sent me and why you sent it to me and the point you want to make there because I think it's I think it's
Relevant most relevant to this conversation we're having right now. And while brent if i'll if i'm a good
Podcast editor i'll put the link in the show notes, but you know how good I am at that
but brent sent me this thing of
Well, actually why don't you describe what the web page is?
And the point you want to talk about yeah
so
There is a company called own net online
And I sent this to alan late last night. So I will
Admit that there is
A good deal of research on on this
That I have not
done
um
so
listeners should definitely not walk away with
Uh, at least brent's opinion is that this is hardcore facts. Okay. I don't know who this company is. I don't know
who funds them
however
They do seem to be
Tracking summaries around various occupations and there is a thing
Uh
Down below and for those who wish to
Follow along ideally not drive me add some missing context
So brent described what onet online is and what we're looking at the page. He specifically sent me
Was a summary report for software quality assurance analysts and testers. That's a mouthful for testers
Right, so we're talking about it
So it has like the typical tasks they do the skills they require what knowledge they need etc, etc
So the thing now brent is scrolling to the bottom or talks a little bit about where uh
Where jobs are going, right?
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah, so it's very interesting in terms of
Like the activities and the sort of things that they talk about right. I look at skills and tasks
Right the tasks very much align with sort of
You know the old what we call traditional testing, but you look at skills. You can definitely see
uh, there is a lot of
Technology that is viewed as important to this like I if you look at the technology skills, they have a thing
They have a little fire symbol that flags hot technology
the technological
requirement
technological requirement
And you look at it and you go, okay
There are a lot of things here that are a little bit more technical than say what we what we see in the traditional test roll
right, um
Although it does humor me because cobalt is listed in in uh
software
Don't quite understand that connection but at the very bottom
it talks about
They they're doing some sort of predictive analysis
And they have projected growth from 2019
to 2029
and it says
much faster than average eight percent or higher
so they are
absolutely
Uh, this site is absolutely predicting. Uh
a growth
in this
space
Now, uh, one of the things I wanted to talk to to alan about is okay
What's that mean alan? What do you think like are we are we?
Are are we on the side of of wrong here is all of the the uh,
Mtp
opponents
correct in their thinking that
that essentially our bubble is
It is basically just in uh unity and microsoft in seattle
Well, you know, it's at many more companies than that. So that's that that's that's that's a
Real straw man. So I think you could look at that and go that eight percent is based on one point
Projected 1.5 million current people in software testing and a growth of whatever eight percent of that is
So yeah, you could say oh there's lots of growth here testing testing is not dead
So you could say that and of course that data is in a nutshell. Uh
I went to look at the reason i'm pausing here
Is I went to look at software developers to compare is testing growing?
As fast more or less quickly than software development and now i'm questioning the data on this site
Because their numbers for software developers are exactly the same as they are for software quality assurance and testers
So there's some weird rounding and bucketing. I I now have questions about the data entirely
Well, okay, so yeah, maybe
But but overall let's assume these numbers are correct. Uh, it's fine. I think
If we look at that cost of innovation curve that we've the
Bell curve of where people are on moving towards things that sound like what we're talking about with modern testing
We there's a growing number of people
Adopting things that are like modern testing whether they know the name of it or not teams are
It's really just agile and lean and we're thinking more about again modern testing isn't that modern. It's not about testing
It's the reaction to our reaction to what we call traditional testing where testing is done often by a siloed test team
or even by a
air quote agile team where a tester is
Where a dedicated tester does all of the testing for that team?
We're talking about how teams move to being able to ship
multiple times a day and
Base their changes on customer feedback
And use data in order to make sure that the customer is always first in how
Crap is getting done
so
The fact that a chunk of the industry is still going to live in the world
They've lived in for the last 20 years i'm not surprised at all
Uh, but of course predicting things is hard, especially about the future
I definitely see more and more teams, especially as more and more software moves to the cloud
Doing things more like modern testing and needing
Not zero necessarily but fewer testers going forward again. It's a data. It's a
One piece of data amidst a system of changes. So it's hard to tell what it really means but actually
Yeah, I dove in deeper because I noticed when you went to dev which was a very interesting idea
Like when you went to dev at the very bottom of it it it warns that data collection is underway
But then I started thinking through and going for example, I just looked at program manager and they don't have that listed
Now i'm actually thinking they they might actually be combining
Devops roles
Because there's no position for that as well. Well devops is a culture not a role
it's
From the context of this database. It's both alan
Yeah, and i'll give you another interesting thing because they they need to find the right equivalence classes or find a way for us to group those
Because if I look under computer programmer
The trend there is well one
It's wrong because the the median wages are completely wrong
But they say the trend there because I think because nobody's using that title anymore
Here's the challenge. I think that title's going away because that one's declining by 1 percent and they say there's only
214,000 of those employed
That might actually I mean that last fact might actually be true
Like I I haven't met anyone that went by that title. Yeah, so what I think here is there's there's something here
But that you need to actually apply some data analysis to all the data here to tell a story
That's my take
So sure someone could take this and I have a book usually on my desk. It's on the floor. So I could go grab a called
How to lie with statistics and i'm sure I could find some quotes to use from that with this data
But i'm not
so
Let's uh drop this and move on to a mailbag question. I found the mailbag
Wave file by the way, so we're saved. I don't have to make a
I've been purposely making bad ones to force myself to
Find the original slightly better one slightly less bad. So we'll use that this time
But
The question essentially is if you want to ask a mailbag question, by the way, you can ping me on twitter you can
You can send me an email the easiest way is to
Go to one of the three dot slack.com and ask a mailbag question
Or you can ask a question and you just tag it with the mailbag emoji
And it'll show up in our mailbag channel and we'll remember to talk about it
Ringo
aka, richard starkie asks
Could you discuss in the next episode on what to automate?
How to coach devs and testers on defining criteria on which tests to automate and we all know the answer
That's what we're going to answer and the answer is obvious
You should automate
All of the tests that should be automated
and
Not one more or one less. That's exactly it. So we're done with that. So the next topic
We should probably go a little bit deeper because that's the challenge
That's the challenge in test designers is of course figuring out which of those tests are to be automated
If you are in the oh my god, I love selenium. It's my life camp
Your tests to automate are everything I can possibly do in the web ui of my application
Which uh probably isn't right?
This goes back to and i'm going to get up on a soapbox
And I don't think it's this one people won't argue with
the manual versus automated and
Teams that have separate automation teams and one one thing worse than having a separate isolated dedicated test team
Is to have a dedicated test team that split into manual testers and automated testers
recipe for disaster
I think when you think about how you're going to test something you need to think about it holistically
And then you automate the tests that would be too difficult
Or too time consuming to conduct with your own hands
In fact, I can't even use the word manual anymore because someone will jump down my throat telling me
It's not manual programming. So I call it manual testing
Uh, because I because I use the words that are commonly known across a million people in the industry. That's why wait wait
But it is manual programming
It of course it is but we don't use that label. So anyway testing
Uh, and really it goes back to the original problem. I said is that
testing is testing
Wow, that's even more of a tautology than you should automate all of the tests that should be automated
But it's true testing is testing and we're going to use the computer to help us do some of the hard parts
So we're going to do this real time
Give me a feature brant
This has not been pre-planned. He's going to really make it hard for me go on
Feature like give me something something you want me to test
uh
calculator
Oh, that's a lot of stuff in there. So do I have
Maybe the first thing I do so say i'm a tester at a company and say we're making a calculate yet another calculator app
How are you going to test it?
There's a whole bunch of stuff. I want to know I want to know
If it's accurate
I want to know if it has different modes they have to display. Let's just say it's a plain
Standard calculator with no extra modes for right now. We can add those later. So I want to know if it's accurate
I'm probably not going to do a bunch of accuracy tests through the ui. In fact, there's very little I want to automate through the ui
On this but i'm going to assume it has a model where I can pass numbers to it do the calculation compare it to an oracle
this is a case where
The test may duplicate
The actual code so maybe i'm going to sit down with the programmer if i'm not the programmer of it and look through it and see
Is my idea for an automated test just re-implementing the code?
Which i'll have to tell a story about the time I had working on uh, I tested gdi the graphics device interface
And and user interface which was all the user interface elements on windows 98
Lots of automated tests and some little bit a little bit of exploratory testing that I won't go into right now
But uh had a late night discussion with a programmer and maybe I don't know a couple people
in the org on whether
Whether or not we could use get pixel to test
Set pixel set pixel would set the color of a pixel on the screen and get pixel retrieve that color
absolutely not alan because
Well, well what happened in that discussion was
We dug into it. I was like, okay, what I can do
Is I can go query the memory of the device of the graphics device driver get that same bit of information
Pull that out and then compare that to the result of get pixel
And do the same thing on set pixel
Well set pixel and to use it i'll go query that memory on the graphics driver and see what it's pointing at which was
100 duplicating the work that get pixel and set pixel did
So the answer so the question is can you use get pixel to test set pixel? The answer is of course who cares?
Because if the pixels on your screen are wrong, everybody in the world is going to notice i'm not going to write any tests there
Rewinding that back to the calculator. Yeah. No and the other one is it's like
on this one
like i've had these discussions in the past and the the thing is is
Is you don't know how it's implemented it could call right? Is it the the reason why you wouldn't use?
Get pixel to test set pixel or whichever one that you just mentioned
is
Because assumption could be applied
To both sides and there was a preference to view it as a black box, right and to me
The the answer is
Okay, let's just go look at how it's implemented
I think more often than not it's going to be some stupid property
That that isn't manipulated within the class. It's just a set and get part of the answer to
Automating all the tests that should be automated is to understand
How the feature is implemented?
There's some investigation work to do there to figure out how i'm going to test to make sure calculations are correct
one way to do it is
Something that the excel team used to do a long time ago is they had some
custom hand crafted assembly that that
did all the calculations in
excel
What they did on the debug version of that there's one way to do testing is to don't do testing just have a debug version that
Checks the crap out of stuff the debug version had a much easier to read c if you can imagine c being easier to read
But a much easier to read c version of all of those calculations that ran in parallel
And if those two calculation engines ever disagreed you hit an assert
One thing maybe not done enough as I think about it
Is testing on debug versions that have massive amounts of diagnostics in place. Let me even back up that
observability
Maybe I don't want to write tests because I have a way to turn on some diagnostics and see the state of the calculator
And see what's going on see if anything's corrupted its memory, etc, etc
All those things go into consideration when i'm figuring out what to automate
so let's say
Calculation is fine. I probably want to test that
Two plus two great three divided by one. Oh, I know i'll divide by zero
You did you can check all those things quickly manually and they're probably never going to break again
but
One thing where I maybe would do automation finally in here, of course in addition to just I would probably write a series of
Common like a sanity check like a unit test that ran against the model super fast that ram
A thousand different calculations made sure they work that would make sure I didn't break anything as i'm iterating on this
But also I want to know if and where I may even use a ui test
Is not to automate that two plus two, but what happens if I have that calculator?
Oh, say i'm doing my taxes or some extensive calculation and I have it open for hours and hours doing calculation after calculation
That may be something I may brute force automate i'm not looking for results because I I trust the engine i'm looking for
After I do thousands of operations, maybe even I might write a smart monkey
That's what i'm getting at to see if I could get the calculator in a state where
Again using diagnostics as my oracle not using a result of the calculation
Can I see if the calculator gets in a state where it is either?
Some of the internal diagnostics are incorrect or maybe just monitoring memory usage
Right now. I was actually I was actually thinking, you know memory leaks
Is this implemented like do we see that as we keep adding operations?
It did the dev essentially implemented as every time you add a new operation
It remembers the whole history and the way it produces the results is it recalculates the whole thing every time
So yeah, so as you kept on adding operations, right?
You need to perform it slow down
But here's actually something I think is really important that you didn't address in this particular example
Pinned that for one second because I realized I went way into solution mode, but my answer to that question on what to automate is
Take time up front to think about all of the testing you want to do
Or all the testing that could be done and think about the most optimum way to do that and some of that is automated
The ui maybe some is automated at a lower level and some you decide not to automate
But that's that's really my that's the short version of that whole answer
But what's something we're still going back into solution mode?
You're saying and you're probably right in this brainstorming of what sorts of things I could test or write automated tests for
I missed something big. So what is that?
Well, um, well, I don't know that I said that you
Did something big i'm trying to put words in your mouth and add drama to our podcast right play along
Sorry next time on yeah, you'll never believe what happens next
In the example test the calculator
Right you went into a place where?
All right. What i'm trying to do is test the calculations
But nowadays if I ask you alan to implement a calculator
What would you do?
like would you actually
If you were to go and implement a calculator to me with all the libraries we have now
GitHub and find someone's to fork
That npm install calculator, right? It's that's
That's true
But if you were to build a new calculator today
More than likely all that work is is ui
Uh connecting to well known
Well tested well established
Libraries like you wouldn't even write the library. You're the one who gave me this example. No, I know
uh, but I did it kind of purposefully because in this case the the
You really don't need to test. Uh a good deal of the
underlying library except for maybe a handful of regression tests to be used for acceptance like because
For example, I deal with python and python libraries update all of the damn time
So, how do you make sure that it's righteous to integrate the the library update into your project?
It's so by the way, I gotta mention it's so cool to hear
About someone at microsoft using a programming language invented in this century. That's great
Yeah, thanks for that I don't
I mean, I don't know that
Actually every language i've used since my career here c was in bit. Oh this century, I guess. Yeah. Okay. Got it
um
But here is the thing I think that is
Is valuable around automation because we also you kind of
You kind of didn't talk about the cicb aspect of this
for me
a decision to
automate
Is essentially how repetitive is this work?
And that's it if it's not repetitive don't automate it if if if it's not going to be part of your
Check-in suite or necessary for cicd. Don't automate it
The other thing I I think is great to automate which doesn't lend itself to this calculator example unless it has some sort of way to pass it
a file of calculations is
I automate a lot of data generation
repetitive
Right because it's repetitive and and also you can randomize it. I love the idea of
Data-driven tests where maybe am I maybe it's a a messaging app
I want to see how many contacts it can handle I would bet that somewhere there's a tester
I noticed I didn't say manual tester, but a tester who
Would by hand careful with my words create
10 000 contacts to see if it would it would wreck the app but something like that again repetitive
I would write an engine to create me
You know using the big list of naughty strings all kinds of fun, which is a cool project
You should look up if you haven't on github
All kinds of cool inputs for everything
For everything that now I I literally in my career have done that test case
Yeah, yeah
Those are great things to automate that if you I don't know if you recall. Do you remember what my very first project was?
Oh is the answer. I don't know the answer and and
It's the only one of these things that I have still kept
Oh my god
Brandt is showing a copy of schedule plus for windows 95
Which was the cali which was the original calendar app from microsoft right calendar and contacts
and um
And we used to have a thing that every every time you ship something you
Everyone it it was even a verb for a long time even after we moved to exchange calorim
People would say could you sked plus me?
uh
It's much rarer now
uh, but people hope
but people still
Still actually say can you s plus me but it's significantly rarer now. Um
I and I forgot about that verb until you showed me
Uh, so you showed me that box. Yeah, so that was that was my first product of I've I've
I've gotten rid of all of the other shrink graft products that that i've gotten over the years
But that was the first one I kept it to me
What you test
The the traditional aspect of of testing
Right. It's around risk control and as a result
Uh, there's an uncertain amount of value back to the business with this work and it definitely is
An ever increasing cost to the business. So I think like allen's
Totology is actually quite
Wise it is essentially you should
Automate what you should automate, but the way I would suggest driving that
Is essentially automate those cases where they're over the lifetime of the product you're expecting a high return
Right. You do not want a developer or or any human being that have to go through
Uh manually say a
an hour long
Integration test for sure for sure
If it's valuable, then you should automate it, right?
Yes, the point I want to get to and now I want to close this and do our last topic and then close out today is
I think a lot of folks just approach the the automation process wrong. They go. What can I automate?
Which is the wrong thing wrong way to start that it's
What is the testing we need to do for this product?
period
And it's it's highly contextual and then once you brainstorm that testing you should look at that
Okay
These are the things of the overall testing need to be automated and very likely in many cases could be all of it
But at least you thought through it in some cases. It may not be all of it. That's okay, too
but
There is a problem I see in a lot of testing
especially again from these test automation engineers who they focus purely on i'm gonna automate everything I can figure out how to automate
instead of thinking about
What's the best way for us to test this what actually or
like I said before
What needs to be tested in order for us to reduce the amount of risk we need to in order to get this thing out to
Customers I was just about to push back on that right because we don't the goal isn't to test something
The goal is to reduce
Business slash customer risk, right? The goal the goal is never testing
And yeah, and that gets lost, right?
And and we didn't talk about it this time
Unless we can get to the other one, but again, I remain a huge proponent particularly in in today's environment
around
leveraging the data and
Optimizing, you know flight control rings of exposure
And and doing a react in services. There's all kinds of safe deployment techniques
You can use to reduce risk because again, that's the goal not testing
one last thing I want to mention so we can close on time here because I have a hard hard stop in like a minute and a half is
Modern test con or as it's been suggested. We call it test of this
I think we should do this. I don't know how to host a conference and
But we've had a number of requests for we talked in the past about having like a test bash seattle
But I think we're still and and do a follow-up day, which still may happen someday
But I think we're all still working virtually for a while
Maybe we can start brainstorming this on our slack channel. I think we could get
Several of the three there
We could get several of the three. I'm not even sure what it would look like how we do if it would even be
I don't know
I
It's worth thinking about i'm not sold on it. I don't want to do it just as a
Oh, look at us. We have a conference. I want to actually provide some value to the overall testing community
I do too and and honestly and I struggle with the same thing right with with test bash
uh and
online test conference
Right my perception with those two, you know, there's a good deal of modern testing
There are most conferences
These days there's some one member of the three seems to show up talking about something
Modern testing ish if not modern testing directly
So that may be the better avenue, but i'm just wondering if there's a one day
Uh thing
I don't know yet, but I love to brainstorm that more
So if you're not in our slack community, you have some ideas, please join in or you can tweet me or whatever
But something for us to think about no plans, but I want to plant the seed and see if it grows
Yeah, it'd be if
if if there's if the three have great suggestions on what sort of is the
Distinct value prop i'd love to hear it. Yeah, we'll get that going. All right
Uh, this was fun
Thanks for getting up early. It sounds like you've been up for a while, but uh, good job
I did finish my second cup of coffee during this podcast. That's a good thing also. Yeah mine's halfway
I still have halfway to go. All right, probably might need to go put that in the microwave for a minute
It might be a little cold by now
Okay, everybody. I am still the a in ab testing
And I am not and brent's a big old b
See you everyone
Bye