Welcome to AB Testing Podcast, your modern testing podcast.
Your hosts, Alan and Brent, will be here to guide you through topics on testing, leadership,
agile, and anything else that comes to mind.
Now, on with the show.
Hey everybody, welcome to the AB Testing Podcast.
I'm Alan.
I'm Brent.
And it is a beautiful sunny Friday afternoon here in the Pacific Northwest.
Push an 80 today, I think, right?
Oh, shit.
That's Fahrenheit.
Yeah, I know.
It's, it's, uh, I've been having trouble sleeping lately because my, it's been too hot in the
bedroom.
Title of your sex tape.
Uh, yeah, it's completely, uh, yeah.
Dog and I took a hike to poo poo point yesterday.
Um, what?
Poo poo point.
I'm not familiar with it.
Is this some place in your neck of the woods?
It is.
Uh, if you ever driven by Issaquah or the Kwa, as the kids call it, you ever see the, uh,
the parachuters floating around?
No.
South of I-90.
There's a hill they just, they just run and jump off of.
Oh, really?
Yeah.
So it's pretty cool.
Good little hike.
That's, that's why it's called poo poo point.
No, I know.
And then I don't know if you saw, there was someone during the pandemic, someone bicycle
for the fun of it.
They decided they were going to bicycle from poo poo point in Issaquah to PP Creek in like
Iowa.
Just cause they thought it was funny.
I I, I, uh, I appreciate that humor.
Yeah, but it was good.
So on one side is they take off and you can see the lake and all the way toward it.
And then just, you kind of cut down.
There's another clearing on the other side where you can see all the way to Mount Rainier.
So that's pretty cool.
But anyway, we did that.
Yeah.
Anything else big and cool going on in your world?
I, uh, as of last week, I am a proud dad of a graduated, um, student.
My eldest is, is done with his bachelor's.
He, he double majored in psychology as well as creative writing, uh, forced him to take
the bachelor of science version of psychology.
So it was heavily math driven by the way.
Yeah.
Have your kids, your kids gone up to college yet?
Uh, my oldest is in running start.
So he's, he's basically college.
Yeah.
So one of the deals I made with, with, uh, my kids.
So we have, what's the Washington get?
What's this?
That the wacky number, that's like a five oh two eight seven program.
I don't, I don't remember where you can pre sort of buy credits for college.
Yeah.
The Washington one is kind of weird and sucky.
We actually invest ours in New York's program, but you can use the money anywhere.
Oh, I I'm, I've been very happy with the Washington one, but I honestly didn't, I
haven't done much of a cross compare to determine if my decision was something I should regret.
Anyway, one of the things I've told, told both of my boys that are in college is essentially
I have the money put away to pay for your degree, but there's a condition.
You can pick any major you want, any major you want, but it has to be a bachelor of science.
Okay.
I'm out of your family.
I have, I have bachelor of, I know my master's is, is masters in music, but as my bachelor,
it's a bachelor of arts and music education.
Yep.
And a bachelor and a bachelor of music and music composition.
I double majored as well.
My son started off, he got applied, he got into the psych program.
He's done exceptionally well there, but he has a real passion for, for, for creative writing.
And one day he called me up.
He's like, dad, I'm just telling you, transparently, I found a loophole in your strategy and I've
already executed on it.
And I said, okay, what's this loophole?
He's like, you said, you said I have to graduate with a BS.
And I'm like, yeah, that's right.
He's like, okay, well I'm double majoring in my creative writing degree is going to be
a BA.
And I said, son, good for you.
Like, like,
Very cool.
I am always big fan of people getting a degree in the humanities.
Good for him.
Well, he's winning.
He got, he got two degrees in the humanities.
I do think psychology counts, even though it is a BS.
The thing I, I was trying to balance him out with and he's, he generally tends towards
the humanities, but I wanted to balance them out with because there's a large degree of
humanity majors.
In my view, you can't really make a living with.
Well, and again, if you want me on that soapbox, you don't go to a university as a vocational
school.
If you want to go to school to get a job, go to a vocational school, go to a university
to learn critical thinking and how to learn.
Of course, there are going to be some skills that are going to help you land a job, but
I think you are better suited and more adaptable to different kinds of work with a humanities
degree.
As long as you have the supporting other education to get, it's so hard to get a job out of
college, but I, I do not believe that a university is a vocational school.
So I do not buy this argument of what are you going to do with a creative writing degree?
And maybe, maybe he writes 75 novels.
Who knows?
Uh, who knows?
Um, and I don't want to waste the whole podcast because many things have stuff to talk about.
What are we, I'm going to edit all the things, many of the things you just said, I, I, unlike
the other topics we're going to get to many of the things you just said, I disagree with,
but okay.
Well, yeah, it just means that you're wrong.
So let's get on with the podcast and cause I'm very passionate about this and it's because
I'm right.
So anyway, uh, are you ready?
Can we go on?
Can we, can we hit topic numero uno?
Yes.
Topic numero uno.
This week I spoke at testing festival, a large online test conference and I didn't really
speak.
I spoke at it, but what I did is a couple things I want to talk to you about and share
with our listeners.
Cause it's all about modern testing.
I did two things back to back.
First thing was I gave a talk, but I gave the talk last week.
No, I gave it to my dog last week.
I recorded it.
I was going to put the link in my, the it's on YouTube and I was going to put the link
in my five for Friday, but it's still unlisted and I didn't want to undermine any plans.
The testing festival folks had for a larger unveiling of the talks.
My talk is on YouTube and I'll share it at some point, but the talk was all about principle
number, which way, uh, shoot, which one's about a quality culture?
I almost said five, but five is about customer data.
It's like four, right?
Remember when we used to have memorized?
So bad.
I shouldn't look that up.
Yeah.
I'm pretty certain that we have all of the controversial ones memorized.
We do.
We know the ones people complain about, but here's the thing, Alan, and I'll do it for
you right now.
The way you can answer this question is simply by going to modern testing.org.
Yes.
And at modern testing.org, which is the one that talks about a quality culture?
Oh, you did it.
Nice job.
Number four.
Yeah.
That's because I'm right yet again.
Uh, I gave a talk on leading a quality culture and introducing the quality culture guide.
And it's just a, just a 25 minute talk.
I gave a little bit of an intro on how it came about.
I didn't go through the whole thing.
I talked about the low level and the high level of the transition guide talked about
why I don't like maturity models.
I think it's a pretty good talk primarily because I was able to edit it a little bit
before I submitted it to take out the crummy parts.
And that worked out very well.
So that was the talk I gave.
And we had someone join our slack after that talk and say, Oh yeah, I've been, I've been
looking for a, what we always hear.
I've been looking for a name for what we've been doing and it was cool.
Uh, welcome.
Welcome to our community.
So anyway, that talk, uh, nothing new here.
It's really me going over the quality culture transition guide and with some intro to prep,
like how it came about and why I think it's important for the audience there in hindsight,
as I got to know them during the panel discussion, maybe just reminding them that quality is a
lot more than testing, which you and I get, and I think our regular listeners get, but
man, I'm never, I don't have a lack of surprise on how others forget or live in a different
world than we do.
I always wonder about the size of the bubble we live in.
Yeah.
It's interesting to do sort of checks like, so one question, I think you began the answer
to it is so they obviously you recorded it.
They obviously had some sort of, I'm guessing a scheduled time where, or somebody clicked
the button and played it back.
How was sort of feedback or interaction?
Did that happen?
So it, so good segue and you didn't plan it to be, but so the way it worked out was
I did a panel discussion with, uh, Alan Richardson, Alan number one, or Scottish Alan, depending
how you want to refer to him and, uh, dot Graham, Dorothy Graham and Paul Gerard both
facilitated and took part in the panel afterwards.
And we took some questions there and somewhere about the quality culture, but a lot were fun
because I got to disagree with the other panelists and that's always a good time for me.
Uh, well, it was fun.
Go ahead, go ahead.
Ask questions.
I'm gonna tell you all the fun I had.
Did you have, cause here's what I'm imagining.
I'm imagining you got to do an encore to the modern test manager versus traditional test
manager.
Wasn't that bad?
Like you were over the top well-rehearsed excellent.
So there was no encore.
So it wasn't like that.
Okay.
They pushed my, some of the questions just teed up things we've been talking about.
For example, there was a question around will ML replace testing?
And I got to roll my eyes, but also get on my little soapbox about how the, the new
record and playback automated testing tools have changed my mind about the value of recording
playback.
And I actually think that it's a better way to do your UI automation than actually writing
crap.
And so I got to, I got to go on that whole set.
Wait, wait, wait.
So that one, that one based off of how you said it last time, it's because of the
ML.
Absolutely.
It's not, it's not, it's yeah.
Every, every single year, some every day, someone's worried about the robots taking away their jobs.
I remember listening to the radio 10 years ago and Amazon's warehouse is going to have
some robots, which they do that automate some of their picking for shipping and people were
freaking out.
Oh, people are going to lose their jobs.
Now there's always more stuff to do.
So let's automate the boring stuff.
So that was one, but another one was, but someone brought up the whole testing as information
providers.
And I marched right up to the top of my soapbox and went off for a little bit on exactly
what you think I would go off on.
And then there was a reply and the best part was on the reply, Alan Richardson said, I
think you're digging yourself deeper into your hole, not me to them.
It was good.
Was with that group, it was a very respectful debate because those are all those people
get it.
They, they see different points of view.
They don't dig in their heels and talk about epistemology or social sciences and how I'm
wrong because I haven't studied the right books.
It was actually a respectful debate around what we see and people bending in the right
places to understand different contexts.
So it was actually really cool, but I got to dissent and bring in my new view or my our
view of modern testing within that panel discussion, which was a ton of fun.
I am looking forward to that.
Yeah, I don't know if they, if they, hopefully they recorded that and they're going to
share that part too.
Well, you said it was up on YouTube.
No, my, my 25 minute talk is on YouTube.
I do not know if they recorded the panel discussion.
Hopefully they did.
That's where all the, that's the money.
I know.
I know one wants to hear you babble on again about the same recorded it from my end.
Like I'm just going to press record on what I could have done.
Yeah, there were, it was fun.
It was your typical questions.
And I wish I still had them in front of me, but maybe I should dig out a copy.
They're on some site somewhere and you and I can do another round of traditional
test manager versus modern test manager answering the questions.
And this time I get to play the traditional.
All right.
But I did a pretty good job being traditional.
And I can't remember who brought this up or where it came up, but I'm still
surprised how many people really, really, really hate the test automation
pyramid because it's upside down and backwards.
No.
And, and again, I brought up my point and actually, and if people don't like it,
cause I get why they don't like it.
And mostly it's because you can't always make your tests fit that model.
But again, my insight that I came up with, I'm not sure, I'm sure I'm not the
first one, but it really made sense to me when I realized the testing pyramid
reflects the number of tests you have when your application is well-designed.
Often you're writing more and more UI automation tests when your application
is designed because you have to test the logic in the UI.
Right.
It's essentially they're designing the tests for the world where you don't
need the tests in some regards.
I talked about also, I can't remember in which context, but I just brought up
monitoring a lot and customer data, which nobody looks at.
Well, I shouldn't say nobody.
There's a whole, it was just people on the other side of the bubble.
So that leads, and that'll be fun.
If there is a, like, if there is a recording of that.
Panel, I will, I will definitely share it.
You said who was on the panel, you, Dorothy Graham and Alan Richardson and Paul.
Dorothy Graham.
Yeah, it's interesting.
You should have brought up the ISTQB.
ISTQB came up.
There was a question, are certifications important?
And of course she was involved very early on in that.
And I, so I was wanting to be respectful, but everyone had their say and they, and I
wasn't going to say anything, but then Paul called on me and said, what do you
think about this?
I said, look, I have no certifications.
I think the courses behind the certifications, this is my, actually my
true feeling, but I was able to phrase it in a way that I think went over well.
I said, but the courses are not about teaching testing.
They've become a way to teach people to pass a test and get, and get people a
certification that may or not be worth anything.
And it feels like the primary outcome of the certification is not better testers.
It's about making money for ISTQB.
The value to me is not worth, not worth what you get out of it.
And Dorothy acknowledged that they turned into a moneymaking, I'll say scam here.
I wouldn't say it for out of respect.
I wouldn't say that there, but it turned, it's turned into a moneymaking scam.
Like you were, I mean, you remember when I asked you ISTQB questions on the,
yes, they're ridiculous and they're dumb and they don't, they're just stupid.
And I'm all for testing.
And if, and if you're trying to hire some junior tester and, and you think if you
get a certification, you'll think they'll be better, that's all great.
But to charge you what they do for that is it's just ridiculous.
It's just ridiculous.
It's a total industry scam.
And
Alan.
Well, now what happened?
Yeah.
No, I was just thinking through.
Oh my God.
Uh, how do, how do I say this?
We're on air cogently.
You know, you know why we are seeing basically modern testing ghosts.
We see it growing, but we see it grow so slowly.
It's because of big test.
Big test is actually suppressing the new ideas.
I'm trying to construct a new, I hear you're looking at me like, I know, I know.
This is the dumbest thing.
People can, there's the thing we will never do a modern testing certification.
There's a great course you can take if you are a ministry of testing pro member.
So do that, but I'm never going to never going to be a certification.
It's all about just helping people navigate as their world is changing.
And more and more, when I give these talks, even if people in that other
world, their world is changing and more and more, we're finding people who have
our, their world's already changed and we'll help navigate the downside too.
The, the more we can help people be informed or prepared when the world
does, when their world does change, uh, the better I that's what I forgot
to say something.
Yeah.
We're old.
That happens all the time.
It's even better.
The next test bash home, 24 hours of test talks is coming up in June and I'm
doing an ask me anything on the future of automation.
I'm going to fuck that shit up.
I can show you the future of automation.
I am going to shake the world.
So you want to get into test automation.
Do you now?
Do you?
No, look, I look, all right.
Here's how we get.
All right.
I'm, I'm, I'm, I'm now thinking through.
Brett is now the wheels.
I can, I can smell coming through zoom.
We need, we need a test automation certification.
No, there are, we need a test automation certification.
We like a modern testing test automation certification because test
automation certifications exist and they suck.
No, no, we're going to provide one.
Okay.
And all you need to do to do this, number one, we'll create, I don't know,
create a video.
Okay.
It's like a five minute video show, showing how to download the dominant tools
and how to set it up to do click and record.
And then, then at the end of it, it's a test to, can you accurately
repeat back to, to our certification program, the, the URL where you
download the tool and if you can, you've passed the modern testing
automation certification.
All right.
No, no.
Hey, uh, I don't know.
Yeah.
I love that.
That's happening.
Let's do a quick hold the cow twice in a row.
Last time.
I don't know if you've heard, I couldn't find my original mail bag sound.
I didn't make a brand new one.
And so I had a little fun with that and I don't know if it's on my other computer.
No, I got a new Mac long story.
Anyway, got to find my mail bag sound.
It is mail bag time mail bag.
All right.
And, uh, this is from, uh, our friend global warming, Andreas warm.
Uh, he says, so BDD.
Right.
Is that anything you think about or are you more data driven needle moving?
And BDD might be something teams are using to get results, but that
doesn't really affect you.
Question mark.
So really he's saying, guys, what are your opinions on B D D?
Which is of course Brent's.
I can't think of anything clever on Brent driven development
or B a V your driven development.
So have you done BDD Brent?
Uh, I have tried doing BDD.
I, I, I find TDD easier.
The, the problem with BDD is, is the construct, right?
The given went then is, is very, it's a very clean thing, but it's not natural.
There you go.
Okay.
Let me give you a different opinion.
Cause I actually find it both valuable and dumb depending on how you use it.
And here's the deal.
BDD is excellent.
And to me, 99% of the value comes from thinking about the
behavior of your software and the outcomes you want from it before you
begin to write it or your, or your feature or whatever you're creating.
Yes.
Given.
Yeah.
And so that part super valuable.
The automation part just feeds into what I call the industry
fatuation with end to end testing.
And there are tools, of course, all the gherkin tools that you
automate all this stuff.
I don't care if you automate it.
I got the most value at a BDD when we just defined the behaviors up front and
made sure we did that as part of our requirements gathering or planning.
Planning that requirements gathering and skip the automated stuff.
Didn't care.
So we'd automate anyway, but I wouldn't worry about automating
those given to end then tests, but getting the team to agree and
elaborate on those behaviors ahead of time as part of planning.
Massively valuable.
It helped people focus on not over-developing or undeveloping.
They focused on exactly what the thing had to do, help them figure out.
It just so much alignment came from that.
If you think of BDD as essentially a breakdown, this is how I view it.
The BDD, the things that you're creating ultimately are, they're very aligned
with user stories, but on a very focused behavioral basis.
Yeah.
I agree with you.
Thinking through it is absolutely valuable.
I don't know.
To me, it, in terms of turning it into a unit test, it feels a
bit overhead ish.
Yeah.
Okay.
I mean, you for different reasons, but it doesn't turn into a unit test, turns
into some, some flavor of end to end or integration acceptance test.
And I'm all for automating acceptance tests.
I think if the, if the focus of BDD is on the behavior, so I don't like
behavior driven development, I just like, I don't care about the, well, it
is behavior driven development, even if I only think about the behavior, I don't
automate it.
It's someone decided, Oh, and we can automate this stuff too.
And people get focused on the automation and that's not where the value is.
It could help, but it's not where the value is for me.
Yeah.
In terms of both BDD or TDD, like the biggest value of that is to drive
a thoughtful process that, that forces you to number one, get, get your
tests done upfront.
Uh, number two, which is the biggest value, which is to design your classes.
Better in some regards.
I don't really care if people go with BDD or TDD.
People, if you, whatever technique you want to make sure that you think about
what little bit of ready aim fire versus ready fire aim, think a little bit
about what you're trying to accomplish before you race off to the compiler.
That's all.
Yeah.
And then in part of global global vermin's, uh, question was, is that anything
you think about or are you more data-driven and needle moving and what, how
did you interpret the or cause to me it's both.
Yeah.
I, I, those aren't, those aren't, yeah.
I, I kind of ignored that cause I didn't, I didn't think about it that much, but
we are more data-driven and I'm always moving that needle.
What I do is I, I, my role, actually I'm managing so many damn people and I don't
even get to do much coaching anymore, but, uh, showing it as an option.
If people do planning, because one of the things I do a lot and now I've
delegated most of that is helping teams understand how to do better planning.
Because we believe our engineers should own their own project management.
So part of helping them think about how to do their estimates and
planning is frequently I'll walk through what BDD is and I'll give them
my same speech, the values and the behavior, not in the automation, and
they can use it if they want.
Right.
It's, um, completely agree.
I do think, again, the value proposition in my mind is, is you think through it.
I, I'm still connecting the dots to the data-driven and needle move.
To me, having a good design of your architecture is needle moving.
It, it, it, because I've experienced it over and over again.
It's, it's, um, replating architecture because you did something screwed
up in the first place is hard.
So any, anything that gives you a tool that helps you to go, like
you've said it before, devs are lazy, right?
Anything that says, okay, how can I design this way?
So I don't have, I have to do less work later.
Hey, Brett, you know what the sound is?
No.
That's us beating the dead horse.
So I have one other topic, which is open ended and maybe fun.
Okay.
Let's talk about DevOps.
What the hell is DevOps?
So first of all, uh, let me get into the three ways that DevOps first,
which we've talked about before on here.
So there's the three ways that DevOps, a gene came up with.
The first way is all about flow and systems thinking that's modern testing.
The second way is to amplify the feedback loops, a little bit of modern testing.
And the third way is build a culture of continual experimentation and learning.
Also modern testing.
So on one hand, lots of parallels between the, what we think about
modern testing and three ways of DevOps.
But I noticed some interesting parallels this week in, I saw an article come out
and, and I can't even remember what it was, but I realized something and I tweeted
it and it was one of those things where I tweeted, people said, uh, yeah, Alan,
you just noticed some things now, which is that, well, Brett, what is DevOps?
Well, the way you described it DevOps honestly is nothing more than CICD.
And then I'm thinking through that.
You were around in the old days of, and we had this definitely in the early
2000s at Microsoft where we built some services and we chucked them over the
wall for operations to deploy and maintain.
So, so where did DevOps come from?
And that's essentially this brand new concept where Dev owns the
operation of the crap that they built.
Yeah.
Right.
So DevOps was originally introduced.
Well, it's introduced as a culture where the wall between developer
and operations is non-existent.
Right.
In many ways, like my view is it enables a, you build it, you run it culture.
All good.
But what I've seen more and more, which scares me is people will have a team
will have a DevOps person or a DevOps team.
And what that DevOps team does is the operational stuff we saw people do 20
years ago at Microsoft, they're an operations team, they're calling them
DevOps and it scares me because it it's backward.
And if we look at what DevOps does, you know what it does?
It accelerates the achievement of shippable quality, accelerate, we're
talking about feedback loops and amplifying feedback loops and
cultural experimentation as DevOps.
That's also modern testing.
Uh, it, I don't know.
I mean, accelerating the achievement of shippable quality, that's a big umbrella.
Right.
It's it's, there's a lot of things, right?
But what I'm saying is two things.
One is your DevOps team does not exist to do your operations for
you or to do your DevOps for you.
Well, no.
So the problem is, is that they probably do.
The bullet prop.
Well, I know the problem is you have a DevOps team, but I think DevOps has,
it's become the fancy name for an infrastructure team.
You often, especially like the scale of unity, we need a team that can do
the high level management of our cloud platform, our CI CD systems, uh, to
make sure everyone, make sure we have some consistency available in what
CI pipelines you use, how you get your code deployed.
We don't want everyone to have to invent their own stuff, but
definitely it's the you build it, you run it culture.
I think like a team, a team called the DevOps team, in my view, their job should
be not to operate the, the code, the devs servicing, but their job, but much
like what we talked about with modern testing, their job is to construct,
maintain and encourage the DevOps culture.
Right.
Well, what I'm seeing, not just in the three ways being similar to the
principles or the intent we have with the principles, I'm seeing a lot more
parallels between, and again, I think having a DevOps team can be a little
bit of a, little bit of a smell, depending on what they actually do.
But we talk about teams not needing a dedicated QA person in modern testing.
I think like the way my team's function is we have high functioning teams with
deploying dozens of times a day and with very, very little interaction or even
questions from my team, they're basically function there.
They don't need our help.
They're, they're running everything on their own.
Some teams need a little bit more handholding and they'll all get there, but
they don't need a dedicated, and again, we wouldn't embed someone
on their team, like with a tester, but they don't need dedicated DevOps help.
They haven't figured out they actually have adopted the culture completely.
So my team exists to help people get to that culture of DevOps and
get to that culture of quality.
Okay.
Lots of paral, I've been thinking about this, lots of parallels.
So I don't think AB DevOps has the right sound.
So we'll stick with AB testing.
Yeah.
C like we go ABC DevOps.
We, Oh, what if we brought someone with a letter C onto the podcast?
Uh, I, I've told you before, we should just rename to AB checking.
Yes.
Cause that's important.
Then, then you have your ABCD.
I took a little dig in my testing festival talk.
Once it's out, you'll see it.
I talk about loud voices and stuff.
You talk about loud voices in testing, throwing out models because
well, yeah, actually, uh, Steve Rowe.
And I think he talked, I think one of the times it's been a long time.
We should bring him back.
What's he doing now?
We should have him back on and find out checking in with Steve.
But he, he talked about how, uh, one of those loud voices was just
riddled with lot logical fallacies.
Oh, yeah.
I know, I know exactly.
Yes.
I just ignore, I mean, I try to ignore it, but it's fun to pick at it too.
The nice thing, the nice thing about the three, right?
Uh, I don't know if you paid attention to the thread on the Slack channel, but
I was getting, I was getting geared up.
Um, uh, to, to like this, this whole language debate on testing versus checking.
It's dumb and it just needs to go away.
And I was getting all riled up and go, okay, how do I help make this go away?
But the three men, this is one of the things I really love about our community.
The three was just like, look, Brent, you're not seeing all the data.
We see it better than you in some regards.
And I agree.
And they are actually living in a increasingly shrinking bottle bubble from 1998.
Yeah.
They basic, basically they didn't say this explicitly, but they said, look,
our time is not as better spent helping people move to the future.
Not like the past is killing themselves all by themselves.
They don't need our help agreed.
That's it.
All right.
Now a real important thing.
So you went to the testing testing festival.
I've been meaning to ask why is it not called the testable?
I was not involved in the creation of it.
Oh, all right.
Fair enough.
It should be, I'm thinking it should be.
So I wanted to, um, I wasn't quite done with DevOps.
Yeah.
Please go back to it.
It'll get like the one thing too, that I'll also say it's interesting
that you're like, Hey, Brett, sudden insight.
Hey, modern testing is very similar to DevOps.
Yeah.
Um, good.
Alan.
Good.
Good boy.
I'm so glad.
Like I'm, I'm with them on Alan really.
Okay.
Sure.
But do you realize, like, I don't, I don't know DevOps DevOps number
one, it's not deployed very well.
It's also number two.
It's also another thing on its way to, to die.
Right.
As I mentioned, uh, when trying to find on the web, like there was, there
were all sorts of star ops things.
And right now one of them is AI ops and even AI ops is, is on its way out.
Yeah.
I think all of these things ops are, I mean, DevOps to me, there's also
fun test ops or DevSecOps or DevTestOps.
Uh, to me, they're all DevOps because DevOps is all about getting rid of the
walls because they are bottlenecks.
And in modern testing, we don't like bottlenecks.
And one thing I like to point out, Brent, is I know you're nodding your head on.
Yeah, these are the same, but remember the podcast is not for you.
It's for the three people that listen to it.
And they may, and they may nod their heads too, but I want to go
ahead and plant the seed anyway.
Is, is that the rationalization you're going to use?
All right.
Yeah.
Here's my question.
All right.
Can you automate DevOps or is it, or is it, or do you do manual DevOps or automated DevOps?
Um, there's obviously a trap there somewhere.
Because real DevOps can't be done.
Can't be automated.
I'm just making up stuff.
You're not doing DevOps.
Oh, you're doing, I don't know.
Oh yeah.
I'm trying to make up something Dev dumbass.
I don't, I don't know.
I get what you're going.
Yeah.
Let's have a, no, that's that it's not DevOps.
That's that is modern testing, right?
I'm actually looking through, I just happened to come into a page and says,
what's the difference between DevOps and Agile?
And unfortunately the webpage I'm on, uh, is not saying frigging nothing.
So, uh, this came up once I was in a conversation, I can't remember what
form it was on, it may have been Reddit.
Uh, I can't, it must've been about one of my articles or something, but
someone was saying that, well, we're moving on from Agile.
I said, what we're moving on from Agile.
Yeah.
Agile is old news.
Now we're doing DevOps.
I thought, what the, it's the same thing.
Um, it's not, it's not.
And I just glanced through it and I understand what they're saying.
Agile is a set of, um, practices geared around the process.
Okay.
DevOps is, is actually much more of a technical practice.
No, it's, it's, it's on, is there is principles around delivering
frequent customer value and DevOps with that one in mind, DevOps is
an implementation strategy.
DevOps enables.
Yeah.
It's, but they're, you don't move from one to the other is my point.
But you, you also like the thing I'm reading right now,
so let me ask you this.
Can you be agile with a separate ops team?
Uh, not in my definition, but mine neither.
Uh, but a lot of the agile, if you have, wait, wait, wait, wait,
checking stuff over the wall at any, a lot of people, a lot of people still today
view scrum as agile, well, they're stupid.
Right.
And, and in a scrum model, absolutely.
You can chuck things over.
Yeah.
That, that just angers me and, and the, there's too much ritual around scrum.
I let teams do it if they want, because I don't, yeah, whatever.
But, and again, actually scrum can be very good, but too many teams turn it
into mini waterfall and it drives me freaking crazy.
So anyway, go on.
Now, I was just saying, like agile, uh, I was actually writing up a, I've been
asked to do this and I've been revisiting the Galazzo deck.
Right.
Oh yeah.
That yeah.
The, the famous Galazzo deck, the famous Brent's too lazy to actually get
off his butt and publish it.
Like he keeps promising year over year over year over year.
Well, maybe after the pandemic's over, it can be presented at modern testing
conference, maybe, maybe the app would happy to do that by that time.
And that certainly would be enough motivation.
Why hasn't there been an online modern testing conference yet?
Uh, same reason, same reason as usual.
Sounds like work.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
Like to me, uh, an agile practice is, is one that achieves three goals simultaneously.
It adds confirmed value, reduces calendar time and reduces engineering time.
That that's sort of anything that does that in my mind.
Uh, does it reduce calendar time calendar time is a constant.
Calendar time to delivery.
This is cycle time.
Okay.
Let's say you and I are working on the same thing and we can continuously, the
two of us working together, we can continuously put it up, push out this
widget in a day, can we bring that down sooner to a half a day or, and, or can
we figure out a way to say that we don't need both of us on it calendar time?
How is I get the, how's that different from the third thing you said though?
Oh, engineering time.
The biggest difference between engineering time and calendar time.
That one's easy and you should know this.
That's, that's the delay time.
That's the time where the, where the work is sitting and doing nothing.
It's not moving forward.
It's sit idle.
It's the equivalent.
Two part of the same thing.
No, no.
Like you and I may have delay in our widget delivery.
I'm I'm all I, and I get what you're talking about, but can't it
all be about just tightening feedback loops?
Uh, I don't know how you brought feedback loops in here, but calendar
time, think of it this way.
Let's say you are working on two projects.
Yeah.
Okay.
You can't, uh, you are working on two coding projects.
Right.
It is fizz.
You are physically enabled to work, but both of us at the same time.
Okay.
So when you stop working on one, that is adding a delay in the calendar
time for that one, because it's going to go out later.
All right.
Okay.
So, so, uh, if you think about it in terms theory of constraints, one of the, uh, one
of the key things in addition to bottlenecks, they, they advertise is you, you
analyze in your root cause.
Uh, this is actually right.
Here's his book is the best way of thinking of this.
That's what I've been visualized.
No time you've been talking.
You, you go when you look at his discussion around whip.
Yep.
Discovering transparency and rooting out the sources of delay in your system
speeds up your ability to produce widgets in a faster calendar time
without impacting engineering time.
Okay.
I get it.
One's about optimizing the optimizing two different parts of the system.
Yes.
Okay.
And I just look at them all collectively as optimize the whole damn system.
Well, that's important.
That's important.
All right.
Okay.
I get it.
And I think, uh, again, uh, ran it some plug is always good here.
So yeah.
All right.
DevOps, agile, parallels, whatever, and a mailbag.
I think we did well this time.
Yeah.
So next, next Friday you're getting shot number two, right?
I am.
Yeah.
This potentially this time in one week, I will be in the fetal position
someplace in the Pacific Northwest.
Savi.
So my timing on mine is really bad.
I talked, I was laughing with my team about this.
So my second, so we have the, we have a four day weekend, eight at unity.
Uh, anytime there's a three day weekend, like from Memorial day, they go ahead
and give us the previous Friday off and make it a four day weekend.
So they actually just gave us some more Fridays off this summer, which is great.
We're taking, getting some extra time off, but this four day weekend at the end of
it on the Tuesday afterwards, I get my second shot, have the four day weekend
and then miss a day probably after that almost as you know, almost everybody
feels like crap after the second shot.
But the good news is it's like a flu without the congestion and mo for
most people, most people get that and most people, it goes away within a day,
but we'll see what happens.
And yours is when Memorial, June 1st.
Okay.
So I should be good to go by Friday.
We'll learn about my, uh, two weeks.
Yeah.
We'll learn about mine and recovered.
Yep.
All right.
We should call it a day, man.
All righty.
All right.
Thanks everyone.
We'll see you next time on AB DevOps.
Checking.
Yeah, that one.
See ya.