Welcome to AB testing podcast your modern testing podcast your hosts Alan and
Brent will be here to guide you through topics on testing leadership agile and
anything else that comes to mind now on with the show so this is the AB testing
podcast how's it going Brent super so excited you should be excited because
this is our 136 episode and Brent types to figure it out because you can't 100 and 30 something
through drive is just 39 or 16 so we're here on another Friday afternoon a
beautiful spring is coming sort of time in the Northwest yeah and we're gonna do
a podcast and then we're going to I'm going to edit it and then through the
magic of the internet you will hear this these words being spoken time shifted by
about two and a half days on Monday or later depending on when you listen or
it's magical right or earlier if you're part of the secret club oh how does one
get into the secret club Brent it's really hard it's really hard you have to
magically navigate Google to find the AB testing you don't even need Google you
can just go to modern testing org oh come on I want them it's a secret club
don't work hard for it no that's the work you're being dumb and then they
have to click the link to join the one of the three slack channel yeah and
that's it and then you could ask questions there and I always post it
again a lot of people stay away from slack over the weekend so there's no
requirement to listen to it early but I always post it on our slack group for
preview of people that hang out with us the weekend before just or two days
before when I get it whatever I get done editing actually as soon as I get done
editing and which is also a good chance for me to get feedback on hey Alan you
accidentally posted audio from a kid's birthday party I said oops wrong video
wrong audio but yeah you get a chance to listen ahead of time if you'd like
doesn't show up in RSS feed just download it of course if you'd rather
just have life be simple you can be in the slack group take part in
conversations and wait until the podcast shows up in your feed on Monday
whatever makes your life easier yeah whatever you want that as long as it
also makes our life easier we're super supportive yeah we're pretty easy going
here for a bunch of old guys or a couple old guys at least two old guys
a couple weeks ago I did a webinar next week I'm doing another webinar nice
Thursday night which is gonna be really crappy time for those you in Europe but
for the Americas I think it's like starts at 6 o'clock I'll try and put a
link in it in the show notes but you can look at my both my LinkedIn feed and
my Twitter feed and probably find it I'm doing a a webinar on just learning
stuff and I'm putting together a presentation I'm gonna tell you what's
in it but was really cool the people organizing it at PNSQC said you don't
even have to give a presentation you can just facilitate some conversation
which I love so what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna kick it off with a little I'll
kick it off I'll do a little bit of both I'll kick it off with a little bit
of stuff around learning I want to talk about probably largely a little recap of
Steven Johnson because the reason they contacted me one is they know me because
I've spoken at their regular in-person conference a couple times right you're a
favorite of theirs if I don't know if I'm a favorite but you know I'm on the
list they're also curious like we're like how do you find these five for
Friday things what motivates you to learn which is really good question of
course five for Friday comes from a brief infatuation I had with what's his
face Tim Ferriss and he does a five bullet Friday thing I thought you know
I'm gonna do something like that for the stuff that I care about but really it
comes back to a book I read that I don't remember the name and I don't know
how it is for you but I recollect what year it was by what product I was
working on at the time so sometime around 2001 2002 I read some book and
in the book it said hey if you want to get new ideas you should probably
read some stuff that's outside of your area because as I learned from Steven
Johnson years and years later ideas come from other ideas oh yeah let me can I
good no let me shit up all right no I'm sorry go ahead just like yeah go ahead
right I actually use this a great deal so as you and the three know I manage
the data science team and as you and the three may not know data science is an
extremely broad term right and there are hundreds of specialization somebody who
who for example is working on face recognition certainly he or she are gonna
know all about the basics you know what's clustering what's classification
etc but in terms of words yeah in terms of specific techniques there's a deep
specialization and in that context okay and so even though I have my unfair share
of PhDs reporting to me they do not in fact know everything about that is like
so one of the things that I do papers we spent a lot of time on on research
papers you go to Google Scholar use look up stuff and you can see sort of
people's prior published ideas okay but in terms of the concept of ideas always
come on the on the old ideas coming together a research paper is exactly
that I will call out you go to the references section and the references
section is not only the old ideas that are being brought together but it is a
very clean follow-up a bowl enumeration of that list and and so when I when I have
one of my data scientists come to me and and say hey I'm stuck I cannot figure
out how to move around this I give them the following exercise okay all I want
you to do is every day I want you to start off and and go to Google Scholar
and just do a search for something that you see as you know do a keyword search
for something you think is relevant that's it and then I want you to pick
one of those articles there and read it and then next day and don't do anything
with it just read it next day based off of that either do a different keyword
search and and read something or go to the references of that one and pick one
of those to do it yes and I'm gonna add that to my presentation something I've
done before but I forgot about is read a in short read a research document but go
look where they got their ideas from right and I just basically say do that
do that just reading that algorithm reading one paper a day for 14 days and
I promise you you will you will find the answer you're seeking yes and even
further than that you won't get the 14 days yes I'm gonna go in that's good
we're gonna get more anecdotes to share I do want to do an AB test here on the
AB testing so I'd technically be at a slash B test on the AB testing podcast could you
take your microphone maybe lower it three inches just keep it above nose
level but a little bit there try it right there now Brent on a scale of one
to ten how much of an idiot do you think I am seven oh what one to ten no four
five okay half an idiot that's that's fair that's so I'm gonna you know I gave
a presentation years ago leveraging Stephen Johnson's material and there's a
slide in there that's probably worth going over in our tangent weave here so
oh back to the presentation it is hard to keep track of all the tangent
sometimes isn't it what the bill I don't bother anymore what the book suggested
which was something became a part of my life for about five years and I kind of
lost track and it went away once I had children but it's suggested I subscribed
to this thing called you know just one of the ideas was science news and
science news was a print magazine tiny it was like it arrived every week but
it was maybe 12 pages and I could read through the whole thing and not
understand most of it but for some reason just like looking at these
research ideas you're for you're looking at something different every day it
planted seeds that made me think about some things differently and it may not
say oh I'm gonna apply this thing from science to this thing I was doing in
testing it was more of oh here's another way to think about stuff and I
would just maybe even subconsciously think about not applauding the thing from
science news but oh here's when it is experiment they thought about this thing
in two different ways can I think about this particular problem in two different
ways but a lot of really subtle things so definitely suggestion there I don't
know if they make the magazine anymore it might have gone from weekly to every
other week and a little thicker but at some point I stopped subscribing but
just fascinating I felt really smart after I read it and I've been
progressively dumber ever since so as part of that presentation I looked for
some titles of some of the best conference talks that were happening on
the test circle for various reasons I go over in a minute I want to share some of
these with you and gonna get your thoughts the art and science of load
testing internet applications that's applicable to developers as well as
testers model-based testing for data centric products also interesting could
be applicable managing user exceptions tests and large projects it's that could
be again it's a little businessy title but in the when we care about like we're
trying to outcome based testing those user acceptance tests can be important yes
architectures of test automation I'm much more comfortable having a
development team own that but I like to hear the ideas there habits of highly
effective testers very generic one but you know good so what do you think
about those talks I just described I don't like the last two the last two
kind of feel you know 1996 ish to me but the other one actually you're very close
because these are all titles from conferences given in 1999 and 2000 mmm
yeah so the point is could we please have some new ideas I'll take new ideas
and test for $500 Alex what is blank the problem one problem in the industry
and something we've talked about before directly and indirectly I'll just gloss
over is that a lot of people get their information on how to improve whatever
craft or knowledge work they're doing from one or two places or one or two
places or people that is not a way to get new ideas you regurgitating for
example I was reading and I'll name drop Michael Bolton here I was reading an
article he wrote on LinkedIn and someone tagged me in it and for good
reasons someone who is not not trying to stir anything up they had actually a
reason for tagging me in and since I was there I asked about this concept of
someone else mentioned oh I found that critical distances blah blah blah and so
I spent a bunch of time searching on what critical distance was and I asked
the person not very much to find Bolton later told me later later to look for a
different term called psychological distance or something but a little bit
better but I'm glad again they've done a lot of thinking on this stuff and they
get it I think this particular thing is in a little bit in a vacuum because yeah
if it is one person doing all of the work some of those things do exist but we
work collaboratively but the main thing was the main disappointment was this
person had no idea what the term they were using meant they just regurgitated
they did no like my reaction is to go figure out okay I want to see why I
have some cognitive dissonance with this term because I can't I want to know
more about it so I can understand where to apply it so I did the research try
and figure it out and it turns out that the person making the argument this was
the reason in this case why developers can't test they're using a term that
they had heard but never researched and to me I find that again for a
knowledge worker I find it some word I can't I don't remember the English word
for it bullshit stupid I mean idiotic I mean I mean you're old but I mean I came
up with three right there yeah whatever but I mean if you if you want to be good
at anything in knowledge work I don't care if it's testing specialty or software
development or data science or Jesus architecture anything that requires the
creative mind and the balance of adaptive learning work that I mean the
definition of knowledge work is that you are often learning as you go along you
have to take the learning part seriously so I could go I could for the
rest of this podcast talk about the different methods of where new ideas
come from Stephen Johnson and I won't know I won't but you have to seek out
places to expand your repertoire of ideas it can't be from one or two places
it can't be from 10 or 12 it needs to be from dozens or hundreds and you have to
be hungry to define those things I'm it's frustrating to me to see people
who their thoughts on tests are based purely on what they've seen one or two
or three people say about testing I don't get how you can I don't get it I'm
up on a soapbox I'd not intend to go on but the point that I want to go over in
this talk is you have to find ways to get new ideas into your head especially
in the last 12 months where you can't go meet with other people the the
Enlightenment and one thing from maybe Stephen Johnson's book is the idea of
coffee shops and getting people together finding a meeting place a community for
people to exchange ideas that helps innovation and ideas thrive the one line
from the book is chance favors the connected mind yes like being in the
right place at the right time to figure out how stuff works he talks about the
adjacent possible which is taking something that's and just and just
making that one little extra step to make to figure out that peanut butter and
chocolate go pretty good together but you have to constantly seek out ideas
and you have to not be afraid to do new stuff maybe this ties into a chapter for
a book I wrote that I I'm really proud of and I don't have a pulled up here to
read from but there's this e-book put together called around the world around
the testing world in 80 days or something where I was given free reign
to write about anything I wanted and I'm gonna tell a story which is a
paraphrase of my article it starts off with me saying oh hey I'll take that
on and it was me approaching a conversation back when I worked on that
stupid science project and I was bored and I happened to walk by on a
conversation of someone wanting to set up a bunch of static analysis tools and
sonar cube and some other tools for our product which built on Linux I joined
that team so I could get my Linux skills and my Java skills up to stuff
it was very early in the product I had no idea how to do the thing that I
just said I would love to take on because for me if I'm not in a position
where I have to learn in order to be successful I'm kind of bored and not
happy yeah and that's actually one thing that you and I have in common is going
back to the orders of ignorance we're pretty confident in our ability to
construct a means by which the one thing that I'm totally mind-blinking on right
the fourth order that doesn't exist any means by which you don't have a suitable
means to discover what you don't know you don't know right you and I both have
a process by which we go well I'll say like for me I just go most of the time
it's like it's just code it's not magic I'll figure it out it's really not that
hard but I do know that a large number of people and I think some of our
listeners don't don't sort of have that same sort of sense the so I've always
been attracted it up until the team I'm on right now like you one thing you and
I had in common is we get bored and change teams for me I got more
interested in looking for and whenever it was on the team hunt is go okay what
is the team that I think would most be able to leverage my strengths but at the
same time is working in the space I know little to nothing about right and if I
can go and find that the people culture there is great then I'm in done it's
over yeah but we could add another topic I want to get to but I want to stay
here a little bit because yes this is absolutely true and what I've sort of
inadvertently done as I've grown into managing a larger team which we've
talked about before drink is I've developed a little bit of a pattern and
reputation for taking on taking a hard problem on figuring out the details on
my own and then delegating it away to part of my team to continue to maintain
and grow it helps me learn a lot and then it gives me opportunities to give
people things to do you know when I joined my current org it was program
management and again I said the same thing my the by hiring manager who did
not have an engineering role for me to go into said hey can you do program
management because you wanted to have me on his team I said sure and I had
never done that before and and again to remind you Brent program management in
the rest of the world is much different than the hybrid thing at
Microsoft it's it's reducing complexity and understanding and what it turned out
to me in the end once I figured it out really what my role ended up being was
running the what he calls the what we both called the engineering system
engineering operating system that's just like running an engineering team
it's the same thing I did for what I was the senior or quality architect or
some high-level senior tester reporting to test directors way back in the day
so and because it involves coaching teams on agile practices and coaching
teams on quality that was great but anyway I did that I was not intend to
talk about what I did but really I took that on figured it out and now delegated
as someone better than me running that portion of the org which is good because
our projects are getting more complex in some cases same thing with quality I
have a super great quality leader on my team who I've I don't have to of
course I'm involved and I'm curious and I'm I try and remain a highly
opinionated about quality but really my whole org is quality but I have a part of
my org who are dedicated to quality coaching and someone very capable
they're all delegated away most recently as I believe we discussed I've
been diving deeply into cutting our again don't know how to do it sure I'll
figure it out but figuring out what we can do to cut our spend on cloud hosting
I learned a lot of things got it all figured out made a lot of dashboards
I'm delegating that work away I'll take on something new when we talk about
knowledge work I've found that people again I'd have to be just like me I'm
like you and I we're happy we're most happy when people can keep on giving us
more and more things we haven't done before I'm most happy when I get to be in
over my head at work and I see folks who pride themselves on the craft of
blah but they just want to do the same thing over and over and it just baffles
me I mean everyone at some point in time is you got pink's principles memorized
better than I do but mash mastery is important but it's like you and I we're
sort of mastering the meta like we're more we're more interested in mastering
the I don't know the journey versus any specific destination but other people
are wired differently but mastery comes from not being able to do it but being
able to have the right resources to be able to do it the first time this
happened to me I thought I was gonna get fired I was three years into
Microsoft remember I'm a self-taught programmer but I figure stuff out well
enough people gave me more credit than I was worth and I was maybe I've told
you this story I was paired with one of the original Microsoft OS guys to work
on the debug version of Windows because it had been neglected for a while and to
get it running from the Win9x platform and debugger development and I thought
great I'm gonna learn a lot from this guy hopefully he doesn't call it how
stupid I am but then he retired like a week in they said it's okay Alan you
could own it by yourself so I am scared to death but I got a book on assembly
language because I had to learn assembly language in order to do this because the
kernel and the debugger are largely an assembly and I slowly poked my way
through the same way you would you make a bug fix here a bug fix there you
tweak another thing and and eventually it was almost like I knew what I was doing
I knew enough what I was doing people assumed I knew what I was doing and I
went from I'm gonna get fired to you know what I love figuring stuff out
that's really hard it's what motivates me and since then I seek that out I
seek that steep learning curve and it sounds too much like I'm bragging but I
guess the point is a lot of in addition to being a white male a lot of my success
comes from just chance favoring the connected mind being available to try new
things out being just being open to new ideas and accepted them yeah well you
and I've talked about it before right in in knowledge work is essentially ideal
work and so for me to sort of lock into this is the best idea ever like and I
think you agree with me but I'll just ask what's what's your thought on the
term best practice I'm pausing because it's a loaded term on one hand taken
semantically correct as written it's stupid because there is no it's all
contextual there's no best practice generally not always but generally when
people use best practice they're not looking for that but not it's it's
similar to using literally to say Brent I'm literally on fire right now I'm not
so for best practice it depends on the for a phrase it depends on context it
depends on the context of how it's being used if by best practice do you mean the
thing I absolutely have to do all the time then I don't like it if I best
practice do you mean a thing that generally works most of the time which
is the typical use of that then I don't mind it what was the answer you
were fishing for the term by itself without a context is in my view just
blatantly offensive the point is it's not used that way in general and you know
you're right the well I don't know like the places where I seen it used is in
terms of weaponizing an idea during a negotiation hey this is known to be a
best practice for the last 10 years of course I would then argue if this is a
best practice for the last 10 years you're wasting my time yeah it would be
easier if we got rid of the term because it yeah it can be abused so I'm not sure
where you're going with that you asked me a question about it but what was the
intent behind of that question it was essentially in terms of knowledge work
and idea work yeah there is a best known way to move forward today however
knowledge work will continue we will continue to learn new things in this
sort of stay locked into sort of a mindset that the things that I've
learned for the last 20 years and I have now mastered this in our space I think is
at best mistaken idea at worst just abject foolish hey I want to change the
subject slightly slightly and get your this is something we've talked about
before but I want to frame it a little bit differently so I could almost ask you
a similar question back but I thought I haven't thought about how to put this
but I'll put it like this inevitably you know I've written these articles highly
opinionated somewhat controversial there is there are a few people who've come
back on both articles and say oh you do you wrote testing but you meant checking
which I think is a big load of crap what but whatever you do you but I do see
from even those folks and a few others there is among the internet a high like
you and I have both said I'll put it this way the readers are all going Alan
get to the point and the point is a lot of testers focus on testing as
almost as the end all of what they're doing and you and I have both stated we
don't really care about testing we care about quality yeah our goal is
different it's weather is for and this is I think the crux of it I don't know
where your question is but the crux of it when you say the word testing do you
view it as the ends or the means well you know the answer it's definitely the
means well for you and me it's definitely the means but it's not for a
large portion like is that what what what led people to believe that customers
care about testing because they don't heads up customers don't give one little
bit of their red freckle on their nose about how many tests you run and how
many which tests you ran on this build they don't they don't and matter of fact
the only places where I've ever seen testing by a customer being communicated
it was an expression of lack of quality hey Apple didn't test their shit right
it's just the only useful term from a customer in terms of testing turns out in
my mind and this is a hypothesis of generating on the fly is to scapegoat
right it's the same shit Deb does no longer have the conversations I'm out of
now at a point I'm like oh my god if I haven't heard it in years but when people
come to me well why wasn't this tested before I'm like is that hypothetical like
are you just asking yourself this out loud like what is actually the answer to
that question and what are you gonna do to fix it let me interrupt you I'm gonna
weave you through some thoughts I've had about this and get your thoughts on how
they relate to this topic where we can go back to Weinberg who says
quality is value to some person quality doesn't say about testing so what value
it brings we've had discussions about that if 10,000 people are using a thing
that has 20 known bugs and only five people are using a thing that has no
known bugs which one has higher quality it's the one with more people right you
know a long time ago did you ever read quality is free the Philip Crosby book
no it's about manufacturing and and and people read it and poopoo it and
there are some it's about prevention which you and I both would actually
prefer fast detection over prevention because it's more efficient and we like
to be efficient go INTPs by the way we were gonna talk about personality types
this time we're gonna do it next time instead because we've already used all
this time on this topic I don't want to end it so another thing he said that
I've been thinking about recently I want to plant this on you is this is
a book where he says quality is conformance to requirements I have a
twist on that but first I want to know I'm sure you've heard that definition
before but what do you think about that definition of quality of conformance to
requirements I'll do it this way I'm okay with it under the condition that those
requirements don't necessarily have to be communicated my statement is what
every customer wants is actually a solution to their problem yes and that
that's the twist I just got I read that and it didn't it didn't sit well with me
when I read it 15 years ago but it's principle number five I would say
quality is conformance to requirements when the customer defines the
requirements their requirements are defined implicitly yes explicitly yeah
now now you and I are in the same page I mean the problem is this is the
problem with this podcast is eventually we're always on the same page because
we yeah reasons yeah exactly it's conformist to the requirements sure but
it's a requirements around what the customer needs not necessarily what they
are asking for that's it now would I ever if I were writing a book would I
ever use that statement no because I know there's a lot of people that will
take that literally and then go off and do the wrong thing so let me build
on my last statement make a statement made by me not by anybody else so based on
the Weinberg definition that quality is value to some person that that would be
a customer and then my modified Crosby definition that quality is conformance
to the requirements as defined implicitly by the customer I would make
this statement and I want your reaction on it if you don't know who your
customer is and what problem you're solving for them you cannot define what
quality is you don't know what quality is yeah but isn't aren't you just
restating principle 5 I am in a different way okay so it made me think
that this when we talk about quality and testing not being the same thing and
people will say oh of course they aren't but then they talk about how they
improve quality all they talk about is the testing they do and principle 5 says
that we can't do that we need the customer we can't build a quality
product without a customer even if it was quality we won't know it's like it's
like the tree that fell on the forest we can't measure it right right I've been
thinking through since you brought it up earlier the the checking versus testing
argument there's no argument system yeah no no I get it hold hold back hold
back the soapbox ramp for a moment and they hold it off and in and honestly part
of me wants to go and say okay guys let's sit down let's have an objective and
real conversation in today's world what is the value of testing that you are
holding up and then trying to drive and improve a specialization and
craftsmanship around because to me from where I sit honestly Alan I kind of think
of testing as a specialization very similar to blacksmithing right it's in a
back in a certain time in a certain context it was extremely valuable it
still exists today and if if I had a choice between let's say a pocket knife
built by a master craftsman and and one built by a factory in China that were
the same price tag obviously I'm gonna pick the master craftsman yes those but
if if what I need is something that's going to last my expected a lifetime use
of it I'm probably gonna go towards the the cheaper option which is gonna be
the factory in me and you know what so it's the majority of right it may be
easier just to buy a new one every six months or cheaper right right so I want to
keep on going I know we're getting to our last 10 or 15 minutes here so there
are more pieces to this and this is why again going back to our first topic is
maybe I'll repeat another statement when I read my first book on test software
testing I thought I knew a lot then I read another book and I thought now I
know a lot then I read a third book and I got confused and realized how little I
knew and the more I've read about software engineering software quality
software testing I realized how much there is I don't know and how much I
need to learn there's is that done in Kruger effect right I knew a little
bit enough to think I knew a lot and then as I knew more I realized I
didn't know anything it could be something different yep there's some
other things that feed into this so the question the context of this is so if
quality is value to some person or performance requirements and testing does
not equal quality how do we build a quality product and then one other flavor
is it's been 15 years now since Ed Keys gave that keynote at a Google test
automation conference where he said sufficiently advanced monitoring is
equivalent to testing so there's something in there too and I would say
monitoring is testing well I'll I mean I feel safer with what Ed said okay
fair right so because there's with there's a lot of crap monitors out
there so if testing is not quality what do you need to do to build a quality
product I can't just write code then test it then ship it you told me Alan
that's not quality so what are the steps to build a quality product are
we redoing episode 83 all of a sudden there whatever it was principle 5 like
the you we do principle 5 is prevalent in this theme but right so then no it's
coming together in a different way it's a experiment there's two things you have
to know to determine if you have a quality product number one what the
hell problem it actually solves right there's a hypothesis hypothesized
problem but it's a lot of the times the problem it actually solves is actually
not the one that you intended right and that that goes to your early example
from Stephen Johnson I actually think of his air conditioner story what
problem does it solve then once you're firm on what problem it solves to what
degree it actually does so you have to have a you have to have a technique to
evaluate quality you have to have some sort of technique where you are
continuously evaluating those two spaces simultaneously and you cannot do that
without here I'll use double quote customer data I'll call it that right
and here I because I don't want to get into the the semantic quagmire around
the term customer but I think the majority of our listeners probably
understand where I'm coming from well our listeners do and sometimes are
preaching to the choir but it's good to think about I like to think about it
this way because I this massive I've noticed because I'm getting you know I
get lots of Twitter DMS and LinkedIn messages and comments on my post because
I've been talking about things that make people feel uncomfortable but the
point is for everyone who thinks I'm a quack and who I've made feel uncomfortable
there are at least as many people that that think well again I'm not
describing this new panacea we're describing what we're seeing if you
disagree with it you disagreeing what's happening in reality so the
feedback I've gotten is more I would classify it more sort of name-calling hey
you're disrespecting the discipline that you grew up in and honestly I don't know
I don't I don't have a whole lot of empathy for that and I don't care about
the feedback right I'm trying to figure out how to I don't say educate but I
want to justify what we're seeing and put it into perspective so let's do
a quick thought if we have five minutes left just do a quick experiment I have
some fingernail clippers you can't see him friend can see him barely again yeah
on my desk I'm uses inspiration I am I have a customer hypothesis a problem
statement I don't believe I don't believe people in a across around the
world are able to to solve their nail clipping problems efficiently enough I am
going to launch fingernail clippers calm it's gonna be great I have a
great designer and time goes by and we have the site as we've tested
extensively the shopping cart and and orders and shipping it's all set it's
good to go we've done a hard launch with lots of marketing big marketing
budget we want to be the premier place to get fingernail clippers on the
internet we tested the crap out of it so on one hand I'm thinking it's high
quality because we can't find any bugs we ran a hundred thousand tests and our
my little website is live and then very little happens we're not getting orders
or getting very few orders what happened obviously ours is our site is failing
you could say it has quality issues because it's not providing value to any
people or very very few people what did we do wrong how do I fix it how do I
do who Brent I've hired you to help me get out of my quag Mars reminds me like
Elizabeth Hendrickson talks a lot about she was hired to fix quality problems
and they were never with the test team so anyway help me fix it what do I do
it did this one this one is I would take the role that I know venture
capitalists do and I would just simply say okay Alan who did your market
analysis like what made you believe this was a problem that needed to be
solved and if you came back and said you know one day I had inspiration and I was
staring at my shiny black nail clippers on my desk and and I moved mountains to
make this website happen then the solution is easy is okay who's your
target customer all right so go on let's say I did market analysis and I
assumed I had a million customers any one time across the US just pretend so then
where do you go so you look at that you basically look at that data and it's
rock-solid and you're thinking wow well you should be doing better now what do
we do wrong did we not test it well enough no testing has nothing to do with
this one so I'm leading the witness right no no it's like the solution
therein is the problem here is why did you ship it right given that the data that
you mentioned why did you invest in it why did you ship it right it's a clear
thing that you showing it is that it is it is not providing an interesting enough
solution to a problem humans have and the fix would be Alan to send you out to
physically talk to not your marketing team you to talk to the customers and
find out why and you didn't want I mean you're exactly right I was leading you a
little bit deeper into it you absolutely need to make sure you're solving a
relevant problem you're really trying to do your hypothesizing you're developing a
hypothesis to determine if you're actually going to provide value for some
person you could because tests of omission might occur so what often we do
as you know may have been a while since work on a commerce site but there's the
whole acquisition funnel people have to know about the site they have to come
to this site they have to put stuff into their cart then they have to check
out I'm just making this up on the fly so it's not great but if you're
actually so there's do you have an audience and maybe we're getting 10,000
visitors a day and that seems obvious like you know well then why aren't we
getting more sales we can go one more step down the acquisition funnel and I
think you'd be better suited than writing a whole big automated test suite
of course you want to test the happy path to make sure people can put stuff
in their cart and enter credit carding and get it checked out and get added to
a shipping queue but monitoring it every stage of your of your funnel every
decision point they can make from this is where you can do your experiments
and your A.B. testing and your monitoring sorry experiments and A.B.
testing are the same thing but you want to look at every decision point from when
they enter the site to where do they find because they have to go through a
half a dozen decisions or more until they check out and they put money in your
in your bank account to see where they may be failing where they may be
falling off maybe anyone with a maybe you have a bad regex weirdness and
anybody with a two digit two digits for the first part of their IP address can't
check out or something stupid like that you maybe you discover that there but
there could be all kinds of things that go wrong where monitoring is and focusing
on customer value and that acquisition funnel is the right thing to do user
journey funnels I like that name I like that name of user journey funnel
is that a real thing can I look that up it user journey user funnels there I've
heard user journey and I call it the acquisition funnel but a user funnel or
journey funnels so there's there there's acquisition funnels there's there are
retention funnels or their churn churn they call funnels but they're really
anti funnels because you're trying to prevent people getting to the bottom of
those funnels I thought at the bottom they check out and make money not with a
churn funnel a churn funnel right it depends on yeah okay fine whatever or
for example support a support thing you would you would look at sort of key
sequences and you're trying to get them to not go to the next level right it's
I frame it normally as an anti funnel because I think it's clear but yeah if
the top of your funnel is has a higher rate and let's say you know your
favorite host of deities were the ones responsible for the testing like their
codes bug-free then you you still have you have something worse you have you
have a problem solution mismatch some place in your system that you need to go
fine I think the meta point before we close on this is you have to go and
go back to what you said earlier focus on the problem you're solving for the
customer and then determine what you need to do in order to know if you're
solving that problem correctly right right testing again I'm not saying don't
do testing testing is great for regressions mitigating risks there's
lots of reasons for it please please please please please don't think of it
as the end goal of your quality efforts it actually just agreed and sorry I'm
gonna go back to one last thing I just thought of it a perfect example for your
scenario where you could have a situation bug-free and a high attraction
rate okay when you sign up people for a trial ask them for a credit card number
right that just pisses people off asking them for a credit card number for a
free trial oh I could do fingernail subscriptions fingernail clipper
subscriptions yeah I get the credit card yeah no I know but this is again
why you will get much higher quality if you get to that culture of experimentation
and hypothesis around what you're delivering to see if it's providing if
it's solving the problem you intended to solve the fact that you ran 10,000
testament mean you well there was the Eric Ries quote if you show me a product
that's bug-free I'll show you a product that shipped three months too late yeah
I don't know if it's three months but it certainly should play so yeah that
all comes into play there too so I want to bring all that together into that
conversation we are out of time but this was fun yeah we will come back in a
couple weeks and talk about personality types a little bit more but that'll be
fun and was there anything else I was gonna say see ya okay then see ya
Brent says see ya bye bye everybody