We need to have everybody gradually moving along on this trajectory to not need the testing
specialist anymore. But you might not ever get there. You might get there. And if you do get
there, that doesn't mean that testers are out of work because believe me, there are plenty of other
places that still need software testers. Welcome to AVE testing podcast, your modern
testing podcast. Your hosts, Alan and Brent will be here to guide you through topics on testing,
leadership, agile, and anything else that comes to mind. Now on with the show.
Hey, good everyone. I'm Alan. I'm Brent. I should unmute.
And we have a guest. We do.
Say hi, Kristen. Hello.
We have Kristen Jackvone. On the podcast this week, we're going to talk about all kinds of
testing stuff, but we should, I should just let you plug yourself. So maybe we can start with this.
So Kristen, you're here for a good reason to talk about something very exciting and important
you've done recently. But just say, introduce yourself and talk about your thing and we'll
go from there. Okay. So I am here to talk about the book that I published in December.
And the name of that book is The Complete Software Tester,
concept, skills, and strategies for high quality testing. And it aims to be sort of a one-stop
shop to help you with all kinds of testing things, manual testing, automated testing,
API testing, testing strategy, performance testing, mobile testing. It's really, that's why it's called
The Complete Software Tester. So I'm really excited about it. It's the culmination of a
couple of years worth of work. So yeah, I'm here to talk about it some more and answer your question.
And I have some, I have plenty of questions about it. I think Brent does too. I don't
know sure where to start. So there's a couple places I could start. One is, well, one, I skim
through the book. You're right. It is complete. I've always been a fan of the testing books that
were more broad and some stay very broad and are not pragmatic. And the ones that are pragmatic
are about one thing. And the thing that's great about yours, it's really cool, enough information
to kind of understand, oh, that's what you do there. Is that fair from your side? Because I have
a statement after that. Yeah, absolutely. And that was a lot of my motivation for writing the book in
the first place. I discovered software testing sort of late in life. I was almost 40 when I discovered
that software testing was a thing and that I wanted to do it. And I was so excited about it.
And I wanted to learn as much as I could. And I had a lot of trouble finding the information that
I needed. And a lot of times, if you don't know what you don't know, then you have no way to ask
questions about it. And just a perfect example would be something like working with a development
team and wanting to make a change to the code. And the developer says to you, well, we'll just
pull down the repo and make some changes and then do a PR. It's like, what? What does that even mean?
Like, what's a repo? What's a PR? And so the book is really aiming to kind of give you like a
starting point for a whole lot of different things so that then people can go on from the book and
know what kinds of questions they need to ask to learn further. Which gets to my point, which
isn't the intent of your book, but it's the way I'm going to use it when I give copies away. So
you have a section in your book where you talk about a couple of pages about what will we still
need software testers, which I want to go to in a minute, because I think you're largely right.
But you may have heard the story I told a few times on the podcast when I was coaching
a team at Unity that did not have dedicated software testers on how to write
developers how to do testing. The VP would ask me, how is the dev team doing at testing? And I say
they do all the tests they know how to do. They had unconscious incompetence. They could test the
stuff they could think of, but they just didn't really think of the things you outline in your
book. And I think this is actually, while not what you intended, I think this is an excellent
book to get maybe it was you can tell me, this is going to be an excellent book to give
developers to help them understand all the different ways they can test the thing they're
building. Yes, absolutely. And I think maybe on my description of it on Amazon, I might even say
that that that software developers, I'm not sure it's been a while since I wrote it now. But
yeah, that's something that we've been working on at Paylocity, which is the company where I work,
because we've been working on an initiative to really have the whole team own quality
and developers can get very nervous about that. What I need to test, what does that even mean?
And so, yeah, so this would be an excellent tool for that.
So maybe, I'm glad you feel that way too. I think it's a great way because Brent,
actually, I don't know what Brent does, but I worked with a lot of teams that don't have
dedicated testers, but it doesn't mean they don't do testing. They do a lot of testing.
Why do we still need dedicated testers?
I think there are a few reasons. One is that teams change. So you might have a team that
is just working swimmingly. There's no dedicated testers. Everybody knows exactly what to do.
Everybody works cooperatively together. But then somebody new comes onto the team,
and that really changes the whole team dynamic. So you might need to have somebody focused on
testing at that point to help that new person acclimate. Another thing is that the technology
changes. So let's say, for example, you've got a team and they're doing a whole bunch of stuff
with Azure, and then they decide that they need to lift and shift their entire platform over to AWS
instead. Well, that's going to require different testing. And so while the team is figuring out
how to do that, having a dedicated tester could be something that would help with the transition.
So yeah, I think those are some of the big reasons.
So can I ask a clarification on that one? Because what I heard you mention is dedicated tester,
but in your two scenarios were ephemeral in nature. Was that by design?
Ephemeral is in. I'm not providing like a concrete example of something.
No. So for example, I'm going to distinguish like your AWS example. I'm going to distinguish
between a dedicated tester versus dedicated testing is needed. And we need people to do that.
And in ephemeral fashion, meaning it's going to be timebox, it's not going to continue.
Did you make that distinction on purpose? Is there a role of a place or do you summarize
the places where you feel a dedicated tester in a more permanent scenario?
Okay. Yeah, I think I guess my feeling is that a lot of teams just aren't mature enough to be able to
handle all of the testing without that person that thinks about how to test things. And I think
that's the skill set that testers really bring is that testers love thinking about what can go
wrong with this. What are all of the really horrible things that could happen? And how can we test
for those? I think that developers can do that. And certainly developers can be trained to do that.
But most teams, they're trying to deal with tech debt. They're trying to churn out features and meet
the business requirements that are put upon them. They might not have the time or even the skills
to do that. So I think it's like they're sort of a testing nirvana where everybody understands
exactly what needs to be done and how to do it. But how many of us are really going to get there?
Some of us. Maybe not all of us, at least not right now.
Yeah, I think that's a good way to see it. It's not exactly what we've talked about with a test
coach, but kind of somebody there to kind of help people. And I've been in that role before
myself and there is value there. So yes, oh, by the way, and it's my mistake, I actually just kind
of flipped through the forward again of your book where you actually do explicitly say this book
could be for developers, too. So good. See, I didn't remember. You didn't even know I asked a dumb question.
Yeah, no, I so that's one thing I adore. I do think so. Like I
were not doing live stream. So the podcast won't see this. But one of the questions I wrote down
is, OK, I wanted to explore sort of this idea around the tester mindset. And I think I think
Chris and I don't want to put words in your mouth, but I think you'll say, yeah, there is a tester
mindset, but not in the way that is often described when those terms are used. That that in other
words, I don't think you would argue that this tester mindset is exclusive to testers.
Right. Yeah. It does can be trained. And as Alan just pointed out, it's in the forward.
And then in your last your last answer to the question, you mentioned that it's going to be
based on the maturity of the team. And you also mentioned you're a huge proponent. Well,
I don't think you said huge, but a proponent of whole team. Yes. And so
a dedicated tester specialist, I think you're going to say you're going to argue, hey, it's going to
be based on business needs. And sometimes you're going to need it because the business needs it
because they have a gap that needs to be filled. Right. But I think you would. Well, you tell me
instead of me constantly telling you your words, how about I ask you a question about that, Brett?
Yeah, that that that might make for a better interview long term. Where do you see it going?
I think, well, one thing that that has made me so happy over the last couple of years,
working where I do is to see the quality of software testers that we have been hiring.
And those those testers have a lot of coding skills and they have a lot of I guess I'll call
it nontraditional testing skills for the lack of a better word, but like they know about security
testing. They know about performance testing. And so what I'm seeing is that we're starting
to develop what I will call a full stack tester. That's a tester who understands accessibility
testing, security testing, load testing. They know how to help shepherd a release through on release
night. They can go in there and make changes to the code when they need to. Like if there's
like an accessibility item that that needs to be worked on, like, oh, you know, we're missing a
tag here or something like that, they can go in and they can make those changes. They can
put together entire frameworks. So I'm imagining that that sort of what's going to happen is
like emerging where the testers are getting better and better and better at more technical
and more development related things, whereas the developers are getting better and better and
better at the testing things. So that's what I would imagine for the future, but I do not have
a crystal ball and things could change radically. Who knows? Go ahead, Alan. No, I want your
reaction, Brent, because you know, I wholly agree with that. Yes. Right. And as a matter of fact,
I would say in general, what we did here at Microsoft kind of followed that pattern.
Right. You merge it. Then then you still have to sort of get stuff done
in this new reality. And I think over time, people generalize. Right. So
Kristen's a listener. That's what I've been informed. I don't know how many episodes she's
listened to, but I assume you're aware of the modern testing principles that we've.
OK, I guess based off of this, principle number seven, this is the one that sort of Alan's
question line of questioning has been on. Where did we get that wrong?
I don't think you did get it wrong. I will definitely say that a few years ago, and I
can't remember how many years ago it was that I first became acquainted with the modern testing
principles. I was reading through them and I was number one, number two, like, yeah, yeah,
this is great. I love this. And I got to seven and I was like, this is oh, my God,
they're talking about getting rid of testers. And it took me a long time. And it took me
listening to your podcast to to really think about it. And I realized that
the wrong thing to do would be to read this and say we don't need testers anymore
because then you're going to wind up with with applications that suck. Like,
what we need is we need to have everybody gradually moving along on this trajectory to
not need the testing specialist anymore. But, you know, you might not ever get there.
You might get there. And if you do get there, that doesn't mean that testers are out of work,
because believe me, there are plenty of other places that still need software testers. I know
because every time I interact with an application, you know, I'm filling out a form to order
something or whatever, and I discover the pop up doesn't work right or or I can't get
to the button I need to click like that. We're going to need testers for a long, long time.
You've seen the light on this and you get it exactly right. And Brent knew this. He asked
a very leading question because everything you talked about before described that the principle
seven says it may reduce or eliminate the need for dedicated testing specialists because it may.
And a lot of times it does. But what we really want to do there is get rid of
a dedicated specialist as a bottleneck and at the point where you're there to
advise and look into some of the the areas that even a good developer tester may not get to
being there for those things. There's there's plenty to do there. And I'm a big fan of the
of that sort of role. And I just flipped it a little bit farther. Like we have,
I think I mentioned on the podcast, I have a small team of people who function as quality coaches,
most like much like you said, being dedicated on one team, they bounce around a little bit.
Sometimes they consult for the really little mini consultant team. Sometimes they consult for
an hour, half a day, a day. One person has been embedded on a team for three months to help them
bootstrap some automation, just whatever they need to help them build that testing knowledge.
Maybe instead of consulting, I can send them copies of your book.
But yeah, I think everything you've talked about says that you have seen past the words on a page
on the page, which can be scary around principle number seven and actually have figured out what
that means in practice. It's not scary. And it's not a definitive like we're getting rid of testers
is you just actually make it so good at making software quality software from the beginning
that dedicating someone to testing all the time would be a waste.
I absolutely believe that a tester specialist today, a traditional tester specialist,
if they invest in what we are, if they invest in understanding and what we're talking about
in the modern testing and festivals, they will not only be excited about the removal of
or the potential removal of a testing specialist. What I've observed in the industry,
every time we go through the cycle and we improve, that individual becomes a lot more valuable.
And I've said, actually, Kristen, you just brought up it. You believe that there's an eventual
merging of these things. Have you actually observed that yet in practice?
Well, I have a fun story to tell you about one of the teams at my company, and I'm going to give
the shout out to the core platforms team just in case they're listening today. So this was a team
of developers. They do as their name suggests, they do a lot of sort of back end stuff. They
they deal with caching and with API governance and with messaging, that kind of thing. And so they
had formed this team. They really wanted a software tester. And it just was not in the cards.
Budget wise, they were told, no, you can't have a tester. So my role at the company is really to
help all of the teams adopt quality practices. And so I met with them and they said, well,
what are we going to do? Well, one of the other things that they wanted to work on was
eliminating silos because they've got a lot of really smart people on their team. Each one of
them was an expert in one of these different areas. And they really wanted to make sure that
it wasn't just one person, they were they were all experts so that someone could go on
vacation and not get called up in Hawaii. Hey, our caching system isn't working correctly. Can
you help us? So I suggested that they form testing buddies so that each one of them as the feature
expert and the one that was doing most of the dev work would be paired with one of the other
people. And that person would do the testing. And in the process of doing the testing,
not only would they learn about being a better tester, but they would also learn about the
other product that they were testing. And so they tried that out and that worked really well for
them. And then the other thing, the other idea that they came up with on their own was they
decided that they needed to have a test application, one that was different from what's running in
production, that they could try out all kinds of things on sort of like a sandbox to say,
let's run all of our tests against this and see what happens when we when we make those changes.
And so they've been working on that. And they're really excited about that. And they've come up
with some other testing frameworks to for observational purposes to see things like,
you know, are they getting any message loss when the messages are going out? So I'm really excited
and happy for them about the innovation that they've had together. And so now they're proving
they don't need a tester. They can solve these problems themselves. Yeah, that's, that's a
fantastic story. It's essentially one of the things that what is it? Necessity is the mother
of invention, right? If you if you set the stage in a way, like you told the story like, no, you're
not getting a tester. And no, you are going to continue to have the expectation of high quality
outputs, right? Well, then you figure out how to solve it. The the other thing I was trying to
get to is we talked about you you predicted that you predicted that over time you see sort of
tests becoming more devish and then dev becoming more test ish. And I'm wondering,
have you have you experienced any sort of ecosystem of that occurring? I have I'm just
curious. I have a question on that. I'm curious if you have experienced that yet. Well, one one
thing that I've seen, we had a push this year to get involved in accessibility testing. That's
something that's very important. The company where I work, we we do payroll software and we and, you
know, time cards and things like that we want to make sure that all of our users are going to be
able to use the application. And so teams started doing some testing, and we had a group of three
testers who got very interested in accessibility testing. And as they were learning about it,
they discovered just how easy it is to solve some of those accessibility problems, like to put in
like an alt image tag or to put in other descriptions or to change the level of headers.
Apparently, that's important for screen readers. So as they were learning these things,
they also realized these are simple changes that we know how to make. So they were going in
to their team software and they were making all of the changes and doing the pull request and getting
the approval and getting those changes pushed through. So I think that that's sort of the
tip of the iceberg. I think we're going to continue to see more things like that as we go forward.
Nice. And I think the second part of your question was the devs becoming more like testers.
We actually had one dev we switched over recently to using Cyprus for for UI automation. And now
we're moving into API automation with Cyprus as well. And we had one developer who was so excited
about Cyprus that he switched over to become a software test engineer instead. So I think,
you know, we'll see some of that as well. Well, that I'll just say this and I can have Jason
Huggins yell at me later. That doesn't happen with Selenium.
I don't know that I don't know that we'll inspire Huggins to come and try to yell at us again.
So that was fun. We I was just thinking about the same thing. No. So one of the things that I've
observed, Chris, and is that when you push what I've observed in my prior histories is that testers
becoming dev, even though they don't have sort of the history on like the the O of one algorithms and
such. I find I have found and it may be subjective bias. That's what I was testing. I have found that
they end up being superior developers. Oh, yeah, I was just going to say I've seen I've seen that
before too. I've seen testers switch over to be developers and contribute greatly to projects.
The other thing that I've seen that I really like is testers who switch over to be managers.
And those managers really understand what it means to have the whole team on quality.
So here's here's another example from from my workplace. Someone I worked with, hello,
Monica, was a tester and she became a manager of a team and she instituted sort of a process
right before the team releases. They all do exploratory testing together. All of them,
developers and testers are all doing that exploratory testing. And so what happened
with that was the testers were teaching the developers here are the things that you need
to look for when you're testing. And then the developers were also learning more about the
product too, because sometimes the developers can kind of get involved, like with one little section
of code and they're not really looking at the whole picture. So they were really seeing the
big picture. And so all of them working together found great bugs before they released. And so,
yeah, I think that testers make great managers. I definitely think that putting the tester in
a manager role, if you're going to go with a unified engineering model, they're going to
think about the whole system in the end. Yeah, testers, people who have spent time in testings
tend to be more systems thinkers, not universally true, but that's my experience in general.
One thing we've talked about a lot here, not directly, but I'm going to call it out is,
you know, you've been in testing since 2009. So I think long enough where maybe you cut the tail
end of the testers versus developers, but there's none of that when you're talking about it. That's,
I like to think in most companies, although for what I read on Twitter, it's not true, but
I think at least a lot of companies, maybe most companies are past that and it's a collaboration.
I think that's helps, but I wanted to talk about a tweet that I did this week, nothing to do with
your book, but I want you to tell a story from your book based on this. So I ran across yet
another, I won't even say where I got it, because I'll probably piss somebody off, but yet
another complaint about manual versus automated testing and labels, labels, labels. So I tweeted,
the coolest thing that happens when developers own all of their own testing is that all the
arguments around manual versus automated versus exploratory versus whatever all go away.
Because it's all just testing. And before I have you tell hope, remember the story you told from
this chapter in your book. One of the thing again, is isn't we're having, we're having
Kristen on the podcast. She can talk about the book. We're not like, we don't, we're not,
we're going to, we're going to talk up your book because it's good. But the, one of the things I
like it and brain, you would like it too, because you have the attention span of, of this
piece of cloth right here and the book, you want to sit down and read a chapter of the book. You
can be done like in 30 seconds, a minute or two, depending on the chapter. It's all little bite
size chunks. So chapter like 564, I'm making this up, is on the whole manual versus automated debate.
And I liked the way you just call bullshit on it. So do you remember the story from there?
Do you want to share that? Yeah, I'm not sure if it's a story, but, well, it's not really a
story, but the anecdotes you shared, like, yeah, the three software testers, Marsha,
yeah, yeah. And then yeah. All right. So I actually, I have the book open here so that I can
remember all the details. Marsha is the software developer and test. So she's very proud of her
automation skills. And she sees, you know, the feature that that's coming down the pike. And
she says, Oh, I know just what to do with this. And so she writes a whole bunch of automation
and makes sure that, you know, everything's running and, you know, the feature is released and all of
her tests are running and passing and isn't it awesome, but she didn't pay a whole lot of
attention to the acceptance criteria. So as a result, she missed one really important use case.
And now there are end users who are seeing errors when they use the application because
she completely missed that. And so then we've got Cindy, who's the manual tester.
Cindy read all of the requirements very, very carefully. And she came up with a very elaborate
test plan where she's manually testing everything, but because she's doing everything manually,
she can't keep up with the frequent software releases that the team is doing. So, you know,
the team is saying, okay, well, I just, I pushed some code here. Can you check it out? And it's
like a day and a half before she's done with all of the testing and the developers want feedback
right away. They want to know, did I break something? I don't want to know a day and a
half from now. I want to know now. So then we've got Jan, Jan's there in the middle.
And she does both. Jan is reading the requirements, the acceptance criteria. She is interacting with
the application to really understand how it works as a system. And then she's creating automated
testing that is going to be sensible and is going to reflect all of the acceptance criteria and all
the use cases that she's discovered. And so as a result, that means that the developers can
make the changes and push the code and know right away if they've broken anything.
Yeah.
So which one should you be? Should you be a manual tester or an automated tester?
Marsha, Marsha, Marsha.
You should be Jan. Another thing I say in the chapter two is that like, I mean,
what does automated mean really? Like if somebody writes a script, like if I, if I need a whole
bunch of like users in my system to test with and I write a script to like put them all in the system
really fast, does that make me an automated tester now? I mean, I made a tool or I did a process
and then like if I'm creating test automation and I push a button to run the test automation and I
now a manual tester, like these distinctions are not important. What really matters.
Right. That's exactly it.
The what's getting tested is what should be getting tested.
On one hand, I get the argument like we stopped calling it manual testing and they're absolutely
right. Yeah.
The problem with the automated and manual discussion, in my humble opinion, is the industry
is moving in a place where again, a lot of this stuff is shifting to development.
I grew up in my career. I've had multiple people like I am a manual tester and I love this job
and I am never changing. Really? What if the industry changes to put you in a position? How
about now? You get right. And so what I see is a lot of these discussions are really my sense of it.
I'm a data scientist now. I have not done a scientific study on this, but my sense of it is
no, it's more of a justification or a rationalization of this is the value we had. But honestly,
it's no different than in the traditional way, the justification we've always had.
Like, like I remember a conversation I had with James, James Whitaker, and we're talking about
what's the ROI of tests. He and I had this over lunch and he's like,
oh, well, if you want to know what the ROI of test is, just get ready your testers and then
you'll see. Well, you know what? 20 years ago, I would have been clear today. A lot of companies,
you know what? I think his statement probably still kind of describes it because you got,
in today's world, you got rid of all your testers and nothing changed. That might indicate that no,
no, no, that's that wasn't things have changed. Right. In terms of in terms of the labels,
I actually think there should be no such thing as automated or manual tester,
automated and manual testing.
Even that's hard. So let me take that and build on that and actually talk about a twist on this,
this last story for the book. Like if I push a button in my manual, if I write a script to
generate stuff or am I an automation engineer, there are, and this is a rant that I've made
before and I'll make it again. There are hundreds, I would say thousands, tens of thousands. I don't
know how many test automation engineers and they are happy with their job of writing
automated Selenium tests all day long. The data show from Nicole Forest was working at Accelerate
that developers owning their own automated tests produce higher quality software. Does that mean
testers write a work? No, because this thing you described like writing a script to generate,
like, oh, I want to generate a bunch of names to test with. I want to generate
a bunch of input strings to put here, whatever. That is a more, for me, that is a more valuable
use of any sort of coding knowledge than writing a gazillion. Is that a number of rent?
They're writing a gazillion Selenium tests. It's what Merit talks about, like exploratory
automated testing. We're going to use the tools to help us get to a state where maybe we can
learn something interesting about the software. That is the kind of thing I want people who are
doing dedicated software testing to be. Ideally, developers do it too, but that's where the magic
happens. You people, and again, I'm not talking to you because nobody, nobody who writes Selenium
tests all day and loves it is listening to this podcast because they've already turned us off and
deleted us from the internet years ago, but there's something there.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. That reminds me, oh, I just totally spaced on what it was that I wanted to say.
Oh, hey, Brett, she's one of us. We do this all the time.
It's related to, oh, I know what it was. Okay. So at my company, we hire what I consider to be full
stack software testers. So those software testers need to know how to find bugs. And they also
need to know how to write automation that could help guard against regressions. So we actually have
a two-step process that it took us a little while to refine this, but the very first thing we do
when we have a software tester come in and be interested in interviewing with us, we give them
an application. It's a buggy application. It's got UI bugs. It's got API bugs. And we just say to them,
find all the bugs you can in this application and just write up a bug report in just whatever
style you would want to do to communicate to us what the bugs are. And then we have a scoring
rubric and we measure, did they find one point bugs? Did they find three point bugs? And it
never ceases to amaze me the inability of these people that can write Selenium tests,
but they can't find the bugs. There was one person who liked it.
Because they don't know anything about testing.
Yes, yes, exactly. 13 years of testing experience. We had a candidate who could only find three bugs
in the application. It's just, it's amazing. But yeah, I mean, that's really the most important
thing is that mindset to be able to say, what can go wrong here? What could I try here?
So yeah, yeah, I don't know. Yeah. Anyway, same rant repeated. But it reminds me a little bit and
Microsoft, I was of course at Microsoft for a long time. For many years there, I was called
was called an as app interviewer as appropriate, which I was at the end of the loop. I was the
person said, are they a good Microsoft fit? Can they do the job? And sometimes it was just
selling them if it was somebody who'd done really well on the on the interview loop. And sometimes
it was sometimes it was breaking the tie, kind of figuring out and those were fun too. And sometimes
actually, if they wouldn't even come to me if they were if they were no hires down the road.
But one thing that kind of blew me away, it's not similar to testing. These weren't all testing
roles. But in Microsoft, at least at the time, it's probably still true. Most of their hiring
has been right out of college, do a lot of hiring adventure level and then grow them through
the system. One thing that was interesting, like here, like, and I want to the topic I want
to get to around this is I am not a computer science major, neither is Christian. In fact,
we have a very similar major, but we'll get to that in a moment is I would be the one
interviewing these MIT folks and and Stanford or and sometimes not always app or stage these very
well educated people who were geniuses at the algorithmic computer science level,
but did not have the ability to think their way outside of a bag. High intelligence, low wisdom
for you, D&D players. And it was I see a parallel there. Like I would say even someone without
testing experience who kind of could see the forest for the trees would be able to find,
you know, they could fake their way through that part. But the fact that we have people
in testing positions doing testing all day, but they're not really doing testing,
does not surprise me. They would fail miserably there. Yeah, yeah. Well, and and that's that's
another interesting thing about the testing profession is that software testing is not
taught in college. I deal with a lot of new college grads because we do a lot of recruiting and we
recruit them as soft as software engineers. And I get to spend a whole day with them and teach them
about software testing. And one of the things I do is I ask them, what did you learn about
software testing? What kinds of software testing did you do? And generally, the answer is we learned
how to write unit tests. And that's it. They didn't learn how to think about anything else. And I
start my day with them by just showing them a little picture. It's just a field, an empty field
and a button. And I say, how would you test this? And, you know, sometimes it's fun to watch them,
because sometimes they'll go to write like SQL injection, you know, like right away. But but
sometimes they'll they'll start to think about, oh, well, you know, well, what if we had too many
characters in the field? And what if we didn't have enough characters in the field? And I say,
okay, well, what what if it's a phone number? And then they start thinking about all the
different things that they could test with the phone number. And hopefully they realize
that phone numbers are different lengths in different countries. Yes, absolutely. Yes. And
they usually do come up with that. So that's good. But but yeah, I mean, and that's another
reason why I wrote the book is because nobody's teaching software testing in college. Right. And
and I actually don't maybe there should there shouldn't be I do not believe there should be a
software testing degree, there should be a software testing course that, you know, computer
science is a lot about it may not cover that. But if there's a software engineering degree at
a college, definitely should have testing you and I and Brent, excuse us, we alienate you,
maybe, maybe, Brent, I don't know how many people you know, who studied music in college
and found their way into tech, but there's of the three people on this podcast that is true
for two of them. What was your path? So tell me how you got from music into tech.
Well, it's it's an interesting story. So I'm old enough that when I was in high school, it didn't
like computer science didn't really even occur to me as being a thing I would be interested in
doing like I took one computer course, the only computer course that the high school offered.
But I didn't, you know, this was before there was a thing called the internet where everybody
could communicate and their pretty pictures and and all that. So I never thought that that
computer science would be a thing for me. So I became a music teacher mostly because I couldn't
come up with something else to do. I mean, I liked music and I liked children. So that seemed like
the way to go. So I like music, but I didn't like children. Actually, so I also taught school.
Actually, I liked children. I taught middle school, but I didn't like the other teachers.
Yeah, yeah. So yeah, so I was a music teacher for a while. I left the I was an elementary school music
teacher. I left that profession when I had my son. And then I taught piano lessons at home for a while.
And then I became a church organist and choir director. Then around the same time that I
was starting to lose interest in that area. I also got divorced and I needed another source of
income. And I had no idea what I was going to do. And I thought, well, what am I good at? Well,
I'm organized. So maybe I could be a professional organizer. So I started a professional organizing
business. I did that for about a year, discovered I didn't like it at all. But that job led me to
being a support person in a tech startup. It was a tech startup that worked with mobile phones,
they needed somebody to keep track of all the mobile phones, make sure all the software was on it.
And so while I was doing that, I thought, this software stuff looks kind of fun, you know,
maybe I'd like to be a software developer. So I started taking courses at night to do that.
And then very early on into that, the job dried up. And I found myself needing another job. And I
thought, I don't have enough development skills yet to even get an internship as a developer. So
what else could I do? And so I started looking for like, tech writing. And then I discovered there
was a position open for an intern as a quality assurance engineer. And I thought, Oh, I think I
can do that. I did a little bit of testing in my previous role. So I'll do that. So I went to the
job. It was software that it was voice recognition software on Blackberry phones. This is before
Siri and all of that. And so I showed up on my first day and my supervisor gives me a test plan
to work through. And so I start working through the test plan. And I noticed something odd that
happens. And I oh, that's interesting. I want let me see if I can do that again. Yeah, that doesn't
look right. Well, what happens if I click this button instead, and I'm clicking the long and then
I said to myself, Oh, I should really stop playing with this phone and get back to work. And then
suddenly I realized this was my job. Like I was supposed to be playing with the phone. I was
supposed to be figuring out what was going on. And it was like the heavens opened. And I was like,
this is what I want to do for the rest of my life. Very cool. I also started off, I want to go
my whole story, but my first job in tech was support for in my case, I got out of grad school,
where I got a master's in composition, where I learned how to use computers pretty well,
didn't know anything about programming, but I got a job at a company doing
tech support for a company that made music software. I knew I knew the MIDI, I knew how
computers connected to musical devices really well. And then the rest I just kind of figured out.
Was it Finale? No, no. I own Finale. Finale is based in the Midwest, I believe. So I've
had a copy in the year, but it was a company called MIDI soft. Oh, okay. So this would have
been a little ahead of your time, because this was, they were mainly an OEM supplier, meaning when
you, in those days, you bought a sound card for your computer because computers didn't come with
those. And when you bought a sound card, it would come with some free software. And that's what we
made. Cool. Yeah, I know a lot of, a lot of great software testers who were French literature
majors in college or history majors or psych majors. Well, one thing to call out here is,
this is off topic, but on topic for this conversation for a long time. I was on,
they took a break for a while, but I was on the alumni board for my university school of arts and
humanities. Cause we're talking about the value of this liberal arts education. And people think
liberal arts, you'll never get a job. And I say college is not a vocational school. And what I
learned there, I learned so many things that apply directly to what I do every single day,
but I didn't learn a skill. I learned why I learned life skills. I learned aspects of leadership. I
learned how to problem solve, you know, this from learning how to play a piece of music. What do
you do? You break it down into little pieces. You take those little pieces and you isolate
them to figure out why they're so damn hard. And then you, you work on them, you kind of
put it all back together and then you're done. And that's similar to how we do problem solving
in tech. It's just different tools in front of us. Now you go to YouTube, you look at the video
and you just copy what they're doing with their hands. Yeah. That's pretty much it, Brent. Yeah.
That's there you go. Music, future music majors. I have saved you four years,
but the thing is, and I'll go into this, we can get to closing, but there's so much more to it.
Like playing the right notes is such an infinitesimal small part of being a musician.
A lot of times we work really hard to make things look easy, but it sounds like you maybe
were a piano major. I was a voice. Well, I was a music major with a concentration in voice.
I did play the piano also. So you know this from choir. It's like, it's like in playing in
ensembles to like listening. I think there's a parallel between listening and playing for
blend and pitch. That is very similar to how we communicate with people at work.
Yeah. And you know, I played a lot of different woodwind instruments when I was playing saxophone
in a jazz band. There are even subtle gestures you can make to get people to do something,
to get your section to do something different together. They just kind of pick up on those
things. And that's kind of where I equate that to little bits of coaching, like a little,
but even a little head nod in a meeting will make people feel like you're engaged.
It helps with engagement. So anyway, all kinds of little parallels I pick up on.
Brent, it's just so much more than pressing the right notes.
Well, and another thing that really benefited me from being an elementary school music teacher
is that I learned how to explain things to very small children. And because of that, I feel that
I'm adept at breaking things down into their simplest parts to then explain to other people,
including adults, including people who want to learn about testing.
You know what? I'm glad you brought that up because people have mentioned that to me before
that something that I do, I didn't even realize it, is I take people that have been in computers
their whole life often have a difficult time explaining technically what something is.
Often, I got some really nice feedback from one of our finance VPs that said,
Alan, it's just a really good job because I track a lot of our cost spending.
And say, Alan, it's just a really good job explaining these things in a way that we understand.
And it isn't that I'm trying to explain it to them in a way they understand.
I'm trying to explain it to them in a way I understand.
But yeah, I think that there is something there, learning or just having, you know,
from either teaching private lessons or studying privately, when you have a good instructor,
they have multiple ways to explain the same thing. They have different things they can try,
knowing that eventually one of them will resonate and you'll nail it.
So I think those skills are all great too.
Well, and they say that if you want to really understand something,
you ought to teach it to somebody else. And so that is one of the things that I'm doing with
this book also. I mean, it's funny, a lot of the chapters of my book are based on blog posts
that I've had over the years. And I actually go back and I look at my blog posts when I've
forgotten how to do something. So I'm like, thanks past me. Thanks for reminding me
what I'm supposed to do when I run into this problem.
I think that's the purpose of blog posts is like, okay, now I can free all that memory from my brain
and bring in new things. But it's interesting. Sorry, I'm going to go back to a thing with,
so I've known Alan forever, it seems. So we've talked on the podcast. He and I are in terms of
Myers Briggs, which is essentially an advanced horoscope, but he and I are essentially the same
type, but he has a bunch of talents that I don't have. It's not, I don't think it's associated.
Like he is an introvert. I am an introvert, but Alan in particular, he can generate energy in
a crowd of a community of like-minded folks. He's always been able to really do that. And one of
the things I'm now actually hypothesizing is I wonder, Alan, if your music degree is where that
came from, the ability to work with and collaborate with others, because in terms of like an orchestral
environment, I think both of you would likely argue that that's pretty critical.
Yeah, I do see the parallels there. What about you, Christian?
Definitely. And I just want to mention, I think it was a most recent podcast you were talking
about the Myers Briggs and saying that you were both INTPs. I am an INTJ.
Oh, a judger. I see what's going on now.
But yeah, I mean, I think sometimes people are surprised that I'm an introvert because they,
you know, I'm happy bubbly and hey everybody, let's do this. But I think a lot of that comes
from my music background. I mean, I did a little bit of musical theater and I took conducting
courses and I was able to lead and conduct a choir. So I think that those leadership things
probably come out of that. Yeah. I don't know about where you went to school, but one of the things,
and again, I can do it all, but it exhausts me. I'm tired at the end. But one of the things I
hated the most out of school was recital hour. Like sit there. Yeah. Okay. We call it convocation,
but an hour a week, every week of performances of students playing in front of the entire
music department, I would hate it when my teacher would say, you should sign up, play
that at convocation next week. I go, no, I don't want to. Yeah. I hated that too. And even when I
was a church organist, playing the organ is extremely difficult. It's more difficult than
playing the piano because you have to play a keyboard with your feet as well. And it was,
every single week I was just so terrified. So performance was never something that I enjoyed.
So I'm happy to speak publicly. I can do that. That doesn't bother me at all. But like having
actually played notes or sing while everybody is listening, I would really prefer not to do that.
It's interesting for me in terms of that. So I will often remind people introvert has
really does not like, um, means your energy from, right?
Shine away from people or public speaking ability is a common symptom for lack of a better. I don't
even want to call it symptom, but it's often associated with introversion, but it is not a
requirement. It's not a causal thing. Because I'm in it for, it doesn't mean I have, I don't have
the ability to speak to people, but I will tell you one thing for me, like I am no longer
uncomfortable talking in front of a crowd. I'll happily go in front of a crowd. No problem
whatsoever, except for one condition where I am the center of attention. Now it's not,
it's not a hypocrisy. Like when I'm, when I'm going and talking in front of a crowd,
I usually view it as whatever I'm presenting. That topic is the center of attention. And I
am just the conduit. But if I'm the center of attention, like put me in front of 200 people
to celebrate a birthday. Oh my God. I have a thousand things I need to do that day. That's
way higher priority, including like washing my dishes. I will run and hide for that environment.
So it's, so we got to close, but there is one thing I did want to share
so I didn't come from a music background. I came loser. Yeah. I just have three tech degrees. I'm
sorry, but I will just pass on. I have learned a way to hire testers in the face of schools.
Don't now it may not be a scalable way, but what I suggest in the past or what,
what I suggest, if you're going to go to school and you're, you're looking specifically for
testers, go talk to the department heads, go talk to the lab managers and find the students in,
in the computer science lab that everyone goes to, to debug the ones that have a reputation
for being excellent at debugging. Those are testers. Man. I love debugging. Me too.
Fricking love debugging. This to me, it's a puzzle. This is what went wrong. Yeah.
So when I was still was a tester, every time I got to send an email, Hey, I was looking at your code
to a developer. You have an off by one bug. Oh yeah. Oh, those just, I just, I adored those
because I'm like, really, dude, really? You got an off by one bug. Like really? Anyway. Yeah.
Those are fun. Let's close here. Uh, Kristen Jack, Voni. Yes. Super happy and excited to be on the
podcast. Thank you for all that your book, the complete software tester available on Amazon or
I guess other places where you can get books. It's awesome. I'm a big, I'm a fan of it. I like,
again, me, the big takeaways are I want to give it to developers and there's lots of little short.
It's just short snippets, but they're organized really well. It's, it's, you know,
I didn't read them all. I looked at, I kind of went through, looked at the headlines and
did my little homework here and, and, uh, I learned a lot. It's like, yes, this is
one of the most pragmatic, if not the most pragmatic testing book or comprehensive,
comprehensive pragmatism. I don't know something like that. Anyway, super excited.
All right. Well, it worked. It, it, that resonated with me. Um,
thanks for being on the podcast. Really appreciate it. Yes. Thank you, Kristen. Yeah.
Thanks for having me. All right. Thanks everybody for listening. We'll see you later. Bye.