Are you actually asking them these questions when you're hiring engineers about their ability to
do software testing? Because I think that is where you nip that in the bud.
Welcome to AVE Testing Podcast, your modern testing podcast. Your hosts, Alan and Brent,
will be here to guide you through topics on testing, leadership, Agile, and anything else
that comes to mind. Now, on with the show. I never know what to say at the beginning.
Hey, everyone. It's Alan. Don't you have a patented starting? Hey, everyone.
All right. That aside, we have another guest, a wonderful guest. We have
Annemarie. Annemarie, say hi. Hi. Hello, everyone. Nice to be here.
Well, I don't know about Brent. I'm ecstatic to have you here. This is, I think we're going to have
a really fun conversation and get to know, I have so many curious questions, which I've
shared with you in advance. Well, in advance by meaning, you know, 30 seconds ago.
And I'm fully, I'm fully prepped, right? If you were a color, what color would,
Can I answer that? No. Yeah. And that was for Brent. Teal. Teal. Teal. Teal. Teal's an excellent choice.
Teal's an excellent choice. Now, the going back to, so number one, your last name is pronounced
Sherritt. Well, it's actually Charritt as in carrot. So, yeah. Yeah. That's a common thing.
I like Sherritt better. It sounds more, more inclusive. Oh, like Sherritt. Oh, good. Exactly.
Exactly. Oh my. The first person who's actually come up with that. So, you know,
I'm going with that. I am Sherritt from now on.
Oh,
and Alan, you're going to ding me on that. And you started off with what's her color. Oh my God.
Okay. No. So I'll just say it's a joy having you on this. I had not, I'll be. So I know Alan and
Anne-Marie have a, have, have crossed paths. We've interacted over the internet together and we
figured out that we've met once. Up until, so I knew that I knew nothing about Anne-Marie
until a couple of years ago, when Lisa Crispin came on and expressed that Anne-Marie is someone
that the world should be paying attention to. So I have started doing so since then.
Well, that's current very kind, very kind of Lisa as well.
Anne-Marie for the, and I'm going to guess, so here's the, what's the name of the bias? We have,
we have the audience bias. There's a better name for that. Everyone who listens to our podcast
probably already knows who you are, but on the off chance and the people that should know who
you are don't listen to our podcast. So we have a bit of a conundrum, but in the off chance,
we have a new version of our three listeners this time. We're going to get to a lot to get
to know you. Maybe a quick introduction. Like I think you may have noticed Anne-Marie has an
accent to like where you're from, what your role is, what you do, just a little blur, the elevator
pitch. I'll do my best. It keeps changing. So I totally realize it's not up to date anymore.
Yeah. So, Irish born and bred, moved to Australia in the early 90s, which gives you some idea of
my amount of experience I have in the industry. Basically came here for a year and much to my
mother's disgust, fell in love with an Australian and I've been here ever since. So yeah, but from a
software testing quality perspective, really came out of uni as electronic engineer and first job
ended up as you do a software tester and just loved it. Just, you know, I was testing protocols
which can be, seem really, really dry to a lot of people, but I was testing protocols for the
European commission and what I found fascinating was, you know, you would get a conformance to a
protocol and then when you connect to the two devices together, they didn't work. So it's like,
this was just fascinating for me and suddenly a whole heap of questions about why and, you know,
and I guess ever since then I've just been asking those questions. Why, how come,
what's going on? You know, how do I pull this apart? And I really enjoyed it and I keep thinking
about what else I could do in my life and I haven't come up with another answer. I desperately
wanted to think about other things I could do with my career. I keep coming back to software
testing and quality because I just really, really enjoy the topic. It's a fascinating topic for me.
Quality coaching is something I guess that is evolved. I'm all about evolution. I'm all about
learning and growing and as long as I learn and grow, I'm a happy person and quality coaching for
me is a natural evolution of, you know, where the software testing role has come to. When you work
in the industry, when you work and you see how people develop software, it makes sense. Like,
you've got to work with the way software is being developed today and the role of quality
coach is really just an evolution of that. And how can we think about quality and how can we,
you know, provide support to the teams that are developing quality is just massively important.
It's a really challenging role, as you both know. It's, but it's a really interesting role to see if
you can actually make that difference without actually being in the mix, so to speak. So
that's where I'm at. I'm at culture at the moment. I recently took a decision to go
and work in the industry. Again, I really enjoy going back and kind of getting into the mix and
working at the co-face. So I'm just doing that at the moment, building a bit of a team there
and really enjoying it actually. It's great. I have a question I want to get to, but now
I have more questions. It's fun. So are you a, is your role quality coach or part quality coach
at culture amp? I am. I guess the quality coach of quality coaches, I mean, the official title
is director of quality engineering, but the really, the, the, the actual thing is how,
how can we transition to a quality coach model? Okay. Quality coach quality.
Unity are a customer of culture amp, by the way.
Yay. I know. Yes. Yes. Cause we look at all the stats.
So I just for, uh, and again, this is not a dig on Microsoft as I usually do, but, uh, there comes
a point in the size of a company where it's just cheaper to build your own than pay a license for
200,000 people. So I for, oh, a quick culture amp is the equivalent Brent of MS poll. Gotcha.
Companies our size actually outsourced that to companies that can give us a lot,
make us work a lot better for us. So anyway, very cool. Um, I think there was a time,
you know, I don't know how long you've been listening, but, uh, Brent and I just for context,
uh, we started talking this podcast maybe seven years ago, eight years ago,
almost eight years ago now. And it was really because we were seeing a lot of changes
happening in testing. We were seeing teams move to using, and of course, agile has been around
a lot longer than eight years teams were moving in directions where they needed fewer testers and
sometimes choosing not to have testers sometimes executing that very well and sometimes very poorly.
And we paid attention to why and what worked. And really, we were just trying to talk about
the changes so that the testers listened to our podcast could understand what may be coming their
way. And along the way, you know, I moved, well, I guess the first time that maybe I was in any
role, you could call a quality coach, like maybe it was a science project after Xbox where we
didn't have any testers on the team. I didn't think of myself as a quality coach at that time.
I just helped developers learn how to test. And then I did it again on another team and
then did it again at unity and thought, wait a minute, this is a thing. And it maybe wasn't
until unity, I started at unity, I reread agile testing and all this stuff I thought I had
figured out on my own. I realized that Janet and Lisa had written about several years before.
It's kind of like modern testing. It's a given a name to something people, a lot of people
were already doing. It's not that modern, not really about testing. It was the same thing
reading that book. And when they talked about, I care about the exact text in my copies right
over there, I won't pull it out. Obviously, I'm not as prepared as I should be. But
they talked about the role of the test manager is to run a community, highly paraphrased,
but pretty close community was the word. And that was a big insight for me. And then
a lot of what I did for my first team at unity was I came in as a director of QA.
And I had a lot of embedded folks, your typical matrix organization,
QA reported to me, but they were embedded in teams. And often, as unfortunately happens in
some agile teams and many of the teams, they're responsible for all the testing on the team,
which isn't a great way to do agile testing, as we know on this call. So I ended up coaching
in two ways. I coach the testers on how to coach quality on the teams they work with.
But I also coach the developers, the dev leads they worked with on how to work with them in a new way.
And eventually, eventually, I moved all of them onto those teams directly, I didn't have a team
anymore. And so I, which, as Brent knows, I've worked myself out of jobs before. And I usually
recover pretty well, I found other things to do. They've always involved quality coaching,
to some extent, now I do a bunch of more stuff as well. So, and somewhere in there,
we started talking about quality coaching on the podcast, it's a thing. But what's interesting is
we talk about it like just sort of abstractly, but then it's not because we mentioned it at all.
You know, serendipitously, at the same time, there were quality coaches spinning up all over
the globe, you know, you're not the only one, there's plenty of people doing it, I think you
write the most about it. And I will put your blog site into your website into the show notes,
but you've written a lot about different aspects of quality coaching. As far as I know,
you've thought more about the role and the needs of quality coaching more than anybody has, you
know, way more than Brent and I have. And maybe there's somebody else out there haven't heard of
yet, but you've done a lot. But you hinted at this before, what I'm curious is some more
specifics, like how did you, like, what was that transition like? Was it gradual? Was it all of a
sudden? Was there a eureka moment? How did you go from caring about quality and managing test teams
to moving to becoming a quality coach? And like, great question. Yeah, look, yeah. Well, you know,
I think, I think this is, you've touched on so many things I want to address here.
The first thing is, it is absolutely an evolution. I don't think, you know, unless you come from a
marketing aspect or as in your consulting firm that wants to name something, you come in,
you evolve because you're learning and growing as the organizations are learning and growing
and changing and evolving. And you're adapting to what's going on in your local context.
You raise your head above the kind of, you know, the fence, and then you suddenly realize that,
oh, hang on, this is happening in other places. And then you start kind of going, oh, this is
a thing. This is where we're heading, right? So I think for me, it sort of felt right. I didn't
go in when I was working in 2014, I was working with this company, and I didn't go in thinking,
we're going to go and have this quality assistance model, whatever. And at that time, you know,
2014, Atlassian, who was just down the road in Sydney, they had started this quality assistance
model in 2010 with Andrew Prentice. And to be honest, I hadn't really tweaked anything on that.
And it wasn't really like, oh, look, what's Andrew's doing in Atlassian, let me copy that. It was more
like, I want to go in, here's an opportunity to go in and really, you know, influence quality
within a rapidly growing tech company. And what an opportunity. And I went in, and actually,
the first thing I did was put testers into all of the teams. It wasn't necessarily like,
oh, everyone's going to start as quality coaches. But as it evolved, and I'm sure you've, this has
happened to you too, as it evolves, you're going, you know what, in the teams that it's really,
really working, the quality coaches are coming, like the testers are coming up to me and going,
I don't know what to do anymore. My team's kind of, you know, really seems to be working without
me. What do I do now? And I was like, Gestalt moment. Ah, so this is what Andrew is doing
down the road in quality assistance, you know, kaching. And I think that's sort of,
personally, that's how it evolved for me. I don't, you know, I had this vision that every tester was
a test lead. But now I think, well, that actually is, you know, you know, that's where it evolves.
It evolves into a quality coach. And I think the other thing is, is that you start realizing
that quality, you happen up the way we deploy software and we deliver means that we can think
about quality beyond testing, right? And I think there's opportunities now, which maybe we hadn't
before, that we can start thinking about early on, you know, what is it? How do we know if we're
building the right product, you know, and of course, in monitoring. And I know you've done a
lot of work in this space, Alan, it's just that monitoring and analytics and feeding that
information into your quality strategy, you know, I think these things, you know, liberating yourself
away from focusing only on testing means that you can start thinking about these other problems,
which are really, really important. And you can honestly sometimes argue maybe more important,
you know. So I think I think it's a really exciting future. And, you know, I'm all about
having opportunity and growth. As I said, growth is really important for me. So I want to create
spaces where quality professionals who are passionate about testing or passionate about
quality can actually see and say, I've got a future, you know, I've got a part to play
in how software is delivered. So, you know, that's what drives me. Yeah. So there was one other bit
I wanted to address. It'll come back. I'm sure Brent is giddy over there because he loves what
you're saying. So I'm going to give him a chance to comment. I love the phrase you just mentioned
around liberating from, I'm going to screw it up, but you said liberating from mostly testing
or something testing. Right. I will say that is exactly how I felt when I went through the
transition, right? The James Whitaker, one of his, so he's very clever with his like one-liner
shots that get the point across. And I remember one of the things he said to me over lunch and
eventually became a blog post, which is all this testing is getting in the way of quality.
And for those of us that have a passion around quality, I'm no longer in a testing role. I'm not
in a test coach role, but I run a data science team that's very much concerned about the customer.
And there's no way to separate any sort of analysis around the customer from
the quality of their experience and the quality of them engaging with the products that you build
and support. Yeah, there is a ton I loved in what you were saying there. The one thing that I did
write down though, so you mentioned 2010 that I don't remember. I remember, so when Alan was
telling his story, like I remember those days very well, right? Alan and like me at Microsoft,
we were kind of risk adverse. I had by that time already gone through the transition.
I was one of the earlier folks within Microsoft to go through it. And I'm like, oh my God,
not only is the grass greener, the water is nice and cozy warm and they have bubbles and unicorns.
But I remember Alan going through it and part of it, I saw him kind of evoking on trust and another
part on instinct. Like Alan, you were absolutely doing the quality coaching role before you had
named it, right? So what Alan had, I would say Alan had realized at that point in time
was how much what we called testing was a bottleneck. And he worked particularly on the team's team.
He had the opportunity to start that effort from the ground and he was like,
now we're going to minimize the amount of actual testing that comes to this. He was doing stuff
that would be the guidance of Accelerate today, I think, even before it happened. But we were
climbing up that hill. It was definitely a steep hill climb. Like the things that we were saying,
the things that we were doing, the things that we were advising was absolutely contradictory to
the well-known knowledge and key breaking. I think it was difficult within the inertia of
Big Core. It was not only that, but we were basically saying, hey, as long as it's not
ripping the tourniquet off, transitioning to a world where QA is dedicated testers is what I'll call it.
Testing still needs to exist, but the world where dedicated testers is not only smaller,
but significantly smaller, not only will not harm the company, we'll probably improve it.
But that was not a popular...
Are you going somewhere, Brett?
I'm long-windedly going back to a question to Ann Marie. We had an uphill climb. We learned a bunch
of things around how people are going to push back and what they're afraid of and things like that.
Your 2010 story sounded a little different, that it wasn't a controversial transition.
Yeah, so I started in 2014. To me, it was an evolution. I think there's an interesting
thing about a lot of this work, which I have observed. One is, if you work with a company
that has an entrenched culture of quality, these sorts of things are easy. They just evolve,
because the engineers are passionate. Everyone agrees that testing is important.
It's not a conversation difficult. When I went into the place I was working,
they actually... It was an XP house. Everyone was doing TDD pair programming.
The first thing that they would do was think about, how do I test this? You would walk any
morning, you'd walk into the organization, and that was the word on engineers' lips.
Now, when you're in that culture and environment, moving to a quality coach model is not that hard,
because you've got this culture of engineers already doing that type of work. The challenge
is when you go into organizations that have engineers who don't do software testing,
who don't necessarily think or understand or have not been coached on how to think about quality and
how to build quality in. That's a lot, lot harder, because what you're doing there is,
you're, as sort of alluded to, you're training two people there in the team. You're training
the QA or the tester to become a quality coach, but you're also educating the team
how to think about and how to kind of care about... Not care about, because they do care
about quality, but it's just a different form. They have to think about all these other things
that they're not aware of, and they make assumptions about what testing is and,
oh, it's just three unit tests per function, and I'm done. Yay, let's ship. You've got to help them
grow and mature in what quality is, and I think that's a completely different ballgame.
And I say this to people as well, because other things that you need to consider is,
are you a tech company or are you a large entrenched bank that, where you've had 400
testers outsourced in India? Those are completely different challenges to deal with
if you want to move to a quality assistance model. So I think, again, it's that sort of,
think about what you're trying to achieve. Think about, is the quality coach model right for me?
Maybe, just maybe having software testers is the better approach because of all the different
things about your belief, the cultural system, the belief system of the organization and things
like that. We don't want to wedge a blueprint. A lot of teams in the early stages of this
randomly followed a blueprint. They said, oh, when we do Agile, we don't need test
testers anymore. You're all fired, which was dumb for obvious reasons. And it's, when we talk about
our principle number seven, all we're saying is that not that we shouldn't have testers.
The principle seven says something like, our quality may get so good, we may not need a
dedicated tester anymore. Kind of like your story, like, I don't know what to do anymore.
It's not, it's the other way around. You don't remove the testers to improve quality. Quality
may get so good that you don't need that dedicated tester there, or they can work across
multiple teams or they can do other stuff. When I dissolve these QA orgs, I find new jobs for them
because they're, these are very versatile people. Anecdotally aligned, I probably shared
half a dozen times on the podcast already, but in one of my quality coach roles at Unity,
VP would ask me, how is, how is, because didn't have a dedicated testers, he'd ask,
how is the team doing a testing? And I would say they do all the testing they know how to do,
which is good. And you know, you too know what I mean by that. They, they,
it's the kind of sentence you wanted. Yeah. You do to push to say, just go away. Everything's fine. Go
away. Leave me alone. They know how to do this much testing. I'm holding, I'm holding up my fingers
about three inches apart, but I'm working so they know two feet of testing. Yeah, nice.
Essentially saying that now it's point of view, the dev team or the teams involved are meeting his
expectations. So no one's going to get punished today. They know, they just, there's unconscious
ignorance and how much testing they think they need to do. They just need more training.
Yeah. When I do it, I basically say, you know, when, when can we move to this quality assistance
model? I said, when your engineers are ready, this is really not got a lot to do with the
quality coaches. This is about the team being ready and how, how do you know the team's ready?
Those are the interesting questions you should be asking, not about the QA, whether, you know,
what the QA is doing. I have, I have a relevant question on that topic. So let's say the business,
the, the, the business leadership realizes that they need this model, right? And, and there's
a lot of benefits to going with this model above sort of the traditional models in the engineering
team is not ready. How do, what, what advice do you give for someone that's either a tester now or
a blossoming quality coach? Like how can they help to make the engineering team
ready? What are your thoughts? Oh goodness. Like it's always a people problem.
It's always a people problem. Yeah. Nope. I know. Yeah. But I think, I think, look, there's, there's,
I hate using the word having credibility and trust, you know, because yes, these are things
are really, really important, but it also suggests that, you know, the engineer and the team is ready
to engage, you know, there's nothing harder than trying to build credibility and trust when you've
got a team that's not willing to, to meet you that way. Now these things are relationship things.
They're not, you know, you've got to have both ways. So I think, yes, well, credibility and trust
is really, really important. For me, the go-to is those CTO, the VPs, and to basically start
mandating or making this, this is what we value and this is really important. I think it's really
unfair to put all that work on a quality coach to come and change an organization, to change the
culture of an organization without having that senior kind of top-down mandate. So I kind of
think that's the first place I go to is like, you know, are you prepared to, you know, walk the
walk on this and come and say what you need to say when it needs to be said? So I think I ask
for that. To me, the engineers, and you kind of alluded this to this, Alan, it's, you know,
going to the tech lead. That's the equivalent, right? It's like, who on the team do I need to influence
to drive the change? And, you know, sometimes the quality coach can do that if they've got the
confidence maturity, but sometimes that's, they're not ready for that. And, you know, that means
that you've got to kind of step in a bit and create that space within the team for that person
to come in and start making changes. So that's your role as a senior quality coach or a director
is to do that. And, you know, yeah, I just think you've got to be really careful if you're a
quality analyst or a software tester, maybe you've got five years experience under your belt.
It's like, make sure you get the support from that around you to make sure that you're successful
and sure that the team is successful. Yeah. I'm going to build on that a little bit. So much of it
in its can't hire quality coach, someone to a quality coach role out of university.
Not just the technical skills, but you need to have some knowledge, but some there's leadership
attributes that are needed. And there's this book by Maxwell. What's his first name? It doesn't
matter. Five levels of leadership. He talks about if you first you're put in a position of leadership
and this is the CTO or the VP, whoever saying we care about quality and Anne Marie, you're going
to help us with this. Now you're in a permission. You have, you're in a position of quality,
but the next thing you do, and that gives you a start, but you're still the trust and credibility.
The next level of actual has is people have to give you permission to lead them. And you,
that's where the trust and credibility come in. Just, it's just like having those conversations
or are feeling more piloting things or seeing what works, having different ways to do things. And
the Weinberg books on becoming a technical leader or secrets of consulting have all kinds of anecdotes
that have helped me get some of those communication aspects across. But, and then the next,
I'm not going to give a book report on the five levels of leadership, but once they have permission
to lead them, then it's about achieving results together with them. And then these things all build
on each other and they, and they're excited about that. But yeah, you do need that permission first.
And that's what your story reminded me of. And by the way, Brad, thanks for kind of jumping ahead
to almost the fourth question in my list, which I gave you before I got to the third question.
Well done there. Where'd you get that idea from, dude?
It is your questions I view as guidance. No, no, I was just thinking as
Anne-Marie was answering on my last question, I was actually reminded of the way I've done it in the
past has helped motivate. And it's very aligned with this. You need, you need, I think you need
executive support. Minimum, you need the support that says, Hey, I'm going to, I'm going to do
something. Your engineering team, if you want to do this transition, I'm going to do something.
Your engineering team is probably going to, has a potential of freaking out. At best,
you need to support me. At worst, you need to be a no op on this topic because you got to,
part of it is people fear change. And some folks fear change so much, they're not even worth
willing to try. Now it doesn't like you, you going into a test job where you start off and
everyone's already doing TDD. I mean, yeah, that's, that sounds wonderful. I never experienced that
while I still held a test management position, but I'm like looking back on it now, I'm like,
Oh, that would be fantastic. It was. Yeah. But now I'm thinking about in terms of the other question,
and I don't know how many companies still have this, right? I think, so first off, I assume it
to be true that you would absolutely dispute the statement that devs cannot test their own code.
Yeah. Okay.
I'm sorry. I didn't know if you actually wanted me to ask that.
No, no, no. I was assuming that. I'm assuming that. Yeah. So in this case, then that role becomes a lot
easier. It's around, it's around in my view. Okay. How do we do the most amount of testing we can
to deliver the most amount of quality? And it kind of goes back to my trapeze metaphor, right? It's,
it's essentially, Hey, I don't know if you've heard this metaphor and Marie, it's essentially,
in my view, test team kind of acts as that safety net at the bottom of the tramp, the trapeze. And
a lot of the times when we tell the engineering teams that, Hey, test is going away. They respond
literally like, Oh, you're taking my safety net away. Right. And what you see that their behavior
up on the tramp, that the, the trapeze has been sloppy. They fall down all the time.
And yeah, you look at them. Of course I know why you're afraid because now the safety nets,
no longer the one accountable to keeping you alive. It's you. Of course, the solution to that
is to train them up so that they're confident, incompetent again at the top of that trap.
That the, what the hell is that thing called? Not the trapeze. The, yeah. The thin wire.
Thank you. When, and so yeah, if you, if you, I'll just keep the metaphor alive. Why not?
So if you join a circus and, and, uh, your trapeze, uh, artists are already well conditioned and,
you know, the safety net is not a requirement. It's a value add. Yeah. Helping to improve their
skills and become better artists on that front is a lot, lot easier. And what I found is that they,
it's far more fulfilling. I don't, at least for those individuals, they feel like they are doing
more things and I don't know. I'm done talking on that one. All right. I'll just jump in. I think
there's a valid points there. Absolutely. Like when you've got engineers who are just like,
I just want to, you know, teach me how to test like, okay, you know, that's, that's such an easy,
I have, you know, um, and I think there's always places to improve. So the things that we did
in that organization was we ripped away, we ripped apart the poor testing frameworks that existed.
So there was a heavy dependency on, um, I can't remember the framework now, but, but it was like
these heavy end to end tests that just took forever to run and maintain and fitness.
Oh, I remember that one.
And we ripped. I ripped it out. I like, and I, I spoke to the other engine, you know,
the C the engineers and I was like, you did senior, the engineering managers. I'm like,
look, I'm really concerned about this framework. There's only, it only does like really 30 to 40%
coverage of the system. And everyone's thinking that this is their safety net. What are we going
to do about this? So, um, you know, the conclusion that we have was that let's just rip it out
because you know, we'll retire it and look like the worst comes to the worst. We can always
restore it. You know, it's all the other world, but psychologically we wanted to remove that
safety net. So there's always rooms for improvement and that did create a lot of fear and anxiety
for some people. So I think, you know, um, uh, I think that was, um, even in some organizations,
you still have to rip parts of, but there's always a bit of a safety net somewhere that you have to
kind of challenge and ask questions about, you know, where is the risk in this? And it was great
because it led to a conversation about what is risk retiring tests, the concept of, you know,
we can actually, you know, there's a retiring date for tests and we don't, you know, are you
thinking about that as part of your estimation that, you know, you're removing tests as well,
you know, so it led to some really interesting conversations. Um, going back to the thing about
sort of changing, say you don't have an organization or you don't have a team that's like that. Um,
I had a great, um, actually a quality, quality coach taught me this, which was, um, the ad car
model. So Divya Kaner was someone who was working and she really, um, suggested, you know, this, this
change management consulting approach, which is, you know, ad car, which I think is awareness,
give people awareness. So you telling people the why, why do we need this change? Why do we need
to do so? Why do you need to do software testing? Why do you need to get that? You know, all those
sorts of things. And then once you've got that, then you start looking at desire. So how do we
actually gain, you know, how do we help people want to do those things? Right. And one is only
once you've got those two, then you start looking at knowledge and skill, right? Then you can start
building up on what is, you know, what do they need to know? Um, what are the skills they need
to acquire? And then the last thing is, um, I think it's R which is repeat, you know, so you just
basically got this thing. You've got to keep going and saying it again and again and repeating
that cycle because just going through it once isn't enough. So that was a big, awful, like,
moment for me. I was like, Oh, this is great. Cause cause I tend to jump into the kind of
just going straight into the knowledge of the skill that this is what you need to know.
And I forget that I haven't taken people on this journey, which they have not been on
themselves. So that was a big way back when I created the, uh, the, the quality culture
transition guide exercise, I was given what is a quality culture? I'm going to go define this.
I just given a talk on it. And one of the things I took from my talk and built into that was the
add car model. Cause I thought it fit really well into try and get teams to adopt a quality
culture that to be aware of what's important, then they have to have, they have to want to do
it. And then they need the knowledge and the skills or ability and the reinforcement.
I want to tell two quick stories to build on that and then to segue into another question
for you. So, uh, we're talking about developers testing. And one of the things I've discovered
is that oftentimes like a developer has been told in a lot of organizations that they can't
test as well as testers. And I've of course discovered that not to be true in many cases.
So I think in some cases they just need permission to test. And you talked about getting rid of a
framework in, I've been in situations time and time again, where by giving the developers
ownership over the framework and the tests versus it being a black box somewhere else,
they end up doing some really cool innovation on top of that. Plenty of examples, but one I wanted
to, what was the one I wanted to share with, for example, on X-Box, uh, we built the test,
a test system. So it's funny, I'm, I've associated with testing, but I actually haven't done
day-to-day testing in a long, long time. I've worked a lot on platforms that enable testing
tested. I've worked a lot on infrastructure and thought a lot about how teams do testing
in our test distribution system. We made it so anyone could plug in their X-Box to the system
or X-Box is in their office and run their tests there. And people, uh, built stress frameworks
on top of that for test distribution, or they would make their own little mini performance lab
outside of the lab. So I've had other places where given developers ownership over the framework,
they fixed long standing bugs at the test team or the test infra team had no idea how to fix
because it just seemed obvious to them, or in learning how to write tests, they've learned how
to be much more, uh, to write much more testable code. Uh, one time I did a little mini one day
bug bug hunt back on teams at the encouragement of our VP. And normally I don't like those things,
but I gave teams some guidelines of kinds of things to look for. I think I gave them
Elizabeth Hendrickson's heuristic cheat sheet, and I was blown away over some of the bugs they found.
Like they dug in deep and found security bugs that I could not find. And I'm not a great
security tester, but you know, I'm supposed to be the expert here and they're like,
oh my God. So again, I've been blown away. So the question I have for you is,
as you've been doing this quality coaching, what's an example of a one or two things that
have surprised you or you think it would be surprising to listeners?
Look, the first one that comes to mind, and I think this is around data, you know,
and the constant problem of how do you have, um, test data that you can actually create on the
fly or, you know, that doesn't slow down your test automation. I think, um, we were, we were, um,
in one organization, we were doing, um, a lot of exploratory testing. So one of the things we were
doing was having the testers do exploratory testing, but also encouraging the engineers
to think about exploratory testing and, and, and to kind of spread their wings in that area.
And one of them came up with this idea of using the API to create test data. Now this was, you know,
like quite a while ago, this was quite a kind of, you know, whereas it might be quite common now.
I think that sort of concept of actually using the API to actually create the test data that
you need in order to do your testing. Um, because we wanted to get the system to certain states. And
so they just came up with this, this idea of doing that. So that was really, really neat. And then
they developed a little interface for the testers at the time. So the testers could just, you know,
jump in and just add sort of lots of data into the system. So that was really neat. Now that's
probably the one that comes most to mind. I'm actually interested. I don't know if it's a
segue and Alan, you can shoot me down, but so recently we've been having a discussion around
a difference between a quality coach and an agile coach and whether or not those might eventually
merge. So I had this question, somebody asked me about the quality coach and then they said,
and I said, well, it's kind of, you know, what is a quality coach? And they were in engineering
and I was, I'm saying, well, it's a bit like, you know, having an agile coach in the team. And they
said, well, we used to have those and then we got rid of them. So does that mean the coach coach
role is retiring too? You know, so I don't know if, uh, I don't know where I'm going with this one,
but, um, you know, I just think that, you know, agile coach, I don't know, it's certain parts of
the community isn't regarded as a role anymore in organizations. It's like we, we now everyone
knows agile. We don't necessarily need an agile coach. Um, my take on that, um, before I go and
actually answer the question you asked, she takes right in here, um, is yeah, yeah. Is, um, that,
you know, you need, there's different types of coaching. There's coaching, you know, if you,
you know, do that movie, the mighty docs or whatever it was where they take the worst team
ever. And you know, they end up winning the league because, you know, you've had this coach who's
instilled belief and confidence and they get to the point where they just, they're so unified
that they're actually, you know, they win the tournament. There's that type of coaching,
but there's also, you know, when people are in the premier league and football,
they don't stop having coaches. You know, it's just that the coach does a different role. It's
a different, it's more of a peer to peer thing. It's more about how we, how can we sustain quality
rather than, you know, um, get to a, get to an end state, if that makes sense. And as you know,
yourself, quality never never changed, you know, the quality is never, never static. We're always,
you know, constantly changing our views about what quality is, what we think quality was five years
ago, we're, we're changing our minds about that. I mean, even if you look about quality as, you
know, you can think about service and SaaS problems and that concept of consistently
providing support, ongoing support, um, you know, it's much more about a service rather than,
you know, something that you just deliver on a floppy disk. So our concepts of what we value
in software have changed. And I think for that reason, quality coaches in some form,
maybe they won't be called quality coaches, they'll be called something else, but,
but that role is always going to be there. Um, yeah.
If I, if I may piggyback on what you're just saying, I like what you said and you brought up
agile coaches. So years ago, Alan and I did one of our worst podcasts. Uh, we did a podcast slash
presentation in the office, live at real estate. Come on. Yeah. Yeah.
I'm going to get one. It was an interest. It was absolutely an interesting idea.
The thing is agile because we're experiment. We're adaptive. We're experimenting and learning from our
experience. Absolutely. Yes, we did. And one of the things, what I remember is that's, that was
kind of the last time that I consciously remember telling a team to go hire an agile coach. Like
it's been a long time since I've advised that because Anne Marie's right. Everyone kind of knows
now this quality coach thing, like it's a new concept, but it's ish. I mean, it's been around
for a while, but it's now gaining more and more adoption. And it's kind of what the, in my view,
what testers have an opportunity to grow into. It's about scaling out. So the way I interpret
what Anne Marie just said is around first off, coaches will start off and they're coaching at
the tactical level. This is how you think about BVTs. This is how you think about exploratory testing.
Now you have to do versus coaching professional adults. So this is why I'm in the, the metaphor
that has to be mentioned before go any farther that this is why Ted Lasso is such a great coach
for Richmond, F C Brett, Brett's never seen. Yeah. I still have no idea what I'm talking about.
Tessa, I'm such a big Ted Lasso fan. I, you know, I just love this. Yeah.
Comment on this topic on coaching until you have watched every episode of Ted Lasso. And that's
my statement, but I'll let you finish anyway, but you can't mention the word coach again until
you've watched it. How are you going to get out of that one, Brett? Yeah. So the role that I am
banned, the, the, the redacted role starts off tactical. And then I think as it moves forward,
as the tactics are, are expected and the tactics are well broadened throughout the teams,
right? It makes sense that the role then becomes more strategic.
I don't think NFL coaches for, I mean, in some guards they might, but I don't think NFL coaches
are, are, you know, teaching people how to tackle correctly. They, they opera operate on that
assumption. Now what they're trying to do is execute higher level strategies and make the strategy
of, of, of a high quality. I do think, and I do think that, that well, well defines my career.
I think it defines Alan's career. I think it very much is in alignment with how you described yours.
Yeah. I think, I think it's like, you know, when I think about some of the things that I'm working
on, for example, right now, onboarding, like onboarding engineers and how do we know that
everyone has the same understanding of what their role is in software testing and do they understand
that software testing is part of their, you know, remit and are they comfortable doing software
testing? Do they need additional support? So we're looking at sort of the first three months of
having this sort of like Academy type things to make sure that everyone is comfortable and
confident, you know, in doing these activities. So I think, you know, you start thinking about
sort of strategies and plans for the future, you know, to make sure that everything you're, you're
preventing situation, uncomfortable situations occurring. So those are the sorts of things I work
on too. No, it's, and I think it's important, right? If you recognize it, that fear is potentially a big
thing in there, you got to make things feel safer. So I agree with that strategy, at least the way I
understand it. Do you ever back off or do you go or do you keep moving forward just finding some new
way? I twist it even harder. I don't imagine you do that. You're not crying, I'm not winning.
Producer. Does it hurt yet? Yes. Look, that's a really interesting question. I think, yeah, I'm,
there's a limit. I tend to give people a lot of space to work things out. I mean, I try good,
I don't know if this is a good thing or a bad thing, but I try to think about how I like to be,
how I like to learn and how I like, I like to be given the space and the time and the autonomy
to learn myself. So I tend to think most people want to learn things. It's just that
they don't necessarily either have the skill or the confidence or the time or the permission,
you know, to, to, to feel that they can do that. So I try and tackle those things rather than
actually looking at the person themselves and, and sort of forcing them into that situation.
I mean, you know, you think about it, it's all about them. Quality is the team responsibility.
So if I go in and sort of take that, that, that account, that, that responsibility away from them,
you kind of, to some degree, are, you're still kind of spoon-feeding them, you know?
Having said that, at some point you do have to kind of, you know, come in there and say no,
you know, I'm trying to figure out actually some ways of doing that, which are interesting,
but I have an experiment to add on them. Gotcha. No. So I do think, you know, sort of easing them
into it, the, the, what is it? Boil the frog or pull the band-aid. Like I think on some of
these things, boiling the frog is a more comfortable way of doing it. You'd slowly raise up the heat.
Of course, that metaphor kind of sucks because everyone knows the frog dies at the end.
Wait, the frog dies?
That's not really what happens in, yeah, Ellen. Yeah, Ellen, that's what happens.
How do you make frog soup without a dead frog?
I actually think that's a terrible, terrible metaphor for, for what?
No, it absolutely is. Because it's really, we're trying to, in my mind, we're trying to,
to bring them to the, the world of unicorn and rainbows and they, they're just afraid of it.
Right. There's a couple of things in that. One is who are you hiring? I mean,
this is one thing I say to the, to the engineering managers, are you talking about software testing
in your interviews? Are you actually asking them these questions when you're hiring engineers
about their ability to do software testing? Because I think that, that is where you nip that in the
bud. Right. I mean, you certainly, you're going to have different groups of people that have,
you know, you're going to have different types of challenges. For example, people who've been there
for, you know, 15 years, that's a different type of approach you want to someone who is joining the
organization and you want to have two different strategies. So stop, stop the problem right at
the start by actually making sure that everyone at least is willing to do software testing. They
might not have the capacity and they might not have the capability, but they're on board with
the whole concept. So that's, that's that I think. And then you can help them with that. I think
that's part of the quality coaching or the department of, of quality engineering is to
provide that support. I think that's on us. I think there's a different strategy
for people who have, you know, entrenched and really do not want to do software testing, I think.
And they don't see that as part of their role. They don't, they think that's a,
I guess, some sort of dint to their ego that they have to do software testing. And it's kind of,
you know, and to be fair, the majority of people these days have really shifted. It's kind of
like, that's, that's, I see less of that. I see more, I get questions. I have a lean coffee
every month where people come in and they can ask questions about quality within the organization.
And the thing is most engineers are going, what is quality coaching when the organization,
I came from all the engineers at all the software testing. So how does this all hang together?
Like those are so, you know, like the certainly where in the tech industry and modern tech,
you're getting people who totally accept that this is how we should be doing.
Yeah. The bubble's moving. It's, it's moving and it's good to see.
No, and it occurred to me, it occurred to me like, so, and Marie was, was describing sort of the new
people in the industry and the old people in the industry. And it occurs to me, non-trivially
her solution, which is asked about testing at the interview is actually probably the solution to both.
Or to ask about quality as well, or maybe even instead.
That's right. Right. Right. Because, because what happens is as more and more of the,
the sort of the, the more comfortable people come in. And I've seen this over and over again,
either the old ones just go, Oh, this is a bunch of crap and I'm out of here. I can't stand this.
This is below. Well, fine. Problem solved in some regards. See, okay. Now we interviewed a new person
over time. What happens is the mix changes, the mix changes. And the, once the org is mostly
people who are comfortable with this, then the, the old guys, and I've seen this over and over
again, they, they, they pick it up and they realize it's not so bad because it's a, it's now more of
a peer pressure thing than, than an ego thing. Exactly. I actually learned this from, I don't
know, what's that, who was it? Google. What was it testing in the toilet? Like if you listen to
there, if you listen to that, that, that talk, it's about, and that's how they exactly, they
targeted the new people coming in, but also they had a different strategy for the, for the people
who there had been a long time and they realized exactly what you're saying, Brent, that, that once
you get to this kind of percentage, it becomes uncool to, to kind of have that, that, that, you
know, it's the hurt mentality, you know, and the culture at that point has shifted. So I think it's
a great way to, to drive change this man. I want to keep on talking for another hour, but I can't
because I got, I got to go somewhere, but Emery, it's been awesome having you here. So thank you
for your time and for this. I will put a link to your website and a link to your Twitter.
Anything else we should point to or anything else you want people to get in contact with you or
learn more about your stuff? Yeah, I guess, I guess, you know, at some points we are hiring
a culture. I guess my, I am doing my, yeah. And also, I guess I'm really excited about my quality
coaching book, which is a new SAS online subscription thing, a model I'm trying, which I'm, I have
never, I've been trying to write a book for about 15 years and I came to the conclusion a couple
of years ago that, that I was actually trying to push a model that didn't work for me. I love
writing. I really enjoy writing. It brings me huge pleasure. And this, this trying to deliver this book
was just taking the joy out of that. But I had all these good ideas that I was saving for the book,
you know, save it for the book. And because the book was taking so long, then these ideas started
becoming redundant because you know how it is, it just changed it so quickly. So I thought,
like, bug of this. I'm going to write the book in real time. And so I developed this concept of a,
of a quality coaching online book where basically I post something every month
and it's a subscription based. So yeah, yeah, really excited how that's moving. And,
yeah, come and join it. Subscribe. Every, all three of you listeners do that.
All right. Well, thanks again. Absolutely. Thank you. All the best. No, thank you for
offering to have me on it. Come back anytime. Hey, I want to talk about this. Just ping us.
Oh my gosh. Oh yeah. Absolutely. Okay. There we go. Yes.
Brant is once again forgetting that we're a podcast, not a YouTube app,
but showing the webpage, but I'll put a link to it. All right, everybody. Thank you again.
Thank you again, Anne-Marie. Yeah. Okay. All the best. Yeah. Take care. Have a,
have a great evening for you, I guess. All right. See you then. Thank you, Anne-Marie.
Bye. Thanks, Brant.