How does someone who is working on test automation or CI tools during exploratory testing,
how do they become a tester in the sense of experimentation?
How do they become someone who administers experiments to customers?
Welcome to AB Testing Podcast, your modern testing podcast.
Your hosts, Alan and Brent, will be here to guide you through topics on testing,
leadership, ads, and anything else that comes to mind.
Now on with the show.
Okay, thank you.
We should do that.
It's AB Testing, the Yacht Rock version.
Next up, let's do it now.
So we have been, we are going to have a shorter podcast today.
One, because I have a hard cutoff and two, because I have been struggling with the
non-sponsored so I can talk about them.
However, I feel like Zencaster, which has been mean and grody today.
So let me talk about my user experience here, because I'm that,
I want to be that guy.
I'm going to be that guy briefly.
Logged on, new interface, couldn't figure out where to go.
Finally started an episode, took me to a blank screen,
refreshed about 10 times, restarted.
Finally, I got to a place and it kind of worked and my audio is not great on Brent's side.
Hopefully the local recording works.
Then I pressed start the episode, it refreshed again and then it restarted again.
Finally, we're here recording and we're here for the AB Testing podcast,
which is about testing and it is modern.
Right.
Unless you're just listening to this episode, not the one before and you're very confused.
Because that's kind of what we do.
I got a thing to tell you about the last episode and what I've done since then.
But what's going on with you, Mr. Brent Jensen, aka aka El Queso Frito?
Yes. Do you know what that means?
It means cheese fry.
The fried cheese.
Either way, it's an old joke between me and my brother.
We've always felt that El Queso Frito sounds like a superhero name.
If there was a superhero man of fried cheese, that would be you.
El Queso Frito.
What did you ask me?
Oh, yes.
So school, school's back from summer.
It's interesting in terms of the Microsoft hybridization report.
Wait, what is the Microsoft hybridization report?
This is where I report out on the work from home.
Hybridization?
Yeah.
Oh, that hybridization.
Yes.
As you know, I am sitting in my office.
I do know.
And Microsoft opened up at the end of last March, at which point in time we went from
five cars consistently in the parking lot, which mine was 20 percent, to maybe 20 cars.
And now I would say we're closer to 40, 50.
It means still plenty of empty parking spots.
Yeah.
I remember the days of, I know what building you're in.
I remember the days of walking around that parking lot and not walking,
driving around in circles and going, damn it, I'm going to have to park farther away.
Oh, yeah.
No, no.
Before COVID, I've had to, if I got in after nine, I wouldn't even try going into my building.
Because I had already learned, nope, I'm just going to go park in the big garage in the Commons.
Can you share the details?
What's the high level?
What is the hybridization mean?
We're at a stage where some people go to work and some don't.
We're good with that?
Microsoft's open for working from work, but people can choose.
So we have a survey.
Same.
All right.
But what's happened is this week, I would say there's been an increase between 30 and 50% of
cards. There's still plenty of open parking spots.
But why do you think that is this week?
Because summer end and.
Ah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
And I think a lot of people just made the decision.
We'll just stay working from home while the kids out for summer.
Yeah, I was in the office a couple of days this week.
Three days matter of fact, and we're still not.
We're still looking sparse.
So we're open for business, but yeah.
Yeah, there's one thing that's fascinating, though.
So because of this, Microsoft kind of put a halt on building.
They have a whole bunch of new buildings that they're working through,
but they put a halt on trying to find new space.
And before COVID, we are having a problem.
Same.
The same.
Before COVID, we were having a problem because we were running out of space.
And we're like, where are we going to put all these people?
And so now what's happening, it's messed up.
So if you remember, there used to be like seniority rules around.
Who gets the window office?
Who gets single?
Who gets doubled?
Crap like that.
So now it's.
Seniority rules are still in play.
Around who gets an office.
Without regard as to whether or not those people are coming in.
Right.
So that's the weird thing about Microsoft.
I think I got to imagine your building is still a little bit of the minority overall.
Maybe not.
But in the rest of the industry, I think individual offices don't exist that much.
So hot desking is a little easier and just, you know, just showing up.
And we have a system for reserving desks.
I figure out where I want to work when I get tired of that place.
I move around, but actually I'm in a good spot now because it's close to little lockers
where I keep my my Bluetooth keyboard and mouse.
So yeah, just kind of work.
So with offices, it's kind of weird if you're going to have like,
it's like you're there all the time.
So it makes sense.
You keep stuff in there and you go there every day.
But if you're going in once or twice a week, are you saying those people have offices too?
Like permanent.
They they do and they don't depending on on the person.
So so for example, we have a bunch of new hires.
Um, and right now,
this is one of those things where I just like, okay, is it just humanly the default
that we never go back and revisit old rules.
We just add new rules, right?
It's like you could make your life easier if you take this existing rule and delete it.
Right.
So we're keeping alive the the seniority rule.
But because that that makes us out of space,
then new hires, the rule is you don't get an office.
Even though you want to come in, you know, eight, eight days a week.
And I'm like, this is dumb.
Yeah, it is dumb.
This is dumb.
I will tell you, we don't need all of our listeners, even all of them,
because they're all smarter than us.
They know this is dumb.
Yes.
So I guess one of the things that's new for me is it's, um,
so because of this, I have actually for for my organization taken over the move map
multiple years in a row.
And, uh, just last week, I put my final touches on an AI for defining the move map.
I've been wanting to build this for years and I finally did it
because it's, it's way smarter than the decisions we've been making.
All right. I'll, I'll trust you.
I'll trust you. It's going to work out.
So that's interesting.
I think a lot of companies are in that space that people like,
I can tell you, I think it's probably fair to tell you that we have some offices
that are basically full, not on the West coast.
West coast of the US has been the slowest to return to office.
Full and occupied.
Full. Well, not full occupied, like at 80%.
So pretty good idea.
Okay.
Lot of our offices, like we don't have a single office that will hold all the
people associated with that office.
Like in, you know, we have an office that holds 200 people.
For example, we may have our internal employee database may show 350 people
associated with that office, but, uh, we think we have quite a while before,
of a reach capacity where everybody can find a desk.
So we have also slowed down.
I guess some projects that were in process in 2019 stopped and remain stopped.
And we're not even filling most of the space we have now.
So anyway, I think that's pretty common for everyone else.
I do want to talk about AB testing.
Okay. Do you at all have any interest in talking about Her Majesty the Queen?
Oh, just that.
I mean, I do because I have a lot of Brits on my team and it's,
it's, it's kind of like, um, when you have a little bit, so kind of like when you have a
family member who you maybe know they're about to pass soon and, or they will pass sometime
in the next year or two sometime.
But when they do, it's still kind of shocking in a way.
And I think that's where a lot of folks are right now.
I mean, she was queen for 70 years, our condolences.
And it's going to be weird because as long as we've been alive and much, much longer,
there has been a queen of England.
It's a little trippy.
Right. There's multiple generations of literally there are multiple generations.
Like her, she reigned for 76 years.
I thought it was 70, right?
She was, she was queen since she was 26 and she died at 96.
Oh, 70 years then.
Right. That's.
If I have that right.
And someone, one of our listeners will correct me because people know more stuff than I do
all the time.
Yeah. I'm trying to, it's fascinating.
And then I'm wondering, like, I find the whole thing fascinating just simply because I'm just
like, okay, number one, why are, is there still monarchies?
That whole, that whole concept, right?
There's still an emperor of Japan.
It's not, it's not a monarchy in the sense of an autocrat or an authoritarian or a dictator.
Right. Right. And then the new.
There is a political system in both cases that supports.
Right. And, and the thing that's fascinating, right? The, the new king of England is 73.
Right.
Right. And, and I just.
That's, that's good, solid blood, blood, man. He'll be, he'll be alive longer than I will.
Yeah. He'll definitely be alive longer than me most likely.
All right. A B test, A B testing or as it's sometimes called ab testing, we're going to
be sending out some self assessments where you do as many sit ups and leg raises as you can.
It's part of the ab testing network. Oh wait, I'm sorry. That that's, that's later.
That's a later evolution of AB testing.
You just have to be able to do at least as many as I can.
Yeah. That's one.
That's zero.
Last time on the podcast, we talked about a slash B testing or experimentation. So we had a little
talk about that and, and about this article. And I actually.
Right. And how did that go?
I don't think it's been played yet. I recorded the talk that we talked about me making last time.
And it went, I think it went well. I can, um, if this, if we had screen sharing,
I'd show you my slides, but, uh, we probably do. I just don't, I turn it on.
It was pretty much a recap. I talked a little bit about where I came from.
Talking about, okay, I did this kind of testing at first where I explored stuff.
A lot of people do that today. That's cool. Um, there probably always be need for that
on some teams, but it's going away. And then I did a bunch of API testing,
both things that would be at the unit level today and wider, some diagnostic tools.
Uh, those things live 90 to a hundred percent in the lives in developers.
So I'm not really going to do that again. That's somebody else's job.
And then I talked about accelerating test teams, accelerating teams through
CI systems. And that's another role, um, that accelerates quality.
But then I said, but another kind of testing I want to do is, and I,
I talked about experimentation first, um, went into AB testing and talked about the fact that
in those scenarios, the tester is the person that doesn't check inputs and put in values.
The tester is the person that administers the AB test and talked a little bit about that,
how to learn more. I mentioned, uh, Ronnie Kowavi's book. You remember Ronnie from Microsoft?
Pretty good, smart mind in this area and tell us, has lots of good stories and stuff.
I've stolen over the years. So good stuff there. And it's, it's a 14 minute talk.
So not a lot there, but at the end, I'm sure it's a twist that'll piss people off.
But then, but then, but then, but then you probably didn't see my five for Friday today.
Did you know, I haven't seen that yet.
You can bring it up while I talk if you want, but one of the links now,
I think link number four is believe it or not. I came across an article.
I do believe it. That said how your QA team can use AB testing.
And I was talking about using the QA team to, to administer experiments.
I thought, huh, there's always someone smarter and ahead of me out there.
Yeah. No, I don't view our job on this podcast is to invent new things.
No, we never do. We never do. We highlight what's already happening.
Even if we don't know it's already happening and then try to accelerate it.
Yes. Yes. So I did that. I'm going to write the article based on that sometime soon, but, uh,
I was thinking, my question for you is this recording. I didn't record it just to, you know,
anger people, even though I'm sure it's going to get a couple of reactions like,
what, I don't get this. Why is this here? Alan, you're so stuck in the bubble kind of thing.
So what do you think if you were, let's say, imagine you were the tester you were 20 years ago,
because that's probably at least a chunk of the people watching this talk.
Okay. But you have an open mind and you love to learn. Well, what do you think when you see this
talk that goes, okay, that kind of testing, I know that kind of testing. I know I know people
that do DevOps stuff and acceleration. That's good. That's good. You want me to what?
If I were the tester 20 years ago, but in today's context, I assume, I think I would be worried,
obviously, right? I don't know what the value proposition I'm giving up. Like,
what are we losing? That's where people are going to freak out.
Well, and here's where I think I can help you. I think what's different,
as kind of a little bit rhetorical, as you and I both know, there are some testers who are,
we'll dig in their heels a little bit on this is the kind of testing I do. I think that's fine.
You can do what you want. I'm not going to tell you to do something you're not doing as long as
you're gainfully employed and happy and learning. If you like your job matters, autonomy, mastery,
and purpose, just go for it. But you're going to have to leave that behind. As you know,
there's a lot of testers who do exploratory testing all day. There's nothing wrong with that.
That's not what we're talking about. There's a lot of testers who do all day doing Selenium
testing to automate UI. That's fine. I don't consider that my job anymore. That's not going
to stop it. So you'd have to leave those things behind in order to focus on experimentation.
Right. If we think about what were the principles, why did we write the principles of
modern testing? We wrote them essentially because we saw people didn't have a clear road path
to get to the world we were already living in.
Right. We saw, yeah, exactly. We saw the changes happening. We saw people struggling with those
changes. We wanted to help them navigate those changes. And we've been doing that for five,
six years. What we're doing now is saying there's a new place that we're already living,
but there's a new place maybe we're going. We want to talk to you how to navigate that.
So the place we're talking about is OK. If we were to sum up MTP in less than seven principles,
we're basically saying, hey, it's a new world. Your expertise is valuable. But it's valuable in terms
of transitioning, helping to transition Dev to actually doing their job, coaching, and
increasing or accelerating the team. But a pivot is around coaching. Now, the question,
of course, and we started talking about this. And right now, I can't believe this is the first time
I'm thinking these thoughts. OK. Once it's ingrained in the culture of how to do this and coaching
isn't needed, what then? Right. And that's what I think we're going into or the path that we're
discussing. Maybe. But I think what's different, though, is moving from tester to test developer
is just a shift. It's not a big thing. Moving from that into coaching or into working on
CI systems, not that big of a change. The change we're talking about here, moving from,
it isn't a progression, moving from any one of those, I'll call them all traditional testing or
checking roles, into an experimentation role, I think, is a much bigger jump than any of the
others we've talked about. Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. For sure. For sure. So that's the thing
I'd like to explore a little bit today than in the future episodes is how does someone who is a,
well, I have answers for these. We can talk about it a little bit. How does someone who is
working on test automation or CI tools, doing exploratory testing, how do they become a tester
in the sense of experimentation? How do they become someone who administers experiments to customers?
A little bit of a yet another, again, Principle 5 rant is people get mad at Principle 5 because they
say, you just want the customers to test your software. And the thing is, yes, we do, but not
in the sense that you're thinking of. You know what I mean, but I'm going to expand. We don't
want the customers to test our software to find functional correctness. If you give your customers
something that isn't functionally correct for them to discover, you're a crappy developer.
That's not the goal. Yeah. We're not talking about code correct. Yeah, right. Exactly. But we do
want customers to test our software. We want them to test to see if the treatment or the experiment
we are proposing to them is a better experience than the one that the control group or everyone
else is getting. We do want them to test our software. If someone were to come to me and
today say, oh, I think Principle 5 is bullshit because you guys just want your customers to
test the software. My response would be yes. But specifically, it would be yes. For me to evaluate
the quality of my software, I absolutely need my customers to use it. Right? Because what I'm
trying to do there is look, I do not expect my customers to encounter code correctness issues.
That is Dev's job. Dev's job now. Okay. Sorry. Dev's job. But whether or not my software has
quality has nothing to do with, in my view, with code correctness. It has some things to do with
code correctness. But what I'm now trying to understand is to what degree this is valuable,
this is useful, this is adding improvements to my customer's life. And that is the definition of
quality that I care about. And if my customers aren't using it, then either I have crap or I have
another problem because I cannot validate that hypothesis without usage.
Yes. The more I've thought about it, this is the biggest hurdle that traditional tester has to get
over, understanding that you actually do need customers to test your software to know if it's
quality software. And again, words, as some of our colleagues in the industry will say,
words have meanings and the meanings for the words I spoke and the meanings that are maybe
more traditionally or commonly used do not match. I want my customers to test my software. I just
don't repeat myself that they need to. But when people hear that, they think of another kind of
testing. It's not actually, it's what's weird to say, we want to use testing and checking,
not mocking in this case, if you want to use those terms from Bock and Bolton is you don't
want customers to air quote, check your software, but you do want them to test your software.
I don't know. And actually, that's not quite right because then I'm using their
definition for check, but our definition for test doesn't quite work.
I am reminded of one of my first presentations I did in Bing. Because I paid attention to
what was going on and Bing, when I joined Bing, as you know, we were getting read a test,
but there were still tests, there were still small pockets of tests there, including test managers.
And so I saw what they did. And I had my test manager hat on and I was just amazed.
Right? The one of the ways I started off that slide deck, as I said, here's something that is
just incredibly cool about Bing. Every single day, there were 600 million test cases being done.
And not only that, there was no way to argue, even with the duplicate test cases being executed,
there was no way to argue that those were anything other than the important test cases
for that day. Because those were the ones being done by the customer.
And then if you combine it with this intelligence that early on, I truly believe this is why in the
early search wars, why Google won. Because they realized it's okay to ship bucks.
What is what we need to do is prioritize our resources around those things that are impactful.
So Google mastered the art of shipping bugs and then looking at which ones were high impact.
Obviously, they couldn't ship anything that would be catastrophic. They couldn't have
outages or blocking little things. It helps you figure out which bugs matter.
How many times have you seen in a blog post or a presentation, someone showing the convoluted way
in which they exposed a bug that nobody cares about?
I think about one of the first bugs that as you know, my career is long and
every day, the time I spent as an IC, as a percentile, incredibly shrinks. I spent,
I think, a total of nine months as a full-time IC in the company. But one of my bugs was so freaking
convoluted. Instead of having the P, the P ended the triage. Instead of having them go through and
figure out what the hell happened, he just won't fix it and then caught it the Brint beep.
Because what happened is I found these weird like 30 random steps and then it would suddenly beep
for no reason. Oh, the Brint beep. Yeah, that's nice. He's like, yep, this is the Brint beep.
And he reframed it as an Easter egg. There you go, Brint. You can be proud. You spent the effort.
You found this issue. And then I just sit back and they go, I think about the Brint beep and go,
how much time did I waste on that stupid freaking bug? Happens all the time though. It's a little
bit of a rite of passage, but I would argue though, there is learning that happened there.
You learn how to explore. It's more of an exercise than a value to the customer. So there is value to
you, but not to the customer. That would help your growth, but it really did nothing for the
customer. Now, I remember this particular thing. This bug did not help me in any way, shape,
or form. It just, it might've helped me trying to recall that was I under a bug quota during that
time. It might've helped me not get yelled at that week. Let's go back to old style testing
because now I want to tell a different story. Nothing to do with what we're talking about with
the customer. But when I first started at Microsoft, I did have a bug quota. I was expected
to find 10 bugs a week. And I was told that it was Windows 95. There are plenty of bugs and I
was doing networking. So plenty of bugs. And I had cool ideas. They don't have to all get fixed,
just bugs. And the manager would kind of spot check and make sure you weren't being stupid.
People would do silly things like open up often sometimes as dumb as seeing an un localized
string in Japanese and also opening up the localized string in Chinese and Korean.
But I would report, I would find 10, actually I would report 10 or 11 bugs every week,
sometimes 12 because I wanted to overachieve a little bit. But some weeks I find about 20,
25, 30, but I would save them for the next week in case my well dried,
which is a horrible behavior. I hate bug quotas are dumb. But one of the bugs I found with me
goofing around was I was working on localized, far east localized versions of Windows 95,
which was a mixed byte character system. So all kinds of cool stuff could happen because the
backslash could be the 5C character could be the second half of a double byte character.
So I would do all kinds of weird network tests between NetWare and NT and Japanese NT and
Japanese NetWare, just copying a bunch of files around with weird names to see what would happen.
And at the time I didn't realize how cool this bug was. But I was running my test and it hung,
it just stopped. I said, shoot. So I walked down the hall to the lab where the machine was.
It was an NT machine. Must have been 3.5 at the time. And the machine had blue screen. I thought,
well, that's stupid. I mean, they blue screen all the time. So I rebooted it, got it back up,
went back to my office, ran the test again. And my test hung again. I walked down to the
down to the lab and I looked at the machine and rebooted it and went back to my office.
Okay, coincidence. It's got to be a coincidence, right? Because these are, and it's like 50
yards away after walk, other part of the building. I run the test, I start the test,
and I kind of jog down to the lab, open the door. I think there was a number key on there.
I get in there, look at the machine and I watch it just blue screen right in front of me. I said,
cool. This is like a superpower. And probably out of all the bugs I found,
I was testing from Windows 95, but that bug on NT got fixed faster than any of my Win95 bugs.
So did you find a way to corrupt memory?
No, I know what this is 30 years ago. So I don't remember what happened. I just know that,
because what happened with these was hitting out before with these mixed by character sets.
If anything in the network stack would parse those as single bytes rather than characters,
it could screw something up and do something unexpected. So the blue screen was an unexpected
behavior of a poorly parsed mixed byte string. Okay, interesting.
You don't want your customers finding that one. No, it's kind of an edge case. So maybe
devs may not find it, but the moment you see that crash, you got to be able to debug it,
figure it out and get patches in, which reminds me of, do you remember years ago, they may still
have something like this? Again, learning from the customer, SQL had this, it's called like a
no repro policy or something. Meaning when they got a crash report from a customer,
they wanted to be able to have the logs in order to figure out exactly what went on and fixed it.
They didn't want to set up repros anymore. And anytime you had to set up a reproduction
environment in order to isolate the bug and fix it, part of fixing it was adding all the logging.
So if anything like it ever happened again, you could figure out what went wrong.
I think it's a good way to use customer crash data, use it to make your processes faster.
And then here we are today, 25 years later. I forgot about the days of doing repros.
I know. I don't like, I don't, um, this is one place where going back to when I went to,
when I went to Bing, right. Um, I joined about a year after one of the best testers in terms of like
the tester mindset and all that he had joined. And he's like, he saw that I was there and he's
like, Oh, Britt, I wish you had told me before you come, this place is horrible. The issue was,
he was just phenomenal at finding bugs, but bugs didn't matter in Bing because there was so many
different things that were happening every single second that literally, and I think even right now,
you type, you go to Bing, you type a query and you take a snapshot and you hit refresh and take
another snapshot. You'll see that there is a big difference between the snapshot, no matter how
often you hit refresh or how quickly you hit refresh because we had new data coming in. We
have a, we have a very smart AI that's making new decisions. And so he thought he'd find bugs,
but then they were completely non-reproducible. And so in this case, it was frustrating with him
or for him because the thing that he had to do, the thing that was valuable is what's the pattern,
right? He couldn't just say what's occurring. He had to in some way, shape or form explain why is
is it occurring. He had also been one of those, one of those testers that said, I am never going
to learn the code. And so he felt stuck. And I, I, I advise him and I said, look,
my life is easier because I, I do know how to code on this front, but I don't see a reason right now
for you to let go of that principle. You just have to learn a new trick. You can't rely on your old
trick all by itself. Like you are a brilliant tester. You are able to connect thoughts between
the systems. Now you're going to have to figure out how to do that from a strategic sense,
not just a pure tactical sense. And he understood, but he did not find any way to do that.
And I don't even think he's at the company anymore. All right, man. So, yeah. So what I
want to get into next time when we chat is kind of how people can get in, like,
how does someone get into experimentation and what skills from testing help with that?
What's going to be hard to learn? How do you learn those things? What does that mean for the
folks you work with? Obviously, you can't just decide as a tester that you want to
do experimentation and have nobody around you to help you. So let's talk through that next time.
A little bit of a shorter podcast this time to kind of kick things off because
Zencaster was mean to me today and I have a hard stop at about two minutes ago.
So good catching up. It was good reminiscing a little bit. And thank you, everyone, for listening.
Have a great time. Stay safe. God bless the queen. And we'll talk to you soon. I'm Alan.
I'm Brent.
Bye bye.
Bye.