And to be clear, when I was in college, I worked at a grocery store and I was a checker.
Welcome to AB Testing Podcast, your modern testing podcast. Your hosts, Alan and Brent,
will be here to guide you through topics on testing, leadership, Agile, and anything else
that comes to mind. Now, on with the show. Hey, hey, everybody. Hey, hey, hey.
Hey, it's AB Testing. It's AAB Testing. I was thinking Fat Albert. Hey, hey, hey.
We're doing a podcast and did you know we're doing a podcast? Are you aware of this fact?
Are you aware that we have a podcast? I just call in. What are we on? 167. So we've been doing this
podcast. Here is the question of the day, a little podcast trivia. And you can play along at home.
Just open your favorite podcast app and put in this code. What was the date that we posted
episode one of AAB Testing? Wasn't that April? April something April 1st.
What year? Oh, God, I have no idea. April 13th, 2014. Okay. We are coming up. We're six months
away from our nine year anniversary. Not too bad for two people who started a podcast for
really almost on a dare from Michael Hunter, right? Yeah. I don't know if it was a dare.
You guys should make a podcast. We're dumb enough to go. Um, sure.
I interpreted it a little bit differently. He could have said you guys should stick your
finger in a light socket. We would have gone. Um, yeah, sounds great. You might've. So I might've
because I'm not particularly bright, but what's interesting. And I want to do a little meta and
talk about the podcast a little bit here today. I was in a meeting today with some folks,
external to unity and with some folks internal to unity and, and almost all the time I'm finding
more and more stalkers and you know who you are. It's like the podcast was a different thing when
everybody who listened was an anonymous human being. We didn't know. Remember when we had three
listeners and like Jim Moore would come up and say, Hey, I'm one of your three listeners.
And Steve would say, I'm one of your three listeners and we only have three listeners,
but yeah. Okay. Good. Anyway. The point I was getting to was as you type away on your keyboard
is that these folks in this meeting are like, Oh, Hey man, you know, Alan was a podcast.
They listened to the podcast. So hi, Wyatt, hi, John. Hi, Stephen. I,
and anybody else is listening. It's not a very good podcast. I guess it is an excellent example
of the, this is no 98% invisible. Now it's the Malcolm Gladwell. Stop. This is an excellent
example of a podcast for the genre we invented. What's the genre? I'm leaving that for the
listeners. Oh, you know, actually we are the number one podcast of all time in our genre as well.
Absolutely. I completely agree. I'm, I'm picking up what you're laying down. So I switched to
anchor FM for hosting, which has been really good. And this, I'm not, I could do ads for anchor and
they pay us, but I don't, you know, uh, but anchor has been pretty good. There's your ad anchor.
If you're grepping text in our podcast, but they keep stats much better than my previous
platforms I used. Do you know? So it's been less than a year. It was last January. I
changed everything over to anchor and screwed up everybody's feeds and got it all correct again.
Guess how many another Japanese question. Another is on your quiz app. Everybody
guess how many people in that last year have gone back to listen to episode number one and
made it through the vast majority of it. Three. Oh, that what's weird. It could,
it could be the same three people each doing it 254 times because we have 700 or two wrong math.
You know, we have 712 listens of episode one in that last year. I don't know what you people
are doing. That is, uh, even though even its debut episode was still the top of our genre,
it was not even meh. It was, it was Brenton Allen trying to figure out how equipment work,
trying to figure out what to talk about, which is kind of what we're doing here. Eight and a half
years later. Yeah. You know, when you, when you master a skill, you make it part of the
environment and we'll call it the dark genre as well. But we've made it very clear on this
podcast and specializing generalists that I'm really a master of nothing. My secret skill
is I can learn enough of anything to be super effective, but I'm not a master of anything.
I will say your secret power in this context. And I do not, I do think that this phrase very well
captures it. And I do not in any way, shape, or form mean any offense. This is nothing but praise.
Right. You are the master of fake it till you make it. Oh, 100%. That is, you know, maybe that's how
we work together. So I was thinking about how different you and I are. Like I was making,
they're asking about the podcast and I, and someone brought up the fact we're talking about
politics sometimes. And I said, yeah, Brent's one of those stupid libertarians who let his political
views get in the way of actually making progress in the country. But we'll get, we'll get back
to that later. But also in this context, you know, Brent said, you're number one, number one of my
genre. That's great. So you have, you are a deeper expert in the areas where you need to be like,
you were deep in test automation and wrote a, a very good and probably one of the best
test automation harnesses used at Microsoft. Both a praise and a dig. Also what you're doing now with
data science and it's, it's super deep, what you know, and I'm more of a, I mean, you've seen me,
I can get around in the data science world and, but I faked everything, but it's, it's even
before I got into tech, that was my thing. I played in high school. I played clarinet and
saxophone. I did not want to bring my nice saxophone outside to play in the marching band.
So I learned how to play drums well enough to make the drum line in my high school. So then
I played drums and drum core, I played drums in college, college marching band. I even,
I did not know that. So here's the funny part. Not only did I do that, and then I played, I
played percussion. I made the top jazz band playing vibraphone vibes.
If you like those are. Is that the cool thing that they use to make the
Star Trek sound? It's like, no, no, no, that's a theremin. It's like a xylophone,
but metal wider keys, two octaves or one octave below often use in jazz. So a big fan of Gary
Burton for those of you want to dig in there. So I, I wanted to do it. It was actually easier path.
There was an easier path to me to get in the top touring jazz band playing mallet percussion
than it was for me to get in the long, long line of saxophones. So I did that for a while.
And then here's the funny part. I went out and everybody knows this that I taught school for
four years after I graduated. I came back to graduate school. You know, it was, I went back
to graduate school at the same school. They knew me, but we had a new percussion director who was
just fantastic. And in graduate school, I studied composition. I did not have to play an instrument,
but it was, I needed a place to like get people to play my composition. So I, so I lied a little,
what did I do? I don't know if I lied. I, I told them I was a percussionist and I joined,
and I joined the percussion department and I studied private lessons under not the grad assistant,
which all the, the noobs had to take underneath the professor. And I played in the, he put me
in the top percussion ensemble, assuming I knew what I was doing. And I absolutely faked it
until I make it. I remember him giving me a timpani solo. You want to tip, you know,
a timpani or like kettle drums. Yeah. They're cool. Yeah. But they're, they're tuned with your,
there's pedals that tune them and they're not easy to tune. There's a lot of ear in there and
a lot of like feel. And I just, you know, I practiced till I could do it. And I, I nailed
my timpani parts. I ended up playing timpani in our top orchestra as well. And just, I didn't
know what I was doing. I was faking my way through it. So that was my, so I faked my way through there,
but even, yeah, my whole life I have, I do like, if I want to do something, I'll learn just enough
so I can do it. And that's, um, until I'm not good enough to do that anymore. And then I do
something else. That's my thing. Yeah. I just wrote down five letters, J I T G E just to see if
it spells something cool because you are just in time good enough. Yeah, absolutely. To me.
So I'm a, I'm a believer in faking till you make it the problem. One of the things I think that is
different than you and I on that front is we both have sort of imposter syndrome.
I, you're in my way of resolving it is fundamentally different. And I'm trying to, like for me, I go to
an analytical space. I say, okay, I need to know this. So I'm going to frigging know it.
And I, in my quest for that knowledge, just to, just to alleviate the fear I have a random
imposter syndrome. I go, I definitely go deeper than, than you do. I don't have a solid sense of
good enough when I'm in that phase when I'm, when I'm running from my imposter syndrome fear.
Honestly, I think it is. And this is, you know, I don't mean this demeaning to myself or praising
to you, but it was a different, we have a different kind of intelligence or smartness.
You're able to go deeper. I get to a point where there are vastly diminishing returns on
me going deeper. I am, I am much better knowing a lot about a little than I am knowing a little
about a lot. And there are some things, obviously music, cause I faked it so long there. I know
some things about the same thing with, with computers and debugging and some of the areas
I've dug into, but I think the way I'm wired, I'm better suited to just to what I do.
I do what I do. Cause it's what I'm best at. This J I T G E is,
is the way for me to be the most effective in anything I'm doing. And I don't, I don't,
I just don't think I'm just build up more clearly. I don't know if I have the mental capacity to go
as deep as you do on some things. Well, uh, I don't know that that's true or not.
Cause I think I don't mean it's self demeaning. I kind of mean like I just,
I think it's the way it is.
Maybe, maybe. I mean, there's other, uh, there's other commonalities we do share,
right? We both, I would say we are both more starters than, than
closers in a lot of regards. You are a better closer than I am for certain.
And maybe that's why you were driven by good enough. It's like, okay, I, uh, you, you got
to close. Um, whereas I'm like, no, I got to figure out how to defer closure. Cause there's not enough.
None of here to make my imposter syndrome go away. But we, we are both fascinated by the new,
very interested by the new, right? Like, even though you and I are discussing our differences,
it doesn't, doesn't at all alleviate that we are, I don't know if there's a term for this, but
from a technical standpoint, ADHD written. Let me talk about the new because let's see if our
approach to the new is different. Cause I believe that I have read, you know, I read a lot of books
and when I'm in a groove, I'll read a book every two weeks and digital cover to cover,
but I probably have 50 books I've read half of because I get halfway through and I feel like I
have learned everything. I w I'm fascinated in chapter one. I am pattern matching the hell out
of chapters two through 10. And then I'm kind of done. Cause I figured out how to incorporate it.
So when I get a new idea, whether it's from a book or a video or a lecture or wherever,
I want to learn it well enough to understand if it fits within the other patterns that I know
and how to connect it. And once I get it there, though, I'm kind of done with it.
I have a similar collection of books and I'll say 50 of them. Well, so if we assume a subset of 50,
I would say 50% of them, I have at least finished chapter one. I'll say easily 25% of that 50,
other than opening the book to go, Oh, my book came. That's all I've done with it. And then
the other 25%, right? I'm still multitasking and working my way through it. Yeah. It's when I
collect books, I do it from a, usually I do it from, I have a very tactical problem that I'm trying to
solve. And I'm like, I think this thing is, is going to, to help fix it. I used to, my daughter
and I were talking about this, so I used to be a big sci-fi reader. And ever since shifting to data
science, I haven't, I haven't read just to read in forever. Stephen Johnson books, those are sort
of the last ones that I would read to sort of understand certain concepts better. Like where idea,
so we've talked about this before on the, in strength finders, I have ideation where ID
ideas come from is absolutely fascinating to me. And strength, the strength finders thing
very much indicates that the more you, that it's not a attribute of me, it's something that it's a
skill, it's something I can develop and take advantage of. And I do. Yeah, so that's sort
of in personal development. I see you reading things from my perspective. Some of the things you read
are just, I just go, that's randomly random. It doesn't, let me talk about what I'm doing.
So I have, let me go back to the first time I was a people manager and in hindsight, I didn't know
what I was doing. I was like, look, look at me. I'm not a micromanager because I'm giving people no
coaching, no guidance. I'm leaving them alone so I can do my own IC work and we'll talk when we
have time. Not very good. I didn't know, I didn't get people nearly enough feedback, good and bad.
I was lucky to have a good team. So we performed well. So if you look at how the team, if you
look at as a manager's reflection of the team doing well, I looked good because my team was
doing well because we had hired well. Then I struggled the first time I had employees who
weren't delivering and maybe I didn't realize they were delivering because I wasn't paying
attention. So I learned a lot. And then, so talking about running away from imposter syndrome. So now
I have a bank. Like I have a bank of knowledge I use to lead my team, to manage people, to
influence people, to make decisions, to build strategies, et cetera. I have a bank of knowledge
in my head, which has come from both a practice on the job training or on the job practice and
reading a bunch of books. So all the time I am looking at when I see a book or hear about a book,
or if I hear a review of a book, because I listen to so many damn podcasts, I hear people talk about
books. I will consider like, can this book bring new knowledge into my new knowledge,
into my body of knowledge? So my goal in all these books I'm reading is I want to think about
the pattern matching. I want to read this book and figure out, can I pattern match this? Does this
change? Does this change my body of knowledge? Does it make me make a fundamental like,
oh, I was looking at this wrong. Does it emphasize things I'm doing that maybe I want to do more of?
Like I, there's a psychological fallacy for this I'm sure, but the books that preach to what I
already do, I nod my head and go, wow, this is a great book because I already do this stuff.
I must be awesome. But still you get ideas on how to influence things. You get those anecdotes
you can tell to help, to help with all of those problems. So I'm just trying to add to my body of
knowledge and I ignore all the rest. So I talked about when I get halfway through sometimes,
and not all books are like this, but sometimes I get halfway through and it's like, well, I don't,
I've read last three or four chapters and found no new knowledge to incorporate. So I go and tell
my ROI on reading the book has faded. And that hasn't happened in a while. I've been reading a
lot of books all the way through lately, but I've been slowing down because work's been super busy
and gross and all that stuff. But that's sort of my approach. I'm trying to add to my knowledge,
bring in as much as I can to help me just get my, I was trying to like you and I the same,
trying to get better at what we do and it's incremental. But I always feel like there's
got to be one nugget that's going to help me do just a little bit better next week.
Because that's what I'm searching for. Yeah, I am constantly, I pay attention to
how do I stay in a leadership position in the things that I'm doing, but I'm also paying
attention to the next transition. Right. We've talked about this. So my role is a data science
and I do believe we're at the end of the data science era and it converts into a primary
dev role sometime before I retire. Right. And so I feel like, okay, while I'm working, I'm beholden
to number one, improve myself there and then guide my team in that direction. Right. And they
kind of benefit each other because then I'm leading by example as well as, you know, coaching and
guiding. Now the other difference is you're now a highfalutin executive and I'm still frontline.
So you're going to be probably guiding your directs more on the strategic sense and how to set good
principles. Yeah. And no, maybe. Yeah, you know, absolutely right. I am much more management
overhead, but also even, you know, when I was frontline, like my main objective,
and we've talked about this before on the podcast drink still in this role is, and one of the reasons
it's so challenging is I'm still trying to make myself obsolete. And this is a fun part. Never been
in this position before as, you know, really purely a manager and, you know, working across
the company, my entire role is to take my nine direct reports and make it so they can all
function completely without me. Let me give you an example. Well, that part makes it. It's not an
example. Let me give you an anecdote. I took last week, last week, oh God, we didn't talk about our
stuff. So last week I flew, which is a red eye Saturday night, a week ago, but no, it was two
weeks ago. I took a red eye from Seattle to Detroit and then flew from Detroit to Buffalo,
hung out with my kid for about six hours, went back to the airport, flew back to Detroit,
flew from Detroit up to Montreal, spent Monday, Tuesday, half day, Wednesday in Montreal.
Flew back to Detroit, back to Seattle. And I worked on Thursday.
Oh my God. That's so exhausting. All that, I did not catch COVID. Pretty exhausting. A lot of work.
It was necessary for me to spend a little time there and see some people. But one of my directs
pinged me and said, do you have time to talk to it? I said, okay, yeah, totally. Always have time.
And they said something to the effect of, I know we don't, because I cancelled all my one-on-ones
because I was traveling for that week. I took a week off from one-on-ones. And they said,
I'm so glad you found time. It's really hard, but I don't have a chance to check in with you every
week. And while I think the one-on-one is the most important meeting you can do,
that is a little bit of a yellow flag for me. I have to get, I think, I don't want that to be
the case. I want people to feel like they have the courage, autonomy, confidence to execute
without checking in with me regularly. Yeah, it does feel a little codependency-ish.
Well, it's not COVID. It's coaching. More coaching I need to do. It tells me I'm not obsolete yet,
so I'm still working. I got a ways to go. And I need all the skills and tips and tricks I can get
to get there. Yeah, I have similar phenomenon. Meanwhile, there's always rumors of, okay,
I'm making some progress and they go, oh, Alan, your org is good. Can we put some more teams in
your org? I go, no. Who are these people who get to define good? So before we get off even further
into whatever agenda we're actually talking about. No, the agenda is this winding road. For
those of you on the first time, welcome to the AB testing podcast where you learn what we're saying
pretty much the same time we are. It's not going to publish. It's, yeah, extra, especially
tangential episode. I know some podcasts have like a title and agenda before they start. Like,
imagine that. I feel like we used to function that way and then we don't, but this is kind of,
oh, by the way, today is international podcast day, which is why I wanted to take some more
time to talk about the podcast itself. That's there. There's the agenda. Anyway, you were saying,
oh, gotcha. Usually segues happen first, but you know, innovation is coming from Alan today.
Watch me magically edit this entire podcast coherent.
Yeah, you don't have the time for that. No, I don't. And you, I don't know, like you,
there was a time when you would listen to the podcast with your, with your son in the car,
but I think your sons are older now. They don't ride in the car with you anymore.
Uh, they don't, they don't. My daughter does still, you know, very often, but she is now at a point
where appropriately, uh, she doesn't want to listen to the podcast. Right. One of the things I'll
bring up, like I had not one of the three. Got it. She is not one of the three. Uh, my oldest
still was, uh, for a while in college, just, I guess, cause you know, he missed dad or something.
It's a way of checking on you to make sure you're not talking about him.
Right. But I encountered something that you've been dealing with for a long time. I encountered
it for the very first time. Um, on August 1st, I met my new employee who started off with,
I'm one of the three. No shit. And I'm like, what? Why?
Do you really not have anything better to do with your time?
Yeah. So it was my first day meeting her. So I didn't want to go into incessant mocking on the
first day, you know, good impressions and all that. You gotta work, you gotta build a relationship
where you can mock each other. Yeah. Right. Um, but I'm like, dear God, why?
Right. And that is my reaction to what I, today, when I heard these people say,
Oh, you should have got Alan's podcast. Alan is a podcast. And they're like, Oh God, no.
Anyway, go on. So the reason why is she, she knew person straight out of college,
was hoping to get some Intel on the manager. Right. And the title of the podcast is A B
testing. She's coming into a data science role. I see. Did she ask you? So I listened to your
podcast and it kind of sucks. What's your data behind continuing to do it? I had my one on one
with her literally an hour ago for this week. Uh, I may, I may need to bring up questions like that,
next time. Is it just basically seriously why like, it's almost to my mind, it almost should be
an interview question. Do you listen to the A B testing podcast? Yes. Oh, sorry. Yeah.
That's not, no, you need to make it a behavioral question.
Tell me about a time you listened to the A B testing podcast.
I wonder, I'm just putting myself in, into the threes shoes right now. And they're like,
what the hell? They're just spending the last 10 minutes bashing their own podcast.
To be fair, I mean, look, it is no 98% invisible. Like I said before,
but it is number one in this genre. It is number one in this genre. And,
what is that genre? What do we, it's, is the genre, it's something like two dudes talking
while they're drinking beer, even though I think we're both drinking coffee right now.
I have a Coke. Yeah. And we've only actually drunk anything adult beverage once.
Yeah. On my very last day at Microsoft. But that was a good adult beverage.
That was, that was an excellent adult beverage. So, uh, here I am, do you know,
and just to get an idea how time flies on the podcast and I should go look up what episode that
was. I think for sure, for sure. We have done more episodes with me, not at Microsoft than we have at
Microsoft for sure. I have been at unity now five years and seven months and the podcast is about
eight and a half years old. Doesn't that blow your mind a little bit? But when I think about
years in time, I try and anchor it to things, which has been really hard over the last two
and a half years. I've lost all my anchors. Like if the pandemic could have began three months ago,
it's all just kind of a blur or 10 years ago. But anyway, yeah, it does blow my mind. Been
here a long time. Still liking it. Yeah. Yeah. It's challenging. I, I tell, I, I need to tell
myself the same time, the same thing I tell people on my team. If it was easy, it wouldn't
be fun. Right. And that's absolutely true. Although the corollary, the corollary is true too,
I think that if it's not easy, then it better be fun. Well, oh, I ran into tangents. I keep on
running into people I knew in a past life. I found one of my skip levels worked on teams.
He joined after I left. I thought that was kind of funny. Oh, and then I found somebody else who
just met in the office in the day. They used to work on, they remember me from Xbox and I,
I had forgotten who they were. Yeah. We're, we're at that age too. No kidding, right?
They're, they're all the time now actually with COVID. So the other thing that's happening
is I'm doing with COVID, you do end up doing a lot of presentations online and you have no
like, you don't even see the audience list on teams a lot of the time, right? Because it's,
it's, it's like 70 people and you, you just see like the three that had their hands raised.
You don't have, does teams not have like a gallery view where you can see everybody?
They do. Because like when I do a team meeting, I use gallery view so I can see people's like,
I can, these days I'm getting good at, I can zoom in on facial reactions. I can say,
Hey Lance, you're making a face. What's up? Do you actually have a guy named Lance on your team?
I do. And I'm probably listening right now. Sorry, just pick, just pick the name.
The, uh, you're talking about teams and lectures. So that's the subject I want to talk about,
but go ahead. The point I was bringing up is, is it's often the case someone will come up
and it will go, Oh, Hey Brent. And then I'll look at them and I'll go
and they don't have a mask on, which, and I'll still go, Hey person,
based off of your reaction, I should probably know, but have no idea why you know my name.
It is difficult to match from the 2d world to the 3d world. But I was in Montreal two weeks
ago. I had a lot of that and people both that I had been on my team. I never met in person to
people I knew that I had seen before in the 3d world is a lot of people said, Oh, Hey, Alan.
And of course I have this, um, uh, small beard makes me more recognizable, but like,
they're there. I just, a lot of that. Well, it depends. Like if, if you, uh,
if you go and search for you on, on the interwebs, right? You find the football
player, Supreme court justice, Alan Page. No, no, no. You, you I'm, I'm saying find you not search
for your name, but search for you. Okay. Right. You, you've had facial hair forever, but not
this glorious, uh, uh, uh, noun that you, that you're sporting. Now I could come up with a good
noun. So, uh, yeah, feeling your best Maine. Maine's a good one that you're, you're sporting now.
Yeah. It's my tribute to COVID. And a lot of the times, a lot of the times I'll go on conference
calls and I keep my camera off. And so it's a picture that I haven't updated in like 10 years.
I keep the camera off because I'm a big old fatty fat from fat Phil now. And I can't stand looking
at my camera. I, if you notice right now, I'm like backed away because then with my eyesight,
my own image kind of just blurs out and for you, I can just stare at you.
All right. And that is a beautiful thing to look at. So, um, I know originally when we talked three
weeks ago, I took last week off, but we talked three weeks ago, uh, we were going to talk about
how someone goes from testing into a more experimentation role and we may get there today,
but I do have one more question now that we're on the subject of, let me talk about podcasts.
And this is not the normal AB testing, but what the hell we can do. We want. It's our podcast.
I heard a podcast and again, adding to my knowledge and a lot of times what happens is
I'll get an idea and I want to experiment with it. So I heard an interview with a leader at
Doest and Doest is the company that makes a to doist, which I'm a big user of for task
tracking. And they also make a, um, sort of a Slack teams like app called, uh, twist,
which I'll come back to in a minute. They are just 90 people in 30 countries and which is,
you know, a little unity, like we're pretty spread out. And I was talking to somebody this week,
you know, Microsoft is actually talking to one of these folks, he used to work at Microsoft in
the Vancouver office. I have one of those on my team and Microsoft. I don't think you can argue
with this brand. It's very Redmond culture that maybe it's different from what I've been there,
but very Redmond culture, 90% of the companies in Redmond. If you're not in Redmond, it's kind of
it's common knowledge. At least it used to be, it's harder to get promoted, harder to make,
you know, influences the, the, it's a very Redmond culture.
Um, I will say, yes, that is still probably true, but it's, it's far different.
Yeah. I imagine, I imagine skinny, but you're getting more global. And I was thinking about,
well, where I work at unity, we're not definitely not every third person in a different country,
but our, our headquarters isn't even our largest office. So, uh, so that, but it's a little,
it's a lot more the same ever, but anyway, do as, uh, because they're global and we're global too.
And you know, I have people spanning 10 time zones. Actually, if I don't count my teams in
APAC, nothing against people in APAC, I'm just limited hours in the day, lots of time zones,
but doest do almost everything asynchronously. And it made me think like, what am I doing? How,
one thing we haven't learned, I'm curious if you've got any tips or tricks on this is as a company,
we're not great at working asynchronously. And I want to get better at it. So I started reading
more of their article. They have great articles on doest.com on, on how they've learned to work
asynchronously things they do. And some of them are kind of out there, but it's like even their
CEO has like four meetings a week. Okay. I'm listening. Right. The, the, if this,
my problem with asynchronously is I do not, I do not yet know of a good technique to work asynchronously
and still build a, a strong team. Right. And so, so as you know, from like my discussions with
Colossal and things like that, what I, what I work towards is not making a team of rock stars,
but a rock star team. And if this book can, can solve both of those things, like,
yeah, well, there's no book. There was a block or there was a podcast that I listened to and I then
started reading articles from the company. And so there's no book. And also you're absolutely
right on the relationship building and the team building, it accelerates so many things.
It's like you got to get people to the whole team together for a week and then they can work
apart asynchronously for a while and be pretty successful. It is really hard to do it off the
bat. It takes, I think it takes some discipline and practice. And one of the reasons they built.
So actually this is something teams is better at than Slack. Oh my God. Did I say that
is, uh, if you remember way back in the day, um, I worked on teams, um, we had threading built in
Slack said, Oh, threads may be convenient and sort of, they added threads, but they're really lame
threads in Slack or lame. So, so what really bugs me is in Slack, somebody makes a post and sometimes
there are comments and reactions or, um, questions to that in the main channel and some are on a
thread and they get intermingled with other messages. It's very confusing. So they built,
it wasn't working for them. And so they built twist, which is just yet another messaging only
pla it's messaging only platform, but it's threaded by default. So it's the old style.
If here's a post and you make comments on that post, you don't make another post to reply to it
just to kind of force people down that path. And they use these threads to work asynchronously.
So it is possible. Uh, you got to get people engaged on it. A lot of times people,
yeah. If you don't get them in that meeting to draw them out, it's hard,
especially if they don't know you, there's that level of trust involved.
I think it takes a ton of work. So kudos to them if they're working asynchronously.
It's you can't just say we're going to work asynchronously now and have it work.
No, it is a battle. No, because there's, there has to be something that is
guiding what gets done next. What, what direction are we heading? Do we adapt, persevere? Like that,
that just going straight up all async from an intellectual point of view. It's fun to think about.
Well, let me talk about a couple of things I'm going to do after reading all this stuff.
One is I'm still going to do all my one-on-ones. They do async one-on-ones. I need
the FaceTime, but how many, I'm going to ask you this. How many times in your one-on-one
does your direct report ask you a bunch of questions or give you a bunch of information
that didn't have to be in the one-on-one? It could have been in a team's message or an email.
Oh, 50 to 80 percent of the time.
More than would be more than is necessary. And that to me, that cuts down on the time we could
talk about career, earlier before we talked about career growth and strategy and working
with them on that. So one thing I'm going to do is make sure we have a shared channel so we can have
discuss more of those tactical things asynchronously, those little check-in things.
Like what do you think about this? I want to do that. I don't want to take our one-on-one
time to do that. I want to take our one-on-one time to talk about how I can help them grow
enough where I can be obsolete. That's my goal in the one-on-one. And if I have to check in on,
hey, what do you think I should do with this hiring thing? I don't want to just ask me elsewhere.
So that's one thing. So there's a little tweaky adjustment I can make. I can add some async and
keep the relationship building part. Well, that's where I think the coaching habit works well.
Yes, absolutely. And that's the kind of, that's what I want. I would like 90 to 100 percent of my
one-on-one time to be coaching and take care of the other stuff. Async. So that's one thing
I'm going to do. The other thing is I should probably glance up my calendar for a second,
which is. Are you writing these down? Because it seems like you're proactively writing up your
New Year's resolutions. No, I don't do resolutions. Oh, gotcha. Okay. So the other thing is that a lot
of meetings I'm moving to from, I don't know how it is with you. I know that Microsoft, a lot of
the meetings weren't very useful where I'm at now. Most of my meetings are, but I'm actively
moving 60 minute meetings to 30 minute meetings. All of my 30 minute meetings right now appear to
be one-on-ones looking at my calendar. Anyway, just looking for things like,
there's a meeting coming up on Monday. I'm not going to name the meeting or the group it's with,
but it is a monthly meeting that is constantly a meeting that should be an email.
And if I gave some feedback after the last one, and if it happens again,
I will do something. I'm not going to tolerate it anymore. My time's too valuable and not like I'm
like, Oh, my time's too valuable. I need some, I got to eat my caviar at 830. I'm tired of meetings.
No, I actually, that's an interesting topic because one of the things, so I have two
newly minted principles working for me.
It is nice, but so I'm trying to help them adapt to what that role means. Because when you switch
bands, it's very common for people to initially start off with, Oh, it's the same thing as the
other band, just more. And new, no, it's not. And they're like, what? Yeah, no, it's not. And
walking them through it. And one of the things that I've been trying to get them to understand,
and I haven't, you kind of touched on it. It's like, look, I want you to be allergic to being,
to spending your time on things that a significantly lower level person can do
competently. Right. That is not, there is no ROI for your time on that.
But Brent, what if as your principal, I can do it twice as fast as the more junior level person?
Well, then if it is something like there's a live site where I need the fire put out,
then it might be the right call. But if it's something that's repeated, then actually,
you are not helping me grow these lower level folks. Yeah, exactly. Right. And I do put it on them.
Like, look, whether you wanted the job or not, you're now a principal and people are looking and
watching and you are leading by example. And I want that example to be something when you look back
on it, you go, oh, I am proud of what I did there. Right. It's not around being a dick and say,
do you? Right. No, I'm not doing that. Let's say you're talking to a PM or something. Like I talk to
lower level PMs all the time and they're like, okay, great. Can you do this? This query for me?
Mm, good. I can. Not gonna. Right. If like with in particular with PMs, my strategy is
so far until I can't scale. Anyone who wants to learn to fish come to me, I will spend the time
and I will teach you to fish. But if you're coming to me thinking I'm the fish welfare department,
yeah, you're wrong. Go away. Yeah. So actually this reminds me as we as we spin our web through
tangentville, you took a little bit of shit. We had an incident with one of our internal systems
two weeks ago and I spent some time in the incident channel helping to debug because
debugging is one of the things that I got good enough that I I'm pretty good at.
I think somebody gave me some crap or like as a as you call me, the uppity exact.
Is it really a good use of your time to spend time looking at this incident and actually
given it was mission critical? Yeah, yeah, I can spend some time there poking around. It's
all right. Yeah. Yeah. But regularly I don't want to do that. I shouldn't be in every incident
helping them debug. That would be dumb. No, it it's it's it's a good it's a good thing to get
your hands dirty on things like that every so often so that you can you can get a sense of
why can't someone lower level? Yeah, figure this out. Let's rewind the stack once. So I'm going to
I'm committing to not making a resolution. I'm going to make my one on ones better by having
more async communication with my direct reports. I am going to again, this is just I'm looking at
information is what I do. I take a bunch of information in I figure out how much is practical
to incorporate with or to experiment in the current way I do things. I want to encourage
more async work. I want to encourage more communication. Sometimes it's a European to
America handoff. I don't know how do I get those conversations to happen? I don't know
getting discussion or we don't really have discussion meetings, but getting
a check in meeting or need to make a decision to get those to happen faster.
I think 90 percent of 60 minute meetings can be done in 30 minutes. I think probably a lot of
30 minute meetings can be done in 15 minutes. Let me go. Can I tell you one thing that bugs
the hell out of me is when we are in a 60 minute meeting or a 30 minute meeting, I don't care,
a long meeting and we get down to five minutes left and we're done and some buddy running the
meeting says, okay, we have five minutes left. What should we talk about that? Does that happen
to you all the time? That's how the that's how the meeting gets converted from
ending early to going a half hour over. Oh my god. Why do people do that? I like I try and make a
practice of it like I have I have employees to do this too and I give them feedback.
If there is a minute left, you do not get to say one more thing. A minute left is done. Anything in
five minutes. If there's a pause in the conversation with five minutes or less left,
the meeting's over, especially in the in the online world where I need a chance to go fill
up my coffee cup or my water glass or use the bathroom. That's that said, that said,
if I have five minutes left, I would rather and someone has a burning question. Why did it not come
up in the first 25 minutes? Sometimes people forget things. Right. When the I would rather them ask me
that now, then set up a whole other half hour meeting, but it's cyclical. They should be asking
you that question in teams or slack or whatever thing you have. But they're because we haven't
figured out how to work a sink because those questions don't get answered. They feel like
they have to ask you in the meeting. Right. And that's wrong. And I want that to be fixed.
That's my point as a world in technology, the fact that we have not learned, and I should say we
generally do rock this as well as probably many other companies. But you and I can say
for our respective worlds, we have not learned nearly as much about working
asynchronously in the last two and a half years as we should have in hindsight.
No, I do think there has been a lot of learning around working autonomously.
Yes. But asynchronously towards a mutually agreed valuable direction has definitely not
occurred in a lot of regards autonomously in that same direction has often not occurred.
Autonomous, autonomous. Yeah. Anyway, go ahead. No, I can fix that for you. So autonomy without
alignment doesn't work. If I give you autonomy to do your work, you still need to know what
problem you're trying to solve. And so what's happened is we have these meetings to try and
get alignment. We're unable to get alignment asynchronously. We use the meetings to gain
alignment or we don't gain alignment at all. And people work autonomously and they just work
on random shit because they don't have any alignment of what they're supposed to be doing.
Autonomy does not work without high alignment. Sorry. High autonomy does not work without high
alignment. Right. No. In a team environment with that. Sure. But seriously, if I'm
working by myself on something, my solo project to do whatever, I already have autonomy because
I'm not accountable to anybody. I can do whatever the hell I want. Anyway, Async would love to hear
each of our three listeners from you on what it means to work asynchronously and how your
companies are doing. I would love to read much, much more about this. There's a ton of articles
from Doest. You cannot believe how many are out there. I'm sure other companies do this. I would
love to hear how it works. And I'm a little embarrassed that we haven't done better. That's
all. Okay, man. So I know I said this at the end of the last podcast, but really next time we
should really talk about what it takes to go from being a traditional checker, tester, whatever
people do, whatever they call themselves. Nobody calls themselves a checker. So why do we call
it checking versus testing? I have no idea. I guess it's because the devs keep checking,
but they're called developers, not checkers. I don't get it. Anyway, I want to talk about
how someone goes from a more typical testing role into doing experimentation or A-B testing or
something that actually helps you understand what your customer is doing and make their lives better.
And to be clear, when I was in college, I worked at a grocery store and I was a checker.
Oh, nice. Nice. Nice. That's good. Then I left that job to become a tester.
That's a really good point. Did you do anything in between? Did you go from college,
right, into testing at Microsoft? Yeah, no, remember. Well, you may have forgotten.
So my path to Microsoft was a little unique. Oh, yes, that's right. I remember now. And then
did you ever read that book called How We Test Software at Microsoft? No, I possess it.
I possess it too. I've scanned a few things, right? It's for me because I know all of the authors.
It was kind of fun to kind of go through and say, okay, can I guess who wrote which and things?
Did I tell you about the time when I was actively looking for new jobs outside of Microsoft? And
I had a recruiter literally asking me. So on a scale of not at all to the author,
how we test software at Microsoft, how much do you know about testing at Microsoft?
Are you asking me? No, that was that was what I was asked. I didn't realize I was one of the
authors or the main author. Really? Is that what they said? Yeah. You're like,
um, to be clear at this point in time, 120%. Well, there I did the math. I said, well,
the other authors wrote about 70 pages each and I wrote about 270 pages. So, um, I did the math,
whatever percentage that is, that's how much I know. Plus whatever you've learned that now makes
that book. And what's funny is they didn't contact me back after that. I think my answer
was too much of a smart ass. I decided I was a Dick. Yeah. Well, it's okay, man. I ended up
with a good gig that I like. So all is good, man. All is good. Dumb things happen to all of us in
life. And we, and we, we avoid the life is all about just getting through the obstacles and
surviving. Life is an obstacle course. I completely agree. But on that last thing that you just said,
I absolutely am supportive of being your, your true self in an interview. And if they don't
call you back, that's frigging fantastic. Did I tell you about the time I interviewed at Amazon?
I decided about a quarter of the way into my second interview. There was absolutely no way
I was ever going to work there. No, you did not. And then I, I, and I, I just, that was my attitude
the rest of the day. What was that? I really convinced me. I want to work here because I
don't want to be here. They made me finish my day of interviews. Um, I asked a lot of
questions about, I kind of mocked their questions because they were, I was, I maybe didn't have a
good panel. I don't know. It was a joke. And I felt like I was inside of like a business firm more than
a software company. And then they actually, they, uh, called me back and said, well,
Hey, you weren't a good fit for this role, but we can, we'd like you to come back for a lower
level job. And I said, actually, no, I'm good. Yeah. Thank you. No, not a good, not a good fit.
I'm sorry, Amazon. I, I, I spend a crap ton of money with you, but you're, you're not the place
I would ever work. I'm sorry. Uh, nor, nor will I. And I too had my own, uh, I had my own experience
there and I'll just say like the, the, their bar razor, you know, do you know that? Yeah.
Yeah. I know all about the bar is actually, I should say Amazon's a big company. There could
be groups at Amazon that I would love working in. I just had like this experience of like, wow,
thank you for bringing me in because now I know I don't want to work here. This is actually very good.
Yeah. Their bar razor had a, had a laptop that had a sticker on it that had, had F but not F
the full spelled out Microsoft. Oh, that's awesome. Right. And, and there, and I'm like,
interesting laptop. Right. And, and to me it was interesting because I'm like, okay,
what culture where you're, what, what can you say about the culture that, that sort of permits
profanity on laptops? It doesn't have like a, some sort of stigma against it. I mean, I'm not,
I'm not anti profanity, but I'm like, okay, that's an unusual thing about, uh, and, uh,
to me that's, that's an antithesis to the culture that I experienced in my interview.
But I do want to say that speaking of the bar razor, I am taking an online training course
available through, uh, unity on, uh, interviewing, which is actually excellent. And it's done by a
guy whose name I forget who was, I don't know if he was one of the inventors of the bar razor or
anyway, or he's involved in it at least, I don't know, but really good tips on not just tips, but
guidelines on doing good interviews. I've seen a lot of bad interviews. As you know, I wasn't as
appropriate at Microsoft, like a gazillion interviews. I had seen so many bad interviews. It's good to,
good to have a refresher. And again, it goes back to that book of, I like the books where I
nod my head all the way through. So I'm, I'm watching this training and kind of nodding my
head all the way through. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. This is good stuff. More people, more people should,
should watch this anyway, man. I don't think anybody's still listening because, uh,
this was a, they kept on waiting for us to get to the point. And the point is that the podcast
is now over. Yeah. I mean, I understand. I stopped listening like 10 minutes ago. Same. Same. All right,
man. It's been good hanging out with you. I will see you in two weeks for episode 168 on the road
to 200 and the 10 year anniversary. We'll see how things go. Awesome. All right. I'm Alan.
I'm Brad. Bonne voir. Bye. Sayonara.