All right, let's dance. Let's go. Let's move it. Let's shake it
Welcome to a B testing podcast your modern testing podcast
Your hosts Alan and Brent will be here to guide you through topics on testing
Leadership agile and anything else that comes to mind now on with the show. Hey everyone. It's Alan and
Brent and we're here for episode
161 of the AB testing podcast as you can tell my voice is a little off today
COVID
You know, that's that's what I thought so I got back from Copenhagen had a little cough like a well, it's my turn I guess
Got a piece. So I had symptoms. Alright, so I had a symptom had a cough and I went and got a PCR test right away
It came back negative. I took a couple antigen tests and said including one just like an hour ago
Looking down. It's still negative. So I think I may actually just have a cold. I have no other symptoms out of cough
Yesterday and the day before my voice was really bad and this is kind of on the mend
So, I don't know
So maybe I have COVID and none of the tests will work on me and the tests give an amazing number as you know
If you know anecdotally from I'm sure as I do that a lot of times they're negative even when someone has COVID
So but I'm thinking not I think because for lots of reasons, but anyway, you have important insights to share
No, I was just gonna say so
So what happened to the team in Copenhagen? Were you were you yelling at them the entire trip? No, no the the
opposite the opposite there was too many fun
Conversations and hugging what happened what I think happens is this I have been in this office
Which Brent can see nobody else can see pretty much non-stop for the last two years
With very few human interactions. I think I lost any immunity that I had to anything else in the world
I think anytime I venture outside my house and with people I'm probably going to catch something for a while
Oh, so you're like the aliens and what was it war of the world? Yeah. Yeah. Yeah something like that something like that
I think there's something like that going on so that you no longer have
immunity against
common human diseases. Well, I think I'll build it back up. I am planning to
travel I'm gonna get back to a
I don't know what to call it a
Regular but infrequent travel. I'm gonna head down to San Francisco for a day
Remember I used to do day trips San Francisco back in the before times. I'm gonna do another one coming up here
Yeah, yeah, obviously not till my voice is better
But maybe July sometime be a good good time frame and then heading to Montreal in
September for a week need to visit the team out there and then probably head back to Copenhagen
Maybe in October or probably probably November and I'll split it. I'll spend three days in Copenhagen
Leaving on the third day and then so two and a half days in Copenhagen and then two full days in Helsinki
I haven't visited that team in a while either and then
Gosh, I got a visit Brighton too. So I'm pretty well spread out
But the biggest pockets of people on my team are Copenhagen Helsinki and Brighton
But I have a lot of my leader
I have a couple leaders in San Francisco probably my top managers down there
I want to go visit them see some of the team there a lot of the partners I work with are there
So yeah, I just got to get out and see people it's
not surprising
but also
surprising how
Effective it is to see people face to face once in a while
There's stuff you get done in a in a conversation in a room full of people that would take
Half a dozen or ten zoom meetings to get through. I don't know why the other thing is
You're gonna comment on that. I'll go on there's absolutely you got a comment there, right? It's interesting as as as
As you know
I've been coming into work for pretty much all but one month of the whole COVID start and
and
Certain things are changing that are annoying. I actually have an old-school commute now when I go back home
Like 405 is is trash
and
I'm like, oh, yeah, I didn't didn't miss this
And every now and again, right? I've gotten to a custom like I'm not gonna mess with the camera
But I have a parking spot
It's been my parking spot for two years and now people are taking you had you had no
It's mine with nobody around probably even light security at Microsoft
You could have put an A B testing logo in that spot along with Brent only I
Still good. That's
It's again
But but let me but it's different like there's a difference like like some people need to leave work and be it like you
Need to be in an office away from home to be productive. That's different
It's the it's the seeing people part and there's two things that one is just
having a proper debate and conversation in a large group is
Just more effective in person in my experience
But the other thing is that was really fun about the trip was in zoom or in your case teams
All you ever talk about on that 30 minute 60 minute video call is work
We net we just don't have enough of those non-work conversations, which are so important to get to know people and
They're more
Recharging then then work over zoom. Yeah, there's there is that there is that that's slow
relationship
building
That you just can't I can't do over over a cough call
It's exactly I had
I guess it's now about three weeks ago. I
Had I was in my office and I had someone knock on my door
And I'm like, whoa
What am I supposed to do?
like
And and she's like hi Brent I am random PM and
I was told that you might be able to answer. I'm like, oh wow
This is like I remember this when people would randomly stop by and interrupt you in your office
I'm like, I'm doing that right now. Wow
Right. It was weird now on the other side though. There are certain people
That I realized I missed working with
Individually like standing up at a white board. Yes in brainstorming
brainstorming shit
That was fun
Yeah, yeah
That that that sort of creative energy, which is really hard to do over
over the cuff call that
For me we've talked about this before my number one strength is ideation. I'm all about brainstorming
Invite me to any friggin brainstorm event you want. I'm in because it's massively energizing, but it's just
It's flat over
At least I haven't I haven't
The white board in zoo, I'm sure it's the same in teams
They haven't figured out how to use it
Well, yeah now and really to do those like right you kind of need a tablet and a pin device
With that being connected to a shared whiteboard
We have one of our conference rooms in Copenhagen, by the way has that has a a touchscreen that you can draw on
And it shows up in the whiteboard for zoom which which kind of works
But it worked better if everybody had one and not just all the people in the conference room
It was also the first time I had a lot of meetings where like it's different when everybody's on zoom
What's a little weird? I think on both ends is when you have
10 people in one room on zoom and then
10 other people all on zoom like like individually
There's a weird meeting dynamic when everyone's in this hybrid world where everyone's not remote
I've experienced that same thing as well and as much one of the benefits of
This conference call world is it was a great equalizer
the remote people
Didn't feel left out
and it was because
Hallway chatter you can't really call into hallway chatter. Of course
the problem is it's a great equalizer because it's
It's focused on the least common denominator, which is not something I've ever really been
Abort on you don't you don't equalize everyone by bringing the highest people down. You bring the lower people up. It's weird
We'll never gonna get and I'm okay with this. We're never gonna get to a world where
90% of all of us are back in the office again, just just not gonna happen
but I think we need to get better at
Figuring out what this hybrid world looks like like I'm going to the office two days a week now
So I'm doing some of my one-on-ones in person. I actually have
Two direct reports in Bellevue now weird, right? No, I thought you've always had no I didn't for a while
I didn't have any team members in Bellevue. Now. I have two direct reports. We hired a director of docks and my
Internationalization lead is in Bellevue. That was the consequence of your last
Last move right? It's too hard to keep track. It's kind of like a never-ending carousel of shifting
Gotcha. Anyway, um, no, you know some insights there good to be back. Sorry about my voice
I think they're wondering who is on the podcast with Brent this week. Who is this guy?
He sounds pretty smart. Maybe he should replace Alan speaking of I don't know about smart
But you got the voice growl there you definitely sound sexy. Well, there's a it's a fine line between sexy and smart
I think that's a lot of a lot of famous philosophers have said that
Well, then there's hope for me yet. Hey, I keep on digging on Microsoft
I'm gonna do it really quick here for a second
But then all right
I want to talk about like then you do some things that I like which freaks me out
So I want to one quick dig is I had to spend some time with the Windows machine this week for the first time in a long
Time and I am so glad we're on two tracks because Brent is like slurping coffee
Anyway, so I had to spend some time on a Windows machine had to troubleshoot my daughter's machine brand new machine
Came with Windows 11 installed could not connect to the internet
Wi-Fi card is working. It's connected to my internal network. It can't connect to the internet
Doesn't have an IP address did not get an IP address from my router. Well, maybe my router screwed up
I'll make a hot spot on my phone. Nope. Can't get one from there either
I download drivers to a USB stick for my Mac and move them over I install those I go through a bunch of
Unbinding rebinding things random solutions on the internet
People have asked had this similar problem on several different computers and they've all tried these different things which is bad enough and
The the error messages from Windows are I hope you realize this are I know you don't work on Windows are pretty horrible
I forgot how horrible they were you don't like
0 X e 8 9 4 C 0 0 8
I actually and then oh gosh my wife's computer is blue screening, but they've now hidden
I used to be able to kind of half debug from the blue screen what was going on and know what to go look at
Now it's all hidden from you because that's more user friendly God
It's like in trying to make things friendly to screw it all up. Anyway, networks not working
I have looked at everything to try and make this work. The internet is no help. It's just broken
So I go in old school. I get to the the the network properties dialogue
Which coincidentally is unchanged pretty much from when I used to test that in Windows 95
But anyway, I go through there and I go I'm just looking at for something. I don't know what it was something
Yeah, a red a red bang someplace. Anyway, there were no red bangs. Everything was working correctly
It gets to my router wouldn't get an IP address. So a
Little voice in my head just something telling me it's probably gonna be the dumbest thing ever. It's Microsoft
It's got to be something stupid. So I disabled IP v6
I unbound IP v6 from the network card boom on the network in a second
No explanation. I'm sure I mean by the time she needs a daughter's computer by the time she needs IP v6
I'm sure there'll be some patch for it that makes it work. But that kind of shit infuriates me. So
Windows is a steaming pile of crap. However, when you tell me Satya is doing good stuff and I go near yeah
Whatever you're actually right
Like I see all kinds of great stuff coming from and the latest is and I want to talk about this a little bit
I think it's really important. I think every company should do this is
is
Going to post salary ranges with jobs
And there's a couple things I want to as we've helped people adapt to modern testing
I think I have a few tips on how to help people and help people adapt to
Salary ranges offer with jobs because there are a few traps there. Did you know about this?
It's announced internally to see the news on this. Yeah. No, I know about this. Okay. I think it's pretty cool
A lot of fairness comes out of this
What do you think?
Before I start with them, what do you think some of the traps are with that? I will say I
Supported but mostly from a principal standpoint
Transparency and data
versus
Invisibility and
subjectivity
I'm always gonna pick transparency and data. I don't
know
Why they're doing this move what problem it solves
And I guess time will will bear it out
I think I think it solves the problem of fairness that a lot of people are worried about
I think people feel often like they're low-balled for a job
Which I working, you know, I they happen. I don't know
But it gives you a range now. I think it's good
I think all companies should do it, but there are some traps in a job search. So what happens if
Okay, I've posted a job level n
we'll just make up a number level n and the salary range is between
135 and 185
You love the job description print you think this is a job I want
But you'd expect to get paid more. Do you just now? What do you do now? It's like the difference is
You may not apply if that salary range is too low for you. I think that's fair to do, right?
Right on the other hand think back to the days when maybe you looked at I think I don't if you ever looked at the
Internal job site at Microsoft and think people just came and got you and and and recruited you but I've done both
Often you'd look at a level higher than you were
Because something you stretch into right I think the thing to keep in mind in that range 135 185
Maybe I would just again transparency. I would be upfront just I would just contact the company say I love this role
I really want to do it. I think I can do more than here and my salary requirements are higher and
Maybe they'd up level the job like today often will in the background someone comes in and they're awesome
They've interviewed for a job. We haven't shared the salary range, but we up level the job in the background or to give them a fair offer
Correct. Yes
And the same thing can happen here's where it gets weird because the same thing could happen the other way say you a lot of
People apply for jobs are not
They're not qualified for it, right?
But I hire humble hungry and smart if you have the right attitude
You have a desire to learn and I can tell you make good decisions
I know you're gonna learn quickly on the job. I want to be able to I guess it just because matter of transparency
I say look, I can't bring you in at level N
I really want to hire you at level n minus 1 and here's why and here's the things you need to do and
Your and your salary may not fit in that range
I guess it just forces me to be transparent in that range too, but I guess the point I want to make is in
Publishing those salary ranges
I think people both below and above that salary range should apply anyway and just be
Transparent about what they want. I don't think when a company posts a salary range with a job
Can we post a job and same as Microsoft you post a level a job at a level?
You have a certain expectation of what you want out of that role
You may hire someone who's a little less than that or a little more than that because they're the right fit for the team, too
Right the one thing about salary ranges that I do think
will help in the fullness of time is
Essentially to sort of level set expectations each of the big companies in in Fang
I guess it's now main the empty MS for meta not right Microsoft
They don't get to be fang
No, actually so so he he updated it and Microsoft is now in the list
I think they're calling it mama now. Oh my god. Yeah, whatever and
Netflix got dropped the
Anyway, my point is you go when you find out Oh
Google's Google's got a perfect role for me. That's an L7
And I'm like, okay, well, what the hell's an L7?
right is
so for me in my roles
Where where I might look into I want to know is this an executive position or not as an example
Right and in unlike you I
Will like the big money, but I don't want the executive position
Now it might depend on the the company
Right. It's one of the things I love about my job right now
I have broad scope but I get to sit in the type of role that that I love which is the ground level
Manager and so that kind of gives me a sense of okay
What would be the role expectations above and beyond what they're communicating here, right? If it's an executive
Okay, you're gonna be spending your whole day in meetings and and
This is where it levels FYI can help
What is that levels on FYI website where you can compare levels between companies?
Fan that'll help it figure it out
Yeah, I I honestly don't think I will ever I think when I leave this company
Well things could change
I'm in the best job I've ever had I don't I don't see any reason to
To move. Yeah, if you enjoy your work and your manager is not an asshole
I would keep doing it, you know, I can tease I can you know complain about windows
But that's it autonomy mastery and purpose if you feel like your work matters and you enjoy it and you're you
Given the freedom to do it in a way that makes sense and you balance that with accountability, of course
And you have the skills you need just keep rolling. That's the gravy train
right, no, it's
Chocked full of happy sauce, right?
There's a couple other things that Microsoft is doing and I'm wondering
Wonder if you so there's another one so like
the equity angle on terms of posting
Salaries that's an interesting angle. I hadn't thought about before
I think there's probably gonna be pros pros and cons
I think people end up doing a lot of comparing between companies and which is gonna be bad at first
they'd be good in the long run because
God, you know, this could go all the way from chaos to
Companies calibrating their their you know in it, you know indirectly calibrating their job descriptions together
Well, I think that for sure is gonna happen. Like I have no idea what what this will do in terms of our competitors
Right as you know
Companies in fangs slash mama
They're constantly stealing employees from each other, right?
So I don't know if that's gonna make that easier harder what that's gonna do
right from a from a negotiation standpoint
Well, it'll change something but change doesn't necessarily mean good or bad now
Microsoft getting rid of the non-disclosure agreement
I'd love to see more details on
that one in
general what I understand of it is
Positive and you don't have to answer this what might take from the outside after me leaving and going through it is
I think it's just too hard to enforce
Why bother? No, so I don't know that they're going to do so that's the thing. I'm like, okay, is this all up?
Because there's certain clauses in your in your in your NDA. I think that they're striking
Right. It's as for example if if you report to so you had this right you couldn't
You couldn't badmouth your old team for a year because that was part of your NDA. Yeah, I did anyway
What the hell see they can they don't enforce it
whereas
technical IP
Even though they don't enforce it
It's still probably wiser to keep that NDA there because once it's discovered if it is
Important then they still have action that can take the other move that's happening is a move. I
Don't like
So Microsoft is going through
We've I don't know how long how long it's been since you've been on campus
Long time the the big soccer field
Next to building 16. Yes, that's gone
I used to play soccer there like in the old days. I will play soccer there twice a week at noon
Yeah, it's a big parking garage now
and
Building with the soccer field on top. No building buildings one through four gone
With an indoor soccer rink rink soccer's in the bottom floor again. No
And buildings one through four gone. Yeah, so if I I they were I think they were like getting ready to tear them down
When I was leaving they've turned them down. They built them back up and they probably probably taller than two stories down
Way taller. I think they're I'm not in any place where I could see him, but I believe five to six floors
All right, so you don't like this change where is this going? No, so they're putting in they redesigned them to all be open space
Which again, I think we talked about this before in the computer science industry
There's multiple studies that show that that is
Anti-productive not productive, but they're now moving it as a response to covid
They're now moving at one level further and that is
You don't even have a desk anymore. So when you come in
You you reserve a desk and that's your desk for that day
Yeah
That's what I do. It'll work over time. I just I just want to see studies
Like I like that makes the company so friggin sterile
Like I don't even have a place to to put a picture of my family anymore. There's no personalization
Whatever put it on your phone like the rest of us. I
Do you get your phone into a little picture frame?
Little digital PF. All right, I guess you're not a board on
Well, humans are hugely adaptable and will adapt to that but doesn't mean
What I want to see is these decisions as they align
to key business criteria
above and beyond the short-sighted view of
Hey, we need to hire another 10,000 people. Where do we put them?
In right now I look around it in my building as I just talked about
Microsoft's been open for business since the big the end of March
Well, this goes back to what I was saying before we're never gonna go back to I don't think we're ever gonna go back to
You know 90 plus percent of the people going in five days a week. I think
Unity have stopped a lot of their office expansion even like the number of people
Associated with an office in many cases far exceeds the capacity of that office
But well, I guess it's a problem we can solve when we get there
But for today, there's today. There's plenty of room
Yeah, the thing I see this thing I see as a beginning trend and I don't know if Unity is seeing this
I see a beginning trend of
I'll just call it remote ism as a
as a requirement for the job
I think that's one thing people learn from Kobe is hey, I can still get my job done no matter where I am
Yes, and no and here's an I want to move on to another topic here
But I want to there's something I've noticed here one is people can do their job from home
But also there's value as I talked to earlier in that human interaction
And what I worry about is there are people that?
Need to see people they need to be in an office once in a while who don't know they need to be in an office
Once in a while, I will tell you in terms of so you and I have worked together for a while, right? The
You know about Colosso, for example, one of the key things around around Colosso
Is that it helps to build a stronger team? Okay, and I will say
Covid has kind of shattered that
But it's it's harder for the team to become a team
and be a team in that
Because you need the members of your team to create multiple different connections with the other members of the team
I can force it in some regards. I can set the stage and say hey Alan this week
You're going to pair program with Bob and next week you're going to pair pair program with Susan and etc
But that that whole knowledge
That that organic knowledge sharing
Knowledge sharing is the consequence
Now in some regards remote work is basically saying hey, I'm going to be a siloist and I'm going to stay that way
Or at least that would be my fear of it if that happens. I'm I'll just be fundamentally against it. All right
Well, yeah, I I think
As in all things the answer is it depends and it's a balance
I want to move on because there are a couple of the topics here today and
One is so we talked last time about Ken Johnston one of the authors of Howie Tussoff or Microsoft going to
Ford
And he's all over posting on LinkedIn, which is that's nothing to do with
LinkedIn has become nothing what it was designed to be but whatever but he's posting pictures of his electric Ford truck
He's been driving around. He's very excited and then he is working
On the test team on the dedicated siloed s debt team
and
He did a couple other things at Microsoft after that and then retired
I think he was in retirement and apparently
in a cryogenic
tube
For about 15 maybe 20 years
Basically, you know, I was working on a test team
Uh based on the mail he sent
He said
I'm gonna read the I know I know he won't listen to the podcast and I think it says educational and like i'll give you the
Whole email conversation. I want to talk about this thing. It's interesting
He says I got pulled into this madhouse and have not had this much fun
Pissing people off in a long time
Point number one is why why are we why are we pissing people off?
Why don't we work together then it gets better he says
Startingly, there is pretty much no software dev test knowledge here nor any consistent automation
Trying to bring in the concept of an s debt who makes devs cry
And I thought oh man
I I feel so 1999 right now
It's not worse
And uh, he's you know trying to recruit me to come be an s debt on his team
He says maybe you write how we test software at ford
and uh
Still
No, they found that
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait ford
Yeah
So he's he's that ford with ken johnson
Two of my previous managers are now at ford
Which I have absolutely no interest in
Are they somehow related to each other? No
Oh my god, anyway, I wrote back as you and I brought up
I said my views on testing have changed with the industry research shows for example that automated tests owned by developers have a high correlation with
Quality whereas automation owned by a separate team has no correlation with quality. So I focus a lot on helping
Developers test better and on giving them better development and analysis tools so they can move faster with higher quality
I imagine the process would vary in the automotive industry
But and there may even be regulations blah blah blah
I'm happy in the world where shipping a few dozen times a day is the norm
We're the only bugs that reach production or bugs that can't feasibly cop before release
The slow shipping world is something i'm happy to leave behind. So i'll see what his response is to that
So
We talked last time. I don't want to spend I want to move on from this before too long but
This is goes into what we talked about in the last podcast. There's this
You know, there's different bubbles of where people live and our next topic is going to talk about that some more
but
This idea of and this one thing I want to hit on is this idea of an adversarial
connection between
different parts of the team
It's so funny because you know, we lived that world a long long time ago, but it seems so foreign and wrong to me
like yeah
You know, it's weird how the how it like I I used to be that person
But now it's like we need to collaborate work together the more connected we are the better we're going to do
And it's like it's weird what you know a decade and a half will do to you
Yeah, it you you try things out you learn
right and
To me, I just I just think of that and I go
Wow, how did they isolate?
Because I I don't think we're in the bubble anymore as we talked about before drink
I I'm drinking tea
I think it's not helping if not taking the edge off
I think the perspective that we we have is far more mainstream and and that the the traditionalist point of view
Is is now
What do they call it the lagers?
right, it's
Certainly, it's going to be still there
Like as I bring up as an example all the time you can still go and find jobs doing cobalt programming
Absolutely
Right, and I can tell from the email that comes to my inbox every day that I can still go get a job as an estet
Because I get enough job offer. Well if I can pass the interview, but you know, yeah
I don't understand that why that's the case like you're linked in like why would anyone find you on linkedin and offer you an estet job?
Because i've been an estet in the past. I need to remove estet from
Everything in my profile. Yeah, but it says vp of engineering on the bloody thing. Why would it?
Oh, hey brent. Here's a news flash
News flash are you ready for is it now?
Yeah, some people are dumb. I am aware of this sadly
um
Statistically half of the people have a lower than average iq
Yeah, yeah, I was gonna say you don't have that quite right but yeah, I fixed it because I adapt
So yes, I want to you know, that's one bubble and i'm i'm if anybody from unity is listening. I have
negative
Interest zero to negative interest in joining forward because um, unless you all want to get rid of me you can let me know
When I also go to copenhagen, it's awkward because I bet nobody on your team listens to the podcast
I have people in my organization that listen to the podcast. Hi everyone
And it's a little awkward for me because I i'm just so anyway, whatever
I'm glad you find me interesting
This is how people find out what i'm up to how they get to know me better without spending time with me
My my my team do not listen to the podcast or at least they don't you should require it anyway, uh,
Our our buddy conference gerald who was in an abt 343 a while back
But I used to do those in fact if you want to be on if you want to like spend 30 minutes with me on a podcast
Ping me alan page on twitter
And we can set up some time. I'll do a little interview show with you when my voice is better
but uh connor's presenting at romanian testing days and
I think we is i've actually i've
Again, this is again the bubble, but this is somebody who
I i've worked with them respect that still is not quite
In line with all the principles and that's okay
We out when people want to debate the principles we say welcome to the conversation and it's okay
We want to be challenged. We want it to you know, make it real for you
but but but
Connor is in line connor is oh very much in line, but there was a reply someone took a picture of
Talking about the ab testing logo principles. He says
Modern testing principles being mentioned by connor
I still do not agree with alan page on principle seven. They never
Mentioned you it's always me good and bad. It's always me. Anyway, I still did not agree with alan page on principle seven
Not everybody contest which is right. Exactly. Which is not exactly principle seven says
Everybody can click around this wait, let me finish. Let me finish
Let me not finish go on brent. Okay. Thank you. Number one you look at the picture
and
This is this is this is your short form of the principles. I you know what I stand corrected
It's not
It's not mine. Now. I I still agree
everyone can test like
But my version of principle seven was fundamentally different. I kind of like yours better, but mine was
Uh, some of them lines of execute fearlessly
Right. It's it's like that's too far abstract from the original
It's the but then if you think about principle seven
It's we're basically need to do this
Even because it's the right thing to do even though it may have these consequences
Yeah, and for those that haven't read the principles, they're on modern testing not over but principle seven
Basically is the one that says you may get so good at producing quality software
You may not need dedicated testers anymore and by everybody here's where it's the the semantics and get lost
I don't mean everybody
in the world
Everybody on the software team
Yes
I have taught so many developers to be good testers. That is far beyond an exception
For a developer to be a good tester. They're not all developers are great testers. Some are okay
but
Many developers i've worked with have become better testers than most testers. I know
Yeah in principle
Actually, you know what? You're short for him
It's not
I get it. I get it. It's not it's it's I see what he did there and it's stolen from me
It's not exactly fair and it does I see where I see where it triggered
but also
Out of context from someone who's context driven a little bit weird, but it's okay. I love you but
The principle does not diminish the testing craft
Which is this final sentence there and even as written it does not diminish the testing craft
No, and I was thinking about that earlier today number one
Principle seven says we expand the testing abilities and know-how across the team
okay, so
seven
You call it everyone can test
A better one. It's too long, but it might be
everyone
Can learn to test or something like that?
Right it's but that that softens it to regard it. I don't want to brainstorm
I think this is one more i'm okay having everybody contest on the slide everyone can test on the slide
But you have to add some context in the talk and I wasn't at conner's talk
No, do I have a recording so I can't tell if he said that but as written it's like
I could see why it would trigger but but again contextually we're saying that
It should be the goal of your team to get a whole team to get better at testing
I do not I don't care how good of a tester you are. I don't care if you are
You know the embodiment of the craft of software testing and you're like that
You're like your neil plugged into the matrix on software testing
You know everything if you're the only tester on that team, you are a bottleneck
So this is the thing it's like it diminishes if you're the only person doing testing you're a bottleneck
I'm I'm I'm entering into rantville
Right this principle diminishes the testing craft. No, it does not
this this principle
Increases the testing craft
It is basically saying
Like they're interpreting it as oh testing something anyone can do
That is literally what is written there, right? But the way you're saying it is
Testing is not on this high ivory tower testing is something
Anyone can do correct
So it's not
It's not diminishing it in my view. It is strengthening it. Yes now more ideas to the party. It's strengthening
You're absolutely right. What diminishes the testing craft?
Is the testers that hold on to traditionalist?
Approaches with white knuckles. That's what diminishes it
They they sitting in their stupid codependency safety net loops
Sitting there patting themselves in the back not realizing that at lunch
The devs sit and talk and go. I can't believe I got this guy to do this fucking work for me
right, it's
like the as I've mentioned before
My humble opinion is that in the old?
traditionalist view of testing
Our number one value proposition was to be the scapegoat for the orc. Absolutely
Oh, I can tell you by the times like a bug was found after release and and the and this actual same test manager
I'm talking about and I
Sat in a room and got yelled at by the dev manager. Oh, yeah. Yeah
I've told you a story before where
um
uh
Where I had a dev lead come to me
And this was in the middle of our trend. This was in the middle of microsoft transition
I had I had joined the team after the transition
And I was set up to partner with them
To do some work. I wasn't a dev but I wasn't a test in this role
And they came to me and said
Hey, why wasn't this bug found before?
And I looked at her and I said
well, I
I don't know
um
If if if you really don't know then you know, let's pull up your unit test suite and let's figure it out
Basically, I very little little passive aggressive. Uh, I very passive aggressive go
Like why are you coming and yelling at me about what's something that is clearly your problem?
Everything we've talked about here on I I totally agree with and actually connor geyser as well. I want to just talk a little bit about
Um, I again, I haven't seen his talk yet
Uh, but he was interviewed about it a little bit for info queue
And I want to share a little bit of that article because I think it's a really good
How to deaden him a really good
grasp of
extension enhancement of modern testing
He talks about uh, the three S's and the three C's and he wants testers to move
Toward the three C's and away from the three S's
And the three S's so these are the things testers are moving away from we've already talked about first one's a safety net
Stop being the safety net
The next one is solo that solo knowledge that that single point of failure again neo
I know everything about testing. I know the product only I can make this work moving away from that towards collaboration
And then being static this is holding on with white knuckles be adaptable
Embrace change is what we talked about in the very first couple a b testing podcast
No, we've actually talked about all three of these in this episode. We have we have because they're all here
So anyway, these are this is but it sums up everything we've talked about
So yeah, these things move away from those testers move on stop being a safety net stop being a single point of failure
Adapt and change stop holding on and the three C's
We've also talked about coaching
I have coached
developers hundreds now maybe thousands to do better testing
Principle seven collaborating working together not making devs cry working with them. We're on the same team
We're trying to make quality software together
Principle four
And change which is principle three
Uh, yeah principle three
And he says uh, Connor says that testers are often the training wheels for the team
Which are like we need to thinking about how can we remove the training wheels?
This is really principle seven's about how do we get the training wheels off the team so it can be fully independent?
In producing quality software and there's some other really great terms and there it brings up accelerate which is always a way to get to my heart
but
really
Fantastic insights. I mean this is somebody who gets it and gets what it means
I mean some people probably look at the principles they go. Oh, yeah, okay
And some people look at them and go. Oh, I hate all of these. These are dumb. They're not in fact
someone on uh, linkedin said hey I read these
And they're not very modern and they're not about testing either and I know they say that but still
it's like um
What conversation are we having anyway? Uh, connor just just nailed it. He nailed the essence of
Of why we think about this stuff and the principles just came it isn't like we decided
Hey, we're gonna write some principles and figure out what they mean
We just tried to capture so the principles
God, when did we first start talking about those in the 70s 80s? I mean episode numbers. Do you remember?
Uh, maybe it was earlier good. We started going I think 87 was our deep dive. Oh my gosh, so
It's a summary of like everything we have been talking about like what are how can we?
Take everything we've been talking about and sum it up into some things that are communicable communicatable
And that's where they came from
All models are wrong. Some are useful. These are helpful
uh, and I think
Anything you disagree with look at both sides. Anyway, go ahead brent
no, and and connor even in the
the thread
All right, one of the things we talk about here
connor
Really has simultaneously represents our content very well and he's actually morphed it into his own
version
that is is
Fantastic, right? He's in that same twitter feed. He hashtag healthy discussion, right?
That's that's the whole point. Yeah of this is to encourage
a collaboration even
as
Even on the the principles, right? I was thinking about
Right that same person that you just said when we say it's not about modern it's not about testing
Right. Why did we give this name?
Well the original reason is because it was a particular set of people we wanted to target and that was one of the thoughts
I had on
On the problem nowadays when this came out
We were we were facing a community of testers
That for whatever reason saw change was on the wind right and microsoft had gone through it
Part of this was to attract the attention of testers and get people to understand
No, there is this is not a negative. This is absolutely a positive
Like don't fight this change, you know swim with the current
um
But it does occurred to me
People coming into the test industry
now
who may not
Have a view like the drama around these changes around testing that's dramatically gone down
Like the last news report I heard was like salesforce
Dropping all of their testers and that was like five years ago. Yeah
And also worth mentioning and we should really post these somewhere. Maybe i'll put them on modern testing org, but
That'd be a great place ago. We yeah, shut up
We um, I remember do you remember when we kind of rewrote and I wrote them down one thing I posted in our slack
Yes, um the dev the the modern testing principles that don't include
It's about the team not about testing
I don't know if they're modern testing principles 2.0 or some other principles, but we did think I mean most of them stayed the same
But we did things like change principle 7 2 we expand abilities and know-how across the team understanding
This may reduce or or eliminate the need for dedicated specialists, which is true for anything
Like you're gonna hire like give the example from from my work
often teams ask me across unity
Hey, we need to hire a dev ops engineers for our team
Can you help me with the job wreck? I go hold on
Why are you hiring a specialist for your team?
I said well, we need to know how to deploy this stuff and blah blah blah
I said we have you build it you run a culture my team
Gives you a good paved road to make that easy and they'll give you everything you need to get it up and running
but
In the long run
When you have a specialist you're going to be in trouble like what if they go on vacation and you rely on them for everything
Oh, well, we'll hire two
Okay
Let's let we're gonna need to sit down. This is now going. Yeah
But you don't you don't appear to be learning from the speech replace tester with dev ops
It's
And it's the exact same years ago as this behind me for now dev said well
I don't know anything about testing can't figure it out now. They're telling me. I don't know anything about kubernetes
So it's okay. We're gonna teach you it's not that hard
and I
Fully believe like we can't scale and give everybody their own little and imagine the chaos that would happen
If I we had 200
Embedded dev ops engineers around the company air quote because dev ops is a culture not a role, you know infrastructure people
Implementing various flavors and different things and in different ways with no consistency across it would be an absolute mess
But specialists you could hire a database specialist a perp or perf specialist
Sometimes you want to do that, but you want a generalizing specialist
so that they're not a bottleneck for the team and
so they
Don't when they work themselves out of a job, which all of us should be doing, you know frequently
They have other things they can do
I I think specialists are fantastic
For sort sort of outside in consulting
Unless you have a large enough company, it doesn't make sense to to have it in your organization
I've had similar
similar issues like I had a
I had a pm
Come to me
About a year ago and he checks in every three months to see if i've changed my mind. He's like brit
I am going to get you eight heads
I'm like, okay neat
right that would tremendously grow my team and tremendously grow the the type of scenarios and impact my team could have
why
and it's like oh
well, so we have all of this data stuff
and
We want you to use these eight heads to build us a data warehouse
And a bunch of power bi dashboards and and data movers
Why?
Why? Because it's too hard for pm to do
and I said
I see
Thank you for your offer. Uh, I'm I'm going to kindly reject it
and they're like
Like like they were surprised. They really thought like oh I could get you eight heads like that, dude
And i'm like, yeah, no i'm not building
There's no career for full-time power bi builders in my role
Right. I'm just like no like hire a vendor team manage it tell them to do your stuff. Right? Like
Like it's just that simple
now and I said
However, if you want to solve your your actual problem
Right instead of building a data safety net then i'm open to talk
and
He of course has clarity and I said your actual problem
is
The pm role is changing and you just told me your
Your pm organization doesn't have the basic
Skills to thrive in the new world every pm should be able to build their own power bi
report to judge the success of their features
Power bi is not that hard and if your pms don't understand the data
Then
I'm gonna i'm gonna tell you they're producing incomplete features
Yep, specialization bad
Yep. All right, man. I gotta go rest my voice. I've had about all I can take for the day
All right
Oh, maybe in post-production I can
Like there's like some fancy filter I can use to fix my voice
Ooh auto tune awesome
No
Go please go go
uh, I swear by this
gargle with with salt water and then
And then find some nice honey to
Soak your throat in and there I mean the stuff made by bees
But you could choose any version of honey that you would desire. All right, I think
Mine comes in a bot my honey. I think it's in a body that says quervo
Okay. Yep
That may work. I'll try some of that
If you if you do enough of that, yes, I can guarantee you the pain will go away
There's no pain. There's absolutely zero pain
I feel 100 fine. I just lost my voice a little bit of a cough
Gotcha
All right. That is it for this time. We'll see you next time on the next episode of
Ba ab testing ba ab testing. Yes
Bye
Bye all