Welcome to AB Testing Podcast, your modern testing podcast. Your hosts, Alan and Brent,
will be here to guide you through topics on testing, leadership, Agile, and anything else
that comes to mind. Now on with the show. Oh, hey, welcome to party night at AB Testing Podcast.
After a long time, listeners will know when I first met Brent,
I would always change his name just to confuse people. But anyway, that's a different story.
And to annoy me. You can hear more about that on episode, I don't know.
Anyway, back to my question. What do you been up to? What's new? What's exciting?
Well, what's exciting for me is it's that most magical time of the year.
We had this conversation last time. Are you still doing reviews?
Well, yeah, now we're in rewards. Ooh. Right.
We're doing the same thing. Yeah.
It's a little less stressful here. You know, it was. Here's the thing that was interesting.
It was non-trivially stressful about a month ago when we were starting the process.
Because I've had people who have, well, I'll just put it this way. There are people who have been at
Microsoft for half of a millisecond coming and going, oh, it's review time. So am I getting
promoted? And I have having to go through in those discussions and given the right message
without doing it. But all of that kind of tapered down once news has gone out that
meta is doing a hiring freeze, potential layoffs. They're like, oh.
Maybe I should be happy to have a job. Right.
I'm holding my comments. Which is a new thing for me.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. It is. So the most recent life adventure for me is going through yet again
emptiness syndrome with my oldest in an unexpected way. So listeners of this,
I've known he's been out to college. He's actually graduated college.
But last week, he moved to Indianapolis and it's so his roommates.
His roommates, which are really tight. And to me, this part makes sense that for him,
this he doesn't really have his next stage of life is to get into a PhD program.
He didn't make it this last time around, even though he went through a bunch of interviews
and he's going to he's going to get a job there, get experience in his in his discipline.
He can do that anywhere. And then staying with his roommates was a really high priority.
And one of his roommates did get into a PhD program at the University of something near
Indianapolis. I don't actually know what universities are. But going back to me.
Yeah. What about you? Right. The fact. So I when he left, it was disturbing. And
my son is one of is one of my favorite people on the planet.
The end, even though he lived out in Spokane, which for those who aren't listening, it's about
depending on how fast you drive is between four to six hours.
I was born in Spokane. I did not know that. The the fact that I can't.
I he's now not longer even within driving distance had had some emotional impact.
Now, I'm of course concerned with him as listeners. The podcast are where
my son is gay and in Indianapolis does not have a reputation of supporting that. So we'll.
Well, I think Indiana in general, generally the larger cities are a little bit more
accepting. Well, that's what I'm going to hope for. That's what I'm going to hope for.
So those are the two biggest exciting things in my life.
Clement, one thing I want to touch on before I go over how important I am.
I'm not is same time you're here, but I want to go back to your comment about,
hey, do I get a promotion now?
One thing I do and that I do is I am my org will tell you, hopefully, is I'm hyper transparent.
So I tell them like exactly how much I tell them how much budget I have.
Here's how much merit is here. Much promo budget is we have.
We do a promotion panel process where I explain how it works.
It's a collaboration between a person and their manager who want to be promoted.
They have a discussion about it if they think, yeah, you're ready for promotion.
You fill out this one page, two page thing, talk listing some examples of what you've done that
correspond with our job architecture, which is familiar,
like ladder levels of Microsoft or career guide, whatever it's called now.
And they get some 360 feedback because we want them to be working, not just getting the work done
and having impact, but in a way that fits with the introduced values.
And then an independent panel also from my org sits down, reviews the packets,
ask some questions and makes a choice on whether one makes a choice,
whether that person is ready for promotion, but two also provides a bunch of great feedback
for that person, either on how to be successful in the new level or what they need to do to
get there. And it's super transparent. People know how it works.
And it's so it's very clear on what you need to do to get promoted. It's not like,
do I get promoted? It's very clear exactly what you need to do. So there's no, there's no mystery.
I, that to me reminds me of, of how I understood the Google model.
Well, the difference between the Google model is Google is the manager wasn't involved.
The employee could say, I feel like being promoted and they would put together their packet on their
own. I feel like the managers, and then there's the other way, the Microsoft way is traditional
way is the managers sit in the room and talk about people and they figure out who should
get promoted. This is a mixture of the both, the mixture of both. The manager's decision has
weight, but it's not all the weight and they can't sit there and try and sell. And you've
been in meetings like this because it's impossible not to where the manager who can sell their
employees the best gets more of the promotion budget. And this just takes that part of the
equation out. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. The, just to point to a point of clarity. So Google,
the manager is involved, but optionally so. So to, to, to be considered for promotion,
I either the manager or the employee can, can state I'm ready. Okay. And, and then as I understand
it, the way the packets are processed are in, in priority order. Obviously the ones where
both the manager and the employee, uh, believe they're ready. Go first.
Okay. I haven't worked at Google. I don't know all other details, but
I don't need their, this is, this is the way we do it in my team.
I, I like, I like the models. I like the model. The, the one thing that's nice about it
is the only, the only change I would do with, with yours, if, if I had the ability to
was make the committee just be outside of your org entirely. Yeah. Eventually. It's honestly,
it's too, and I've involved people from outside the org. It's just too foreign of a concept for
a lot of people right now. Eventually, eventually I have to grow into that. I couldn't train,
I can train my org and give them training on how to be a panel member and how to be a panel lead.
I have less control over training people outside of my org, how to do that.
Gotcha. So, but we also do for our, um, more senior positions, uh, like for example,
I wanted to open up a high level position, uh, recently. And what I have to do is I have to
bring that to a panel outside of my org, a VPs to explain the role and why it's important for
the company that has keeps me from going, Hey, I'm going to open up a VP role or a director role.
Instead. I can't just do that. I have to go through a panel process to even open a role
and all the senior senior promotions go through a similar process. Anyway, uh, that was my comment
there. What have I been doing? No, oh, um, normal stuff, avoiding COVID. I got my second booster
shot because I am going to, I'm traveling, I'm traveling again. I'm going to Copenhagen,
leaving Sunday, my first trip out of the country in over two years. Fun. Um, my passport expired
during the pandemic, but I have a new one and I remembered to sign it in everything.
Do you have a fast path to, to passport enablement? I have not, I have never possessed a passport.
Oh my God. You're such a stereotypical American. Really? I'm on my, I've, I've had, yeah. Okay. Yeah.
Um, oh my God. I have, I have a new passport. Get a passport and see the world.
I would love both of the same. All right. Do that. Yeah. The, a lot of people are surprised
that I've never been to Europe. I have been outside of the United States. Don't you need
a passport like it, or at least an enhanced ID to even go to Canada now. The last time we went to
Canada, those rules weren't in place. Oh my God. Yeah. Do you leave Bothell? I do. I'm in Redmond
right now. Do you leave Bothell in Redmond? Um, for those of you away, it's all just a big blob
of suburbia and East side. I, I was in Seattle getting Krispy Kreme just, just last weekend.
That's fantastic. All right. So anyway, I'm looking forward to that. Should be fun.
Just hanging out with the team there. You know, I added 50 plus people to my org in Copenhagen
six months ago. I have met about five of those people in person in my life and none since I
started. So I'm looking forward to hanging out with them. So that'll be fun. All right.
I got a, I kind of a, because it's been a long time. I got a little bit of a
potpourri of topics on the agenda. And what are we at? Did I press record? I did. I remember how
to do this. We're about 12 minutes in and 10 after editing. And we're getting to stuff that,
I don't know, this is, this is going to be fun, but a little bit of a throwaway. So first,
I would like to point out that practice test just published a list of their favorite podcasts.
Did you know this? I did. And you know, which one is, you know, there's a bunch of podcasts on here,
but also one called AB testing. I'm familiar with this one. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. It's the link there.
And we talk, we both talk about, we're asked independently or we answered independently on
our favorite episode. And of course it was episode 67, the traditional versus modern testing manager.
And so if you, that's what you should go check out. If you don't know what modern testing is,
you don't know what you guys do. And I would go check that one out. You probably wouldn't
say it that way, but yeah. I would hope not. I mean, it's more cohesive. They have a great list
on here. I was going through and I'm like, okay, who are the, uh, who, you know, number one,
what's the sword order? Normally we're number one because we're, we start with A, but this is not
where we're listed in number three. I do think in terms of adding awesome, colorful stories.
Oh yeah. Interesting. It's actually you, me, and Joel. We're the only ones that sort of added
stories to, to, um, to their list there. I don't know, but it's the whole list of things you can
go check out. It's a good way to sample and see if there are undoubtedly better testing podcasts.
Undoubtedly. Right. And what, what's funny is we're on this list, but our podcast really,
I guess we talk about testing, but it's not a testing's in the title and we've been testers,
but we talk about a lot of other stuff, but today we're going to talk about testing.
Let's talk about AB testing with the slash, which is a, uh, yeah, it's right up your alley
cause AB testing with the slash of course, about compare experimentation and comparing different
treatments. And it's all out of Eric Ries and something that I know a little bit about. I
give him some talks about, but I would think a data scientist is far, far more knowledgeable
in this area than I would be as much as I, you know, I try and I try and learn what I can, but
I think Brent, would you agree with me that you between us, you are the expert in a slash B testing?
Oh, absolutely not. Well, you would be right. Because if you look at the list of, uh, from,
uh, KELOLAND.com of 58 influencers and AB testing, you need to know in 2022,
my name shows up, not yours. Yeah.
It's interesting and it's interesting because it seemed like, uh, I don't, I don't know who wrote
this harder. No, me neither. I suspect the next girlfriend of Allen's or something there.
Gets better. It gets better. I'm in a section of, I'm in the section of AB testing influencers
in feature management. I don't know what that means, but you're the only one there.
Oh, you're right. Yeah. I don't know what it means either. I don't know any of this. I don't,
the world doesn't make sense, but I wanted to call it out. In terms of like the category,
well, feature management, to me, it looks like they, they might've done a LinkedIn search on
AB tests and looking for, looking for executives. Oh, maybe. I don't know. Yeah, maybe, maybe.
I don't get those anymore. I took, I took, I think I took advice from you on that years ago is basically
right. You change certain keywords in your profile and now you no longer show up in that,
in their search engine. Yeah. Recruiters don't actually read. They just keyword searched your
profile and they go, Ooh, S debt. And I was an S debt a long time ago. I want to come back to
S step, but do you know who else is a VP of engineering that we both know?
I know several people that we both know that are VPs of engineering.
That was a dumb question. Yeah. But before, before we move on,
Oh, okay. Like I, I'm, I'm looking at this, uh, this, this highly suspicious list of AB testing
influencers. The one that includes me. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. That was, um, and it explicitly
mentions that you are now hosting the modern testing podcast. Apparently. So when did that,
when did that start? I don't know, man. I think for Brent, for Brent's, the also ran. It's like,
yeah, it's, it's, it's the Allen's podcast. Welcome. This is the Allen page podcast with
a special guest this week, Burt Jensen. Yeah. You know, one day, uh, when I get tired of your
bullshit, dude, I did not like, do you see my byline there? I didn't make that page. Somebody
else screwed it up. No, I'm just going to tease you for it incessantly. It just occurred to me
that like the name of the podcast is AB testing. Right. And if you just erase that small little
bump in B, it very quickly becomes AP testing. That may or may not have already happened.
All right. I'm, I'm now searching Spotify for the modern testing podcast.
All right. We may have a discussion later. Is it called them? That's so funny. They call it
that the modern testing podcast. They called it the modern testing podcast. Oh my Lord. Oh my Lord.
I just, I don't, I don't know why people even make these lists. Some, some, I don't know. Anyway,
uh, back, back, so check fail. So a long time ago, modern testing
podcast. Nope. Nothing on Spotify. So you don't, you're not hosting it there yet. All right. I'll
find it. Mr. Page. Wouldn't it be funny if you found it. Oh my God. Alan has a podcast. It's like
totally produced like those ones with like the sound effects and the music in the background.
It'd be like this American life, but it's a modern testing podcast. Oh, I can weave some
stories together. Oh, it'd be so good. That's such a good idea that I don't have time to implement.
Now you had to hire people for that. All right. All right. Oh, remember, remember that
one time I wrote a book about software testing. I do. And I didn't write at all. I wrote most of it
and I take damn, I was damn clear with this. I counted pages and how many I wrote and I wrote
most of it. BJ Ralison wrote part of it. I don't know what ever happened to BJ. I did look him up.
I did a Google search. He did like, he like sailed his boat to Hawaii and then Fiji during COVID.
But the other author who wrote two chapters, one chapter on, uh, one chapter actually interesting
on like where the term S debt came from. Like, you know, how that was invented at Microsoft.
And some of the stuff around some of the history of tests is actually still accurate,
even though it's changed so much since then the snapshot's accurate. But he wrote another chapter
on, uh, I don't know. I don't think it was even called service testing, something around how we
were testing services at the time. And he, within a year, he was so embarrassed about that
chapter and how horribly out of date it was. He was writing that at a time. Microsoft was still
figuring out how to do service testing. But anyway, BJ, of course, left, uh, Microsoft a long time
ago. I left five years ago, five and a half years ago. And as of last week, Ken Johnston has left
Microsoft. No more authors are left. He is now the VP of AVP of engineering at Ford motor company.
Yeah. He sent me a message on linked in recruiting you. He needs data scientists.
He told me initially, it looks like on LinkedIn, his title is different. Right. But he, um,
he's the director of data platforms and analytics for the EV division. That's, oh, no, he's, he's VP.
Our listeners can hear anyway. Anyway, I'm just, just saying like, look right here.
Ken telling me that's his title. Um, look at the, look to the left where it says I'm happy to share
that I'm starting a new position as VP engineering at four voter company. Yeah. No, I see that.
Right. I'm just telling you, I don't, I don't, can tell me this is his title. Okay. He fold.
He's told everybody, this is his title. I don't know what it is. So Ken's a big fat liar. That's
what you're going to share your screen on an audio podcast. Ken's a big freaking liar.
No, I just say, I'm basically saying, is that your power move? Ken is an executive at Ford.
And, um, there you go. What ifs, what ifs, um, I hope he does cool stuff. He's really,
super excited about it. All right, man. So anyway, Ken went there. So all those authors are gone.
The book is blah, blah, blah. I got a couple of questions for you. Yes. So I love ministry
of testing because, uh, for many, many, many, many reasons, uh, one is like a couple of every day,
they are awesome. They asked some questions on Twitter that get a variety of answers depending
on who answers them. So I'm going to ask you a couple of days. I'll give you the answer I gave
on Twitter. Don't look at Twitter right now. So I'm going to ask you this. What's the most
common cause of failed automated tests in your experience? Uh, crappy automation code. Well,
with, um, I just wrote code. Sure. Which one it was either people or code. I didn't want to
blame people. So I, I wrote code. Um, yeah, you can't the way, the way I would frame it is more.
Yeah, there are better answers out there. People writing automation code under the
false assumption. It's easy and learning the hard way it's not right. Quite honestly,
yet sure. Sometimes things change and that causes things to break, but that's not a failed
automation test that say automation test that failed subtle difference. And the wordings were
there too. Cause is it failed? They mean flaky failed. Does it mean the product under test failed?
I don't know how to answer that, but it was, I copied that to share that with you because
that was interesting question. There was one yesterday equally interesting for different
reasons. And as you can imagine a variety of answers, I'm going to throw at you also.
Does a market shift towards S debts concern you? Yes. Me too. And mainly because I wonder
how this tweet from 24 2004 got into my timeline as a new tweet yesterday.
Oh, that's fun. No, it was tweeted yesterday. And I think it's weird. To me, maybe it's because we're so
into the modern testing world, right? I just, you know, there's a bubble I live in where I think
Estes are still a thing, which was my, actually my answer.
Yeah. What does that mean to you? Like, like, well, so it, it means possibly two things.
Great. So in my career here, I've noticed that things kind of seem to circle around again,
around every 10 years ish. Right. Where, um, I've often noticed, and you may have noticed this as
well with, with, uh, let's say let's take the topic of duplication of effort where, where you'll
see teams go duplication of effort is bad. And, and then they try to centralize it under one
leadership and one mission and everybody's going to benefit from this. And then that central team
eventually becomes a bottleneck and they're only able to provide the 80% solution for everybody,
which there's where everyone then has to make their own 20% and they don't have the ability to do it
on that platform in which that encourages a decentralization. And I constantly see that
pendulum swinging back and forth on this. If assets are coming back, uh, I hope it's because
we're now going into a new realm of complexity where, where it's just not possible to develop in
and test in parallel. If it's that's, that's not it. And I'm going to interrupt because what I think
is actually happening is every once in a while, when I think it helps see the bubble. We've talked
about viewing where modern testing is as the change of innovation curve. And I forget, it really
has a lot of companies that are still hiring a good number of Estes or which want to go back
in time. Just like somebody wants to go back in time and save JFK. I want to go back in time to
that meeting of the test leadership team at Microsoft and just not, just not use that term
and get it erased from history. But what they want, they're hiring people to write a bunch of
gooey automated tests because they can write code and what that means. Wait, wait, wait, pause.
That question was in context of what you just stated. I don't understand the question. The
question was, does the market shift towards Estes concern you? And you're saying that the
context in which that question was raised was around UI automation?
Well, it's unclear. Some of the answers were around that. Some of the answers were around that.
And I think a lot of companies are still hiring test automation specialists, calling them Estes.
That was my takeaway from the answers and that concerns me.
Okay. So what that tells me, and here's the big concern. I think you and I, and well before
modern testing, Agile testing was around talking about whole team ownership of quality and we're
all part of the team. What hiring Estes means is more silos because you probably have manual testers,
your automated testers or Estes, and then developers who don't have to write tests.
Even though we know and the data's out there showing that if the developers write the automated
tests themselves, there's a higher correlation of quality in their organization. So in fact,
you're hiring Estes, you are setting yourselves up to some extent, at least for lower quality.
By hiring Estes based off of studies such as the one that you decided, by hiring Estes,
you are actually harming yourself. That's my belief. That's my belief.
I share that belief. Well, you're no fun to argue with.
No, how else are we going to parallelize? Let's quickly redo episode 67.
No.
Yeah, that's, so you had a small sample set and right now I'm just going to choose to believe
that the vocal minority in the world that died is the one that contributed to the Q&A of that.
Or are you saying these are active ministry of test people?
Well, I mean, it's whoever's on Twitter. They asked, the thing I love about them,
they asked these questions knowing they're going to get a variety of answers.
Yeah, that part I love that's fun. The random questions and
things like the MT has shown up or modern testing principles has shown up on there,
I think more than a couple of times. I love that they are spawning conversation.
Yeah, they are. And they know they're going to get debate in a different set of answers.
And good conversations happen. And it's, yeah, I'm actually really happy with it.
Look back at the thread because people are answering in different ways. There's the whole,
well, I'm a manual tester and I don't want my, I don't feel like I have to program. And it's, we,
all those conversations go away. If we, if we really embrace whole team quality and look at
whether you're entirely a non-coding tester or a tester who writes lots of code, there are
valuable ways for you to contribute to quality on your team. But the developers should be writing
the test automation. If you're like, if I'm a, if I say I'm hired as an SDET, but I'm hired as an SDET,
I wouldn't be hired as an SDET, maybe hired as a developer, developer and test. I'll say I'm
hired as an SDET on a team where developers are writing a whole lot of automated tests,
not just their stupid little unit tests. They're writing actual functional tests and they're doing
a pretty good job of testing. I'm spending some of my time probably teaching them to write better
tests because who wants, who wants flaky tests? And I know I have some good ideas how to not do that,
but maybe I'm also looking at writing analysis tools or tools that will help me put the application
in a state, right? Where, whether it's a stress test or put it in a state where some weird things
may happen or diagnostic tools or linking in the telemetry from the app and some other analytics
tools. Those are the sorts of things I want to do as an SDET. I don't want to just automate
a bunch of GUI operations. And that's what I, that's what I fear. And what I observed in some
cases happening in some of these orgs. And I, I wish we could just move past it. And again,
it's the siloing, the siloing doesn't work. And you and I have lived through this at Microsoft where
we had a huge functional dev org and a huge fun functional test org. And that conflict between
developers and testers that we thought was kind of cool 20 years ago is unproductive today.
So the only way I can think of why a customer, a company would do this, right? Would be
because they could hire people to do automation, potentially at a much lower pay scale.
Maybe, maybe not everybody has embraced this, this style of software development. I even call it
testing because remember modern testing isn't really about testing and it's not that modern
either. It's just, just the antidote to traditional test late test last, conflictual siloed
testing that we had seen coming up in software in the nineties and two thousands.
Yeah. I wonder if ministry of tests even has any data on this.
No, I mean, again, I, I, yeah, there's value. I did. They teach test automation course,
think it's valuable and people still need to learn that stuff and it'll need to for a while.
But when I see some answers to these questions, I go, wow, my bubble is smaller than I thought.
And sometimes I think my bubble turns out to be bigger than I thought. I, people come up and say,
oh, Hey, thanks for putting the name to what we've already been doing. Or,
you know, we're following these principles. I go, Oh, okay, great. And sometimes I see some answers
go, Oh, the bubbles, I can't tell how big the bubble is and where things are on the curve.
Sometimes I'm constantly sort of probing and checking in on that as well.
And I'll just tell you right now, I obviously like you, I don't have proof,
but the number of conversations and the number of insight, like, I think we talked about it the
other, the other day, we're mainstream now. We're not, we're no longer sort of leading
right. The, the, the change curve that, that you've put it multiple times in your presentation.
We're no longer part, MTP is no longer really part of the leading edge. It's more mainstream.
Yeah. It's on, it's on the downward power of that curve. It's in, we're past the,
yeah, yeah. Anyway, go on. No, it's, we're at a point where it's well duh, right? Because it's
just so commonplace. I think, I think more of the traditionalist point of view is actually on its
way out. But I think there's enough of us in the industry. That maybe what's happening actually.
There was a, do you remember the QA series you did in partnership with an external organization?
I think they were a contract agency. Michael Hunter presented a presentation there. They were like,
they hosted it and they were in like downtown Bellevue.
Talking about Sasquatch. Yes. Seattle, are you a software quality assurance group?
Yes. And actually less, less, I think it was the one that did the presentation. Now I think
about it. You brought him in, you brought him into, no, Lee Lee, you brought him into Microsoft.
And he, he, his presentation was around, I think he called it the 10 great for giddings.
Oh yeah. Yeah. Yeah. And I'm wondering if that's what's happening again. Like we've been
that people are considering assets and think it's new. I wonder if that's what's happening.
Oh, I wonder. I wonder. And there's not enough people around that remember the old days now
to go, Oh dear God. No, no, stop. No, no, stop. Anyway, I don't know. It does bother me.
Uh, I think which the points of the question, uh, and I dearly hope M O T does not have any
data that points towards this. Although Joel probably would, would have the data.
I love that Joel calls out like, you know, what kind of testing do you and MT is one of the things.
Um, I want to, uh, change subjects completely, which will mean we either have a three minute
conversation or a 15 minute conversation on something I've been thinking about a lot.
I want to bounce off you, but really I'm bouncing it off of our listeners.
You know, yeah. Is that cool? Then it is that, or ask you some IST QB interview questions.
So I'm going to skip that part this week. I've been, uh, of course, as you know, at unity,
I manage a bunch of stuff, including whatever you want to call our infrastructure or platform,
et cetera, team, the team that builds all of the infrastructure and tools we need in order to,
build, test, deploy, maintain our products in production, whether it's desktop apps,
service apps, I think people know that some of the traditional names are internal platform, et cetera.
One thing I have a part of my team, uh, doesn't matter what they're currently called,
but their purpose is interesting. Their purpose is to focus on helping teams internally use our
tools. So enablement, advocacy, awareness, developing training, um, some internal community
management, et cetera. And two things, uh, and this could go anywhere, but what I've found is
kind of like when people, this is cool. You know, when people, this is a good segue.
If I would have thought it this apart farther in advance, thought I had planning,
this was one of those podcasts knew what the sound effects like, like the modern testing
podcast. Uh, you would, um, I would have wove this in much better, but people contact me frequently
and say, thanks for putting a name to something we're already doing. Didn't know what it was called.
Recently, I had one of those moments myself when I realized there is a name for what this team
does. And I don't know if a lot of companies have a team called developer relations whose job is to
do this, you know, basically make sure, work with customers to make sure they understand how
to use your API and how to use your tools, et cetera. There is a whole bunch of writing on the
internet about a thing called internal developer relations, which exactly describes what one of my
organizations does, which is everything I just said, engagement, developer experience,
enablement awareness. They're doing communication and classes and brown bags and working directly
with teams and sort of a consulting role, like a test coaching sometimes, or actually test coaching,
working with teams to make sure they're successful using all the rest of the stuff my org builds.
And the question is, when I look at that, you know, now I'm like thinking,
where have I seen this before? And right before I left Microsoft, when did I leave Microsoft?
2017. So a couple of years before I left, I don't know if it's still a thing at Microsoft,
but they had a thing called one ES, one engineering system out of the VS team
to try and again, Microsoft isn't on one engineering system, but you know,
they all use Git now, I think most teams use visual studio team system. Oh, I'm sorry.
Azure DevOps, another dumb ass name. So some of us there, but what do you remember about
one ES? Is that still a thing people talk about at Microsoft?
It's still there. One ES in the concept that you're referring to is, I would say is not
really talked about, but it's still the spirit behind it is still moving forward.
Right. It's just Microsoft is huge. Right. The for a long period of time. I mean,
hell, we've talked about it before. In terms of what the hell were those things called?
The career stage profiles. But even then before, right, the things that you, you, Alan Page,
helped to author. It used to have crappy things like it in order to get to principle and test.
You had to architect a test. I didn't work. I worked on the old, the newer version,
the old version said like, and again, it wasn't a checklist. It was a horrible
architecture and those things are challenging. I could talk, I could do a podcast talking about
those things, but yeah, it didn't, but there were, they were individual accomplishment over
efficiency and in it together. It encouraged individual accomplishment over company
accomplishment. Yeah. Quite honestly. Yep. I fully agree. And that definitely is changing
under under Satya. Yeah. And to be fair, it was Satya who kicked off. It was one ES was his idea
to try and bring some consolidation to give the idea of the landscape back then. Let me get
Microsoft was even huge. They're bigger now, but every team had a different way of building,
deploying and testing and even tracking bugs for their stuff. It was just a big fat mess.
There is in various different places in the company. So earlier I mentioned sort of this
tendency to, to shift back and forth between centralization and decentralization. And I would
say right now we are, at least in the group I'm in, there is a shift towards centralizing again.
I don't know. I'll just tell you, I will help. I will contribute and collaborate. I am not yet
bought into the vision and I hope the leaders there convinced me otherwise because on the face
of it, it feels like there is a, there is a, there's a committee that's going through and trying to define
the set of standards that will cause everyone to standardize. And, and I'm like,
you can't make those things. Every business will require you to change your standard.
You have to have a way to handle that. And that's a huge scale. Let me talk about how I'm doing that
at my scale because I, we really believe in autonomy and letting people and giving people
choices. So, but in some cases we can't do that. In some cases around like security tooling that we
implement, we're going to be very strict about that. The way I look at it is providing paved
roads. And you're going to, if you want to get the absolute best support from my team and have your
best chance for success, you're going to stay on those paved roads. But sometimes you need to
go onto a dirt road and it's fine. It's probably, it's probably still going to be okay. A lot of that
dirt road comes back, connects to a paved road, but you're going to get a little less support
from us because we don't want to support you there. If you're going to be all off mountain biking in
the wilderness, you are on your own and nobody's, no exec business is going to support that. They're
going to say, if you want to run a service, you stay as much as you can on the paved roads that
are already provided. That's how you're going to be successful. And so it's not, so you may get a
couple of different things. For example, you maybe, for example, you could use, I don't even name
any names. There's a couple of different CI systems you could use. You could use a couple
of different public cloud providers and we'll help you with those. But generally the paved roads are,
are, we want to, again, the metaphor is getting burned out here, but I want to give people a
chance, give them a chance to choose where needed, but I can't just let them go wide open, willy
nilly, whatever you want, because eventually you're going to need support from my team and
you're not going to be able to get it because we don't know what you're doing.
Well, yeah. And if you can, if you can put constraints around that or principles,
to me, the, the solution to this is establishing the right set of principles that, that serve
as guardrails. Right. Guardrails. We want to help people stumble towards success. The other thing
is again, easier to do with a company of 5,000 than it is 200,000. I don't know if that
translates into engineers, but there's a level of trust I need to establish with the
business leaders, neither organizations where they come. Like I have one leader for a big org.
He tells me, tell my team what to do. He wants us to tell him what to do.
Go wash my car.
You know what I mean? It's like we can, we can say do X like, okay,
we're going to do X, but usually it's here's what we've learned from this analysis and looking at
these incidents going forward. We should always do X and they go, okay, it's canon. It's done.
We're doing it. And those things just turn into the paved roads. I don't know how.
Well, first of all, again, I think this is very difficult at Microsoft. I think to some extent,
the Azure DevOps team probably does this internally. One thing I was really impressed
with is it is very, very difficult to take a product that's shipped both internally and
externally. And I have been talking to VS folks about this for a long time. They said, nope,
Microsoft employees, not our customers. And eventually Satya said, yes, they are.
And it is a difficult thing to do. When I think of companies that have
something they use internally, they ship externally, it's almost always a forked version
more often two different teams working on those things. So full credit to that Azure DevOps team,
despite their dumb name, figuring out how to deliver to both internal and external customers.
So that part is great. And I know they probably have a team that kind of functions as internal
developer relations. I know I would get pinged a lot when I was there by I didn't look up to see
who they were. People on that team to say, how's this going? I see you're doing an
inordinate number of queries against this data set. What's up? And I explained,
I built a dashboard. They go, okay, that's cool. But I'm kind of wondering,
this is very similar to someone else's journey into modern testing. They go, oh,
this is the thing I already do. I can read about it a little bit. How often is this?
How often is this used? So what I'm curious about from our listeners, and you can go to the
one of the three dot slack dot com or get an invitation from modern testing dot org,
if not already there. And I'm just curious if you have a team like this, if you call them
internal developer relations, or if you don't, that's fine too. But does your company have
a team whose role is to evangelize sort of a central set of tools? And then I wonder,
while I ask this question, if your company is 100 people, you probably don't need that,
because everybody knows everybody. And there's no need to do that. They know about stuff. There's
some tipping point where one or two degrees of separation are so prevalent that you need
to have a team to help make sure that people know how to use the dozens of thought, hundreds
of different things that we have to help developers get their job done. So very curious.
So I know they haven't been engaged with me if they exist. But as you correctly call out,
a lot of within Microsoft is now public. One thing we are about to do, which I think you've been doing
this for a while, back in the day, when you join a new team, right? What's one of the first conversations
you had with your admin? Do you remember? You're about to join a team. They always ask you,
okay, you probably forgot. One of the first conversations is which machine you're taking
with you. Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah. Right. The laptop or the desktop? Well, I forgot. Yeah,
I would never would have pulled that. We are about to remove desktop from active life here.
Yeah. In the world. Yeah. We just have laptops.
It'll start with Azure, but then it'll go to it'll go to all of Microsoft pretty quick.
What's interesting, I'll see if I can start the story real quick, but early on in the pandemic,
what was interesting is the our desktop developers were a little slow at first because their
desktops were stuck at work. They needed to either VPN into them or get them and bring them
home. But on the services side of things, it was business as normal because we do all our work
on laptops and all the heavy lifting happens in the cloud. Right. Right. And honestly,
that last plug, my M1 MacBook Pro is faster than my desktop. It's a my desktop is fast.
It's a rocket. Anyway, go on. I am beginning to go into a market. So I don't know if you've
encountered this as well. Maybe your glasses are better than mine. I find that as I'm getting
older, my eyesight is getting worse. I have a piece of shit laptop right there on the ground,
which you can't see with a 14 inch screen, which I just can't work from anymore.
I have to I am at the age where the resolutions I run out, I need glasses to use.
Even with glasses, I will get a headache. Oh, or I have to blow up the resolution so much that
all I can see is like the text box that says your first name. Right. And I'm like, yeah,
now give me my monitors at work with Dolmon. And when I heard about us moving to the cloud
with virtual desktops, I'm like, okay, that makes sense. Right. And dog food. I've always been a
believer in dog food. But I don't want to give up multi-mon. Multi-mon super handy for me.
And it turns out it works. I'm running three monitors on my laptop. Well,
can I have the laptop plus two other monitors? Yes. Yeah. So we're going to get apparently
workstation class laptops. I don't know what that means. It's a good plan. And honestly,
that whole you can take one machine thing was dumb because those machines
half the time didn't end up going just end up sitting around doing nothing anyway.
Oh, not me. My, my last machine, the machine I took with me to Azure was like an 80 gig box.
I had, wooed the admin to allow me to buy the memory for it. And people are like,
how much memory is in this thing? And I'm like, a lot, but now with the cloud, I'm like,
80 gigs. Anyway, I got to get going. We're talking to the old guy talkbook and I love to hear the
chatter on this in our stock channel. So bring that on. I got to run. And, but it's been good
chatting with you again. Yes. See you in a couple of weeks. All right, man. Bye. Bye.