People lie, chat GPT lies, chat GPT is human.
Welcome to A.B.
Testing Podcast, your modern testing podcast.
Your hosts, Alan and Brent, will be here to guide you through topics on testing,
leadership, agile, and anything else that comes to mind.
Now on with the show.
Hey, Brent.
Hey, Alan.
How's it going?
Well, you know, been a while since we've recorded three or four weeks.
Which means it's been a while since I've used Zencaster and I want to love Zencaster
so much, but it's extremely broken today.
I, it does feel from my end, it's broken.
It feels like we did a podcast every day.
You would absolutely hate Zencaster because I cannot recall a podcast set up where you
didn't spend at least the first three minutes turning the word Zencaster into a four
letter.
Yeah.
So here's the deal.
Here's, here's why I want to like Zencaster.
So today, if you've been listening to the past few episodes, Brent's audio clarity
has been much better because we're getting a local copy of his audio and not the
one that zoom compresses the crap out of and shoves over the internet.
Today, you're getting that compressed version of squished up version of Brent.
And so I have to tweak it a little bit different way.
It's a little bit of a pain.
I kind of like having the local audio, but whatever.
Yeah, you get it.
I want it to work because I get better quality recording of Brent and everybody
wants to hear Brent in the ultra most high fidelity possible.
And we're just not getting that today because Zencaster decided to be a piece
of crap.
I'm not certain your assumption is true, but we'll just move on.
All right.
Talk a minute.
I'm going to, I'm going to look at a wire here, but, uh, I think if I'm just a
minute ago, you were typing something and I'm curious if that was into a search
bar or if you were talking to a particular bit of AI that's been popular this week.
Oh, I was AI.
Tell me about that.
What, tell us about the question you asked him what it said, then
I'll tell you some stories.
Yeah.
Uh, I asked, uh, well, first off, I asked describe the A B testing
podcast, and it says, I'm sorry, but I am not able to browse the internet
or provide information about specific broadcasts.
I am a large language model trained by open AI to assist with general questions.
Then it asks, can I help with something else?
And I said, sure.
How can you make Zencaster actually work?
And told me, well, it's a web-based prop form.
It told me what it is.
And then it told me, uh, you have to have a stable internet.
Do you have a stable internet?
Check.
Okay.
A good quality microphone.
Uh, check.
Okay.
And any other necessary equipment?
Sure.
It's all here.
Same stuff we've used.
You may also need to adjust your audio settings.
Uh, that's what I tried to do.
Here was the problem with Zencast today.
And Zencast, if you were listening, love to have you on the show
sometime and we can talk about it.
The audio settings I was setting in the app did not reflect what it was actually doing.
I said, use my little recording mixer with the high, high brand, um, quality, high
HBQ, high brand quality.
And it said, okay, I'm going to let you select it, but I'm going to send the
sounds out your Mac book speaker.
Is that cool?
And I said, no, that's not cool.
And it said, that's all I'm confused.
I need, I need another beer.
Zencaster is drunk.
It's, it is out partying.
So I've been playing with, uh, I've been playing with a chat GPT a little bit,
the new AI chat that's all the rage asking it some questions.
Uh, I had it write a poem.
My team just finished a big migration this weekend.
So we, I had it write a poem and then somebody on my team said, I thought
there would be references to battleships and swords.
So I say, MIMP, what new sentence reference battleships and
swords, and it got even better.
So I like that it it's remarkably good at creating code.
What I've noticed in talking to folks about, I'm just kind of curious from your,
you know, ML AI data science point of view, but it very confidently
gives you an answer that may be incorrect.
Oh yeah.
If you have here, follow, follow along.
What is one, two, three, four, five times five, six, seven, eight, nine.
And it will absolutely.
Oh my God.
What is it doing?
It generated a new algorithm.
I will share screen because it didn't do this the last time I did it.
Oh my Lord.
It is physically, uh, I'll just cause Brent is unable to describe this.
It is adding plus one, two, three, four, five.
You're writing out the edition.
It's going to do it five, six, seven, eight, nine, 56,709 times.
So it won't be done by the time we're through with the podcast.
No.
And the other thing too, it's if you, if you look at the score, uh, I don't
know what that is one, two, is that that's 700.
So it gives me an answer of 704 million and a whole bunch of other digits.
Okay.
That answer is wrong because it is 701 million and a whole
bunch of different digits.
You must be wrong.
No.
Don't you dare tell the robot overlords they're wrong.
No, the thing is this is fascinating and I have spent, as I'm sure a large,
Oh, I guess it stopped.
Doesn't look like it's doing it anymore.
So I'm going to do this is wrong.
The correct answer.
Riveting podcast material.
Absolutely riveting.
12.
Okay.
It says I'm sorry.
Blah, blah, blah.
Anyway, I've had fun asking it some rant, kind of getting to know it, which is weird,
but there's been hundreds of thousands of people doing the same thing.
And I think it's learning from all of us.
It's kind of interesting, kind of interesting.
Anyway, you should play that lots of stories.
It's fascinating.
Let me tell you, let me tell you what I suspect it's doing.
And I'm sure you have other, uh, there's probably a whole bunch of other
people who like me are busily trying to reverse engineering.
One of the, not me.
Nope.
Okay.
One of the, there is a technique known as a GAN.
It stands for generative adversarial network.
Okay.
It's a, it's a, it's a really cool data science technique where it is able to
identify a massively multivariate relationship between multiple different
variables and generate things on its own.
I've had it build me a country song about unicorns and data science.
And I mean, I can't look at it and, and from a lyrical point of view and go,
okay, that's a country song, but you can have it do a play.
You can have it do a haiku.
You can have it.
Go ahead.
I was going to say, so I, along those lines, I did want to share, um,
for you and our listeners.
And, you know, if I can get my guitar chops up, this may get recorded soon, but I did
ask it once to write a, um, write a song about Brent and Alan in the style of
Taylor Swift.
So, uh, if you want to indulge me, I can read a little bit of this.
Um, Brent and Alan, two best friends, they've been through it all time and
time again, they met in school.
Now they rule their own little world.
Oh, so cool.
Then the chorus Brent and Alan B and A they're the perfect team and every
single way they've got each other's backs.
They'll never stray Brent and Alan forever and a day.
Oh, oh, check it out.
Check it out.
The next verse Brent's got the brains.
Alan's got the brawn together.
They can tackle any problem that comes their way.
They're unstoppable.
They know the score Brent and Alan.
They're always ready for more.
Okay.
I'm done with that.
I'm going to do Snoop Dogg.
Same question.
Same question, but Snoop Dogg, Brent and Alan.
They're the ones living life like they're having fun, always up for a good time.
Never letting the party die.
And the chorus is Brent and Alan.
They're the crew making moves.
They never lose laid back.
They take it slow.
Snoop Dogg style.
They're the pros.
Your songs better.
Yeah, but hanging out, just chilling, smoking, never ones to get too crazy.
But when the night falls, they turn it up, dancing and laughing, living it up.
So they, so the algorithm definitely did something other than just add Snoop Dogg into the lyrics.
Right.
Definitely.
It definitely looked up and said, okay, he's, he, well, it, it understands it didn't do a look up.
Right.
It, I am trying to explain how generative adversarial networks work in a way that would make sense to us, but it, it absolutely doesn't work that way.
Uh, there's one favorite one article, for example, where a guy said he created a VM on here, create a Linux VM.
No.
Okay.
So he, he managed, it's telling me, it's telling me how to create a VM and try to do something that is not entirely boring for our audience.
We're way beyond that.
Oh, okay.
Then I'm going to, uh,
the thing is it's kind of addictive.
You can't stop playing with it.
It is absolutely fun.
I want you to act as a Linux terminal.
It said no.
And then, well, this guy got it too.
He's lying.
Hmm.
Well, so people at Microsoft lie fact.
People lie.
So I'll just show you if I were to write a bunch, if I were to write all of this stuff, which I am absolutely not going to do.
Uh, what you will see in the article is chat GPT came back and acted, looked like a Linux terminal.
And if you go even further down, like they did an LS and they still acting like a Linux terminal, right?
And it would make you believe.
Uh, but it's not, you know what, you know why I do chat GPT lies.
Um, wait, people lie.
Chat GPT lies.
Chat GPT is human.
Uh, so my team does a lot of NLP.
So there's, there's been a lot of processing for those, not in the acronym world of Brent.
Right.
So there, there's been a lot of discussion on this within my team in terms of like, what are
they doing here?
And it is an absolute brilliant text simulator.
Right.
What is doing right here where it is, where it's generating UI that looks right.
Alan's looking at my screen, right?
This looks like a Linux terminal that you might see after you do an LS command.
Sure.
Right.
But all it has done, it, it is not going out to the internet.
It is not actually being a VM.
What it is doing is it has known from its train model.
It, it is actually able to generate the HTML code to simulate being a Linux
terminal that's all it's doing.
Right.
It's lying.
It's all it's doing.
But the fact that it's doing that is freaking amazing.
We haven't talked about it.
Uh, at least not yet.
I presume you are doing advent of code.
I'm not.
Oh, that makes me sad.
I am first time, like in six years, I've not done it.
And the first time in like in six years, I have.
Well, as long as one of the brave A and B strong pair do it, we're good.
The world is fine.
This thing is, it is able to, uh, uh, definitely it's able to, to write the code.
Oh, I see what you're doing.
Yeah.
It can do the work for you.
Right.
Write some code to parse input that looks like this.
Uh, one second advent of code.
This is a podcast print advent of code type along at home.
This is a type along podcast.
I'm just literally copying and pasting day one of the advent of code.
The instructions.
I'm not even reading it to see if I copy paste it, right.
I'm just copy pasting it and it is now generating a solution.
I've already done this beforehand.
It's telling you the algorithm.
Now it is writing pseudo code, uh, to this.
I did look at the first day and thought, Oh, I could do that.
Then I didn't do it.
Oh, I, I, I did it in, I was expecting to do it in five minutes.
It actually took me, uh, seven minutes longer because of my loop.
I forgot to reset things to zero, but now rewrite in Python.
Right.
Boom.
Riveting.
Right.
It's yeah, it's, it is amazing.
You're the good news is, is a lot of people fast forward past the first 10
minutes of our podcast anyway.
So in this case, because they don't care about that stuff, they
want to get to the meaty stuff.
Uh, so let's do that.
I don't know what I have a little bit, what our meaty stuff is.
Um, so advent of code and talk about for a second, it is, uh, kind of a cool
series of programming questions.
We haven't heard of it before each day kind of builds on the day before,
if not conceptually, uh, sometimes using, sometimes you'll end up
reusing an algorithm or a function from one day to the next.
It gets pretty complicated by the end.
It's a little harder every day in general.
I saw a talk maybe four years ago from the guy who puts it all together.
It was pretty cool.
There's a lot of, a lot about it.
Yeah.
Talk on, okay.
Talk on the advent of code.
It started, it was typical.
It's started from a server in his closet and ended up needing to use some
AWS, uh, compute and eventually got done.
Another thing I wanted to talk about, uh, which you tease me, we should talk
about sometime is have you ever done?
Like we have a request.
I'll just say it's like Brent and now and never talk about cybersecurity.
Yeah.
I advent of code reminds me of capture the flags.
Which I really like.
Have you done capture the flags?
Uh, the game.
No, the, the security type event.
So capture the flags are, no, usually it's a bunch of security related
security adjacent, uh, problems.
You can solve them by yourself or on a team.
And we just did one maybe three months ago at unity.
We do one every year in practicing different kinds of ethical hacking.
The idea is that you can understand how to prevent those in your
code and practices.
So what's really cool is some of them are straight up.
Uh, look at the, which I had the questions in front of me, some of you
have to just grip through data files and figure some stuff out.
It's, it's actual code monkeying.
Now I want to tell a story about that in a second.
The sort of, it's also the social engineering part.
I forget what they call that.
There's a name for that.
Shoot.
It escaped me, but ours was, it was a survey and they said, looks like
somebody has, has hidden the answer to this in this survey and it's a Google
survey and things you're supposed to figure out is that Google surveys, uh,
will output the results to a spreadsheet of the same name.
And sometimes owners will accidentally leave the access to that spreadsheet open.
So the idea was you thought you figure out the name of the survey, you experiment,
figure out what kind of spreadsheets day, and then you search Google drive, uh,
for that spreadsheet, you find it and get the secret out of there.
So it's just kind of a, it's just kind of a scavenger hunt and a bunch,
in a bunch of different ways.
So those things are fun.
I did one with my son, did a couple problems of one over a couple of days
last year where it's, um, just some problem.
They find the packet with this or figure out which packets will cause this
to, you know, reveal your secret.
And the one I did with him was really cool.
It was every solution.
Remember those games you played in the old days and you get like a save
key had to write down so you could enter in to get back to your, your old spot.
Old days.
Uh, it's kind of like that.
You get the, you get a text file, it gets to your save key.
You can start there the next time, start the next problem.
But the way I learned to solve most of these, this is my little story is way
back when, this is before Allen and Brent were a thing, when it was Allen,
trying to figure out how he could stay employed at Microsoft.
When he didn't know anything, I began working at the time, the predecessor
was, I worked on windows for a little while.
I was working on video capture drivers for windows, what eventually
became windows 2000 back when there were three different.
Devices that use our video capture drivers.
It was fun.
I liked it, but then they got the windows millennium team back together
and I went and worked there.
I wanted to work on debug windows cause they hadn't shipped in a couple of years.
And well, it didn't boot in a couple of years cause nobody cared
about during windows idea.
I thought they'd be fun to elect analytics and analyze things.
I made debug windows work and I was working on it with one of the
original Microsoft MS Doss dudes.
It was really cool.
I got a pair with him.
Okay.
I got, I got someone who can teach me some skills, but he showed up one day
and decided that he was too rich to work anymore.
So he quit.
And rather than put somebody else smart on the project with me, they just said,
you'll be fine.
You go figure it out.
So this was my crash course into understanding everything about the
portable executable format, how binaries are put together on windows,
where things lived in memory, assembly language, et cetera, et cetera, et cetera.
Brant just staring at the wall.
No, I w I was looking for in my live.
So my library is over right there.
And I was looking for my security book and I'm not able to find it.
The adjacent story I'm telling is the goal was to get, get the damn thing to
boot and then get it so we can use it as a development platform.
Cause it'll find all kinds of issues that the debug version of, of at
least windows nine X was just, it would find every little thing you did wrong.
As far as like releasing stuff after you using stuff, after you've released it,
all the, all the good memory corrupting stuff, uh, very, very handy.
Got a booting it almost booted.
And I don't know if it's a well-known fact, but at the time when
millennium came out, downloading things from the internet, wasn't really a thing.
So was there an internet?
There was the internet was around, but it wasn't really a big, wasn't
really a big download vehicle.
Most people still had dial up, I think then.
So windows was the ship vehicle for all these little projects at Microsoft,
Microsoft hearts, all the card games.
There was some other little things, you know, some health and safety thing.
Windows had to ship to those things could ship.
And we had some other random apps in there.
That's the only reason we did millennium.
As all these teams said, well, if we, if windows 2000 is going to be late,
we need a place to ship these things.
So we did.
So my goal was to get the damn thing to boot.
We had a couple apps in our startup that had asserts in retail.
They had retail asserts.
They had, if you are familiar with XO six assembly, it's an int three X
instruction cause it to stop in the debugger, which was no good.
We didn't want it to stop in the debug.
We want the thing to boot and run normally.
So it could be used for debugging.
We don't have to have to press G in their debugger a couple of times.
There are probably half a dozen of these.
And for three or four of them, I was able to track down the owners
and get them to fix it.
And what's surprising is some of these were still actively developed.
And I still remember dev teams coming back to me and saying, Oh no,
we don't want to fix that.
It's not a real bug.
And me, me just being, okay, I don't know.
I don't know what to say to that.
Uh, but eventually, but eventually I got all, but two of them to actually
fix their code.
So it didn't have a, a, a, basically a debug break on the retail
build, trying to boot windows or debug by trying to do windows.
Uh, for those last two though, I did a little, this is where I learned
that at the time sort of, I had sort of between doing a lot of the
debugging for overnight stress runs and knowing how binaries are put together.
If you've ever debug at assembly level, when an int three instruction
happens in, in code and binary or in hex code, that's a, that's a CC
instructor next 86.
So if you hit a CC, it's a, it breaks.
That's a code check.
Yeah.
So you could check, right?
So interrupt, interrupt three.
Yes.
So what I did was I don't, I don't think I ever revealed my
secret to this day until now.
I told the build lab, Hey, I have finally have fixed binaries for these
two things we've been waiting on.
So great.
I said, can I just drop them to you directly?
And I said, um, we should get them from the team.
No, I needed to do some, some stuff on my end, but just, just, let's
just put these debug build only.
It'll be fun.
So they'll work.
And I gave them the two executables and, uh, all was good forever and ever.
And, and within a month we were playing direct X games over the network
on debug windows without any problems.
It was fantastic.
I was, it was one of the first times in my programming career where I really
felt like I knew what I was doing.
So what I did, do you know what I did?
No, I got out a little hex editor and you, and I found the address of that.
That's that in through that interrupt three, that's that code check that
CC and I overrode it with a 90.
Change that CC to a 90 saved it.
Disk did that for each of the programs.
I wrote it back.
90 is the very fancy instruction called a no-op.
Mm.
Okay.
It was fun.
It was my first time where I actually felt like I was hacking, even though
I wasn't hacking, uh, but it was, it got me curious about how, well, the things
you could do, and then of course it was only a year later, I should have kept
my curiosity up because only a year later when Microsoft was getting
hit by virus after virus after virus.
And we said, wait a minute, we need to think about security.
What you just said brought me back to the day where I would do a lot of
hex editing along those lines, right?
But it was mostly, Hey, I'm out of gold on my game.
Let's go hex edit the save file.
Oh yeah.
Now I got infinite goals.
I remember doing stuff like that too.
Yeah.
It's, but it's fun.
It was, it's not exactly cybersecurity, but it's, it's, it's cybersecurity adjacent.
And is, I am interested.
I asked a chat GPT to explain to me how capture the flag works.
All right.
Is, is, is chat GPT your new best friend?
Uh, you know what?
Do I'm going to have it write you a love song?
Brent's asking right now.
Anyway, go on.
No, uh, actually multiple teams have, um, it's, it's fun to put certain things in here.
Like the thing that this does.
All right.
Let's, let's talk about ethical ramifications of, of this.
Like to me, there's a couple of things that I'm, I'm, I'm, when I poke chat
PT, uh, chat GPT, right.
It's very clear in terms of things it can do, right.
It can write code.
Absolutely.
I haven't tried to get it to write anything super complex, but this thing can
absolutely shortcut the process of writing code.
Now there might be some concerns later on around intellectual property.
Can I, am I allowed to use the code written by GPT in a production thing?
I don't know.
And I want you to not say anything being employed where you are, but I can say it.
As you know, this is very similar to the, uh, the AI it's in, uh, GitHub to
help get up where they call it co-pilot to help you write code.
And there's a bit of a lawsuit from people going, Hey, wait a minute.
Don't you, do we have to give you permission?
You've you're basically reproducing our code to solve your problem.
So, um, there are some ethical things to think about when you get, and I'm
sure chat GPT has walked all through, get, you know, not just GitHub, but stack
overflow and all the places where the programming, the programming's happen.
I haven't done this research, but in terms of what it can do, I have to
believe, uh, this thing has been trained on petabytes of data, right?
Oh, yeah.
Many, many, I would say many, many petabytes.
Um, and again, the technique caught again, all it's trying to do is take any
context and generate something that would pass the Turing test.
Okay.
And people have done this with computer vision, right?
There are apps you can go to and say, generate a, an image of a
waterfall with a yellow bird.
Oh yeah.
I, they have that AI played with that one.
This is no different than that, except this is text.
Okay.
It's, it's exactly this exactly the same concept.
This is text.
This thing knows, this thing knows nothing about any of the
things that we're talking about.
It just knows the, it understands the characters put together the way
you do have a semantic meaning.
It doesn't even know the meaning.
It just understands the relationships and, and it can generate, uh, responses
that we interpret as, holy crap.
This thing fucking knows everything.
Okay.
It knows nothing except the relationships between many different things.
However, like I don't know, I asked it, Hey, with this, what are you missing?
What capabilities are you missing to become Skynet?
Right?
Yeah.
Oh, if you asked it.
And I saw something today while you think about you, I'm going to interrupt here
that very similar along the Skynet things that somebody better take a snapshot
archive of what this has and put it in a vault somewhere, because once humanity
decides to destroy ourselves, we can use this to rebuild everything.
I think it was half tongue in cheek, but I thought it was pretty funny.
Uh, it may, maybe.
Right.
Um, uh, it's answer it's answer as a large language model trained by open AI.
I do not have the ability or the desire to become Skynet or any other type
of artificial intelligence with malicious intent.
I, I am a machine learning model that has been trained to assist with
general information and answer questions to the best of my ability based on my
training, I do not have the ability to develop or evolve beyond my current
capabilities.
I am not capable of becoming Skynet or any other type of malevolent AI.
And of course, my response is, well, of course, if you're trying to become
Skynet, that's exactly what you're going to say.
Um, but there is another thing I assume because the Skynet and are the
Terminator movies and the matrix, there's going to be a large number of people,
particularly data scientists that are looking at this with enough ethical
point of view.
Okay.
However, there are other countries and such that would take this and go,
this is fantastic.
We're going to teach it those capabilities, right?
This type of tool in the wrong hands, uh, could be very dangerous.
But you've been, you've been in data science for a minute on the AI side,
but I mean, we're having fun with chat GPT, but also it's been in the
adjacent possible for a long time.
None of us are going, Oh my God, I never thought somebody could do
something like this.
It's pretty cool, but it's not, it's not, I mean, we all knew it was coming.
It's not surprising.
No, I didn't, uh, just like anything else.
So I have been telling you, and I'm pretty certain I've been saying it on
the podcast, I believe we're at the beginning of the end of the data
science error where data science just becomes API.
People call.
Absolutely.
Um, uh, I think this, this thing is further proof that, that,
that my belief is true.
Like I, my team is heavily into natural language processing.
And I I've talked with a couple of my teams and I'm like, yeah, I don't know
if we should continue working in that space, even though this is where we
specialize, it's something that distinguishes us from other data science
teams, but with something like this out here, maybe it's just wait until.
Uh, these guys get some APIs that we can call, right?
Because I am, I am years away from anything like what these guys have done.
For sure.
But there are other ethical, other, other ethical questions that I have here.
If we think back, uh, I think this really occurred either in between us
being kids and us being parents.
And here I'm talking about you and I, but there was a moment in time
where when I went to school, calculators were frigging banned.
Right.
And now calculators are commonplace at school.
Because at some point in time, it was just like, okay, this is, this is archaic.
This is stupid.
We need to rethink how we approach this.
Okay.
This thing can do homework for you.
Right.
Is this, is this thing going to become a tool that kills learning?
Like think about your children.
Write me an essay about Paul Revere.
Right.
Boom.
If nothing else, it's going to significantly bootstrap.
And how are we as humans going to go?
All right.
Well, part of the human condition is, is learn and adapt and move forward.
Now, maybe this becomes like calculator where essentially, all right.
No one writes essays anymore.
Let's talk about the evolution here.
Um, because for 10 years or more, people have been copy and
pasting from stack overflow, like nobody's business.
Right.
So have those people.
So what I tell, what I look for, like in a candidate for a program position is not.
Do you have the answer memorized?
But can you figure out the answer?
Cause you need to be adaptive.
And I believe that knowing how to look for those things in stack overflow is actually
a skill that I want in a programmer.
Now it's a little different with chat GPT or AI for things.
You still have to know, you know, this from kind of trying to craft questions.
You still have to know the best question to ask, and then you need to apply some
critical thinking to the answer.
Cause as we discussed earlier, the answer could be wrong.
Right.
So, and then let me tell another story.
So it's something I've told maybe not on the podcast in a while, but a lot of
people talk to me about how I got from where I came from to hear is they go,
what, how'd you get from writing music to writing code?
And what I tell people is there's the creative part of trying to figure out,
like what's the way to solve the problem and how do we need to do it?
What's the pseudo code even, which chat GPT does a little bit of itself,
but there's that creative part in composition.
Same thing.
There's a creative part trying to figure out the sound you're trying to get, uh,
the flavors you want to get the core progression structures, but you get to a
point and it's all wrote and the wrote parts boring.
And if we can get the AI to jump in and if like, even when you pasted the
problem in when a little while ago, you knew the problem you were trying to
solve, you just wanted to shortcut the solution.
I still think there's skill needed in there.
It's going to accelerate people.
As this grows, it will accelerate people, but it still needs.
We're not quite yet, or we don't need people.
We need the people to figure out the problem we're trying to solve and to
figure out that, and then we can accelerate ourselves using something to
go basically look up all the information from the internet and the learning model
that it's going to give us the right answer most of the time.
Uh, and, and even though, uh, like the right answer, wrong answer, I'm, I'm, I'm
really not worried about that because that I very strongly believe that that
will work itself out in the background over time, right?
We've talked about where, where ideas come from and, and the adjacent possible.
Yeah, this, this could be an accelerant, right?
Cause what this is going, what this is potentially going to do is just
accelerate the output possible.
Right.
I think about, I think about math, right?
If we go through elementary school, there's an obvious level by level or grade
by grade progression through math.
You can't do calculus in second grade because you, there's a whole shit.
It builds on a bunch of different stuff.
Right.
Um, now do I believe you could rapidly progress with a tool like chat GPT to,
to correctly answering calculus homework within a span of, uh, I don't know, even
months, absolutely.
Yeah.
Would, would you walk away understanding these concepts?
No.
Would you walk away potentially understanding how to use the answers?
Maybe.
Yeah, but it could not.
Now let me twist this again, because I'll start backwards.
I think I was going to say first, which is that there is 0% of my job that can be
audit, that my job today that can be automated with chat GPT.
And that's fine.
Doesn't mean I get to keep my job longer.
It just means that it does not what it's good at.
I think the thing you need to teach honestly, to use this effectively, you
know, as a school aid is the same stuff that schools are not teaching well today,
which is interaction and critical thinking and critical analysis and, and
how to figure out it's the thinking part today in schools, we focus a lot on the
doing, we focus on outputs, not outcomes.
Same thing in software.
Well, if you use this tool a lot in your software, you're going to create a bunch
of, you can create a whole crap ton of code, but are you solving a customer problem?
I don't think chat AI, maybe, you know what I mean?
Yeah, I can help you figure out the problem you're solving with the human
part is the more important part.
We get bogged down in the real work and the same thing's true in schools.
In schools, it's all about.
We want to be able to do calculus so we can, I don't know what, so we
can do harder calculus, but it's just building on years and years of other
things you need to know so you can solve a problem, but we need to think
about like what kinds of problems.
Here's what I'd love to do as a school teacher is I would love to take a
problem solving approach where you, and this is possible where you start with
what is a problem I want to solve that seems difficult to solve, but here's
how we could use math to solve it from every level, everything from
additional application fractions, all the way up to calculus.
So we understand why we're going to use it.
That's often missing in the calculus curriculum taught in the schools.
It's like starting with the problem, starting with why, starting
with what we're trying to do.
So that's my little sub box.
Yeah, there are, as part of our discussion, I was inspired and I, I don't
know if it makes sense, but I asked GPT to create music notation for a new waltz.
Um,
that's what's weird is there's two chords per met per measure in that thing.
You're showing me, but waltzes have three beats per measure.
So I'm not sure exactly what they're doing there.
Yeah.
I'm not podcast.
I'm not going to read this thing.
Yeah.
Right.
I don't understand this music notation.
I earlier, I asked to jingle bells and I don't get this either because jingle
bells is, is, uh, I'm pretty sure this three, four measure.
And I don't even see jingle bells in here.
So those are the chord progression.
So it's, it's, it works.
This is a chord progression, but it's piano.
Yeah.
I don't get it.
I don't think it's quite right either.
So it has a ways to go on the music.
Uh, we are, believe it or not, the chat, this is the chat GPT podcast
with Alan and Brent.
Um, we probably are actually, because it's a little shorter because we started
late because then caster is drunk, but we got to close here in a second.
Anything, anything else you want to say before my very special closing today?
No, let's close.
Okay.
So, um, because of the spirit, I asked chat GPT to write an
inspirational monologue I can use to close our AB testing podcast.
So with, with my heart in my hands, I would like to say this to all the
listeners, thank you for joining us on the AB testing podcast today.
We hope that our discussion has inspired you to think more deeply about the
incredible power of technology and the endless possibilities that offers as
software developers, we have the unique ability to shape the world around us
and make it a better place, even with AI edit.
So let's continue to push the boundaries of what's possible and
never stop learning and growing together.
We can create a brighter future until next time, keep coding
and never lose sight of your dreams.
Goodbye for now.
I'm Alan.
I'm Brent.
And we'll see you next time.