What I want to do, let me just talk through how I turned the corner on this.
Which was 100 and 100 million billion
kazillion percent in agreement.
And this is a man who knows his numbers.
Welcome to A.B.
Testing podcast, your modern testing podcast.
Your hosts, Alan and Brent will be here to guide you through topics
on testing, leadership, agile and anything else that comes to mind.
Now on with the show.
Hey, everybody. Howdy.
Alan, you're lovely.
I'm love.
I'm lovely. Yeah. Who are you?
I'm Brent.
Brent, you're a lovely host.
Yeah, I'm uncomfortable with the term lovely.
I like this.
You know what? You're going to have to go with it.
You know what we're going to do today?
No, make a podcast that's better than the one we made last time.
Continuous improvement.
Yeah, that's that's that should be an easy to achieve.
Yeah. Retros are important. We retro.
We say, you know what? Let's do better.
So we're going to do that. We're going to do better.
So how you been? What's new? What's exciting?
It's just coming up.
Not a thing for me, but whatever.
Chocolate Bunny Day.
Is that what it is?
Yeah, I think it's chocolate Bunny Day.
Well, if you if you play Animal Crossing, then it literally is.
Bunny Day coming up.
I don't play Animal Crossing.
Oh, all right.
Do you Animal Cross?
I did. I'm not currently.
We got a whole community at Unity.
It's like they have a shared spreadsheet of what they make and everything.
And it's they're into it.
Yeah, we've talked about this before.
Anyway, go on.
Do you even have a switch?
No, there's there switches in the house.
I don't have one that I claim as my own.
Like Nintendo switch.
I know what you're talking about.
Yes, a Nintendo switch.
No. So so there's like a bunch of I'm not as dumb as I look, Brent.
What data do you have to back that up?
All right. Well, we'll just go for it.
All right.
So that'll be a continuously disproved or not yet proven.
People are doubting our opening statement of doing a better podcast already.
No, but it's going to be higher energy, therefore, just by definition better.
How can two old farts like us have high energy?
Coffee. Oh, yes, I did.
Yeah, yeah. So were you I have stuff to say, but I can't remember
if you were saying anything or not.
No. So, and I'm a long story short, I played a lot of Animal Crossing.
There's really I've now played it enough that there's really no more sort of goals
to achieve, like there's not any sort of like achievement points.
Like there is an Xbox.
There are all these other little sort of achievements you can do.
And I've kind of done them.
So my my my game of today on the switch is one known as Hades.
Oh, yes. This is a hard game.
I've played this. You've played Hades.
Yeah. On Xbox. Yeah.
Yeah. So like right now I'm on my 150th run.
I have yet to beat Hades himself.
I have I was bummed by the last time because I almost got him down to the
to the second one and I'm like, oh, I'm going to do it.
Oh, I'm dead. Yeah.
So for those who are not as nerdy as us,
Hades is a game where you start off your character.
You're you are the son of Hades, who ancient Greek God
who controls essentially the Greek version of hell.
And you are tired of living in hell
and you are trying to get out.
And Hades has insisted that no one gets out.
I am playing a game where I'm continuously trying to just prove this
and continuously fail anyway.
One bit of news for me is kind of hilarious.
I think I mentioned last time I was traveling to Montreal for a team offsite.
Yes. Yeah, that's not happening.
Montreal got nixed for some reason.
I can't remember.
I was out so I can't remember what I went on a bike ride last week.
We're right about 200 miles.
Anyway, Montreal was canceled.
I came back. It was going to be Miami.
And then we found out the Miami Grand Prix is the weekend.
The week were there. So I talked.
I think I think I think I think I think I've talked my manager
into doing it in Los Angeles, a much closer plane ride for me.
And I don't care about anybody else.
So I go somewhere, you know, travel somewhere, go and travel on a plane.
So that's kind of it for me.
Work, work, work, bike, ride, bike, ride, bike, ride.
Yeah, that's it.
I have a question about work.
If you want to get into the podcast proper in record time.
Just sure.
But I'll just do one last thing.
I just looked it up and apparently Fallout 5
won't be out until at least 2025.
Oh, yeah. Anyway. All right. Let's go.
Should I? Should I preorder it now?
Um, I don't know. I don't think so.
If it's anything like Fallout 76, the answer would be no.
I played 15 minutes of Fallout 76.
And when like not when it came out, like maybe it was over winter break.
Oh, just like three months ago or whatever it was.
Oh, so the news I haven't tried, but the news is saying
that it sucks way less.
Yeah, it wasn't too bad. I just I just lost interest.
So I have a question.
It's actually hearkens back to a few of our earlier podcasts.
For those of you that may remember, at one point I worked at Microsoft,
small little software company in Redman where Brent remains employed,
as far as we know, and probably while we were there together,
Microsoft went through at least three, if not 12,
different iterations of employee performance programs.
And they still use the Connect.
Is that today's thing still?
That's a record for how long they've used that.
Because I've been around for about three or four years when I left.
And I don't recall anything being used that long.
But yeah, they they haven't changed Connect in a long time.
This year and literally in the last month, it is the first time
they released. I don't even know the name of it.
It's employee. I think it's employee signals is what it's called.
It's the dramatic replacement to MS Polls.
Oh, we use a third party culture thing called Culture app.
We just finished up our poll today.
In fact, I will let you know confidential unity information.
I'm going to get busted by comms for this.
My team had 94 percent participation.
Wow. Looks like that's as far as reading it.
So not bad, huh? Not bad.
That so I did not.
All right. So anyway, the Connect is the the employee review thing, et cetera, et cetera.
We talked about the toxicity that can generate when people are more concerned
about getting their own goals done.
We used to joke at Microsoft around peak in May because that connect you do
because all the pay stuff is done in June.
And and then the straw, one of the straws that broke the camel's back with me
was my manager making up stuff in my connect that never happened or he never told me.
I said, OK, I'm done. But so all that happens.
It's very awkward and weird about I can't remember how long ago.
Maybe I won't get there yet.
I've talked before about Unity's three Q system of feedback.
So three questions, three times a year.
What is your mission or why is your mission important?
What are you doing to achieve your mission?
And how's it going?
Just sort of the framing for a reflective one on one,
looking at the work and opportunity for feedback.
As we grow, we're seeing the need for more opportunities for feedback.
And so we're building in we're building a goal setting system
and which set off my Spidey sense and red flags at first.
I was furious.
I can share that.
I do not want a performance management system.
My organization gives feedback just fine.
As I've lived with it, we haven't visited a soft launch.
I'm an official thing to like forever from now.
But as I've sat with it and thought about it and talked about it,
I'm feeling a lot better about it.
And I think it's possible to have a healthy culture and organization
and still have these goals you can work on.
In fact, you can even do better if you do goals in the right way.
But the reason I want to I'll talk a little about my ideas,
but we want to bring it up to you because in our conversations
in the past, you have said that Microsoft is getting better
in some of the toxicity that I experienced when I was there.
And of course, there's pockets.
It's a huge freaking company.
Can you talk a little bit from what you can?
And we'll both have to be a little bit nonspecific in some areas, I'm sure.
But I think I think we can be fairly transparent on
how do you approach that goal setting with your employees?
And I mean, how do you come up with good goals?
What makes up a good goal?
And I'll jump in and add some flavor as we go through.
But let me let me kick off with that question.
Oh, what was your first one?
So you said what makes a good goal?
Well, there's a good goal.
And really, how do you approach setting goals with your employees?
Oh, what I will do is I'll share with you.
So there's a bar that I have set very high for the principal band.
So at Microsoft, we have multiple bands, but the most popular,
most populated bands are in order, just simply a one.
So you could be a PM one or a software engineer one or a data science one.
Or you could be a two.
Or you could be the natural that is a senior.
And then after that is a is a principal.
And then lastly, after that is a partner.
You weren't a partner when you left, right?
You were still principal.
Yeah, I was 67 in Microsoft terms.
I was a principal.
Yep, I am.
I am a principal myself now.
And so when I have conversations with and I'm not entirely meandering,
but when I have conversations with my seniors
who are who their next promotion would move them into the principal band,
I start off with a setting expectations on the principal band as follows.
OK, so you want to go to principal.
What I want you to do is think about what KPI
that the business cares about that you want to own.
And then they look at me befuddled.
What do you mean?
Own like I'm already I'm already driving a bunch of KPIs.
I'm like, no, no, no, no.
Here's what own means.
You're going to you're going to say, Brit, I want the food KPI.
And then I say, OK, great.
Start working through.
I want to I want you to start working through your strategy
around how you're going to move it.
And then I'm going to be basically hands off.
That's what own means.
I want you to practice moving needles.
Yeah, that's I'm going to jump in because that's a it's not
I don't know if we've got into the setting goals part directly.
Maybe we're getting there, but yeah, that's I've had a very similar conversation.
So the levels that every company has a very similar growth of or leveling system.
They're not all identical.
For example, if I look at levels, not FYI, I see that it's about makes sense.
What we call principal or director
is the top end of sixty six, sixty seven and all of sixty seven at Microsoft.
And when I'm talking to those folks, a little little higher up.
But I tell them at at that level, you have to run your business.
Yes, that your business could be small. Right.
But that's and that's what I'm kind of trying to drive them to
is basically understand, no, when you're the owner, you are
essentially part of the business team
and you are going to specifically drive improvements in this thing.
They're like, well, but wait a minute, that KPI multiple teams are like, no, no.
Scope it down and and to something that is drivable.
But getting to goal setting.
So the at the very top level, the reason why I told the story is at the very top level,
I'm very explicit. What's the KPI? You're going to move.
You're a senior now.
You should have everything you need underneath your belt.
Like one of my expectations around the senior band
is that they have learned to master leadership.
Right. And leadership is the ability to get people to follow you,
not do what you say.
Follow you. Very distinct difference.
You should also at that, depending on your role, you should also have at that point in time
has sufficient skill set in whatever band you are.
If you're a developer, like you probably know all the coding
you need to know at at 64.
Sure, there might be other things that are that would be fun to learn.
Always learning support.
But it's enough to give the team trust in your ability to lead them.
And I keep on thinking when you say followers, I keep on thinking of the Maxwell
levels of leadership and there's you're put in a position of leadership
and then people give you permission to lead them.
And I really like that. It's like, yeah, you can I trust you.
I trust you to help me figure out the path.
We just had a reorg and and I picked up a couple of people
and part of my first speech because you shrunk it last time we talked to you
and shrunk. Yeah. And it's it's back up and circle of life still growing.
Yeah, it's it's a headache because
right for me, Brent needs the right balance of talky and dewy.
And right now I am over pivoting on talk.
I'm too much talky right now.
And it's it's I'm working on it.
So I want to jump in and I like where you're going.
But I'm going to I realize I can be more specific here and help out here.
So by talking about you want to talk about commitments?
No, I mean, you commitments goals.
So here is the deal.
And I can compare Microsoft and kind of where some of my my rage flare up came in.
Like, oh, we're going to have goals.
And I'm not saying goals are bad.
Goals are good. But things change so quickly.
At Microsoft, the commitments were they yearly, twice yearly.
It's really hard because stuff changes super fast these days.
So what would happen is people would either set very vague goals,
which you could morph into success no matter what.
And it's hard to tell if you're hard to coach on those or very specific goals
or or more, I think very even more specific goals that may become irrelevant
a few months down the road.
So how do you go about setting goals or commitments?
With your team to to avoid falling into either of those two traps
or those traps, OK?
Enumerate again, the two traps.
So vague that you can't tell if you've made progress or not.
So you can make shit up the the what I thought was the canonical Microsoft model
or an amount of specificity that if anything changes,
that goal is irrelevant, just just becomes an A or not done.
So nowadays with goals,
here is what I here is a major difference,
I would say, about the current Microsoft thing.
OK, Microsoft doesn't care about goals.
We have these things called commitments, but we don't care about goals.
You get reviewed on impact.
And I think that's the key. Go on.
I like that better.
The problem is, as it stands right now, the term impact
is kind of because there's still too many, you know, old timers here.
The term impact is just becoming a synonym for for goal
in in in the old world that existed when you were still here.
OK, the like this idea of of of committing
to something, to committing to something that you've written in your connect.
That is something that has died down.
And for me, it makes more sense.
But this idea of committing to
shipping this feature by this date, right, you go and look up smart goals
and they'll tell you, oh, yeah, that's a fantastic goal.
But committing to it, and at least in my world,
is just absolutely nonsensical.
I heard a great quote about smart goals on a podcast today.
The quote was everybody knows about smart goals, but nobody's excited about them.
Yeah, because smart, the smart goals and I
actually you've been long ago, a manager of mine, Damien.
Ah, Damien Lindauer.
Where can I sit on LinkedIn?
I just doxed Damien. Sorry, man.
No, do you remember there was a there was one time I called you in
to do a presentation at a at a Damien team meeting?
And then I at that same meeting, I presented around
smarter goals like I've done.
So I created my own acronym Smarter Goals.
So anyone can go up and look up smart on the Internet.
I had a measurable, actionable result oriented and time bound, something like that.
Relevant and time bound.
Yeah. And then I added an E.
So everyone know a
the A stands for actionable in some places or attainable in other places.
Or astonishing. The E.
Or sometimes Alan.
So the E I added was exceedable.
Though can you get past it?
Can you can you overachieve?
Right. Right.
If if if you are because one of the big problems at Microsoft at that point in time,
if you had the goal that wasn't exceedable, then right.
Your goals are setting you up for a three.
OK, tell me the R that I want to react.
Reasonable set.
OK, so you smart has you go through these goals.
Right. But if and you could create an individual
goal, but if you have too many of these goals,
then you're diluting your effort.
Yeah, absolutely.
You can't have multiple.
But let me give you some reaction because my the part that doesn't sit well
with being the part I will ignore and fight and do my own way
is tying those goals to pay.
We can tie the impact to pay.
So what I want to do, so let me let me just talk through my
how I turn the corner on this, which 100 and 100 million billion,
gazillion percent in agreement.
And this is a man who knows his numbers.
So what I want to use the goals for, and this is where
the Connect stuff comes up three times a year, sometimes two.
Is that right?
It doesn't matter.
What I've decided is I will get goals from my whole org,
starting with my direct reports, and we will check in on the
and we're going to get some wrong.
We're going to practice doing it because it takes some practice
to get it right, as you know.
And we're going to check in on them regularly.
Maybe not every one on one, but at least once a month
because they provide a ton of coachable moments and times
where you can give specific feedback.
Here's a challenge with feedback.
If I go to my manager, actually, my manager doesn't know how
to get feedback, bad example.
But if I were to go to my manager hypothetically and say,
do you have any feedback for me?
He'd be like, uh, yeah, when you ask for feedback,
it should be around specific things.
Do you have any feedback on the delivery of component A to team X?
And then hopefully we can get that.
Then what this does is having goals that we work through
can give us some opportunities for feedback.
And then my model here is I'm not really into smart.
I am time bound, not worried about smarter,
but remember the unity three questions.
Why is your mission important is the first one.
And I find I'm a disciple of Dan pink as much as I am
of Eric Reese.
And if people have autonomy, mastery, and purpose,
and I give people autonomy and I balance that
with accountability and transparency,
but I give them freedom to run their own business.
I make sure they have the skills to do
what they need to do, mastery.
And purpose is so important.
I want everyone to feel like their role and their job
and what they do is important.
So we start with that question.
And then from there, move into what are some things
that you want to accomplish to help achieve this mission?
And we come up with two or three goals sometimes
and it kind of depends on level and experience.
Someone more junior, they may be shorter term,
one month goals.
Someone more seniors like by the end of Q2 or Q3
or by the end of 22, they need to accomplish this.
And then they'll go through and break it down.
Like what are the milestones?
It's almost like objective and key results for the goal.
We'll have a goal, like what are the things
I need to accomplish to make sure I'm working toward this?
And those are the things we can check in on.
And then finally, after we kind of get through
that little exercise, it doesn't take long.
I make sure that those goals represent both
what they want to do for the business
as well as their personal growth
and or growth in that, whatever they want to do.
Does this feel like it moves you forward?
Remember the old ACB model.
A certain amount of your work is above you
and stretches you.
Some is just stuff you're good at that you do.
And then there's a little bit of grunt work.
We want the below work.
We want to minimize that and find the right balance
between stuff that stretches you
and stuff you're just good at.
What happens if you don't have any stuff
that stretches you, Brent?
You burn out and die.
You're bored as fuck.
Yeah.
So remember Microsoft used to accuse me
of changing jobs every 18 months,
which I deny, but it turned out being kind of true.
I didn't accuse you.
I was just putting out the facts.
Damn data people.
But what happened was in every single one of those cases,
except for the last one, which is special,
I was bored.
There wasn't really anything challenging left for me
to do in that role.
So I wanted to do something else.
I, in hindsight, I have found
that there were two primary reasons for me leaving.
One of them is, yeah, bored as hell.
Bored, bored, boredy, boredy, bored, bored, bored.
The other one is not bored, love what I'm doing,
but there is a critical problem within the organization
that I have attempted to do my part to fix.
And just not only is it done on track to get fixed,
it's not going to be fixed.
And I have a big problem staying in broken orcs.
I'm like, oh my God, it's gonna drive me
incredibly insane on a daily basis.
It depends how broken and how much ability you have
to fix what's broken.
If it's a hopeless cause, yeah, I would get out.
I mean, we are so fricking lucky to be able to work
in an industry where we can have jobs
that are fun and challenging.
I am sharing on my screen right now.
For those of you not watching the closed captioning version
of this podcast, Brent has a screen full of Venn diagrams
and other charty looking things.
I'm going to explain it to you,
my beloved listener in a second.
And Alan, I'm gonna focus his attention on this.
This is a diagram that controls 90% of the time
of my one-on-ones with my staff.
So can I attempt to describe this for our listeners?
Cause I think you are on the money.
You have found, you have the diagram close at hand,
which represents what I just mentioned.
So this is a three circle Venn diagram of what we do well,
what we want to do and what we can be paid to do.
And smack dab in the middle of the intersection
of those three circles is hooray.
Right.
And we should all, I mean, knowledge workers rejoice.
Knowledge workers have the ability to seek out
and find that role.
It's not always easy.
And sometimes it's a little bit in the outskirts,
but we're lucky.
And so I will talk to them and I will go through
and say, okay, we can talk to them.
Or like I just picked up a couple of employees.
I know I've erased it now.
Otherwise I'd prove to you that right over there
on that whiteboard where it says,
predict risks and mitigate, I had drawn the circle.
I've been using this thing for years
in terms of my one-on-ones and say, okay,
so where are we?
Where are you with this particular task?
Where are you on the task of growing your career
in this diagram?
Now, circling it back to the goals, right?
The reason why I brought up that top level KPI
is that's what I do when people are going in
or are part of the principal band.
And then you would imagine that at the lower bands,
I'm basically training them up to get to the point
where I can have that conversation
when they're principal band.
Like at the level two, their job,
in my view, their job is execution excellence.
You have to get shit done.
At senior band, your job is to figure out how to lead.
And in this case, I don't even care how you're leading.
It could be a technical leader, it could be a people leader,
you could be a strategic leader.
I don't care.
My only bar is that you have evidence
that there are people following you.
And as you correctly called out,
a follower is someone that's making a choice.
Like they don't have to choose to walk your path.
Now, on goals, I particularly,
now I am lucky to be in a space where I can do a lot,
I can go a lot of different directions, right?
My space is customer analytics.
Like we've talked about that before
and I can go deep on a lot of places
because it turns out in the software industry,
it turns out a lot of things are about the customer
if you look at it right.
Right, Am.
I'm sorry, a podcast, did you hear my eyes roll on that one?
Did that come across on the microphone?
Anyway, go on, sorry.
What I try to do with this diagram is to go,
okay, let's talk about intrinsic motivators.
What is it that you want to do?
Whether it be work related or not work related,
what is your passion?
What is driving you?
And what subset of those things
can I help you get paid to do?
You said you very clearly enjoyed riding your bike.
Like I remember stories from your college days
where you were a pizza delivery
and I think you said that you did it through bike riding.
No, I was a, I delivered pizza by car
but I was a bicycle messenger.
Oh, bicycle messenger, that's right.
I delivered anything from mail to blood.
Yeah, I mixed up.
I just combined your before Microsoft job history, I think.
So you have an interest in riding bikes.
Well, unfortunately, like if you were to be
a future employee on my team,
I can't yet figure out how your passion there
might be something that I could combine
with a lot of the work that we're doing.
But if I can, I'm gonna tap into it
because I have learned happy people are productive people.
Yes, yes.
And in fact, you and I have arrived
at the exact same destination via different routes.
We were talking about our engagement survey earlier
or as used to be MS Pulse has a new name for you,
MS Insights.
These are measurements of employee engagement.
And I don't care what the survey says,
I want to make sure people are happy about their work.
And then of course, the study from Pat Lanchoni
in The Advantage, finding massive correlation
between a healthy organization
and the quality of the products they deliver,
regardless of the industry, it all ties together.
Our part of our job as managers is to not just get people
to get their work done, it's connect them with their work,
make it important for them
or find the work that's important for them.
And then the good things in the delivery
and the velocity and all the things we want will happen.
My job as a manager is to get to the point
where I do not have to manage, right?
It's essentially, how do I light a fire?
How do I show them that they can achieve
a business impactful goal at the same time
as develop things that they want to do?
Yeah, so this is where, again, I've turned the corner
from us not having a specific goal setting process
before at Unity to where I'm at now thinking,
first thinking it was horrible and now thinking,
you know what, if we use this right,
I can actually do the things I've been trying to do
much more effectively.
It just took me a while to get there
because I had been tainted by some poor goal setting
processes that I've been part of in the past.
I'm not clear on what you're classifying as goals, right?
Because you already have language,
like in your questions,
you already have language around mission.
It's reflection.
The previous questions are more reflecting back.
What is my mission?
What have I done to achieve my mission?
How have I done in achieving my mission?
All I'm doing now is twisting that a little bit forward.
What else, what are the next things I want to accomplish
in order to achieve this mission?
So in goals and in your context,
are they more rallying cries?
Are they more North stars?
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no,
concrete goals.
Let me make up one that's probably,
I could probably just let me get away with it.
I will kick Alan in the shins by end of year.
Here's one.
Here's one for my one I play, I should be safe.
We'll have a pipeline for pseudo localization available
in all of our build pipelines by the end of Q3.
Okay.
That's probably too much jargon.
My team will reduce test time by 25% by the end of Q2.
Okay.
So pretty concrete stuff, not North star.
And I'll, but those goals all require a multitude of things
be done to complete them.
Okay.
Now, is that goal a commitment?
No, it's a goal.
Okay.
So what happens if you don't achieve the goal?
It depends.
Yeah.
See, I think you see where that comes from.
What we can do is we're not,
I'm not going to wait till the end of Q2 to go,
did you hit it?
Did you not hit it?
Okay.
Here's your grade.
We'll have a discussion regularly and maybe it's Q3.
I'm making up stuff here,
but we're going to have a regular check-in.
How's this going?
What are the next things you need to accomplish?
I have traditionally done OKRs with my team
without telling them they're doing OKRs
because once they know they're doing OKRs,
it gets all messed up and I have experience of this.
So I'll approach it very similarly.
Although these aren't OKRs to that.
I will ask, we'll check in on it.
What are the top priorities for this goal for next week?
What's coming up over the next month or so?
That's the check-in on it.
And if you're not achieving it
because you're getting distracted
or just leave the OKRs out,
if you're not achieving it because you're distracted
or you didn't feel like doing it
or you've become disengaged on it
or you made a big mistake in the wrong direction
and that was preventable
or maybe you went and did something I asked you not to do.
For whatever reason,
those things are a different sort of feedback than
we did all the right things.
It ended up being, that last 5%
ended up being much harder than we thought.
That's what I mean by it depends.
So we're going to talk about,
the difference is we're not going to wait
till the end of the time bound to bring it up.
OK, here's your deadline for this goal.
How did it go?
It gives us a framing for ongoing conversations
which are going to provide opportunities
for feedback and coaching.
Yeah, so my...
So I kind of don't care if you hit the goal or not.
What I care is we can have meaningful conversations
about doing the work you've committed,
use your word, you've committed or set out to do.
Yeah, sorry, you were going to say something.
I got to say it.
Yeah, so I understand
what you described at the beginning of the conversation
as, I'll just reframe as anxiety
or frustrated or upset in some regards.
Because I'm just like,
oh my God, that is a slippery slope
to just death spiral doom.
And I must do everything to avoid it.
Like I'm vicariously living that emotion through...
And that's what happened at Microsoft.
It got, it would get to be a month before goal time.
And you would screw your teammates in the back
with an iron spike just to make sure
you got your stuff done you committed to.
I care a lot less if you've reached your goal or not.
Because what I also want,
what I want to reward you on is not just impact,
but what I'm going to pay attention to
and we're going to get feedback throughout this thing
is the way in which you accomplish those goals.
If you are doing it in a way
that's leaving bodies in the wake,
that's going to have an effect
on how I'm going to evaluate you.
If you're doing it in a way that's inclusive
and involving other people and showing respect
and listening to everyone's ideas
and you're rocking out of the park,
I am going to rock you out of the park with a pay raise.
Yeah, I don't like,
I don't like directly connecting those goals.
Not connecting the goals,
I'm connecting the outcomes
and the way in which you achieve the outcomes.
Yeah, so let me, oh, so many things.
So we do have OQRs here at Microsoft,
but OQRs are never,
at least they haven't been in my team
or in my manager's team.
They're not specifically in anybody's commitments.
No, no, no, no, and I am against,
I mentioned the model, it's kind of like that,
but I would never use an OQR for personal goals.
No, an OQR serves a valuable purpose,
but it serves the purpose around a rallying cry
for a virtual team.
And here's where people get stuck and screwed up
on OQRs for quick tangent.
OQR is done right, as you mentioned, rallying cry.
They are a massively valuable tool for alignment.
Yes.
People try and use them like scorecards
and they're just,
Yes, also yes.
Although you just,
I'm thinking 99% of all the sentences
that you could ever say,
they can include the word scorecard,
I'm going to be against.
As an aside, there's one of my meetings
where I've instituted a drinking game,
which is tough because it's an 8am meeting,
but every time someone says,
we should build a dashboard for that,
I faux slam a shot.
Ha ha ha ha ha.
Yeah, you know, it's been a while since we've,
we had our own version of that on the podcast.
Like we've said this before.
Yeah.
All right, now,
so I'm energized by this conversation
because I'm just like, oh my God,
no, yes, no, yes, no, no.
Like for me,
I was also thinking through one of the reasons why,
so it's, for me,
goals of that nature,
like Q2, right?
I don't even communicate them as goals.
I want to make sure people are understand, no.
As it stands right now,
it is, that is my plan, okay?
But it's not a goal,
it's my plan.
I'm okay with that.
And I softened that communication
because of my, because again,
the business that I'm in,
and I can explain why that's important.
Number one,
number two is my training on Kanban.
Kanban has really said,
look, no, what I rather do
is start funding
the highest ROI thing
when I have idle people on my team.
Like whatever is not yet started,
I want to start those things that have the highest ROI
and it may not be this pipeline
that handles all localized languages, right?
It may, and it may never be that.
Right, that's a good goal.
This goes back to the first thing I said was it's hard.
If you get too specific and things change,
or priorities change,
then that goal is like,
oh, I didn't do this goal, what happened?
So I like the idea of thinking of them as plans
and not goals.
So that's a nugget I like,
because it takes care of that trap.
Now it allows you to be specific to a point.
If you know it's a plan
and you know that plans can change.
And if the plan has to be committed,
then I have an even bigger problem
because like as most of our listeners know,
I am an Azure, Azure is a service.
And a lot of big design upfront
just does not make sense in this space.
It just does not.
We have to be adaptable and failing to be adaptable.
We end up being interrupt driven then
because there are higher priority things,
higher urgency things that are constantly coming in.
Well, again, again, going back to why I wanna check in
on these frequently, super frequently
is so that we can deliver frequently, super frequently.
I don't want someone to say,
here's my goal for the end of QTQ3.
And mine are made up of it
and my people are listening slightly.
But I don't want you to just deliver the whole thing
at once and say, okay, done.
What we're gonna talk about
as we look at these, like,
what's the minimum first step?
What's our MVP?
What do we need to do?
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah, absolutely.
So absolutely using that.
And I'm stealing stuff from your combine.
We get to a stage where like your combine question is,
I think, tell me if I'm wrong,
what work is remaining to complete this task?
I can use a variation of that
to check as a method of checking in on these plans.
Oh, you're talking about, yeah.
What work is remaining to move this ticket,
one column to the right?
Oh, right, right.
What needs to be done, right?
That's exactly right.
But that framing could work for these plans as well.
Right, but the other thing too,
the problem is, so that question works very well
for sort of tactical work, right?
When you talk about sort of goals or strategies, okay,
I actually changed the question.
I basically say, I am now at a point,
so do you remember the pivot or persevere conversation?
Oh, yeah, yeah.
It from-
Yeah, I agree, Chapter 8.
So now in a strategic sense,
I say what work remains
so that we can have a pivot or persevere discussion.
And that pivot or persevere discussion
is part of that plan.
And it may change the goal.
That's fair, that's fair.
And another thing I've been very clear about
is these things not being written in stone.
I want to encourage my team to discard
or change these goals as needed as we get more context.
Absolutely.
I like adding pivot or persevere to that discussion as well.
Up to and including abandon the goal.
Yeah, absolutely.
I tell my team, look,
when you write this goal, like number one,
if anyone on my team said something like what you did,
like your pipeline by the end of Q3,
I would have just, I'm like, no, okay.
Don't put the Q3 part, right?
I get what you're trying to say, okay?
But you're locking yourself into something
that may be abandoned, right?
Just saying remove,
I don't mind having the time bound bit on there,
but you're saying remove that.
I just don't think it's realistic.
That's fair.
But that's in my business, right?
In what my team operates on on a day-to-day basis,
because I'm just like, oh.
On the other hand,
it comes with psychological safety as well
because they may say this thing for Q2 or Q3 or Q4.
And if they miss that date,
again, it's the impact outcome,
the way in which they accomplish that.
They still need to,
they're stakeholders that may need these things
and practicing commitment
and doing so in a safe manner.
If they miss a date, I'm not gonna get mad.
I'm not gonna change their pay for missing in most cases.
Depends on their effort and how they got there.
But I wanna give them,
there's a short story, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
I want it to be safe for them
to fail in achieving their plans.
So it's okay if they have a date
because it's a plan.
It's a guess.
And you know, we do P50.
In fact, we do P50 estimates on our work items.
I would say we have P50 estimates
on our goals slash plans as well.
I will say I not only want them to feel safe.
I'm, so my statement,
I'm trying to do it a clear fashion,
but my statement is a little bit more aggressive than yours.
So I do want them to feel safe to fail.
I want them to feel morally obligated,
business obligated, investor,
like something along those lines.
I want them to feel obligated
that if this goal is to fail,
to fail it as fast as f'ing possible, right?
It's, I don't want you onion peeling for six months
and then then going, oh, well, my time's up.
I failed.
But again, again, I'm not gonna, it's, I think,
I think we're far more likely to be in agreement here.
We are.
This goes back to the point I made about checking in on like,
what's the logical next step?
If there are no, if they're going for a big bang delivery
at the end, that's gonna get some feedback right away.
Right.
I guess as long as we're making progress,
like what's the next step?
What's the, yeah, what's the next step?
What's the next bit of value we add?
I guess we can have that conversation.
It might take some practice.
I think, I think I'm okay with the dates,
but I can now see why you wouldn't have that.
Again, it's gonna take some coaching to get there
to make sure because.
I actually think you could take this and combine it.
Okay. With what?
With our two philosophical ideologies.
Come take what we talked about in terms of the goals
and then combine it with the three questions.
So let's imagine one of your reports had this goal
and it's two weeks into something that's six months out.
Right.
I think it's important that you continuously check in
on those goals and say, all right,
what evidence do you have that your mission,
that this goal is still important?
Like I'll say from my point of view,
one of the biggest things that,
one of the biggest speeches,
I am delivering to leaders throughout the company
because I'm getting called in to sort of collaborate
as well as advise on multiple different projects now.
And this one team came to me
and then I talked to their leader yesterday,
or at night, talked to them last week
and talked to the leader above the set of group.
And I said, you have a real big problem.
And I said, your team is not,
they're busily going and doing something equivalent.
Like I will build this pipeline for localization
or I forget what you said, but it's a great example.
And I said, your team is not addressing
the very first and basic question.
Why does the business care?
Why do we care?
So what?
You did this.
How would this have been-
We have that as part of the goal setting
or plan setting session,
but I think what we can do as we go forward
is ask questions like,
is this still the highest priority for your team?
Well, you don't wanna start and then stop, right?
But it's, do we still,
with the best available information,
do we still expect to get the return
from this investment?
It's gonna be contextual on all these,
but I think there are,
I guess the short story is,
as long as we talk about these things regularly,
and I remember at Microsoft,
we would not look at these often
until the week before our connect,
we go, oh, shit, I said I'd do that.
Huh, wonder what I did there.
And so I like the idea of getting some plan,
get people used to setting some plans or goals,
reviewing them often,
figuring out what works and doesn't work,
both as far as goal setting and feedback
and trying all these things is all really powerful.
And I guess the revelation I'm trying to share here
is I went from, oh God,
not a performance management system,
to, oh my God,
why didn't we have a performance management system?
It took me several months to get there
and a lot of reflection and a lot of thinking
and a lot of just kinda typing away,
trying to come up with a model that works.
And it sounds like from bouncing it off of you,
that we're aligned and it sounds like you've made it work,
so I'm feeling more like in a different model
that this should work,
but it's not gonna be easy,
it's gonna take effort.
The issue is, what are you managing
with the performance management system?
And-
See, that's the part I don't like thinking of it,
like a performance management system,
because it is, to me,
it's a guideline,
it's a method to achieve business impactful outcomes,
which I want to reward on,
I don't want to reward on the stuff we put into the tool.
If it can be framed as an employee growth-
Yeah, that's how I'm framing it for my work.
I don't even like the word management.
No, I don't use that either.
What did you call-
I like how I refer to it as,
we're gonna use it as a growth framework.
Right, if it's a growth framework, I'm all aboard.
To me, the second you add in the word management-
Nope, not adding that word.
Right, it's command-
It was unveiled as a performance management system,
which hit my, I triggered, made my blood boil,
but now that I've embraced it
and looked inside the guts of it
and kind of made it what I think it can be,
it's a growth framework and that's how I'm gonna use it
and it's gonna be effective.
So for me, summarizing, I think goals are great as long
because I think it's important for an individual
have a sense of where they wanna go.
I do think that it's also important
to sort of train into that individual
and evaluation of what's gonna be the investment costs
and what is gonna be the expected return
and have an idea around the return.
Failing to do the return stuff, by the way,
is how you get all of these, build it
and they will come, science fair problems.
Feel the dreams, bull crap, yeah.
Right, and well, so hey, I spent six months doing this,
now I'm gonna spend the next six months
setting up roadshow meetings
and see if I can get anyone to care.
Nah, no, no, no, that's, again,
what I like about this is more chance
to check in frequently on how those things are going
to make sure none of those traps are falling into.
And then again, my directs won't do that,
but I don't think, but in modeling that,
as this cascades down, they can catch those things as well.
I think we can actually get,
I think good things are gonna happen,
but you know, I'll keep you all posted.
Sweet. Sweet, man.
All right, well, that other topic,
we're gonna do that next time.
Good.
Because we, this was fun,
thank you for this conversation.
I didn't know if you'd be as interested in it as I was,
but you were, and I appreciate that.
I am all about this stuff, right?
So we've talked about it on the,
like the Kanban method that I've kind of modified, right?
It's all about teamwork,
and teamwork takes people,
and you need those people to be engaged.
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes.
And this is, that is what I want to do.
I want people, and this is getting harder
two years into this pandemic thing, but yeah, all on board.
All right, man, I gotta run, I gotta go,
but this has been a fun Friday.
Thanks for being part of episode,
let me look at my recorder here.
158.
158 of the A.B. testing podcast,
which was way better than 157.
And then if you wanna go back, listen to 57,
you're welcome to, but don't.
Anyway, I am Alan.
I'm Brent.
We'll see you next time.
Bye.
Wack-a-no-n-