Because now it's more martial arts. It's not boxing, right?
It's not like who can punch each other in the head the hardest
It is can you use the momentum of the people around you to be able to achieve the effect you're looking for?
Welcome to a be testing podcast your modern testing podcast
Your hosts Alan and Brent will be here to guide you through topics on testing
Leadership agile and anything else that comes to mind now on with the show
Everyone welcome to episode 182 of the a be testing podcast
Brent is I mean, I can't even see Brent. I think he's lost but we do have Brian Pulliam here. Say hi Brian. Hey
And oh, there's Brent Brent just came in he was shoveling out the barn. Hey Brent, how's it going? Hey
Yeah, so I hear I'm
I'm on today to interview my replacement. Is that right?
The B does stand for Brent and the B could stand for Brian. So yeah, we're doing a trial run here. Okay
Actually, there's a reason I wanted to have Brian here and it goes back to I don't know
I think you maybe you can
Brian we all worked at Mike Brent still of Microsoft. I left Microsoft seven years ago
I think Brian left before then and we'll get into all that if needed or not
We have no plan here
But Brian can you refresh me and our listeners more because I remember most of it on how like how did we cross paths?
Yeah, so
Let's see. Wow. I worked at Microsoft for about nine years. I actually got hired
They say they hired me as a PM
But my my FTE sponsor at the time for my contract work needed an analyst
But he couldn't get a budget for an analyst. So I heard an analytics PM, which was no PM work whatsoever
They just basically straight up lied to get the right person in the role
So I joined as an analyst and I learned how to be a PM at Microsoft
Not a bad place Nathan Mira vault having come up with what that role means
originally and I worked with in a group called engineering excellence, which had a lot to do with a rotational effort to
Understand what it meant to be a really good tester or a really good PM or a really good engineer and then rotate back
into the product works and bring what you've learned back to
office Azure
and name any other big orgs you'd like so there I I
found a close friend in the name of Paul God who was a big test champion and
he since moved on to Zillow and a few other places, but
we got to talking about product quality and
Then your book how we test that Microsoft came up and so ever since then I've sort of had that your name in the
Back of my head and I stumbled across to find out that you live in the same city
I do we live like a half mile from each other
Yeah, we've walked to like what 10 minutes each way to get to a coffee shop or at least I drove it was raining
Drove he probably would have got there faster if he walked but that's fine. So
Good so I'm looking at this like you met outside of EE we know we I think we just barely
Didn't cross paths. I think I may be left as he was coming in. Yeah
So it never we never met while we were at Microsoft. In fact, we didn't meet until probably what like a month ago
Yeah, something like that
but Alan having had a background in
Microsoft and in games and me having started out my professional career as a game developer
There were too many commonalities to not reach out to Alan for a coffee chat
Having him having worked at Unity me having worked in children software at a small company called humongous entertainment that melon made
Children's games and one thing you didn't call out that I and this is what other good connection
there's a data analyst part Brent's going ooh interesting and
but
You know everyone knows I thought everyone knows I shouldn't say that all three listeners probably know I do a blog post every week
And there is one where I talked about the different sort of tests and a big fan of this one from Pat lunch, Yoni called
Working genius. I've also done strengths finders and Brian knows a lot about strengths finders
I thought oh, you know who else I know who loves strengths finders. It's Bert. Jertson
This well, I don't know who that guy is
But you know three then Alan
Yeah, and to be clear I would be very clear
I am NOT against strengths finders and actually Brian walked me through I took the test again
He gave me a key to take it and results are slightly different than before but you know in the same ballpark
And I've evolved it's been 10 years since I took it
So not not a non van
But I thought it'd be cool to maybe have you two talk about strengths finders a little bit because I know Brent Brent's a big fan
It sounds like we're gonna be singing to the choir. I've said this on this before my view is strengths
it's got all the
The mystical
psychotyping of things like Myers Briggs
But it's actually useful
Actionable and something you can develop and grow in so for example
My number one strength is ideator
But that's my top one
That's why you drive me crazy. No, it's actually
The ideator is I would say one place where we where we
Connect on the the problem is is every strength is also
Perceived by others as your biggest weakness sure right right my me beam ideator. That's actually the place where
my my
Tangentation comes from if I can
Be invited to invent a word
It's because I see
So a lot of people who don't have ideation will view me as constantly having my head in the clouds right
whereas I
go
well
It's it's actually the same thing
So Alan back in the day when we predicted the the beginning of the end for test
I had people come up to me and go wow that was really
As if I was like a prophet and dreamed it and whatever and I'm like no
I just saw how things were connected and I saw the momentum and I saw that
Yeah, unless something changes and I don't see anything in
The way to do that change the momentum is in this direction
This is an obvious conclusion as we've also talked before I kind of feel the same way around what's happening around in the AI space
Brian butts so I feel listeners as I was talking Brian was doing all sorts of positive body language like thumbs up like oh wow
I'll interpret it as someone who can at least pretend to know least talking about on this topic
Oh for sure. I will tell you I'll give you my quick spiel
I think the gallon might have heard this already, but
I've been in tech for about 26 years, but it hasn't been in one discipline. I was a TPM for a while was an engineer
I was an EM
Work for Microsoft Zillow Coinbase and other companies, but my most fulfilling role was none of those
my most fulfilling role was this volunteer volleyball coach role with my wife for 13 years and
What really struck me about this is I didn't even want to go the first day
My wife got this job as coach. She and I met playing volleyball
It's kind of like part-time relationship status, and I said why would I ever want to coach like I love playing volleyball
Why would I ever want to help people that are terrible at it get better at it and?
And then after the first season I remember thinking wow if I had three million in the bank
I would probably just do this for the rest of my life until I was physically unable to do it anymore and
Then maybe five minutes later Brent. I said wait a minute
how am I so bad at
interpreting or
Predicting what will make me fulfilled in life if I can go from something
I thought was going to be stupid to it being one of the most fulfilling activities. I've ever had
That freaked me out
I'm like wait do I have to say yes to everything going forward or to all I know I need to go learn a little
Bit more about myself. I need to run this post mortem and figure out why I felt so differently before versus after
And I turned it turns out
I love helping other people succeed, but only when they are excited and committed to their goals so not a teacher
Okay, so I'm guessing you have developer in your top five. I don't anymore. I used to okay mine are strategic
maximizer who
Communication and positivity if that's not a coach. I don't know what is but that's that is 100% a coach
Yeah, yeah, it's it's amazing so I remember or sales or sales could be sales
Yeah, easy to I like influencing other people as long as it's for a good cause so that's great and to the listeners
Yeah, yeah, please translate to English for everyone else
Alan is is
Like I think this episode might just be for Alan because he is busily cracking him home
His own self up so Alan maybe you should share with the audience
We're not doing a live feed today
No, no, no live feed today
But maybe I'll draw some pictures for the show notes. Yeah, the it's interesting like you you mentioned maximizer
I am a restorative. So for for the audience
Maximizer is a strength. They want
I'll put it this way
maximizers can't stand the use of the 80-20 rule like what do you mean 80-20?
I want a hundred right it maximizers
strive for
Perfection one one fact I don't know Brian if you've ever actually done this Gallup has a bunch of really
educational things on on YouTube for each of the strengths and if you have if you have
restorative in your top five
something ungodly like 95 percent chance that
Maximizer is your number 34
Interesting. Yeah, it's someone with restorative is driven to fix broken things
They're good at identifying broken things and they want them fixed, but I'll tell you once it's fixed. I'm good
I don't I don't need to take it the extra 5% that differs from a
Maximizer who's like no wait wait. Why are we stopping? We still got more
So how when you're a maximizer, how are you doing on your investment? I mean, I'm I'm coast fire now
So I guess you could say good. I mean, you know, I work maybe three hours a day
Oh, no, that that that's fantastic. I'm just thinking I'm not a maximizer obviously
Yeah, but I'm wondering do you ever find yourself going? No. No, I'm not gonna sell now. It's gonna go another point
It's gonna go another point. No, not at all. Like okay
philosophically, I have a certain approach to
Money I have now can be used for something that not only is useful for me now
But better for long term and with as much as research I've done
Most people lose money when they make decisions to change where their money is. That's where most people lose their money
so
I'm okay with the Ron Pope you'll sort of set it and forget it approach with you know
call me a boggle head or focused on index funds and I have a year of
Savings set aside kind of guy, you know live within my means. Yeah, I
When it comes to investment, I refuse to accept that I am in my 50s
So I still like oh I totally could make it a killing on that one. Let's go see. Anyway, all right
I will tell you like this I've been grabbed glad you brought up this idea of
What's the flip side of that strength and how other people would be annoyed by it?
Because that is something I think a lot of people
Who are exposed to this originally don't don't see there's a there's the three or four perspectives here. There's
How does it help you in your career?
There's
Given that strength. What does your manager need to know about you and to get the best out of you with that strength?
Sometimes you have to manage up because they don't know this framework
What kind of environment is really good for you like is the team you're on?
Recognize your strength as a currency. Is it even valued there?
And then thirdly like what are those red flags to watch out for?
Because with maximizer, for example, it is
Very much you want to eke out that last bit like I used to work you guys know Bruce Dawson at all like
Don't know that name. Okay. No, so Bruce Dawson
I used to work with Bruce Dawson back in the day in game development and he went on
To go work on very nerdy stuff at Google
But he is like the maximizers maximizer like he's trying to figure out how to optimize the last little bit out of every single thing
So if there was a picture in the dictionary of maximizer, it would be pushed awesome
But with ideation right it is about how do you not come across scatterbrained?
And how do you make sure you're balancing?
Your ideation with execution right because other people will be like when are you actually going to do something?
Rather than just spout these ideas but with the restorative they help balance each other out, right?
So you you get sort of more of the centrist approach where you don't have to worry about it as much if I didn't have
Restorative and I did have ideation. I don't even know that we would be having this conversation
Yeah, right it the the other problem with people
With with ideation so think of it from like an architectural those who are good at identifying
better ways of doing thing
Suddenly lose interest in how we're doing it now, right? This is the common phenomenon with with a lot of architects like segue
they they invented a but I think is a brilliant strategy and that is
Run your your v1 project sort of partially shifted with your v2 project
That way once your your v1 project is halfway done you start funneling off your your architects
On to v2 and let them go ahead and start ideating for v2
But then you have your closers working on the v1 and I'm like, oh, that's freaking
Beautiful. Everybody's happy
Yeah, the the product ships on time because when again one of the flaws with architects is that?
We're really good at coming up with a better way of doing it
And if we get the power to stop ship we will because it's better. Let's do it this way
This is smarter and then because we continuously do that will never actually ship that has been
Without my wrist even with my restorative at times that that has been a struggle
But I learned early on how to balance it
Yeah, you said maximizer what else were yours Oh strategic maximizer
whoo
communication and positivity Oh
Yeah with those strengths
I'll just tell you straight up
Having someone on my team with those strengths because my team is all data scientists
Right. I remember one of the best employees I ever had in one regard
And I'm thinking through if it was the best because he really complimented the team
He had communication and it was his number one and he would send status reports
I one day I was I just tried to experiment, you know what? I'm gonna have him. I hate writing the status reports
I find them a waste of my time
I hate writing in general because one of my strengths is analytical
So I will literally spend a half hour looking at the same sentence and judging every possible way
Whether you combine and restorative and I'll go no that's broken. I got a rephrase it this way. No, that's it's torturous
I hate it. Whereas I live in the moment. We'll talk about that in a minute
Alan Alan I'm amazed at Ellen when he and I've commented on just different skills, man
It's it's different skills different talents. I had him take over my status report
now number one
He loved it. Right? This is the first thing to learn about strengths. I don't have communication
He does so I go to him and go and I I really can't ask my employee to do this thing that I guess to me
Status report and pain like there is no there's it's a perfect Union
It's it's complete intersection. No, not only did he love it. I had people
Asked to subscribe to my status reports never had that before ever
Like are you serious? Right? It's this is what I like about both strengths finders and working genius
In a little bit different, but it's actually two things I like and what I want to talk about
But what you just said is if you understand how they work
you understand how to actually maximize and play that jigsaw Pete puzzle maker or conductor of a team and
Leverage each other's strengths working genius. I could go deep into that
But it's the same sort of thing
It says some people are you're good at two of the six of these things wonder invention discernment galvanizing enablement or trinasty
and
there's two things probably in there you kind of hate and if you things you're kind of in the middle and if you
understand that different people are good at different parts of this
Of going from an idea or wondering what can be done to actually getting it done
You can orchestrate your team that way the other thing that's interesting and brain
I haven't gone over this with you
I'd love to get your feedback on it and Brian are gate already gave me a walkthrough so he can give me add some
certificate commentary as well, but is they both can if they can change
Yeah, I
Myers Briggs based on the work of Carl Jung and says it's to you are it's not gonna change you can adapt but
And it's a little horoscope and I like it I can read mine and go yeah, that's pretty much me but these are much more
applicable and
Here's the thing brain. You've known me since the first time I took it
You know what I was doing and then in my I've evolved and I've I found other things
I like doing more and I'm better at I took it last time. I was basically an IC
building tools on Xbox
Lots of influence involved that back then I was in order strategic learner
Achiever
analytical
Intellection ten years ago. Okay, maybe 12 years ago
today, I'm
strategic still
Relator because I'm I've I've become a stupid VP and I have to have to relate
Arranger, which I actually love it's the favorite part of my job or like
Seeing what can like putting all the pieces together. Look here's the pieces I have okay here and here and here
It's like cooking. It's fun
adaptability
and
Intellection so I'm just kind of curious maybe for you like I missed one
Strategic Relator arranger adaptability
Intellection are my nose. Okay, my old ones here
strategic learner
achiever
analytical
Intellection and probably if we went down and got my top ten, they probably have much more overlap
So Brent just maybe starting with actually starting for either one of you like
one am I correct in my interpretation that these can change over time and
As you grow and change there, there's no so Gallup
So the nice thing about Gallup doing this they have over 50 years of like stats on this one, right?
There's no evidence that these are are
permanent and even Carl Jung mentioned not Meyers that everyone calls it Meyers Briggs, but it's actually Carl Jung
They did it and it's his psychotyping. Yeah, he wrongly stated that it's it's
Permanent but even recent things show no. No, it's actually very common
For example traumatic events will change your change your psychotype. I will tell you I experienced this myself
I'm not gonna go into details in the traumatic event 30 years ago. I was intj and now I am intp
I am a strong P and previously I was a strong J
Didn't have much of effect obviously on the other three letters, but that one massive
Impact and totally makes sense in terms of you like I could see this all makes sense to me
right except maybe a
ranger
In terms of my knowledge of you relater. Yeah, I totally see that one
At the when you left Microsoft like literally the episodes I
Bet you we even recorded it because you were nervous because the majority of the time I knew you at at Microsoft
It was hell. No, I will never friggin be a manager and I want to get Brian's take on this thing
But and that reason was at the time remember this is I did not want to be a manager not couldn't like managing people
frequently thought of being a manager being a manager at Microsoft in the
2010s kind of sucked
These have changed because I've actually really enjoyed leading large teams and the challenges go on with that different set of challenges and I faced
in the old days
Anyway, Brian curious on your thoughts on my evolution, you know, you didn't know me back
Yeah thoughts on my evolution. I will say this
I think I don't you know, I didn't ask Brent this question
But I think I've probably taken about a hundred and five people through StrengthsFinder so far
So I've done it a bit and one of the reasons why I found it
So natural for me was when I became a leader
The only thing I could look back on for a foundation was athletics coaching. I'm like, okay
We here's a group of people we're trying to work together. We're trying to achieve something
It's hard and I remembered saying well, I need to use this strength spaced approach in the workplace
I might as well try it. This is what I know and it worked really well and it worked so well
I started asking other people like hey, why do you do it this way?
Like here I have like two years of experience as a manager and
Yet my didn't realize how much of my coaching experience would apply in the workplace
But what I didn't have were stats, right?
I didn't have stats that were meaningful in the workplace to say Alan should do this job or Alan would be good as a TPM
If he's unhappy being a back-end engineer and here's why
So if he wants to consider that discipline change, we should talk about it
But when I found gallup StrengthsFinder, I said aha, this is the conceptual thing I was missing
That is domain agnostic, but tells me what Alan will be good at it or Brent is good at
so now when I look at your transition those new strengths that got added there were later and the
Arranger and there was one other that was new. What was that a third one a cheever?
Cheever was there before I think? Oh, no, no adaptability
The old one sorry, yeah, so I mean it doesn't surprise me either
You know you get to a point where what you can accomplish by yourself
Is now a small fraction of what you're expected to accomplish in your role, right? You start off
What what's the analogy I use for early career people, you know, you become an engineer or tester
It's like baking a cake with a recipe like here's the ingredients. Here's the recipe now
Go bake a cake and I'm gonna turn around and make sure you don't burn down the kitchen and don't swap the sugar for flour
Cuz it's a bad idea. Yes, they're both white. Yes, they're both kind of look like powdery substances
But don't swap them and then you get better and now I care about what you think not just about what you know
But I want your opinion on things right when you become a senior
But at some point around senior when people need to make that transition to what to staff or principal depending on the company you're at
this
You need to develop these skills or focus on how do you bring other people along for the ride because it's now no longer
Whether you're the smartest or you're the loudest or you're the most successful person in the room because the projects are too complex
To be able to get it across the line if you can't relate with somebody right or you can't adapt
And so I don't think it's a surprise at all
to say as you advance
higher in leadership and the larger percentage of your work is
Dealing with peers that you don't really have a lot of authority over you have to relate to them
It's the only way you're gonna convince them that to make a to make a compromise, right?
Or or you're the one that has to make the compromise
So you have to be adaptable because now it's more martial arts. It's not boxing, right?
It's not like who can punch each other in the head the hardest it is
Can you use the momentum of the people around you to be able to achieve the effect you're looking for one thing?
I'd like to hear more about and maybe bring you off some stuff here, too
But like you mentioned you brought over a hundred people through this and help them
What often happens with these tests is is people take them they go. Oh like me like you
This is me as an example. I go. Oh
Interesting. Wow. I like this. This is really fun and then ever do anything with it. So
What advice do you have for managers on let's say let's say I put all of my directs through it
Again, not knowing their results. What would be my approach to look at that stuff?
Do I put them in different jobs? Do I what's like the quick managers guide to using this to?
To improve myself on my team the directs that I've had every direct I've had has gone through this
I made it a point in our one-on-one document
Right like a Google Doc or shared doc or whatever to have the strengths at the top of the one-on-one doc
So every time we open it we see it like so we're using process to visually remind us and there's a lot of engineers that
Don't do great with verbal cognition to begin with right? They either have ADHD and attentive like I do or
They subconsciously got into coding because they could see it. They didn't have to remember things because they could look at them all day long
so
Re-engaging the visual preference that a lot of people in software
Have is the good first start put it at the top as a visual reminder every time. So that's number one to I
Have discussions with my directs and say hey these strengths are like tools in your tool belt
so when we talk about the projects you're gonna go on to or a situation at work the
Manager's got to reinforce that well. What are your tools in your tool belt again? I'm asking them. Oh, I'm really good at this and that
Really? How might you use those strengths in this scenario, right? It's a coaching question
It's open-ended and and then thirdly
I'm a big believer in having an entire team
Like you said Alan take strengths finder and then I create like a matrix and it's basically got all the strengths as rows
The people as columns and I sort it by most overlapping strength to most unique strengths like in this spreadsheet
And the idea is the top four or five that are up there are like the social norms of the team, right?
They are the cultural norms that people should expect when they join this team new employee joins
I show them this and I say hey this team really loves research right or this team really loves solving problems
This team really loves strategic thinking
But there are some people at the bottom here who have strengths that nobody else has and you need to know who those people
Are because if you need help with X
There's one person on the team that has that superpower and that's Sally or that's Sarah
And so it becomes a means of onboarding
But it also gives and unlocks capabilities for peer mentoring that didn't exist before
Because the granularity in strengths finder is so high when you talk about
34 choose 5 right that's a lot of combinations the odds you have somebody on the team that's identical to you is very very small
So use always something you can learn from other people and this helps
Provide a roadmap for that
That's that's great advice and I just want to point out because people that are not watching the video feed that doesn't exist Brent is in love
Yeah, yeah
There's there's definitely a bromance
Potential here a couple of things that Brian said it cracked me up because I'm like yeah
I could I could share my version of that right now
We've all shared our five online except me
So I'll go through that quickly and I and then I want Brian to analyze you
Yeah
I was good just I was going to to set that stage and then I want to answer your question
And there's another question that I want to weigh in on as well
ideation number one
relater
individualization
restorative analytical now my
question to Brian
given
Individualization what do you think I do with strike fighters? Well, let's see if you're an individualization
Strength you're intrigued with this unique qualities of each person if I am prime customer. Sorry, go on, right?
Yeah
You know if I was your manager
Then I would ask if you want to get deeply involved with matching people to projects because you're probably a good judge of each individual
Strengths and their weaknesses which is probably going to optimize the org's productivity
I'm probably gonna ask you if you want to teach internal training classes or mentor new employees
Because you're likely gonna spot how each person learns differently. Yep. I would say I don't like the teaching idea, but I love mentoring
Yeah, yeah, it kind of depends on the person right? No, no getting at the strength like in in its isolation
We have to combine it with the rather ones. Right?
I was gonna say and you would have realized that once you combined it with relater, right? Right and
and
given that
You know your ideal environment is definitely one where you don't have leaders that think that every dev is fungible, right?
You don't philosophically you're not a believer that I can take any dev and put them on any project because that kind of goes against
What you're thinking about from individualization perspective
So you don't you don't want to work where you have a leader that's like we need to hit this target
Like how many warm bodies like even the phrase warm bodies, you know
We're butts and seats are things that you want to steer clear of because that's it often not your ideal environment
Those are trigger words for yeah. Yeah
Yep, and then thirdly, you know because I work with a lot of clients trying to find to find jobs
There's a set of questions that I usually suggest people ask in the interview to help suss out whether or not
Individualization is a strength that this team that's hiring a position for
Would would find value in right and you would try to ask sort of balancing question
Let's say you're behind schedule on a project and you can take three people that don't understand the code base
But they're immediately available and they'll have to ramp up or you have one person you can apply to it
But it means you're not gonna hate your deadline. What do you do?
What I would look for is a leader that's like well
I'm gonna take the person who's the expert and put them on this team because those three people are likely gonna create
More bugs along the way and I'd rather be a little bit over the deadline
With someone who doesn't require a lot of ramp up. So I think I so in your example
I think I would actually I think I would far more
Be far more likely to actually take the three not because of the heartbeats
because more of my perspective on diversity and inclusion
Because I believe that with three I'm gonna get more rounded across the 34 on strengths and I do actually almost literally think in
This way. Okay. Now, how quickly can I understand these guys and get them working as a team towards a positive direction and work in the
The appropriate training as they go along like you did an excellent job there much of the things
I thought you were gonna go into like you can look at those strengths and see why
For a big part of my career people would say Britt. You should not be a manager. You should be a
Architect I got that for a large portion of my career
But if you look in my view correctly at these strengths you go. No, that's a mistake
This is not a guy. This is a guy that I don't like being an IC. I
Don't like being a manager of managers. I
love being a frontline manager and
With my understanding of strengths and I'm sure Brian you you you see the same thing that makes sense
Yeah, it makes total sense. You know if you have one of these top fives in execution
That's about as far away from execution as you can get without feeling like you don't get to solve
Those type of problems right restorative like there's a fingerprint to the top five
Where I play this game and I say guess what my job title is based on the top five strengths
And it doesn't mean that's the job they have but oftentimes people feel like their job is off
We do this exercise and I say, you know that fingerprint
It doesn't look like the title you've got and I wonder if that's
Supporting evidence for something for you to consider like a transition at some point
I would say I'm surprised someone said don't be a manager Brent, you know when you've got
This individualization and relater you've got two of these relationship building
strengths in your top five
Engineers on average you don't have that you know
I'd say 90% of engineers end up with what two of their top five in execution
Maybe one or two in strategic thinking and then the last one is you know
What it's either an influencing a relationship and that's kind of the footprint the way I would describe the scenario
Now looking back is that the people who made that feedback?
right number one this was
This is like the first 10 years of the career and strengths have been around a lot longer than that
But I didn't have visibility to it till I don't know last 15 years
So I didn't have the knowledge
But if you look at the strengths that there are certain things that people see
Though the see outside in even though they don't know the language for me being an idea guy
I got that all of the time me being effective at fixing broken things and being highly analytical
They saw that all the time
They didn't see the other things because they were outside looking in
The other aspect is looking back at least two of the people that I that said this
I'm fairly certain were activators
Okay, and and for the for our audience an activator is someone with with
It's a it's an awesome strength. It basically means they need very little data if any at all
to make a high confidence decision the risk of an activator is
They can make bad decisions. But what they do is they they they really drive
This energy around Ellen my answer to your question
Where they don't make sense right? You're an introvert
And you're now put in a job where you you
Do more?
people
Work, okay
There's no way for you to avoid talking to people as much it maybe it was when you were in I see
When we talk about the strengths like why do they change? I'll go back to that question. Here's an observation I
Have done and and I have done actually several at this point in time
I think I'm I may not be as high as you
But I have done at least triple digits on these ones and I if you print out all
34 was one exercise that I find fascinating and that is
Like Gallup does the top five and they do a sort of a simplification effect
but if you print all the top four what I find to be an education or 34, sorry an
educational exercise is
Go down from the top and then write a line
Where where you where you feel?
That you are not using this on a daily basis
Right. So for me, I know I use my top six on a daily basis and my number six is responsibility
I know I use my top six on a daily basis
Then then make a new line where you go
You know what?
I've noticed that I can keep going down and I go I use these ones on a weekly basis
Command is for example my number 10 and I have to go to command mode
At least once a week, but I don't do it daily
Then you could also go monthly and then there's some of them like you just like straight up like for me Maximizer
I literally never do or if I do it is so freakin rare
I might as well say literally never do and if you think about that
Right, if you go into a new role, it would make sense
That you're gonna go down your strength preference and then going
Oh, I'm in a new role where where I have to use this not weekly but daily and as you practice that because they're not
these are
The the Gallup company will refer to them as what they are identifying here is your top
Inherent talents and so they're developable
Developable I'm not certain that's the word you can you can train in it the resources that that I mentioned on Gallup
I went there for ideation and they talk about
Okay
How do you know if you're overdoing it?
What to do about it?
How do you know if you're underdeveloped in your ideation and what are things to do?
Alan and I we spent a lot of time talking about Johnson on here
right Johnson from my point of view is a guy that is
Formerly teaching you how ideation works and how to take advantage of it
This is Steven Johnson author of where good ideas come from
Okay, and and the other thing that's fascinating if you go and look at if you go and look at
the Gallup stats
Anyone can can get better in any of these strengths
But if if it's high in your natural talent list you developing in this
You'll see they claim a ten times productivity boost because you're naturally inclined anyway
They're just formalizing the things that that instinctively you already understand
design patterns fits within
analytical and restorative in ideation and up until before I learned design patterns
I kind of designed that way
But I didn't know why and what it was then when I learned that I'm like whoa and suddenly I had a huge boost in
In my coding Alan for me. I totally get why relater is there?
I kind of would have expect something more and I'm bringing out my cheat sheet
Yeah, was there any influencing strengths on there? Yeah, that's what I was looking at I don't see
None. No, it is fascinating that achiever was there both times because it really is just summarizes the story Brent just said right
You know if you are if achievers in your top five, so you care about doing a really good job and having a high impact
What are you gonna do you are gonna run experiments subconsciously on what skills are?
Working well in your new role, right? You're gonna AB test this right?
You're gonna have control treatment right and then you're gonna try something that works well
And you're gonna say I'm gonna dig deeper on that right and so it's not surprising to me that those with achiever
Will start to develop their strengths to a point where their top five might evolve when their roles change over time
Yeah, I was just looking at it at the same the same pivot that
Brian was just mentioning in execution you have a ranger
who the way I summarize a ranger is
They take joy at getting large numbers of other people to do their job for them
What's interesting with me is that?
Influencing doesn't even show up in my top ten. Oh
Really that is pretty common in tech like I I've had a number of people take it
Generally speaking that the results skew a little bit more towards
Executing and strategic thinking as the top two themes and if I recall correctly
I didn't write it down, but if I recall correctly you have three and influencing Brian
Yeah, which is why you know, which is why I did well as a PM, right?
I come into Microsoft as an analyst and then I take this career builder cuz you know
L&D offers it and like the bottom thing on the survey is like project manager and I'm like, wait a minute
I got a PM and the project managers like it's a hundred and thirty fourth
It's like literally like the last job title they suggest for me, but I'm like, wait a minute
Is PM a project manager in this case? And I was like, no, not really like if you could
Design a role where you need to influence without authority, right?
Then it is this PM role at Microsoft is why I enjoyed it while I did it
Yeah, that's the yeah, that's the the influencing skill the way I describe
So Alan the way you can think of it, right is it's almost like with Myers Briggs
Executing if you were if you were to think of executing as
Getting tasks done you can think of strategic thinking about getting thoughts done. So it is and the way I
think this works is obviously people that work with me know I I
Have you would say I have influence I'm able to get people to change
But I don't do it through the traditional influencing skills
I'm I'm heavy on strategic
Heavy strategic thinking, you know relations and executing I do it by
Getting I did it to it by getting stuff done
Here's an example. I was talking to a team today about how we're gonna do a migration and
It isn't about going to convince a team like this is how you do it and get them all bought on board and and
And doing the influencing part of that I do it via execution. We're gonna hand hold the team through
Initial migration or get some learning from that
When we're going to
From there, we're gonna get some documentation in place
So another team can try and follow that while it will make sure we're there for support
They can get through that once we get enough
Automate workflow automation documentation in place where think everybody can do the rest of the migration on their own
We'll let them do that and it'll it'll snowball from there. But we get stuff done and people
See it as a good idea, but not because I've gone in and played the role of maximizer or or whoo
I just just not in my wheelhouse
I'm gonna do it through getting a good plan together
Getting the pieces in place to execute that plan and then making sure we produce results
Yeah, one of the things that that you brought up earlier you asked earlier. It's okay. I do this with my whole team
How do I how do I leverage this as a manager? Okay, the very first thing is I will say I
Now don't do the book you showed I do this one straight this is for the for the listeners
Strength finders 2.0 Brent has strengths leadership 2.0, which I probably need to go read
Here's one I suggest which is called. It's the manager
Okay, I gotta I gotta go expand my my book list, which is basically
Brent's book with an appendix for all the strengths, but it's also about
The role of a leader transitioning a little bit more to coach
They compared to telling us what to do in the past the thing I find it's great about this one
And I don't I don't have that other one. I have three more here
I could show but but I don't have that one. I'm like damn it
No, the thing that's nice around this one is you can go through and it gives you a clue as a manager
How to kind of put yourself in other people's shoes now me as an individualizer I do that fairly well
It's sort of the thinking man's empathy like I understand
Well, but if you don't have a clue and you need a clue because what I find is you just just start with five
And then you start having conversations around
How would you solve this problem?
your way
Right in the confused because they're like wait a minute. I thought you're supposed to tell me your way
No, no, no, I'm not trying to clone myself what I'm trying to do
Right. If you are a clone of me then yeah that job to figuring out your way of doing this is gonna be a lot easier
I have a lot of hands-on experience
But it's it's around how do we
Because if you if you if you help them learn how to solve the problem their way
They are gonna do it so much better
So much differently than you most likely and they're gonna be happier at the same time
An old manager of mine used to tell me productive people are happy people and I'm going to tell you that is bullshit
It is happy people are productive people get causality in the correct order
Yeah
Yeah, I will say like when I've I've had to learn this as a parent, right?
You know
I have chores for the kids to do and you know
Not all the chores are created equal one of them takes 45 minutes and one takes five minutes and the first
Dozen times I tried coming up with the system and then I was like wait a minute
Do I care about the how here or like I didn't do we need to more be more like Alan like I need to be
In a ranger and then be like look this is the list of chores that needs to get done
You know what done to find is because I'm in tech and so of course there's requirements that list what a clean bathroom look like but
So that my ten-year-old doesn't like, you know do half the job and I said go figure it out
I don't care how you break this up and they came up with a solution
I would never have come up with in a million years and it was the following
We will do every job every both kids will do every chore
They will each just do half of it and I was like that is so brilliant and so simple and I wouldn't like and I was
Embarrassed like that how stupid I felt when my nine-year-old and my twelve-year-old
Came up with something in five minutes and I was like well
Let's come up with a wait and then you can bid on it and then there's a budget
You know like I'm trying to PM this with story points
They're like no
We're just gonna all do both that we're all gonna do both
Both of us will do all the chores and we'll just get tell when it's halfway done and then we'll switch and I was like wow
That I just got to get out of the way
Like I like I don't have these execution strengths like my some of my kids do so let them run with it
Into my to that I'm just gonna comment like seriously what problem can't pair programming solve exactly
All right, we are out of time here, but Brian I do want to give you I know you have
What do you do in these days anything you want to plug or talk about?
Please please take some soapbox time. Sure. So
I'm I now do career coaching for people in tech having been
Had something like 11 or 12 different job titles and found what fulfills me has changed over time
I now help people in tech with three use cases
Landing a job in tech getting promoted and career clarity
There's a fair number of people that are looking for two or all three of those these days
so if anyone's interested in talking about
My approach and how I help others they can just go to refactor coaching calm
All right, I'll put that link in the show notes and
It's basically just a landing page. It's not a lot out there
But it is very much a strengths based coaching approach to helping you achieve your career goals
Very cool. Very love it. This has been fun
I've never seen so many hearts come out of eyeballs. I have with Brent today, but
Super fun. I learned a lot and I'm excited to read some more about this and I have reinvigorated my interest in this stuff
I think it's really valuable. All right. Well, that's all we have time for because I have a four o'clock apartment
I'm Alan. I'm Brent