Can we just do no, we can't.
But couldn't we just know we can't.
Oh, my God. Why do you?
Why did you just set up a daily one on one with me?
Oh, my God. No, stop. Stop.
Welcome to A.B.
Testing podcast, your modern testing podcast.
Your hosts, Alan and Brent will be here to guide you through topics
on testing, leadership, agile and anything else that comes to mind.
Now on with the show.
I worry that we've already had all of the interesting discussions
in the afternoon.
We have if we're going to get out.
Yeah, it's it wasn't that I forgot to press record.
We were just talking and it was interesting.
And then I thought, let's just press record and continue the conversation
in the middle, because I don't know what I said five minutes ago.
As anybody who works with me will remind you.
I'm Alan and he's Brent.
And together we make up the Alan Brent testing podcast,
where we rarely, if ever, talk about testing, but we do talk about stuff.
Yeah, we do talk about Alan and Brent quite often.
Yes. Mostly Alan talking about Alan and Brent talking about Brent,
because it's our podcast and we're the centers of attention.
I was going to go a different angle.
It's more normally Alan bitching about Brent and vice versa.
Oh, I can fire you.
A B could be Alan bitching.
Bye bye. All right.
Talk to you.
Brent has hung up.
I'm leaving.
I mean, boy, oh boy.
One of my favorite things to do when I'm just done with a telephone
conversation, it reminds me of it.
I will go, oh, hey, Alan.
Do you know what I have?
I have a pop quiz for you.
And if I do it right, you'll go, what?
And I'm like, can you guess what is this sound?
And then I just hang up.
Sound of silence.
Did we talk about the last of us already?
You've been watching that? No.
Oh, it's good. You got to watch it.
Yeah, I am up to date on Doom Patrol.
I am up to date.
I mean, and none of this really matters.
No, it doesn't. Anyway, I got to I got to get back on Doom Patrol.
I watched a bunch of that when I was stranded in Buffalo.
But I have to get back on.
And then I got distracted by White Lotus and and it was better.
But I want to get back on that.
What is last of us on with streaming?
HBO, HBO.
OK, maybe I'll check that.
Yeah, I have that one.
And I think I maybe didn't say it's on the podcast before.
But I normally do not like well, because they're not very good.
Usually the movies or series that are modeled up your video games
are just not good.
Yeah, I don't have to list them all off.
But I watched it anyway.
And I was surprised. It's very good. Very, very good.
I am hopeful that the movie that they're going to do for fallout
will not follow that path.
Oh, that's right. We did talk about this a little bit.
OK, let's we are forgetful old men.
I don't know how old I am, but it's old. It's super old.
All right. I want to talk about I mentioned it on the three of my five for Friday.
I mentioned this invention
and we've talked about it before on the podcast.
Everyone drink. I have coffee. I'm not brand has.
I have a coke.
Let's talk about again, yet again,
because it never goes away and it's getting more interesting.
And actually, it takes a lot to make Microsoft interesting.
Satya has fixed a lot of things wrong with Microsoft.
Oh, by the way, glad to see you're still employed.
I see another round launch today.
Yesterday. Oh, my God.
He's done some stuff. He has really made Microsoft interesting.
Microsoft caters to corporations.
People buying tens of thousands of licenses of office and windows.
And although there are consumers use that stuff, it's for corporations.
And it's boring. But Microsoft is getting less boring.
You know why? And in my eyes, as a non Microsofty, former Microsofty,
it's getting more interesting because I'm seeing our old friend chat
GPT pop up all over the place and press releases from Microsoft.
We know about the Bing one.
And we've also seen chat GPT integrated with Microsoft Teams.
And I'm going to ask you a question.
I know you want to ask us to talk about chat GPT,
but I think it'll generate some interest.
So Microsoft invests heavily in chat GPT, right?
But I know that that part you can answer.
So to be clear, there will be no accidental release of Microsoft
IP today. OK, no, no, no.
But I do have a request and I'm almost afraid to ask because if it's
if it's something that you can't answer either, then I'll tell you,
I can't answer. All right.
But here's my suggestion for you.
Here's my here's my top notch suggestion for you.
Can I just get myself rather than go through chat GPT?
Can I just get my own Azure VM or Azure cluster
with GPT through technology so I can just run my own language processing service
so you can without GPT?
No, well, with GPT, like what I'm saying is here's my tip is
build in GPT through technology into pre build it into some Azure VM
so I can just huck training material at something that I check out
in his mind and I pay you for and everybody's happy.
Well, so that's that is officially.
Well, I guess I don't understand the distinction.
So maybe I should double check if this is public.
So maybe maybe maybe I'm just going to say that because it's something
that should be available. I think it's it's Microsoft will absolutely
enable or directly enable a scenario similar to what you describe.
OK, so really all I'm saying is is Microsoft is all of a sudden
in an interesting place in making by making this technology accessible,
it makes some of its old stodgy business, the applications and and Bing,
which I will soon probably have to I will have to stop reminding people
that being as a search engine like Google and that you can use it
to Google stuff because I think it's going to become relevant.
I think a lot of interesting things are happening.
And then you have stuff you want to say.
But the other thing for my side is I posted an article today
showing how chat GPT was helping people.
And I like that. I think a lot of the photo, a lot of the comments
I see on social media and articles are people showing, oh, look,
chat GPT sucks for this. It sucks for this because they're using it
in things it's not designed for.
Or someone pointed out you can gaslight chat GPT
as you can with any AI.
They're trying to rather than trying to use it for good.
They're trying to find ways that it won't work, which are endless.
It's endless. It's infallible.
I think it is not Skynet, nor does it claim to be.
I would say it's probably closer to a very advanced version of that thing
in your text app as Brent is texting and in Gmail
that tries to predict what your next word is going to be.
No, I'm trying to quickly scan the article that you sent out.
Oh, just why do you look for it?
I'll talk about how I have ended up using chat GPT.
I use it for brainstorming.
I know that's interesting. It's interesting.
I use it as a creative tool. Walk me through it.
I use it to help me figure out.
Well, walk me through a scenario if you can. Sure.
Let me just look at my history real quick.
Well, I tried to figure I didn't help me directly.
Well, one, I was just trying to think of a new name for my org.
I described what it did. It gave me some ideas.
I said, those are horrible.
How about something more like this?
We kind of go back and forth as a can you make sure you use this word,
but don't use any words like this as kind of a brainstorming partner.
I use it for I use it for summarizing articles for for having
having to explain complex things to me.
There's a medical article I read once I had it explained.
Oh, OK, I get it. I understand it now.
Well, of course, of course, on that one, there is a risk.
You're aware that there's a risk when it summarizes things that you don't understand.
It could it could summarize wrong.
Right. Of course, it could it could present itself as truth,
something that is false, and then you walk away.
Yeah. And usually what I do, because the way I work,
I work around that is I don't I paste in a chunk of an article
and the odds of it giving me something and then maybe another chunk later
and the odds of it giving me the wrong thing twice or two.
If those things don't jive, I have to go look up more.
But again, I do know to take it with a grain of salt because it's not
it's it's it's not a language processing engine.
It's not it's not self-aware.
It is not even a language processing engine.
Yeah, you would know you would know the right words.
But but yeah, I use it for OK.
I'm going to cut this one out because I don't want the secret to get out.
So somebody will figure it out someday.
So anyway, I use it. You have a you have a I mean, you have a clear hint.
All right.
I might leave little bits of that in there, but I'm just
because somebody, if they thought about it, would figure it out.
They just they ask chat GPT what these names have in common.
Breadcrumbs. All right.
So but you and I want to mark it today is
we're recording this on Friday, February 10th, episode 175, A.B.
testing, and this is the first time in three, four, maybe five years.
Brent has topics for discussion.
And I probably stole some of this thunder because he wanted to talk about
chat GPT and I'm going to join in the conversation.
But I think he's going to lay down some some insights.
Is that true or or or did I read the wrong agenda?
I don't know if it's going to be insights like I am.
Part of my brain is is trying to convince another part of my brain
that I am just in conspiracy theory mode, and therefore I should ignore that.
The part of my brain that's generating all of these conclusions.
Well, I want to pause and remind people that who hopefully this isn't
their first episode, but back in our, you know, well, I don't know
what number it was, 170 something probably our prediction episode.
Really, a month and a half ago, Brent predicted that chat GPT
was going to be a multi billion dollar business and grow super fast.
And here it is already.
So I think anything you want to say about chat GPT
probably has a good chance of happening.
So how fucked are we?
We're doomed the but before I go into that story, I don't know if we are,
but I absolutely believe our grandchildren are.
And in terms of short term stuff like you remember when we were at micro
when when you were at Microsoft's do or as well, and we knew way in advance
that test was disappearing.
Yes. OK.
And I don't know if you had these arguments, but I did.
Right. People saying, what are you talking about?
You're so full of crap and blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
The way in in particular today, because I got even more information on on this topic
because I run a data science team that specializes in NLP.
And it has a lot of it has a high reputation
and a lot of people throughout Microsoft know it.
So I keep everybody in their mother is coming to me around chat GPT.
OK, and I will say if another goddamn PM comes to me
talking about chat GPT and cannot distinguish the difference between magic
and data science, I'm going to explode.
Any sufficiently advanced technology is indistinguishable from magic.
We know this. Yeah.
But they're like, well, can we go like you helps also?
Can we just do? No, we can't.
Well, well, couldn't we just no, we can't.
Oh, my God. Why do you why did you just set up a daily one on one with me?
Oh, my God. No, stop, stop.
That's kind of my life the last two weeks.
So what do they what?
Give me an example.
What do they want to do?
What is their what is the odd Brent them chat GPT threesome they want to set up?
Oh, in this particular case, they they want to use.
I'll just say, can't we just use chat GPT to just eliminate our entire
support organization, right? Things like that.
I'm using hyperbole.
That doesn't even fall into.
Well, actually, I mean, I was going to say the answer to any sufficiently
complex question is it depends.
And there I would basically say, you know what?
Bing team is probably already ahead of us on that one.
We probably don't need to do anything because customers,
when that's once they realize that
and Bing is very focused on these data science, particularly on the issues,
they're going to get they're going to get their well ahead of
certainly my freaking team of 10 people of which for focus on NLP.
Why are you talking to me anyway?
I got I got to ask, because is this
is this testers going away all over again in a way?
I mean, not this is what it feels like to me.
My my emotion right now around how I feel
about a prediction I'm going to.
Well, I've already made.
I feel it as strong as you and I did then.
And it's not because I'm predicting.
It's because I see the direction the momentum is going.
OK, you follow. You follow.
I have I have a thread in my head.
I want to have been all you. OK.
So today I woke up in a bad mood.
I wake up in a bad mood every day these days.
And it was it was fully thinking of this because I'm very
I feel very responsible to my team.
And as you did when you were a test manager.
Correct. Before you went and joined Bing as a dev manager.
And what did I do?
I went to go and learn.
I had a very clear sense of what's coming next.
I went to go learn it so I could broadcast it.
OK. And and help those who don't
who who weren't believers, who didn't understand, be prepared.
Right. That whole process led to ultimately things like modern testing principles.
Right. It's OK. Over the years, we see more and more evidence of this and et cetera.
Right now, though, I'm at a point.
I don't know.
I run a team with data scientists and NLP.
And I'm not certain what direction to invest them in.
Where they should train.
OK. And and it certainly doesn't help
where when we're in an environment where we've been told, yeah,
layoffs going to keep coming until March 31st. Right.
But there's that's a shorter term problem that will get resolved.
I'm pretty certain that like just before our podcast,
I was having a similar conversation with one of my key partners on this.
And I basically told him, look, I'm seriously thinking about getting out of NLP.
And he's like, what?
Oh, my God, Britt, I need you.
What's going to happen?
Bubba, right?
So things will converge and we'll work out the business thing.
What I wanted to talk about today.
And hopefully I don't take too long to do it because I'm hoping we can have
a discussion around what are options to deal with it.
I mentioned on on our Slack channel
that there was a new invention that came out.
Apple glasses. Are you familiar with Apple glasses?
Have you done any research into this thing?
I wouldn't say I've done research, no.
OK, there is a feature.
You go look at the marketing thing and there is a feature that's being discussed.
OK, and it says there is a camera
on each lens to track your eyes
so that the glasses can be more confident in what the user is looking at.
How do you feel about how do you feel about that sentence?
Well, doesn't bug you yet.
It bugs me a little.
I just remember to take my glasses off when I don't want it to know where I'm looking.
OK, what if I remind you
that roughly 80 percent of your eye movements are subconscious?
Yeah, I would never wear them.
OK, the only thing about Apple glasses here
that I can come up with as a positive
is that they are not their competitor Facebook, who's also building a similar thing.
Yeah, Apple has has has shown very publicly
a very willingness to tell the government to F off if they ask for private data.
But I will tell you the wares of these glasses,
that company will have the data.
They will have the data to know everything about you,
including things that you don't know in about a month.
All of it. They will know.
Hey, are you gay?
They will know what religion you're in or believe in.
They will know the perfect
the the image of the perfect mate for you.
They will know everything or that data will contain
all they need to know to know everything about you.
Now, there is one thing about human behavior that I
I have seen over and over again.
And it's this old phrase, the road to hell is paid with good intentions.
And so now let's imagine Apple glasses
and someone comes up with the idea of, hey,
since it is so effective at knowing what they're looking at,
could we not put them on infants?
Could we not make like Apple infant goggles or something
where where we can start getting additional insight into
what their thought process is?
They can't communicate yet.
So that's harder. This could help.
Oh, and even better.
Could we use that to sort of understand the difference between babies
with autism and normal babies?
Right. This would then start to build a process.
By the way, just just to interrupt the the
for those listening air quotes around normal.
Brent is not saying anyway.
Just just want to clarify that for for that statement. Yeah.
No, actually.
So I understand what you're saying there.
Okay. But that pushback is exactly what I'm afraid of.
Who gets to define normal?
Right. Right.
No, we're on the we're on the same pager. Right.
Because yeah, I don't.
That's why the air quotes are there because you don't.
This is very possible.
I would say almost inevitable.
Oh, it's absolutely inevitable.
This is where I'm going.
But even if you don't wear glasses, there are going to be ways to.
But we've seen glimpses of the future in films
where the ads you see, not just in your browser,
but the ads you see walking around are tailored to you.
Your world tailors around because there is no so much information about you.
Right. If some today, like 20 years ago,
if someone were to ask you some fact about something,
you know, how deep is the deepest part of the ocean?
Maybe you have a guess, but you you wouldn't know and you'd be fine with it.
You're OK to estimate it today.
We look up those things immediately on our phones,
on Wikipedia or the Internet somewhere.
But that's a lot of wasted effort to get that phone out
and either type it in or voice recognition that query.
Mm hmm. Why don't our why doesn't something connected to our bodies?
And eventually maybe that we're going way off the deep end here.
But why maybe even something implanted?
Recognize that.
And then with a thought or an action,
I can hear a conversation and ask for more clarification.
Like this is to keep it to glasses for now.
My glasses obviously have microphones, too.
And someone asked me a question and I can say, I don't know.
And I give a special blink blink.
And I get a little little thing in my ear telling me the answer to this thing.
Oh, my God. Schools are irrelevant because I can cheat so easily.
Everybody has to take the glasses off for their test.
Oh, my God.
Yeah, right.
So I when I was in high school,
I guess it was a period where there was a transition where some
some math teachers allowed calculator, some didn't.
Now it's common.
Every every class has a high school. Right.
Going back to the baby example, the other thing that that would do
is it then normalizes the glasses.
These are new human beings that don't.
Yeah. They don't know a different world.
Yeah. It may be glass.
It'd be something else.
I think there are.
I remember this from I used to show this video was made by Microsoft
when I used to give a talk at our new employee orientation.
And it was a view into the future of health care
and how through a wristwatch or a smart ring or some bit of jewelry,
you could get a lot more constant feedback on your health,
which I think, you know, there's some good benefit there, too.
But just the same case, these glasses, there is potential for
all of this data to be used in different ways.
Raise your insurance.
Understand when you're drinking too much.
Understand if you've what you're if and what you're smoking.
I think there again, all of this is inevitable.
It's how the data is used.
There's some ethical discussion, massive, massive ethical things.
And here's and here is actually the crux of it.
OK, and then I want to go back.
Crux me. The dangerous part of this is at what point in time
is this data being used to make decisions on your part,
whether it be good or bad.
Right. For example, I drive an F-150
big gas guzzler right now.
It's telling me I get 11 miles per gallon.
You drive a Tesla purely electrical
and you know this is going to be true.
I don't know if it's in your opinion, but in terms of the people
who are concerned about the climate, hey, wouldn't it be cool
if we could get access to this data and force people
to make eco friendly decisions?
It's where this data becomes dangerous
is when decisions are made for you and you're not involved.
I think that's very Philip K.
Dick yet, which is sort of in the adjacent possible of future possibilities.
Well, no, that's not only a future possibility.
People are going to willingly let the system make those decisions for it.
I want to go into that, but I want to back up.
This is do some magic editing put this way back, but I'm not going to
because I'm far too lazy for that.
But very early in the conversation, you were talking about
grow way off in the future now.
Talk about the now you're said you're feeling much now with this data science
like you were with test, however many years ago, was 15 years ago,
10 years ago, actually 10 years ago when we started realizing that,
you know what, in the way we're shipping software, we're not going to
test as much anymore.
And now you're saying with the way with the tools available,
we don't need as much data science anymore.
Is that a clear is that a fair summary?
We're not only not going to need as much data science, it's going to go
into other places as well.
Yeah. Okay.
So let me let me talk about let me set the stage for people that
remember and remember also, as I discussed when I posted my made my
post on why most teams don't need dedicated software testers, the
uproar of illogical really rebuttals.
There are lots of teams out there still employing testers who are
convinced, who are convinced they are absolutely essential to
delivering software even on fast moving stuff.
Can't change that.
They're still around.
Yep.
Thus data science still be around.
I think when we first saw this, we didn't know that we didn't
know about the rise of data science yet.
I think partway through we were podcasting with that.
I can't find the, I don't know when the date was.
I can't find the presentation, but there was a Microsoft
internal event.
God, I wish I could remember when it was, but Seth, Elliot and I,
Seth, Elliot and I sat there.
If you're listening, she does sometimes not very often.
Hello.
Hey, Seth.
We were, we give a presentation on data science and I told the, the
famous target story of how, of how target knew this girl was pregnant
before her parents did and very famous.
Go look it up.
I can tell the whole story again through data science and analysis of data.
What you're talking about seeing for the future is this turn to 11 or 11,000.
Yeah.
But what are the graphs I showed was a Google trends graph showing the data
science, the phrase as it was showing up.
It didn't exist.
It really didn't exist at all.
Other than, you know, insignificantly it existed 12 years ago,
whatever the timeline was.
It certainly wasn't really a title.
And now it's now it's a huge thing.
So I'm wondering if the thing that's next and whether it's a new role,
you know, data, what's the, what's the joke?
You know, what's the data scientists?
It's a, it's a, uh, statistician that works in Silicon Valley.
Ha ha.
But I think the creative parts missing.
So let me, let me, let me just finish my thought here.
I'll ask you a question and go on.
So you still have to figure out, you can't just give GPT three,
here's a bunch of stuff.
Tell me what I should do.
Someone has to figure out what questions to ask, how to dig in there.
But one thing, here's an observation I want you to comment on, and then
I'll show you for a while.
All right.
One of the things that data scientists have told me for as long as I've
known what a data scientist is, is how much of their time they spend cleaning
up the data so that they can actually do something meaningful with it.
Yep.
And you can tell me, does GPT through technology, it seems to me,
it works fine on dirty data.
It is.
That is not a limit, a limitation to, to the tech behind GPD.
Yeah.
I just realized this.
So, uh, anyway, just a real little relevation while we talk, but, uh,
I've talked long enough.
So anyway, I made my point to continue on your stories.
Tell me all kinds of things.
Tell me how doomed we are and we'll make a movie.
I don't know how doomed we are.
Right.
I just know we, I know our grandchildren from the, the context in which we
judge the world today, our grandchildren are doomed, but it'll be normal.
I guess the positive thing is that it'll be normalized for them.
What that means.
I don't know.
People will go and say, but chat GPT can't do this and chat GPT can't do that.
Chat GPT.
Yeah.
They, that's all true.
So the hell what?
Right.
It's it's, to me, it reminds me it even further, it further solidifies my point
of view on this prediction is so happening because the immediate thing is people to
go and, and nitpick on what it can't do as sort of a self-defense mechanism.
We saw this in tests.
Oh, but who's going to find bugs?
Devs don't want to, oh, that's a stupid argument.
But your ship it to cut.
Oh, that's a dumb argument too.
Uh, it's eventually they lose the grip on the white knuckles.
Right.
Cause progress keeps moving forward.
I'll give you a great example right now.
Chat GPT does facts like ass.
Okay.
You ask.
But people are like, Oh, chat GPT will never do facts.
Okay.
Well, we will wear the, the, the news article that came out this week where
Steven Wolfram, the head of Wolfram alpha is offering to, to work with chat GPT
to fix that problem, like stop.
Google, Google has come out with an algorithm that you say, Hey, generate
a song for me that feels like this.
And guess what?
It's pretty damn good.
Right.
Here's the thing.
When you say creativity, like I'm going to be nothing but doom for the next five
minutes, I'm just telling you, when you bring up creativity, what we view as
creativity is the generation of new ideas and where do new ideas come from?
Allen.
My.
Okay.
Well, all of those ideas generally are documented someplace and this
system is really good at pulling those in.
Now, will it come up with random directions initially?
Probably.
But when you say, okay, generate a new idea for me in this direction, it'll get
better and better and better and better.
The last one that I, because I've been sharing this with, let me pause right
there, cause this is the creativity brainstorming I was talking about.
I can be writing a song.
I could say, help me find a, help me find a word that rounds with orange.
I could just say, what would the next line, what should the next line of the song be?
And it may not be what I want or use, but it gives me an idea that I can work from.
Ideas come from other ideas, which is what you wanted me to say earlier.
Right.
And that's what I use chat GPT for.
I use it to get ideas.
I might not use its ideas, but I may use, I may use its ideas come up with
a new idea that I couldn't have come up with on my own.
It's great because I don't like people.
And now I have someone to brainstorm with.
One of my employees today, we brought up some data and one of the things I realized.
So my team documents all of its work in one note.
And I'm like, huh, if I was a word I haven't heard in a long time,
I forgot about that app.
Right.
And we do very tactical work, like two, two weeks at a time.
And I'm like, huh, if I were to copy paste that into the chat, GPT, every
six months for each employee, and then ask chest GPT, Hey, um, given that these
are the principles for me as a manager that are important, write a professional
performance review based off of this work.
Right.
And I'm like, Oh, I, I now have just gone down the path of, of automating
management and then my employee said, Oh, but I could do the same
and create essentially an employee bot.
And, and, and that just set me off.
I'm like, Oh my God, we could Alan could create a, uh, an Alan.
But we could, we could go and put these glasses on for a week so that our
bots could really understand us and create a remarkably train it with all the,
the, the code we've ever written, the bugs we filed and create a very
realistic simulation of us in that particular persona.
And then let's say you and I, there's something we disagree with.
We get just instead of you, you and I could go get beers and just have the
stupid bots argue it out until they come to the conclusion.
And, and I'm like, uh, I even think I know how I could write that.
And if I can do it, these experts building chat GPT absolutely can't.
I'm not entirely sure.
I could do that one.
The only defense, by the way, there's only two things I've seen in terms of sort of
defending against decisions being made on my behalf without my permission.
There's only two things I've been able to is number one, come up with a new service
and, and change regulations that makes it very clear.
My data is mine.
And I want the ability, a first ability is I, I want to know any time, even
a single bit of my data, as in there are eight bits in a bite, even, even bit of
my data was used in some decision-making process.
I want to know the decisions being made off of my data or the other ways.
So the whole new service that, that basically like the data gets moved
to one of my vaults.
I can delete it anytime.
It's not, I have to ask Google to delete the data.
No, it's stored in my location.
It's mine.
The fine line here is I get exactly what you're saying.
Yep.
And it should give, AI should give us suggestions, not decisions.
But here's the deal.
Let me go back to Apple glasses.
Let's say could do some things like just something simple.
Like today, you know, a lot of people use apps like my fitness pal or similar
things to track their calories and exercise throughout the day.
They're trying to get the right number of not only calories, but macros
between fats, carbs, and protein.
And they're painstakingly looking up things to get the breakdown and guessing
here and there and trying to find the best diet for them in order to
optimize the kind of body they want to have with their, with their
exercise routine and everything.
Now, theoretically, Apple glasses, they can automate all that.
They can look at the food and look at a database in the background AI,
figure it all out.
It could just be automatic.
It could tell me what I should and shouldn't eat from a plate or from a buffet
or even from a menu I'm reading, which I think a lot of people, a lot of
fitness and health conscious people would actually look at that as a plus,
a positive.
Yeah.
And they be right.
But also, you know, it's on the edge of when does, when does good for you
become creepy and then bad?
The road, that's what you're worried about.
The road to hell is paved with good intentions.
So there are some good intentions in how our lives will change.
And you can even think, I mean, I can, we can tell the old fart story
about how we didn't have the internet.
By the way, in your 2000, you and I both had internet.
I used to dial up.
I have an ISDN.
No, by 2000, I might have even had, I can't remember what I got cable
for the first time, but I had dial up.
I saw this interesting stat.
400,000 people worldwide had access to the internet estimated in 2000.
And today it's again, think the whole world, even third world countries.
I don't, I just had a percentage, it's like 65%.
But 65% of 7 billion, 7 million or eight.
It's a big number, a big number of people have access to the internet
to get their questions answered.
What is that we used to talk about, I'm going to say Murfrees law, Moore's law
in that computers were, computer power was doubling every, like three years,
every number of years and getting all the numbers wrong.
But it's this ease of access to information.
It's going through the same sort of exponential growth.
And the way that information and data is acting on is now going
through exponential growth.
Yes.
And it's going to enable a lot of cool things.
The good intentions.
It's also going to enable, as we've seen already with Facebook and other places,
a whole bunch of bad shit.
We do not want to happen.
Yep.
And I'm wondering just really twist this thing in a different direction.
Here's a run at a time is we have in the US at least we have a government made up
of 99% of people who do not understand any of this because they were born
a hundred years before Brent and I also, I'm worried.
I like this need, this needs some regulation and some people
thinking about how to solve it.
But I don't know where those people come from.
So now I'm on the Brent train and maybe we are all doomed because there's
no way to even protect ourselves from the evil we're making even with good intentions.
There's only one, one, it's either lock it away and make it such that lock it away in a way that even
the slow assholes running the government don't have access to it.
Right.
But then right now with the laws, that's just a regulation away.
I don't know if you're paying attention to crypto coin.
That's kind of what I view the government's doing on crypto coin and doing it way too slow.
Right.
By the time they realize they need to get regulations in place, it's not only going to be too late,
it's going to be way too late.
So now I'm wondering.
And here's the thing, I'm not even certain as something they can do.
Potentially not.
Because there's going to be other governments that will do the exact opposite.
They're like, no, I am a dictator of my country.
I want this because this allows me not only that, but I want the ability from my office to be able to
control the decision making from my populace.
Free apple glasses for everyone in North Korea.
Right. Exactly.
The only other thing I can think about is of how to prevent this is if a company comes up with
something like it's basically fight fire with fire.
There needs to be a technology where you can have a chat GPT type thing that that's whole role in
life is to defend you.
Yeah.
If I was smart enough, I'd go work for that company.
Hopefully that company exists.
Maybe.
Why can't it be Microsoft?
How come you can't be the defenders of because Google do no evil.
Google could do it.
They're not going to do it.
Yeah.
I keep hearing that motto and I have concluded that that evil is an acronym, but I don't know what
it stands for.
So one other thing I thought of, we're going to go a little bit over time because I'm sure you
have some closing thoughts here.
Not again, you're wondering, we started late.
All right.
We started late.
It's not an hour podcast.
It's as long as we want it to be.
That was for the list.
I think you know this.
I go backpacking two or three times as much as I could get out of the house during the
summer.
I like to be out in the middle of nowhere with no people around with no cell service
because damn it, it's just too easy to glance at my phone all the time when I'm home or
look something up or stream a video.
And I think a lot of people have forgotten what it's like to be a little bored or to be
a little undistracted.
And every time I'm out there, this story is going somewhere.
Don't worry about it.
Every time I'm out there, I think, you know, this is why people live off the grid.
There's a lot of intrinsic value you get from just being off the grid.
And we've all known or at least known of people who know people that have gone off
the grid, no social media.
Maybe they use a flip phone and they just do not go online at all.
They would never buy Apple glasses.
I wonder if this, I mean, in the dystopic science fiction thriller I'm viewing as
this conversation, I think it's a growing number of people and maybe even
communities in our doomsday future who consciously stay off of every single
thing that can track them.
Oh, I know of multiple people.
Like, but I think there will be more as this track, as not only this
tracking becomes more ubiquitous, but suggestions are as you worry decisions
are made on your behalf, it would encourage more people just to say no to it all.
Uh, yeah.
And in there, I'm like now I know I'm going into conspiracy theory, but, but
there are some on the, on the crypto coin thing.
There are some that believe that a boot, a push towards a pure digital
currency is blocks that as a solution.
Right.
It's essentially, right.
Yeah.
If, if your option is to then go back to God, what is it?
600 BC and, and, and do trading of goods and services, right?
The whole point of money was to, to simplify you, you go off the grid,
you start raising sheep, you want eggs.
You're like, okay, I'll take a hundred eggs for my one sheep.
Bartering work.
Sure.
Right.
And so if we move to, to, to pure cryptocurrency, well, that can't happen.
Then, then the other thing that's going to happen, of course, I think Burt, yeah,
I don't happen to burning man becomes a year round thing.
Exactly.
It becomes, there will be, that's exactly right.
And I'm nodding.
I'm not against this feature.
Bernie, man, I don't think has enough space to fit all.
No, we need several of these, all these entities.
All right.
Uh, I got to go, man.
Yeah.
Um, and you're eating, so what's being the podcast is over.
It's over.
All right, everybody.
Thanks for listening.
Um, if we're, if the world still exists in a few weeks, we'll
be back for another podcast.
I'm Alan.
I'm Brent.
And we'll see you another time.