It needs to be safe to just no matter what level, it's your manager, your skip level, your skip level, your whatever level.
It needs to be safe to ask questions and challenge what you see other people say regardless of level. I hate that.
Welcome to A.B. Testing Podcast, your modern testing podcast.
Your hosts, Alan and Brent, will be here to guide you through topics on testing, leadership, agile, and anything else that comes to mind.
Now, on with the show.
Welcome back to the A.B. Testing Podcast. I'm here with Brent.
Howdy, oh, yeah. Long time. Yeah.
Listen, a long time. We took a little break. Yeah. So a couple of things going on. One, Zencaster is working. That's cool.
Yeah, you I think you beat your record on getting it to do what you want to do.
We're going to do a little bit of a shorter podcast. We have stuff to catch up on. We're talking.
But I when I slug into Zencaster and Zencaster, I love you.
And I should say that because you work most of the time and I don't pay for you as I personify Zencaster.
I guess this has been true since March. I just never noticed before.
But we do have a two hour recording limit per month, which does feel record every other week.
I think we're probably good. So I'm not going to worry about it too much. I just noticed it today.
I never noticed the time remaining counter. We have one hundred and nineteen minutes left to record in July.
So I guess as long as I don't do a bunch of bonus episodes, long stuff, we should be in good shape.
But yeah, it's going to be back. Took some breaks. Got stuff going on.
It's summertime in Seattle. How are you doing with the heat, Brent?
Oh, so I have AC at home. Same. It's not on right now. Today.
Today has been a little bit better. I'll just share it this way.
My wife and I have a bit of a disagreement around what is an appropriate temperature for the AC.
For me, wives are like cats and they seem to like things about five to ten degrees warmer than I do.
Yeah. Plus one. Right. So this is one of the things I have a sensei.
Okay. That's the temperature I'm showing. Alan, the temperature it says seven four.
Yeah, that's the temperature of my house. You also notice right there, three letter word says off.
The last two days I have come home and the temperature of the house has been above 80.
And I have been now at a point where I don't even talk about it. I just go upstairs. There's
an app for that. And I open up the app and I say air conditioner on 74. 74 is my max tolerable
range. I have noticed that it's about the same for me. I would prefer it slightly cooler.
I would too. But I can't if it's above 74, I actually can't work.
I can work. I can't keep my concentration up. I just the heat gets me.
The thing that bothers me is and I say 74 and I think that's a bit of a mistake, but
I have noticed particularly in the last week that if it's above 73, I can't sleep.
Oh, same. So our bed is me, you know, with the window open with no blankets on my wife
next to me with it with a blanket plus an extra blanket on her. Yeah. It doesn't matter what
time of year. It's ridiculous. That is crazy talk. Like the other day, the other day I came home
and it was, it was 80 in the house, right? And it was 85 outside. And I'm like, what the hell?
She's like, just open a window. Why would I do that? It's hotter outside than inside. I don't
want to heat my house. I want to cool it down. True, true, true, true. All right. So that's
the podcast for today, everybody. Thank you. I'm Alan. He's Brent. And no,
how temperature, we're going to do a short podcast today. Yes. And a couple of things for,
I have two topics and we'll do, I think the order I put them in Slack is probably good.
And then what do we got to know? Oh, these are both, both these topics are open to drive some
discussion. So if you'd like to discuss these topics, give us more things to think about,
go to modern testing.org where there's a link that usually works. And if it doesn't,
you can email me and tell me I'm stupid and I'll fix it to join our Slack group at one of the
three.slack.com. And I can tell you right now that we are, we are driving towards a thousand.
We have 905 members in the Slack group and not all those are active, but a chunk of them are
there's activity almost every day. Yep. You can do things there like, you know, bonus, bonus material
one, you can just give us, you can yell at us there and we'll listen to it. You can give tacos.
I posted photos from my hike last weekend, all kinds of great stuff, but it's a good part to be
part of the community and tell us what's going on. So that's going on. I don't know. Do you want
to get into the topics? Yeah. Okay. So the first one, this is something that I see once in a while.
I just, I just, I, I just was kind of curious on your thoughts, Brent. We'll have a little
bit of discussion around it. The second one is a more interesting topic, but I'm going to call
this the age old issue of premature escalation. Okay. And, uh, what this is, this happened this
week. There's a little bit of a fire drill on Wednesday when I got back and I'm not going to
go into the full story to protect those who must remain innocent, but there was a thing going on
with a vendor and it was just, it's look in software writing code. The technical part is easy.
It's the people stuff that's hard. And basically the story is we had an issue with a timeline.
We wanted to figure out what we could do with it to make it work better for us. And the end ended
up being a non-issue. It doesn't matter. But someone in the meeting pulled out premature
escalation. And what they did was we are still very much in the diplomatic, uh, portion of
this discussion where we're trying to figure out what mitigations are, uh, what we want to go
investigate next steps, et cetera. And they jumped right to the I'm going to tell dad card.
You know what I'm talking about, Brad? I, yeah, I, I call it the mission from God.
Yeah. It's essentially, I have authority on God from, from God to tell you what to do.
And if you do not make me happy, then you will be on slide number one for the next God update deck.
Yeah, it was interesting. It was, I thought things were progressing well and someone jumped in with
the wall. If this doesn't get solved, this is going to go to dad and dad being some level
of upper management and which is a car that you can, it's not the one you never play that card.
You never play that card in the firsthand too often. If you're going to, if it will
dis equate this, we'll just see if I can keep a metaphor of some sort of card game going.
There's one, you don't play it in the first, first round. You got to know when to hold them.
You may even play it in the background. You may not even need to tell. I mean, the, the fact
that it was a, I was going to call it a thinly veiled threat, but I'll leave off the thinly
veiled part. Yeah. To me, it's cringy. It's a cringy way to, it's a cringy method of diplomacy.
It's not diplomacy at all. Right. I don't know if you've, you ever read getting the yes.
Oh yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Very much. It's, it's a perfect example of what's known as a positional
argument when it comes to negotiation. I don't care what happens to you.
I want to win, right? You're basically trying to work out what's the definition of a win-win scenario
and all of a sudden you have somebody who's losing patience and just goes for the throat on a win
lose. Yeah. Yeah. And now you have people defensive, which makes it even harder to get to a win-win.
So it's an interesting leadership trait that I realized it's a, it's a, it's a, I don't know
how I learned it. And I, maybe I did this at some point too. I was, you know, I've, I grew up being
mentored and led by type A assholes at Microsoft. So I'm sure I did this at some point, but at some
point I realized some later point I have learned and realized that the high road's going to work
99% of the time. And just having a discussion, being cordial, being, it's in it together
attitudes of problem solving. It's going to work far better than trying to put a thread in there to
try and put like I motivate again, 99% of the time with carrots and 1% with sticks
building shared problems, building shared solutions for those problems or shared
understanding of the problems and shared solutions of those problems for me just works much better
than this weird, I'm not going to call it political because political is not bad. A lot of times it's
the political, it's just influence. Call it the mission from God. I'm going to call it premature
escalation. Interesting. It came up. I had been thinking about it all week because I thought
the situation was kind of cringy and just weird. So whenever something doesn't sit right with me,
I can't help but reflect on why does this feel weird? So I was wanting to share that with you
and go into your thoughts. I pay active attention to people who take that tact. They're basically
willing to in a political war, they're going to go straight to the nuke. I have a habit
when someone tries to do that against me. And I'm like, look, I have a one on one with that guy
every other week. Like let's call him right now if that's important to you. And you can be the one
to inform him that even though you are paid at extremely senior level salary, you need to go to
a CVP in order to work out this part of the business that you're supposedly accountable for.
Like I don't see the reason why we can't work it through. I feel like you're threatening.
That's what you want to do. Actually, the other thing to do
in today's environment is just call them out and say, I feel like you're threatening me.
Right. Because just those words are fighting words in a world where
everyone's sort of anti toxic environments.
Yeah. So this I want to dove.
It's like, okay, you're going to go to the executive at the same time. I'm talking to HR.
Right. But let's see. Let's see what happens.
Yeah. So it really comes down to culture and you know, we've talked about the cultures I try
and have on my teams and and what's interesting is I'm not going to talk about any specifics of
work because I've perhaps signed things that said I wouldn't. But.
Perhaps.
Culturally what I want to do, whether I worked at Subway making sandwiches or at a
broadcast company that happened to have software teams, regardless, there's a culture I want to
try and build of. It's the opposite of telling dad. I want a culture where telling dad doesn't matter.
And I'm very much in a Ronnie Kohavi talked forever at my when he was at Microsoft and
since then about the hippo, the highest paid person's opinion and why it doesn't matter.
Right.
Where a lot of the data driven decision making comes from. But also I remind my teams,
very generic here all the time that I may spout off ideas. I may have thoughts on how to do things, but
my way is rarely the right way. It's just one of many opinions,
regardless of my hierarchy and regardless of my title.
No, it's I agree. I view my job. Right. Part of my job is to make decisions when
when we're bottlenecked. OK. However, like the definition of bottleneck in my world view,
and I think I think you share with this. This is for some reason my team is unable to make this
decision. Right. Whether it be lack of experience or right. They're not certain what the tradeoff is.
Right. But I really view my my long term goal with the team is to have them understand the
principles by which I want decisions being made and then let them go.
Yes. Yes. And that's a conversation I've had very much that decisions should be made as close to
the people, close people close to the work as possible. I here's the hard one. I want
to be challenged. I can give us an example scenario today. I posted something and someone said,
what did you mean by this basically? And I said, I thought I meant this. I said,
that's not right. Not private DM. And and I said, can you please clarify, go ahead and clarify
what I wrote or question what I wrote in the other conversation. And they said something that
lets me know that I still have work to do something to the effect of I've been taught
not to oppose my manager in public channels. And so something for me to work on because I actually
want that I want to be. Oh, I may have a fancy title and I may have hierarchy, but I need to
be challenged, not because it's it makes me I'm going to go beat you up, but it needs to be
safe to just no matter what level it's your manager, you skip level, you skip level,
you're whatever level it needs to be safe to ask questions and challenge what you see other
people say, regardless of level. There's different level. There's different levels of challenge,
right? It's yet don't be a douchebag. No, obviously, you do it respectfully. Right.
I love it when people tell me I'm wrong because I know they're right.
But when they do it respectfully, they don't just call me dumb. But so many times, like I really,
really value because it gives me a chance to learn. And I know and I also know that I that
a couple of things happen. One is an example of the culture I want to have. So I feel like,
okay, they're getting it. But also then other people see it and the next person isn't afraid
to challenge. And it's hard and it takes time. But it's so important for people to feel empowered.
It is it is the the worst. You need them to have enough trust to be able to speak their mind so that
you kind of understand what, okay, what additional changes you need to make to your culture.
Right. I'm thinking through the two things that you told me so far, right? This inappropriate
escalation, premature escalation. And, and I have been taught to not challenge
my manager in public. And I'm like, okay, yeah, the feels right right now I'm walking away with
all right. There's a big opportunity there for Alan, because I feel like he is potentially in
a big command and control environment that needs to be brought forward.
I am not, but there are people I would say I'm working with people who have been brought up that
way. And I am very I mean, this is my job as a pointy here, senior manager, right?
My job isn't to go implement a bunch of terraform. My job isn't to go tell a bunch of people smarter
than me what to do. My entire job is to create an environment where these people can be successful
doing this stuff. And I 100% believe that a transparent and psychologically safe
environment is the best way for them to do that. So that's what that's what I'm going to work on.
Yeah, it's, in my view, it's sort of set the direction and then get out of the way.
Yes, yeah, yeah. And that comes from there is a there's this writer whose name is going to come
to me wrote the leaders guide to radical management. And I forgotten his name and he wrote the age of
agile. And I still don't remember his name, but in the leaders guide to radical management, he's
talking about very early on an agile, maybe not that early, but in the in the early 2000s,
he is talking about how agile applies not just to software teams, but in the way teams need to
work before Reese wrote his stuff. Just he really got he really saw something exciting coming.
And in that book, in the leaders guide to radical management, one of the phrases I took away from
that, which has been, you know, paraphrased in my mind over the two decades since I read it,
is that the leader's job is to give people a framework they can work in and then get out
of their way. Stephen Dunning. Denning Stephen Denning. See together together we can accomplish
so much you can you can look up the book while I'm talking and then mispronounce the name that I can
correct you because it gives me enough information. Perfect. Teamwork right there. Yes. Yes. Hey,
I got another topic a different a different direction. So I don't know if you caught my last
sub stack post. Is that the five for Friday? Because I actually read that today. No,
so my sub stack is the one I did last Saturday. So I do. So now I have to go on a tangent. So
once upon a time I used to write a blog haphazardly I did it for years and years. My very first blog,
which is still up on whatever blogs dot MSDN.com came says I'm not a blogger is the title of my
very first blog post and I want this is back in 2000 and four, three and I just wanted a way to
engage with the windows CE community. And why did I get into this story? Now I have to finish it.
And then I ended up blogging more and more and sometimes good, sometimes bad, mostly bad,
but I wanted to get better at writing and then end up writing a book and I got a little better
at writing or a better blog post and eventually move those blogs to anger weasel dot com or
blog there. And then eventually I got too busy to blog at anger weasel dot com. And then I got
inspired by Tim Ferriss and his five bullet Friday and about three years ago began doing five for
Fridays on anger weasel dot com. And then kind of the end of 2022 I was thinking, you know what,
I miss writing. I want to blog again. And I thought, well, you know what, I'm going to commit
to writing a long story here. I'm going to skip most of it. I'm going to commit to writing
a blog post every week on anger weasel dot sub stack dot com. And I have so far from,
I think from the end or middle of December until now, I have written a blog post every week,
usually on Saturday, sometimes Sunday. Last week I wrote it on Thursday instead of auto post
on Saturday. And, but so far so good. So I've done about half a year. So that's like 20,
26, 27, 28 regular weekly posts there. I'll read another one tomorrow or Sunday,
probably Sunday this weekend. I have some plans tomorrow.
I did read this one. So, but the gist is I was revisiting something I put in,
it's the diffusion of innovation curve from crossing the chasm, which I originally posted
the very first time I talked about modern testing at a conference at a test bash in,
I don't remember what year 2016, I think. And my hypothesis there was that modern testing or
again, modern testing isn't that modern, not a lot about testing, but sometimes it is
depends on the kind of testing and your definition of modern. But at the time I gave that talk at a
testing conference, I was a little freaked out, thought I'd get a lot of anger, but they let me
give the talk on what it was like to have a team that didn't have any testers or may not have the
need for a dedicated testing specialist. And what I was pleasantly surprised at that talk and many
talks afterwards was that people came up to me, multiple people came up to me and said,
thank you for giving a name to what we're already doing. Oh, this is actually, and again,
is what Brent and I had seen, we know we're in a little bit of a bubble, but the bubble was
bigger happily, much bigger than we thought. And here we are seven years after that talk,
and a lot of people are still freaked out by this idea of delivering quality software
without dedicated testing specialists. And you and I both know hundreds, if not thousands of
companies do this, and it's crossing that, it's getting over that hump. And we've talked about
this a lot before, but I want to talk about it in a slightly different context. One of the best
testing conferences remaining is coming up in a month or two, which is the Agile Testing Days in
Potstom. There every year, it's always great speakers. This year, no exception. Good speakers,
good content, it's well put together. I've never been there, but every year I follow it on social
media and read the reports. I look at what talks are there. And again, all the talks are good,
but what's interesting, because Brent, when you and I first started talking about this thing that
became modern testing, it was in reaction to watching teams become agile, watching what
happened when they moved quicker and could get data and feedback and testers doing what they did
before just slowed them down. So what we talked about, what does that change? And we talked about
delivery, which is really what modern testing principles are. So long preamble aside, but I
want to get your thoughts on them. I look at the conference talks for Agile Testing Days.
And again, I think they're all very good. This is not a dig on them, but they're all
one step still, one step back from that edge I talked about seven years ago at the early,
the innovation I talked about seven years ago at Test Bash in that they're all about having dedicated
testers on the team, testers writing automation versus developers. Everything's about what testers
can do to improve quality, how to improve testing. Some of it's about improving testing mindset on
the team, I don't know the talks in front of me, I read them earlier today. But it's,
you know, what I'm going to say is it's not a lot different from the talks we saw,
I saw at Agile Testing five, six, seven years ago. So I'm just curious, why do you think that's not
changing? Why do you think that's not, I'm not going to use shift left, not going to use shift
left. Why do you think that's not drifting across the chasm on the diffusion of innovation?
Uh, or am I wrong?
I, I, I think you have a subject, you have a selection bias.
Ah, talk to more.
So crossing the chasm. So as you mentioned, this, this is one of the better test conferences
out there. I would say, right, anything from the ministry of testing is another one.
So the best, let's just say this is the best testing conference, right? Let's say the industry
as a whole has made a transition. Okay. I argue that the best testing conference will be the last
one to die. Right. So in here, I would actually, I'd be more interested in looking at, okay,
has the rate of testing conferences worldwide over the last several years gone up, gone down,
stayed flat, right? That sort of thing. Like something like agile testing days,
that's probably going to be the, one of the last ones to, to go, right? And they're going to
continue to talk to their audience, which is still dedicated testers.
Yeah.
Yeah. But, but if, if, if we, as the migration towards non-dedicated testers continues,
over time, there's going to be fewer people in that role. They're going to be mostly developers
and that content's going to show up in developer centric con and you're going to see the popularity
for these test conferences fall, right? They're not going to be able to, they're not going to
be able to sell enough tickets to, to support the conference. Um, yeah, maybe you're right. Okay. Well,
I mean, I see some things in here, right? There's some things in here that are absolutely,
do you remember what year it was? Were you asked me to come in and present to unity?
Oh yeah. That would have been November, 2017. Okay. I see a talk refactoring your end-to-end
tests from an ice cone to a pyramid. And I'm like, yeah, I saw Alan present that same freaking talk.
That was Marcello. Marcello on my team presented that he's, he's less unity. He is back at Thought
Works, but cool guy. But it's right next to another one called embracing home team quality,
making myself obsolete, which to me feels like, yeah, that's, that's, that's very empty.
Um, and, and, and actually that one wouldn't have been there six or seven years ago. So,
no. And actually I want to touch on that a lot. I think, you know, I see so many,
I still haven't done this, not gonna my post tomorrow, but someday I'm gonna write about this.
So many posts I see on LinkedIn as I go there talking about how unique and special testing is
because it requires creativity and autonomy. As Peter Drucker would have told you 80 million
years ago, all knowledge work does get 50 years ago, whenever, whenever that was.
Right. So one thing that I think all knowledge work is about making yourself
obsolete. And I don't, I don't think enough people in, I'm gonna call them traditional test
roles think that that's as critical. I think it's the opposite. They want to make themselves
more important. And I have as long now, now, because I'm old and I have less ability to remember,
as long as I can remember, I've tried to make myself obsolete. And, and maybe it's not even
I've tried to make myself obsolete by doing the things I do, I've made myself obsolete.
So I just think that's a, maybe that's the eighth principle. It's not, but it,
but it's a critical thing that we have to do. No, it's the thing is, and I think about
the series we've done on GPT. The thing is, we almost made it a whole episode without
talking at all about AI. There was no way. Cause I, I have already loaded up the next
topic on this one, but without talking without the words GPT, I completely agree. Right. There
is, cause what you and I have learned is as we pursue obsolescence, that we learn new skills
that enables us to even become more valuable than the things we're leaving behind.
Yes. Yes. In terms of the world where, where GPT exists, like it really is the same way
that the, um, whatever happens as we move forward with these potentially very beneficial or very
terrifying, uh, AI systems, right? Really it's, it's always going to be the case that, that
human plus AI outperforms human or AI alone. And this is the way I like to put it now. AI
is not taking your job away. People who know how to use AI, however, will. Yes. Yes. That's
absolutely the case. Number one, I don't know if you saw, saw first off, just sort of tangent.
I don't know if you saw this, we can't screen share on this stupid app. Um, but one of the
time, it doesn't matter. One of the talks is building an awesome character sheet for agile
teams. Right. And I'm totally thinking of your war craft model for four teams. Yeah. Character
sheet is different than the war craft model of project management. So that well, but you want
to have a, you need your barbarian, you need your cleric. You do. You need to balance it. And that's,
um, you know, it's like when you're quick out of the tangent, like when you're building a team,
if you have four head count, you might have one, uh, job description for all of them. But when you
hire the first one, maybe it has to change a little bit, what you're looking for the other
three. Every time you get to that last one, you're actually being kind of a lot more specific
about what you need because you know what gaps remain. You it's it's puzzle building. It's fun.
Great. It's building the right party. Or you could even call it like, uh, in war craft or any of
those games, it's coming up with the right skill tree to balance your attack even on a single
character. Uh, yes, completely agree. One of the things that I, the other thing I'll say around
AI is so far I have found at least two talks, uh, at Agile testing days around, around this
concept we talked about, like one of them is titled 10 times software testing. However,
you dig into it and the, the mission is incorporating AI into our software testing workflows has
significantly improved our processes leading to faster and higher quality results.
Sounds like a great talk. And I, again, I, I expect every single talk of that conference to be good.
I just as I always look at the talks that are happening there. And again,
why I started this conversation is I, and again, maybe in hindsight, some of them are more on the
empty side than I thought in my first pass. I think that AI one's definitely one too.
I just, you know, I, I, I want more companies to leap to be less afraid to leap the chasm.
And not again, the goal isn't to get rid of your testers. The goal is to improve
the way you ship, the way you deliver software so much that you need fewer or no,
or fewer dedicated testers, dedicated specialists. Totally agree. And actually like this AI trend,
I absolutely adore like there's another one that's a workshop. Like you used to do workshops.
I did. I did. This is a workshop where two guys are going to guide people through training
an AI model and even using basic, the, the, the basic scoring mechanisms that we,
we generally use in data science. Like I have gone through and had GPT write unit tests.
Like if, if I don't know if you've coded recently, but the, the GitHub co-pilot is fantastic.
I haven't played with it, but I, I've been meaning to, I don't, I don't, actually I'm going to write
some code this weekend, but not anything significant. So I don't even go into the project. So I will
want to play with that. All right, man. Well, that is good stuff. And this is stuff that again,
we would appreciate your input on, do we talk about, I guess talk about testing a little bit.
All right. Well, when, when I'm waiting, we'll see waiting. Ah, damn it. I like you.
I asked, um, I asked GPT to give me the number of worldwide test conferences in the last 10 years.
Okay. And, and it told you my cutoff is in 2019 or wherever. It's 2021, but no, it, it said,
no, I, I don't have the ability to do that. And then it gave me some random link to
IEEE conferences. So it was stupid. Like really, really bully it. What happened?
What happens when you, the thing is it doesn't care when you bully it. Just apologizes.
It'll probably tell me I'm done with this conversation.
Okay. Brent, do you know what episode this has been?
One 83.
Yeah. Cause it's in the title of our Zen Castro link. All right, everybody. Uh, we are going to call it
good, but please engage with us online and we will, you know, think about replying. No,
we'll reply for somebody else. Somebody will, somebody will talk to you.
There'll be a, maybe it's AI who knows. Yeah, really.
All right. I'm Alan. I'm Brent. We'll see you next time.
Bye.