Welcome to AB testing podcast your modern testing podcast your hosts Alan and Brent will be here to guide you through
Topics on testing leadership agile and anything else that comes to mind now on with the ship
Mary ho ho where that's not right. This is a it's December 24th and we're recording and and Brent's here and
So is Alan and they got my name, right? We're ready to go here
It's been another year of a B testing podcast. This is our our
Ultimate is if penultimate is next to last is ultimate the last this is the last show of 2024
Yeah, we reflect on the year and
Talk about you know stuff. I don't know. What do we do here? How's it going? It's going
Fantastic, how about you? It's it's going really really well, I think a whole lot of crap going on
Dog is crying behind me. She's gonna show up on the podcast this week. We got a lot to talk about
We got new stuff old stuff
Reflective stuff. We had a pretty fun year in the podcast which reflect on in a second, but yeah episode 213
Can you believe I mean what a frickin waste of time it is for us to get together
Every couple weeks and this podcast put it once twice. We do it 213 times over a little over 10 years
What are we doing? Yeah, what is that? I?
Don't know don't I've five five weeks over ten years five working weeks
Oh something like I don't know plus it's been it's been a long time
213 episodes
Sometimes they're good and the rest of the time it's like
Two people talking over beer even though it is actually we're ever late start today. It's 10 a.m. Yeah
No, well, normally we're recording much later. Yeah
We did yeah, we've been all over the place so
Anything else new and exciting to share before we get into all of our normal stuff I'll share it during
Yeah
Yeah, all right, okay what we like to do in last episode of the year is kind of reflect on the year
Talk about some of the highlights lowlights if we had them, but you know
Talk about some of our predictions last year. We didn't have very many
And we but we'll talk about those and then what do we think is gonna happen in?
2025 when the world falls apart
so I'm gonna walk through our Spotify wrapped for the ABI testing podcast and
I think the Spotify wrapped is
complete bunk because my I know my wrapped for my
Song to listen to was not right. I don't think it was right. But well my mine was totally right
Are you still listening to acoustic alchemy all the time? Nope
What was your top? What was your top artist?
My top artist was the yeah. Yeah. Yes
Very interesting. Very interesting. Yep
my top song
Was float on by the AAS. No float on it's interesting because
None of my top songs were from the AAS, but my top song was float on by modest mouse
Well, interesting and my second top song was ain't no rest for the wicked by cage the elephant
And it's interesting to me
That
both of those songs kind of
Express a similar emotion
Which was very relevant to me in 2024, but we're not at that section
It doesn't matter how good I feel or how bad I feel I always listen to
like my my jam is
just
People who singer songwriters who hate themselves?
Okay, there's a lot of those what's it? What's the current example? So I
I
Gotta think of one
Because my top artist isn't one they have some happy songs too, but they kind of fell
You know how Spotify very often of tangent already it will
Like some songs. Let's do go. Hey you like those songs you like this. That's alright
I'll listen to that for a while and I got I fell down a huge
Apparently a huge Casey Musgraves hole because Casey Musgraves should have my top artists, but I think that's wrong
I don't think I don't think it was that much
I don't know. I don't even know who that is. But if you know who like Elliott Smith
If you want to hear so yeah, yeah, Elliott Smith from the 90s
That that's that's the stuff I listen to all day or even even Sean Mullins
He had a little hit for a minute there in a while
But the singer songwriters who sing songs about you know, dogs dying things like that old deal are those from the same genre
No, Casey Musgraves kind of considered country or country pop and
Elliott Smith does more of I guess just call him indie folk or indie pop and and I would say that Sean Mullins is indie folk
But anyway before we go into somebody's gonna go. Oh, that's not indie. This is indie and shut up
I don't give a fuck. Let's talk about our podcast. So apparently we grew our listeners by 66% and
That means we went but if we went from three to four, I don't know. I still think we have three
No, we went from three to three. So so I'm gonna ignore that one
So 66% I'm assuming it's 66 repeated
Yeah, so that means we we went from three to three by increasing by two. All right
83% of our listeners something
Discovered our podcast this year. So but the numbers don't reflect that that doesn't make any sense
Your fans have a clear favorite
And I don't know why
but which
episode 202 the return I care what we even talked about that episode but that had for some reason
according to Spotify wrapped
999% more streams than our average episode
So I don't get I didn't look to see what the numbers were this stuff. Oh, I
Don't remember what we talked about. It's at the return of Jason Arbin. Maybe he pumped it up or something. I bet it was
Transcript hey Spotify has a transcript
So I don't think Jason was in this one, but we like the title is
organizational change which means
And we did a mailbag so maybe whoever we mail bagged for
Forwarded it on worth checking out worth checking out the wrapped itself is horrible this year because
There's no deep stats. It's all just top level stuff. Our top streaming country was the US. Yeah, right
Dumb things like 61% of our audience also watched a video on to modify this year. So here's the fun part
We are a top 10 podcast for
1000 listeners. Oh
How about that? Oh, okay. People have not updated there something. We're a top five. So we're a big fish in
We are a top five show for
851 fans what this is showing me is that the average A B testing listener does not listen to podcasts that often
We are we are the number one show for
353 fans
353 of the three listen to only one podcast. That's the A B testing podcast
Okay. Yeah, it's kind of these feel like weird stats. They they are super weird this year not happy
I'm done with those. I'm closing. I'm closing the wrapped window, but I shared it last year wanted to share it again
So that is our that's our episode for this week. Thank you all very much. No
I do want to look one of these windows. I have some notes from last year. I want to talk about
Oh
Before we do that what I mean, this is an easy answer. What was your what was your favorite A B testing podcast of?
of
It
I'll surprise you because I know what I'm supposed to say, which is my number two
My number one you're my number two
Yeah, and you're my number one
The episode with Dagna was oh she's a delight. Yeah that that was
2000 or not 2000
Where we walked through her book a lot of the times like when we get people on there. They're mostly on
Make we go. Okay, can we can we help this person hawk their wares and still have an interesting conversation?
Right and it's clear from their point of view hawking their wares is the primary
pivot with Dagna
Yeah, that was a that was a big part of it but her book I have it is
really good that conversation was
fantastic and
Very well, yeah, mine's actually ups. I have a copy also. It's really good
Yeah, and I feel like I walked while you're looking around for that doesn't matter it doesn't work for a podcast
Yeah, I felt like I mean I felt like I was getting coaching from her during the podcast you as do I
As as do I or did I okay?
I like that one a lot and I would be remiss if I did not say that are
the not just because it was our 200th episode but that we
we I
through the power of manipulation of statistics made sure that our 10 year anniversary our 200th episode and
our
Brent Brent just you know, if you only looked as good as I told to give us a little bobblehead that we got
Here's mine. But we managed to get our
200th podcast our our 10 year anniversary and our
1000th member of the slack community all on the exact same day
Did I manipulate things a little bit to make that work I did do we do we
Crush in like three podcast recordings in a week to make sure we could get there
Do we record at night at that night? Yes, we did all those things we but we made it happen
We made it happen because we wanted the stars to align we did we made or or did we?
Or is it like all the science fiction movies where you have this like all the moons on?
Planet zen bar are gonna align exactly at midnight at this time and we have to make sure we get there in time or else
The you know the catastrophic moment occurs. So yeah, that's the AB testing podcast
What other podcasts is listen to this year?
Oh
I just wanted the list off number 200 was my number two and then I also want to call out
Like literally all the ones with Jason were in
Positions, you know three to and whatever because I don't remember how we we did at least two with him
We did I think we did those were great discussions. Those are great discussions. He's a good guy. Hey Jason
What other podcasts do you listen to anything?
I I
Recently have followed suit with Alan
Yeah and got rid of
Xfinity
And so I don't know which things on on YouTube
I would count as podcast or not because they do podcasts on YouTube. I'm like, I'm like, I'm so confused
Listen to podcasts. I got a pot like it like the the one and only one I did this year
Was we started out at the beginning of the year was 60 songs that explained the 90s, which was a
fun
little podcast where he felt where he goes way beyond 60 songs, but
He talks about particular songs. Oh, yeah. I remember this talk. It was it was like
Musical anthropology. I greatly enjoyed that that podcast
Yeah, I should check that out. So yeah, I listened to too many podcasts. I'm gonna start weeding them out
But the new one I started listening to this year
I don't listen to every episode because they do two episodes a week and every episode is an hour and a half long
But but there's actually only 30 minutes of each episode of really good stuff is pivot podcast by Kara Swisher and Scott Galloway
They have some good
Good moderate sometimes sometimes absolutely not moderate opinions on you know, you know Kara Swisher she used to be
Major tech writer. She was like working with Walt Mossberg back in the day on and I read her book this year, too
Which is really good and Scott Galloway is just an asshole, but he's fun to listen to but anyway listen to that a lot this year
That's a political podcast
political tech comment, whatever is new because
Galloway is a professor somewhere doesn't matter
Filthy rich and
Kara Swisher is a tech writer, but super smart. It's like super super smart. I like them both a lot
So they're fun to listen to I like their rapport back and forth
They're like a really imagine if you and I were smart and we had really deep discussions about anything
That's them, but we're not capable of that. So we're like if they're the pros we are
Single a made not even single a ball. What are you before single a I don't know my sports that were little league
Junior high little league. All right. So listen to that one
Um, I don't think I thought I listened to fewer trivia podcasts because they're running out of time
And so just weren't warning as good. I was on a few trivia podcasts this year
Were you didn't announce them anywhere? But I did I one was a head-to-head one on
The throwback trivia was called a throwback trivia podcast. They do like
They do random questions from in 12 categories across
You know six decades like you get you pick a category and they roll a die and you get like it's okay
60s music and anyway, I I won the episode I was on
That was fun
I was on another podcast called
How did you get on the podcast? I support them on patreon so they they invite all their
In the same with trivial warfare, which is are probably the best podcast out there. They do a really good
They have really good commentary
Sometimes a little they're a little too proud of themselves that I like them and I was on that one one
So my team lost I had a really smart person with me and I drug them down and we lost on that one
So, yeah, I did that
Traveled a little bit. I don't know
What do you last year you had some good YouTube recommendations for me and one that stuck with me was Josh Wiseman
I still watch Josh Wiseman his videos really great cooking videos
Just really well done well produced a lot of fun to watch but what do you what even watching on the tube of use?
I have been mostly watching so
Ice-cream sandwich is
Okay, it's all one word ice cream sandwich
It's an it's an animator who kind of tells little stories and they're I'm using af as the kids would say
Still watch Josh. So watch Guga
Zach Friedman is another guy I'm watching a lot
It's it's old news for you
but
Last year got my daughter a 3d printer and it's the first time we've had a 3d printer and
in
Do you know the the thing?
Or the models known as grid finity. No, okay
very popular set of models for 3d printing and those were invented and then
open source licensed by Zach Freeman
And then whatever random Oh
My son's gotten me into I think it's called monster factory
Mon
It it's not great. Um, but it's fun what they do
Their whole shtick is they play game. They play games that have a character editor and
then they go in with the character editor and
they make it as
Ugly as they possibly can the character
And this is interesting and then they play the game and they invent sort of a backstory with with the character
It amuses my son and spending time with my son is important to me
Yeah, how about you I should look but I
Probably nothing new in my subscriptions on the tube
I got like everybody else I get pulled into the YouTube shorts all the time and they were
I do watch
Let me see what's in my subscription list, um, here's a good one
I watched this to be called five guys FC, which is this just these 20 something year olds in England playing in this
Six aside soccer league and they film it. It's kind of funny and there I don't know why I watch it
But now I watch it every time the ever sees it's funny Josh Wiseman
I
Watched I might have mentioned it before the only new one here is
Rick Beato who I probably mentioned him last year. He's a former musician producer
he does a lot of
Breaking apart songs and talking about why they work along with some interviews of musicians. He knows everybody
But he does a really good show on
On kind of how music how pop music is made and why stuff works and he'll listen to you
I love he'll listen to you like the Spotify top ten
Kind of cold and I'll play along with it and go. Oh, oh and I think it was
It was a Sabrina Carpenter song. He said he stopped it goes. Oh my god
That could be the first top ten pop song in the last ten years that has a key change
So little things and he goes, oh you're probably right. It's been a while. It's been a while
He has a serious. I don't think he does anymore
He used to do a series called what makes this song great
You know take some hit song from the last 20 or 30 years and he just break it down completely everything from the
everything from the music and lyrics and chords to the production to the
Just you know everything so really really interesting to see the production behind how the song was repaved. So that's another one
Anywho, I have a couple more I can share cuz sure you and
Then we then we need to talk about the year coming up. Sure
or
Okay
One the only political based one I have in here is by lady
shoe on head
As you know, I am neither left or right
She is left
But will throw shit at anyone and is funny
Like crap in my humble opinion
the nerd Forge
These are two Norwegian people who just make random shit
Like they did it. I did it. They did a
gigantic
reprint of Harry Potter
Where?
Literally, the book was like three feet tall and they just combined all of the books and reprinted them and they and they walked through
How they they'd leather bound it and how they
Prep the leather and how they formed the stitching and I'm like, okay, that's fascinating. I already mentions that Friedman
Musically, I have two in here
a
Davy 504 who's just a fantastic bassist who who
who's
When you have a comedic pair the guy
That's sort of the silent one that always straight man straight man
He's he's he's got the he's kind of got a straight man attitude, which is funny
and then the charismatic voice which is a
opera
an opera singer who does
sort of reaction videos around
Music videos across a span of
Genres what's that one called?
charismatic voice
The charismatic is fine. Go ahead and finish. I'll tell you about some of these. Oh, I have seen her
Here's my view on that. Mmm
I don't you know, there's a bunch of these out there. There's a whole genre on YouTube of I'm gonna I
Never heard this song before I'm gonna listen to it for the first time
And I think it's all I think it's largely staged
It's largely there. It's largely entertainment
You know and some of the stuff they point some of the stuff she points out even as complete BS
Some of it's actually interesting but but the entertainment factor top-notch the factual factor me
Again it's entertaining
It's interesting. Yes, it's entertaining
but yeah, but anyway, and she has a crap ton of
Views and listen to it's about entertainment. Not here is here is the state of the world in
As I go off and this could be about anything about YouTube videos or you know politics whatever
The entertainment factor has far outweighed the need for things to be accurate. Oh
Oh
Yeah, and and that and that's that's what I think about the curious man. That's where well, I don't know
I mean, oh, I'm not saying I'm not saying it's as bad as politics. What I'm saying is
entertainment getting getting views getting clicks and
Even even the meat in the media does this across both sides and down the middle
The goal is to get clicks and reads because they're trying to make money. It's not about being accurate
News week especially is horrible at sensationalist headlines, but they're all over the internet. They do these they they
purposely either ignore facts or
Change facts in order to get more views and clicks. That's what's happening with with what's your face the charismatic voice
That's what happens in what you and not just political but all over the place. He's saying that's what's happening with her
Oh because she's she's wrong some of the times
She's trying to be entertaining and she's very entertaining, but she's also you said you hadn't seen her. Oh, I have seen her
Oh, okay. No, I have seen her. Okay. I had to bring her up. Yep. I've seen her talk about stuff
She's a lot very entertaining, but not always accurate. That's my that's my take
Okay
All right. There's there is
Anyway, okay. Great. So speaking of lies moralize and lies disguised as statistics
What are some of the things we should talk a little bit about what are some of the things you think are gonna happen in
In the world will get more specific on the A B testing podcast. What things are gonna happen in the world in 2025?
well
We kind of skipped over reflection on 20 for let me pause that was there more reflection on 24
Well, let's do that. I'm sorry. Let's do that. Well, I'm gonna edit this. Let's go back on 24
24 was a big year. We talked about the podcast in 24, but not much else
Right in the only the only big thing
For 2024 so it's finally closed
Alan's known about this for a year and a half. We've we've not talked about it
And I'm not gonna I don't want this to be a downer episode
but on December 11th, I
Have completed my divorce
And
accordingly
Kind of sucked
So
Yeah, so I
I'm not gonna go into a whole lot of detail on the suck a tube there not in this episode anyway
the completions gotta feel
something
It feels
Yeah, I keep reminding myself repeatedly
That every time a door closes a new one opens
Yes, right. Um
Right, it's it is easy
to
To think about the future and if you're in the wrong frame of mind
Go quite apocalyptic
Pretty quickly
So that's
That's the the number one thing
I'm focusing on not going apocalyptic but realizing that in battling against it
Yeah, yeah, I can see that it was a lot long long path
Well, and on that lovely note, but yeah, yeah
I don't know what to say. You don't say congratulations, but it's a it's definitely a milestone. I'm not sure what to say about it
It is what it is. I don't think I think the listeners were afraid you're in divorce me, but
No, no, no, no, that's that's not 20 24
That's a 2025 thing yeah, we'll get there we'll figure who gets fired first
Ha anything else from 20 I gotta think in my 24 I did the the Wonderland trail again
I did I tell you this on the podcast that I attempted to do another section of the the PCT for much
I have to die
Steven's past to so call me past and my water filter broke and it was just too hot for me to try and
Fake it through there. So ended up bailing a little early, but I'll go back and finish that sometime you should have a I
Don't know what you're using is your water filter, but they're small. I mean you should have a backup
Yeah, I think
so as a
Nobody's the van of hikers and listeners for this overlap. I use a one called the Sawyer squeeze which works out really well
I don't know why mine just decided to puke
But they're not that much but they also make a Sawyer squeeze mini which is even smaller and lighter
But they kind of suck because the the flow is so awful, but it's so it's like a couple ounces
It would be it would make sense to just carry an extra one
Just in case like the odds of your especially if you're using it every day the odds of your water filter dying are pretty low
But having the the lighter weight one
Kind of just sticking in the bottom of a bag somewhere just in case would would have would have been super helpful
What do you do for fire?
The fires aren't allowed most of the places I go. So I have a oh, I see I have a little a little stove
I've a little called a pocket rocket and it's teeny
I don't have here but it's just all it is
It's just a little screw thing and a couple little it's hardly anything to it weighs like an ounce
and you screw that on top of the fuel canister and light it and
That's where I get heat from I have also done hikes before where I did not cook anything just cold soaked everything
That gets a little old after a while
So it's worth it for the extra weight a lot of people who like a lot. They just get nuts around weight
They want to see how light they can get everything so they carry nothing and what I've discovered in my experimenting with this is
Like these folks that carry nothing. They're carrying about nine pounds of weight on their backpack including the pack and
For me I can carry two more pounds, which isn't that much and I can be
Comfortable I can have a little bigger sleeping pad. I can have a stove. I have camp shoes
I take off my wet shoes at night
It's not that much you can look at oh, it's like 20% extra weight
Nine pounds and 11 pounds. It's easier for me to lose 20% extra weight
When it's the difference when the 20% is two pounds, right?
Yeah, that's one of the things I bring up in data science all the time
Like what's the important number? Is it the percent or is it right unit?
The thing I bring up because I get this question sometimes from folks and they say
They'll ask well
Wouldn't you like to use that 12 pounds down to 10 pounds and I say I
Will be more I mean you want me to carry two pounds extra weight
I will just go lose two pounds of body weight and keep the comfort
Right and keep the comfort and safety like these folks will sleep like I have I have a tent
it's light, but I have a tent and
My tent is made so it'll stand up with with trekking poles, but I don't like them there
So I thought a bike trip once I use the tent and I got some actual regular poles for it
They're great
It also means I can pick up the whole tent and move it if I don't like where it is
So I I carry poles it's extra, you know 11 ounces
But some people like I don't need a tent. I just need a tarp to sleep under
I'll just string this up like they're just this ultralight is like no, I'm not comfortable there
I kind of like being totally enclosed when I'm out in the middle of nowhere
I don't want bugs and mice crawling up on my sleeping bag. Yeah, I mean I
Was just thinking okay just a tarp, huh?
Do you have like barbecue sauce scented like deodorant or something?
Like just to lather it up for the bears
I mean not that the tents gonna really do anything in terms of bear protection, but no
But but the bugs for certain the bugs for certain. Yeah, there's just no way so anyway
Okay, I buy a pack fully loaded is about 11
Touch over 11 pounds and but that gives me all the comfort I need which is fine. It's still really light
That's not including food or water
That adds weight to so anyway, I'm 24. I did that I didn't do much else
I think your dog is trying to dig into your couch. Oh, she insists on making her bed. She has
She's a burrowing gotcha
Yeah
Try it she's trying to make it nice. Okay, so let's I don't think anything else exciting in 2024
Let's talk about 2025. Let's do the world first software and then a be testing podcast
What's something you think will happen in the world in 2025?
Okay, we'll do that one I
Can chat GPT what's gonna happen no, I'm reorganizing my list, okay
my theme for 2025 is
On that topic is death death to the uni party long live the uni party
Okay, tell me tell me more
right well
One version of the uni party just got kicked out of office a new version of it just got
Brought in
I do not think the sky will fall
Whether that is a bullshit affirmation or not. We will find out
But again because of my reflection in 2024
God damn it 2025 is Brent Jensen's year of hope so I don't care what else happens. I
Will find the hopeful way of viewing it. I do not think the sky will fall
but
it's
Yeah, things are gonna change
that's
like
generally
World stuff do I think Ukraine will stop like I would very much like to see
the two major wards
Stop, I would like 2025 not to be the year of World War three
Yeah
So I see three world threats right now
Like I'm continuously afraid of China trying to take Taiwan
Will you can war in I don't know
We can't know but I it's a worthwhile thing to talk about. I think we both agree that
Both of those major wars should stop. Yeah, I think it's I think it's
It's likely I think the Israeli one will stop
This really Palestine I think that one will will will likely stop next year
Well, here's what I mean, I think the politics are more complicated
Particularly with Russia bringing in North Korea. I think I think it gets interesting
With the new administration because it could just be that Trump pulls the plugs on all the US funding to Ukraine and Putin steamrolls them
And it's over so could be
And then and Trump will take credit for stopping the war in Ukraine and his his fans will worship
but I think it's actually a reasonable chance that I
Actually, you know what after the election? I did two things the highly related one is I removed the politics subreddit from my subreddit feed
I read it food and then I kind of stopped going to read it very often
I just I stopped checking the news. I just can't
I just can't it's it's the potential and this is again going back to the news
But the potential of very bad things to happen
is very high and
It's higher at me looking at it does not make it
More likely or less likely of the bad things to happen. It just raises my anxiety
so I look at enough to know what's going on in the world and
Just try and ignore the headlines because they're there to get a reaction out of me
It's kind of like I
Think we've talked about art before here and did you paint it all in 2024? No, so art
Yeah, enough stuff other stuff going on
art is
The piece of art isn't the art the art is the reaction of someone viewing that
Sculpture painting banana duct tape to the wall. That's the art. The art is the interpretation of what's there same with music
Why John which is art by the way?
I'm aware. Thank you. Yeah, but it's not the piece itself. It's it's how is it felt like when Stravinsky premiered the Rite of Spring in
Paris there were riots. That's a reaction to art because it was so different than anything else
I could was bad they listen today. This is fucking cool. But back then I was like what a minute my cheese got moved too much
so I think it's the same thing I you know I
Internet headlines or art
It's not the headlines just words on the page
It's how those are interpreted by people is is the reaction and those things get clicks and those things get money
And that's not going to get fixed in 2025. So I am
Moving myself as much as I can from looking at those things because I don't want to be part of I don't want to contribute
To that art. I don't want to be yet another person reacting to something in a way
that is
Irrelevant to the underlying facts
the I don't think
I was thinking in terms of a data science like to me
Like there's a lot of place where crowdsourcing
Data science is able to show crowdsourcing this benefit. I do not think news is one of those things. Yeah
like I think it is
It's a massive echo chamber
in
So, yeah, I get I get where you're coming from like what part of your speech reminded me early on in this in
2024 I I came across
Have we talked about the stoics or the stoicism? Oh, I don't know if we have but I have spent a lot of time
Reading about stoics this year interestingly, so please go. Yeah, so did I earlier this year?
um, and one of the things that really resonates with me is one of their key tenets is
only
Control the things you can control right and you cannot control outcomes
Right, that's it
one million percent and
And they felt there was no point in having an emotional response to any outcome at all because you're
It's nothing you control
Yes, and in fact
Go ahead. Yeah, no, I would like to do an episode maybe our next one sometime on
Stow system in modern testing. So let's let's pencil it in that would be fun. Let me thank you for bringing that up
As far as other things like world stuff
I don't know. I don't know. I'm trying not to pay attention trying to
Yeah, I don't have a good thing there. But how about let's talk about the world of software
So which is gonna be largely around Gen AI
But what's different a year from now in the world and one thing I said last year just to bring this up
I didn't quite happen, but I still think it's true
was
That you you you wrote down our predictions from last year, right? Oh, there's there's somewhere around here
but I kind of went through most of one of them was that I think that the ability to read code and
interpret it and and and
not interpret read it and
Critique it is going to become more important than writing code and I think that's actually true today people just won't admit it yet
I think we can rely on Gen AI to generate large amounts on all large amounts of our code
But we have to be able to see in the articles this year on and the research showing that
There's lots of bugs in this Gen AI generated code
which means that we haven't shifted yet people haven't able to take this Gen AI code and and
Look at it and fix it or look and see why it's wrong or why it doesn't apply and yeah
But I think Gen AI has has dramatically changed both
right how I said priority though, I
Didn't you that that
Reading is gonna be a higher priority than no I said it's gonna be a it's gonna be a more more important skill
Yeah, what we're gonna use. Okay, and more important sure
Reading is going to become more important than writing
Yeah
And I don't know if that occurred because I think I think it's I
Like the fact that you put more important because I think that's true
Right because I've seen reading and writing
Being done through LOM quite often
like even in my own own
coding I
am using
GitHub co-pilot just a lot more
and
It's mostly because I find that it's a great education tool. I go. Oh
How would you improve the perf of this and it generates?
Code options for me and I look at and I go. Oh, whoa
I didn't even know that class could do that like there was one example
where I had a
nested a two level nested loop so n squared
Mm-hmm, and it got rid of the whole damn loop and I'm like and it's because it used
Part of an interface of a class that I didn't even know existed and I'm like, oh
Thank you GPT. You know, we made my code better, but you upleveled me
It's actually really that's a good story. We need more stories like that. I
The it's a rare story honestly because I can also see places where where
I'm very actively paying attention to my own interaction with GPT
Because I can see places where intellectual laziness comes in
Right when it when it comes to interviews
Like my stick at interviews used to be no, I don't remember much. I'm old and
Like I haven't remembered much
In the interview basis since 30s my 30s
But I know where to find it right? I'm not a rookie in the industry. Don't ask me how to
It's not important for the type of jobs that I do to have to traverse a doubly linked list
right
But if if in the real world we need a doubly linked list
I know how to
You know do find the go through my reference materials and then we'll build one. Well now I don't even need that right? It's
GPT generate me a class that I can use as a doubly linked list it like
I've never actually done that but that would be something I have very little doubt that it will do well
Okay, so what's gonna happen? Tell me something. It's gonna happen in the world of software in 2025
Here are my three big predictions and I have three and I wrote them down
I do not heard so much more prepared than me, but so prepared. Please tell please chair. Okay, I do think
we are
Officially at the beginning of the end of the data science era officially God
Yeah, I feel like I've talked about this for a few years, but please go on elaborate
Yeah, no, I so I think 2025 will be the year
where data science
Scientists who can't actually code
to say a bachelor's CS degree level
Will not get hired. I believe 2025 is the is it won't be formally constructed as such but 2025 is
The unofficial year where data science becomes a specialization within death. Okay, I agree
Um
number two, I believe in here I'm
Soft and fuzzy. Okay, I believe the first major instance of
L. O. M. Causing a human harm or safety issues
Because its controllers don't know what they're doing
Will occur in 2025 and I don't know if I completely fucked the grammar with that sentence
But I think you got what I'm saying. I do I do and I think
Unfortunately, you're right, but we'll see what happens and then lastly I think
RTW
Will become a much bigger thing. I mean return to work. Yeah, talk to me more about that
And
Here I think it's because of the new
I think that's a tenant an old-school tenant of the new that
The on the onboarding version of the Uni Party. I think that will be become
far more politically correct to
Force everyone back to work. Huh honestly
What do you mean by so this is a good one to discuss because we may have talked about in a long time enough a ton of
time today, but everyone is a lot of people what about orgs that don't even have offices or
Like there's not even an office for me. We'll be fine
They'll be fine
Because if they started off with that as a key tenant, then I think they'll be fine
I think well, I think these people these companies that have all of this office space
That's going on utilized. I have an idea for that
Never sure this is freely available
I had an idea because we work kind of they're still around but they kind of died during the pandemic as well
I would love all this unused office space
Here's my idea. We work buys it like sometimes I want to go to an office. I'm gonna go to the house
I don't have a place to go
What I would like a company to do say a company I'll say I'll pick a generic company
ACME software company what I can do is for my I
Buy a certain number of credits like, you know for my thousand-person company
I'll buy you know 10,000 credits that we work and what that means is my employees then can choose to go to these offices
It's kind of like a gym membership
And I can pay these companies and my employees when they want to go to an office and work and be around people
They do their work and have internet and a conference room
They can book where they don't have an office to go to they can go to an office
And that would I could I think what I think is I think there's a lot of people who would like to go to an office
But if you're gonna rent a place that we work it's like every day and it's expensive
I think I think there's a way to do sort of a subscription service of of office rental
There's some details to figure out and I'm not enough of the innovator and entrepreneur to figure this out
It's been done already by there's got to be a way to use these like downtown in Seattle
especially sounds to go dead because so many people aren't going back to work and very similar in the two cities because
The people that used to work there have don't live anywhere near the cities because it's so expensive to live in the cities
They live farther away and it's expensive to commute to work
Right, right. Yeah, so I I don't we're gonna talk more about that throughout the year about curious to see what happened there
We almost time here. Do you have a picture here? So what we'll see is
I
Do you think like I realized myself just in the last couple of months?
right the
so I have my own leadership team that reports to me and
We just have a better meeting when we are all in the same room. Absolutely. Absolutely
So the question is why aren't we putting more effort into teaching people how to have a successful virtual meeting?
Like it's doable. It's doable. I've been very good
Figure it out myself. Yeah, I think people just kind of forward in I think that one of the challenges
I fully agree on why there would be a reason to go back to work and I think people are just frickin lazy
Remote, I mean, oh my god. So many people is the thing that kills me if you're in a meeting room
And remember the old days somebody we're gonna go a little bit over here
Somebody be on a laptop in a meeting say hey close the laptop. No, whatever
Because we're virtual then the people multi and you know
multitasking during a meeting like I'm so frickin tired of repeating myself for someone because they couldn't be bothered to pay attention in
It's ridiculous
Anyway, I want to have a whole other thing about there. So they're like
There I think bringing in
Open space principles. Yep
If you can't be bothered to pay attention to the meeting then why are you get the hell out like get the hell out
unwritten rule
There should be an unwritten rule
Where like a socially charged rule where where people are like if you're not actively paying attention
Yeah, get out get out. I think it's laziness
Shouldn't have to kick you out. You should feel guilty and get out. I think people are lazy. Okay very quickly because then I got
What's your predictions? I don't have any whatever I comment on yours
podcast what exciting things are we looking forward to in 2025
All right. I did the last topic that one's you okay once again
I'm every year I say I'm gonna I'm gonna get the it's like asking the hot girl out
I'm that was I was really sexist
If I'm so afraid to ask Nicole for his grin again, that sounds weird in context
But I'm such a huge uber fan of Nicole for his grim that I've been afraid to ask her actually
I don't know how to get a hold of her, but I really like to have her on the podcast at some point
We gotta do that I feel like I committed to helping on that one. Yeah, that's right
You have you have her email address right didn't she did can't you just like send her a message on on?
I could I think I could teams are right now. Let me see
I think we will have
We're gonna have a lot like connecting with her
Okay, not right now
Well, we're gonna have an odd recording schedule in 2025 because I have vacations and weird stuff going on
We'll probably talk more about that throughout the year and then that's all I got
Those are my I don't have really much going on there
We're gonna get to
We're gonna get more people listening but more people wondering why the hell do we have a podcast when we just talk about nothing for an hour
That's it. All right, Brit. Yep. Anything anything else before we go for the day? No, I can she's
It's all right. It's nobody's looking at it's holiday year. Of course, of course, of course
Alright, this has been episode 213 of the EBT testing podcast last episode of
2024 I hope everybody has a happy holiday. This will go out probably on Christmas Day. We'll see what happens. I am Alan
I'm great and we'll see you next time