Welcome to A.B. testing podcast, your modern testing podcast.
Your hosts, Alan and Brent, will be here to guide you through topics on testing,
leadership, agile, and anything else that comes to mind.
Now on with the show.
Hey, everyone. I'm Alan. No, I'm not. From now on, I will only be referred to as spy.
I do not answer to my government name anymore. Please don't use me that name.
I will correct you. Brent isn't here. There's no B.
So we have Bani, Bani, Bani fought and Bondreas.
I have Andreas Varming and Danny thought are here to talk about stuff with me
because I felt like doing a podcast. Welcome. Say a quick little intro.
Say hi, everybody. And something, something interesting.
Go Danny, you're up. Hi, I'm Danny.
This is my second time appearing on this stream,
but the first time on the actual podcast. So that's very exciting for me.
Glad to have you here, Andreas.
Yeah, Global Varming is a nickname on the slack.
And it's almost second time here. We have like a suite for three or something.
And I hope I don't embarrass myself like last time.
I embarrass myself every single day.
So if this is your first episode, this is weird because this is our first episode
in maybe close to six months. I can't count that high.
I was gone for four and a half months, took a long walk, had some fun,
met some cool people, saw a lot of animals. It's pretty much it.
Got back about a month ago. There's a map over your shoulder.
You know, intriguing.
Yeah, there's a map over my shoulder of the Pacific Crest Trail.
It's been there forever.
It was there for six months before I told my last company I was leaving.
They just never nobody ever asked.
And then I can say this now.
So I think I might have been clear about this on the last.
I can't remember. It's the week to week is gone from the last podcast.
But because it was six months ago, a last job wasn't a good fit for me.
I am unemployed right now, so that's worse, I guess.
But one of the things I figured out on the trail was that for my next role,
I want a job that I really like and I feel like I'm valued,
that I have fun at and do what I'm best at.
What I'm best at is building engaged teams
and people who like to grow the career, understanding how that works
and building good software.
And my last gig, they kind of didn't care about either. And my
when I left that job, my blood pressure was high like it was when I left Microsoft.
And now I went to get a physical a month ago after I got back.
And like my health is like the best it's ever been in my life.
My blood pressure is like ridiculously low and good.
So I'm going to keep this healthy living going,
even if I can't get up and walk 20 miles every day.
So you're looking really good right now, Alan.
Yeah, I'm feeling good. I'm feeling good.
I I will tell you, and this is probably is going to be a whole story about
trail stuff that we'll get some we'll get some leadership and software stuff in there, too.
But I've always known I've done a lot of hundred mile hikes before I did the 2600 mile hike.
And one thing I really figured out is that
that time like somebody told me this one, so I'll tell a story here.
Said the legs are for walking, the heart is for beating blood, the lungs are for air
and the brain is for thinking.
And when you're just walking and you let the brain wander and think,
you figure shit out and it's great.
And really got a chance.
I thought about the job stuff a lot, thought about myself a lot.
Yeah, I just the way I put it from the following my sub stack post,
plug here, anger, we will the sub stack dot com.
Go read my stuff, subscribe.
It's free.
And I just stripped away all the BS out of my out of my brain.
So it's like this this Zen.
Oh, I mentioned
spy is my trail name on the PCT.
I got so used to being called spy when people use my other name,
my government name, it sounds weird.
So I am spy.
And this is a normal occasion that people give themselves trail names.
They don't give yourself a trail name.
Somebody gives you a trail name
and you can reject it and they may stick or they may not stick.
So spy stuck a wonderful couple.
Yeti and Spout from Philadelphia gave me the trail name spy and it stuck.
And that's who I was.
But somewhere in Oregon, I kind of like the pieces fell into place.
And then I became Zen spy.
So now I'm like, I'm just like doing the Zen thing, doing the spy stuff.
And being called spy is cool because when you bust out of the woods
someplace after, you know, things you do in the woods off the trail,
somebody says, like, hey, where did you come from?
I said, doing spy stuff. I can't tell you.
So it's really great. So anyway, it is revealed.
That's what I've been up to.
I've been back.
I've been kind of looking for jobs.
I'm being selective because, like I said, I want to do something that
I want to do some work that matters.
Work that I care about.
I have enough savings.
I can take my time in doing that.
But I I feel like I do want to work some more someplace and make some things happen.
So I'm going to poke around and see what happens.
I will let it's of course, as you know, it's a weird time of the year
to looking for jobs, not a little people are hiring in Q4,
but I will keep my eyes open, my ears open, activate the network
and see what I can find.
So is it as difficult to get an interview
as for an executive level job as it is for management or programmer
and that sort of thing?
I I think so.
I don't know because I'm I'm looking for VP level jobs still and
I've had a recruiter screen so far.
I haven't really ever really applied for that many jobs.
And but it's it's definitely a different.
It's definitely a different
vibe than it was a couple of years ago.
I've never like here.
Here's this is I don't.
This is not a humble brag or anything, but I've never
I haven't applied for a job since I started at Microsoft many, many years ago.
It was the worst way to get it.
They talk to me.
They talk to me about a job that I was hired.
Oh, yeah, we need your resume.
So, OK.
And when I went to NBC, again, the recruiter contacted me.
I'm sort of used to having recruiters.
They're just not doing it anymore.
Like I would get a recruiter ping every week like, hey, I'll talk about this.
I say, oh, no, not right now.
Not not the best time.
But there's none of that.
I'm actually doing the legwork myself and actually
spending time tweaking my resume.
It's weird. It's good. It's fun.
What's not fun, but I'm also.
But also my general routine is I get up in the morning,
I feed the dog, have a little coffee, walk down to the gym, work out,
stop and play pickleball on the way home with the retirees,
come back home, look at a few jobs, apply.
Maybe usually I find like one a day ish, probably on average.
I want to apply to I poke around.
I think about like blog posts or newsletter articles I want to ride.
Right. Do some reading, take another walk with the dog.
It's kind of a good life, but I do.
I am starting to miss working as every day goes by.
So coming along.
So hang out with those.
So good.
But is your privilege in that way that you have like that?
You can take your time that you can like figure out the stuff
that can write stuff, get like there might be some some
the blocks and LinkedIn posts of that that get recruiters to you.
Maybe right. Yeah, maybe.
I hope so. I hope that, you know, my inner hope is that someone
and I put my sub stack in my resume and it's on LinkedIn.
I would love like I would love to get hired by a place that comes to me.
It's like, hey, I like what you wrote.
I want to see how you apply this to a team like my my H.R.
screen, my recruiter screen last week.
They really had no idea who I was.
It's like, are you still working someplace?
You all know, I was like, man, pay attention to your homework.
Like I did mine. You do yours.
That fair. Am I asking too much?
You're asking more than you're going to get.
Eh, that I don't care.
So I don't know the kind of the kind of stuff that you say that you're best
and that you want to do should be like the first thing on your CV.
Right. That everybody should be able to like this would be the headline.
Right. I build and gauge teams.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
So hanging out with those pickleball players,
are they trying to draw you into their ranks and join the retirees?
Oh, no, I'm in there. I'm in their group chat now.
And all they are.
They are. I'm hanging out with them. They are funny.
So they're ruthless.
I'm getting good enough now where the where some of the retirees will cheat a little
and I don't care. I'm just there to have fun and get some exercise.
But like it's, you know, it's it's not a bad life.
It's not a bad life.
I just think having some pickleball.
Oh, like something's obviously in the go out or just stuff like that.
Like or little things, little things.
I don't care. Or it doesn't matter. I don't care.
I just want to have fun. So I don't care.
So, yeah. So what's what's exciting going on in your world, Danny?
I actually did hear from a recruiter.
I'm seeing more of that the last several months.
I mean, so not much, but it's a thing that's starting to happen again.
So, yeah, I'm I'm still still on the lookout to fill up my schedule more.
I did a tiny bit of consulting with a startup, which was really cool.
And I'd like to do more of that.
I even put it on my LinkedIn because the recruiter said, well,
if you're doing that thing, why don't I see that thing?
Well, it wasn't much of a thing, but sure.
So, yeah, looking for love to get my consulting going again.
It would be a different kind of consulting than what I did before.
More, you know, developer development focus then then testing exclusively.
But, you know, if a fun full time thing comes along, then I'll consider that too.
Yeah, I must say one thing about that.
I don't hear it's anything of you, Andreas, but what I thought about going
and doing some consulting myself, I'm kind of tired of paying my own health insurance,
but I guess I can keep doing that.
But I mean, the problem is the people I could help
probably aren't listening to the podcast.
If you want me to go help your team learn how to deliver with fewer testers
or or or get rid of dedicated test teams or
I could I could I've done that so many times I can help you figure that out
and I could do it in a way that improves velocity and quality.
But those people are not the people listen to the podcast.
Those are the people that hate the podcast on principle.
So I got to work on how to find those people because I could do that.
I could do that.
And I could do that job while going to the gym
and playing pickleball with retirees and helping them out.
That'd be great. Yeah. So I'll figure that out.
You know, when I was consulting, I got at least half of my business
from like you were talking about from writing and people just would Google.
I want help.
I want to learn how to do this and this.
And Google would say, oh, here read this thing that Danny wrote.
And then I would get a consulting gig out of it.
But I guess they're they're not googling for podcasts
or they're not clicking on the podcast link.
So the maybe actually when they're googling,
they're getting an answer now. So I don't know.
Oh, and they're not saying transcripts are like index. Sure.
Why not? Like, sure.
It doesn't say I learned this from Alan and Brent.
So no, it does. And I'll figure it out because it isn't just that that I do.
That's just something I could do that's easy.
I I'm good at organizational change.
If you want to take your team from A to B,
I'm really good at that.
One thing I struggle with my last job is they wanted to go from A to A.
A was fine. Like, that's fine. Whatever.
But that's not for me.
I don't want to take it from A to A.
Andres, what have you been up to lately? What are you doing?
Yeah, what just happened?
My boss a bit was like his his patent panic.
Online e-commerce startup thing.
Otherwise, like I've been working as freelancer before.
Basically, the freelance market is like quite dead here in Germany.
Like nothing is happening.
Like the the hourly rates are dropping very hard.
Everybody's scared.
Everybody's like looking for a permanent employment.
Now, I mean, everybody, but I'm maybe on the low key
looking for a permanent employment somewhere.
But nothing, nothing.
All these people and nobody's working.
Yeah, I don't know.
But at least like when on the full full time employment side of things.
At least my skills seem to be at least like still look for looked after.
So yeah, let's see.
Still crazy scary time.
It's a weird time. Yeah.
Off off. I'm not worried yet.
I don't think I'm worried.
I am because I'm not if I was out of money and
which I'm not yet, I am spending a little bit more than I'd like to of my savings.
I do. I just I really, really want to be selective
and find a place that I like.
I'm probably not going to work a lot longer.
I do not. I'm not going to work till I'm 65.
I'm not going to pickleball is calling pickleball is calling.
But I do I do want to work a little more because I think I'm good at what I do.
And I want to find some places to do it.
But I'm going to I'm not going to go someplace that wants to be a cog in a machine.
I'm better if I can go drive a culture change and take your team from good to
great or from great to awesome or from awesome to elite.
So that's what I'm going to do.
I'm going to go find that. I don't know where it is.
I'll figure it out.
So not too worried. That's for a matter.
Why why you have time?
Like maybe as a suggestion to try to get the transcripts
indexed somehow.
So if anybody's looking for a culture change and like how to
deal with that, they find me.
I'm going to see if I can figure out how to do that.
Because the transcripts, I think, should be since all the episodes
are in Spotify now, they do a little live transcript.
I might be able to figure this out.
Yeah, make it Google a little note.
It'd be interesting.
But I don't know if and here's I don't think I care.
I don't know if I'm a recruiter.
Am I going to Google to find candidates?
No, I have 10,000 people applying for every single job.
I don't know if I'm going to Google and look for candidates.
I don't know how people I need to think about this some more.
And listeners, all three of you, oh, shit, two are on the episode.
The other listener out there, if
you want to give me ideas on how to make myself more discoverable, like
there are I guarantee you, I guarantee you right now, there are half a dozen or more
companies who need someone exactly like me.
They don't know it yet, or maybe they do.
But if they did, how would they find me?
That's what I got to figure out.
So anyway, that's my plan.
If I can subject change, I want to and Danny, especially I want to tee this up for you.
Uh, the, the modern test, the modern testing principles, which is, we know are not about
testing and not really that modern.
They're just around software delivery in a world where, um, things are moving very,
very quickly.
These came about historically because Brent and I, Jesus, 10 years ago now,
we're seeing changes happening in delivery that we saw the writing on the wall about
what was going to happen with test rules.
They were going these at the time, Microsoft probably still had 10,000
testers when we started the podcast or close to it.
And we saw a world where testing could be owned by developers.
Uh, data from a customer telemetry could, uh, substitute for a lot of testing and
the ability to get feedback very rapidly daily or up to hundreds of times a day
meant that those large test teams probably weren't going to exist.
And we were right, uh, which is weird because Brent and I aren't that smart,
but we were right.
We saw the way software was delivered changing and there are people that are
good at testing who will always be gainfully employed because they can one
apply that critical thinking and do, and I'm going to come back to critical
thinking, they can help their teams.
They can either by helping developers do better testing or by, or helping
people see the big picture or by doing some of that work themselves.
That's always going to exist.
The days of test teams that equal the size of dev teams, focusing as a,
as a gate to release, they're gone.
I mean, I know they still exist at some companies, but they're basically gone.
Teams aren't delivering that way anymore.
So way back when, uh, I remember I read Ray Dalio's principles and it came up
to these modern testing principles that again, aren't modern, aren't about
testing and we've tweaked them a little bit over time, but they're pretty
much the same.
We're trying to make them apply to the whole team.
We wrote them originally, like here's how testers can think about
surviving in this new world.
I'm not going to read them all, but one just came up in a LinkedIn discussion
yesterday, not even a pick on the people that I'm going to tell you where
to find it, but it's one that's oddly controversial, oddly controversial.
So principle five, we believe that the customer is the only one capable
to judge and evaluate the quality of our product, which I probably, I, I
gotta, I'm not going to go edit this and get a beep out of here, but,
but this one freaks people that F out.
They go, Oh my God, you're making the customer test our software.
No, we're not.
So Danny, you are one of the experts in the world.
I know of on the writing of Jerry Weinberg.
What is Jerry Weinberg says quality is it's, um, let's see if I can get
the wording right.
Um, value to some person.
Did I remember that right?
You did.
And then some folks have even added value to some person that matters.
I'm going to ask you both this question.
It's rhetorical, but you could answer it anyway.
If I'm building software for a customer who matters the most, the customer.
How about that?
What I don't flip and understand is why people who the same people that
added the who matters to this.
And like, this is a, to me, and I, I just, it just blows my mind.
The people that tout themselves on critical thinking and blah, blah, blah.
And I, I hate to pick on them because I kind of don't care about their world very
much, but when they flip out over, they call this principle irresponsible.
Or whatever.
And then yet in the same breath, they can say quality is
value to some person that matters.
The tester doesn't matter.
I mean, I'm not saying testers don't matter in this case,
tester doesn't matter.
Testers do good work and, but it doesn't matter how well you've tested something.
I gave a talk 15 years ago at a conference and said, testers don't care about like
remember when software shipped in boxes?
It's maybe it was 20 years ago.
So you don't put it on the side, 90% code coverage, 87% of the
test passed, blah, blah, blah.
No, they don't care about that.
They care if it solves their problem.
It brings them value because it's offers for them.
They matter and it solved their problem.
The tester certainly can help with all that.
But to say that someone besides the customer is better able to evaluate
quality, eh, not really true.
So I did want to soapbox that because I saw it last night and I thought about,
I thought of replying and I do not engage in LinkedIn conversations.
It is not worth the effort because some people on LinkedIn just, I mean,
this is what I hate is when Twitter went away, X, basically Twitter went away.
And for me, it started bringing all of their BS conversations to LinkedIn.
And I'm not here for it.
It's gross.
Now I have to go to LinkedIn and see if there's any jobs available, but I'm
actually finding all the good jobs are on indeed and elsewhere.
So I kind of stay away from LinkedIn, but I went there last night.
I was bored.
I was weak and I fell into a trap thoughts.
I find good stuff on LinkedIn.
I avoid the nonsense.
I don't know about you.
How do you avoid the nonsense?
Is there a nonsense filter I'm missing?
Well, I mean you, you sense that it's nonsense.
And then you scroll.
Oh, the, um, as soon as you start scrolling, you're lost though.
Right.
Uh, you know, I do make a point of who posted this because I might have to come
back to their profile and find it again.
So yeah, there there's that.
Do I, do I mark where they work and mark it as a company I should never ever work at?
I mean, what do I, what do I do?
How do I like it is?
It's bad.
You just, I don't know.
I don't really have a good answer.
If it's one of your connections and you really don't like what they said,
then they need to not be a connection anymore.
I suppose.
Yeah.
I actually did that once a few weeks ago.
I went and un unconnected a whole bunch of people who were showing up in my feed
and just pissing me off.
I need to do more of that, but I'm going to ask you this.
If I do that, am I just creating an echo chamber?
Do I want to heal it?
Sending opinions.
So is an echo chamber bad?
Yes.
What do I do then?
Help me solve my problem.
I see, uh, learning is gesturing.
Uh, sounds like you need to unmute.
It depends, right?
Like an echo.
You want to set healthy boundaries, right?
Nobody is saying no to healthy boundaries.
Um, though, if that's just the bubble, you can't escape off.
It's a different question.
I don't know.
I, I'm really not that worried about it, but I, I feel like I should be on
LinkedIn to kind of keep my eye on jobs, but I'm also not finding very many good
jobs there.
I like it when it gives me, uh, this is the thing I love about LinkedIn.
Here's a job.
When I click on the job, it says you're not a good fit for this job.
So why'd you even show it to me?
God, you should see some of the ones that says I'm a great fit for no LinkedIn.
Oh yeah.
I've seen, I've seen those too.
They've been wrong.
All right.
Here's the thing to look for.
You want people with a different opinion than you have who is willing to have a
rational discussion about it.
That's the difference.
Yes.
How I, I wish I like on dating apps, they have like this match thing.
I need to know, even if I disagree, I want to know I can have a rational
discussion with you.
How do I, I guess I have to, I guess I have to filter that out.
I don't, it's, it's blah.
Yeah.
There's even someone that we all like to talk trash about that if you have a
private conversation with them, um, it's, it's a rational conversation.
Yes.
And I've, I've, I have experienced exactly that.
But I've, but I've told you that LinkedIn is just bait.
It is just, just picking principle five and dumping.
It didn't used to be that way.
I think it was.
Okay.
Maybe, maybe I just spent more time on LinkedIn because Twitter went away and I
used to spend time on Twitter.
I think my account still exists.
I haven't launched Twitter X, whatever it's called in definitely not shitter.
The X I haven't, I haven't been on that platform in forever.
Uh, I had to join Facebook last summer.
And I have no friends on Facebook because that's the trail angels who are, we'll
talk about them in a second here.
Uh, they, that's the way to communicate with him is on Facebook.
So I created a Facebook account.
They made me put a picture on there to prove I was real, but I have no friends.
I just, and I've left all the groups I was in.
I just needed to delete my account.
I deleted my original account for way back when years ago, but I
created a new one, no friends.
I know I obviously don't spend time there.
Uh, I posted on Instagram about my hike this summer.
So I scroll there sometimes, but I, I've kind of, it's weird.
And maybe it's just cause I was remote for, I was off the grid for so long.
Social media in general, including LinkedIn.
Like I can't scroll.
I can scroll like two screens.
I said, that's enough.
I'm done.
I am.
I've, it's weird though.
I used to love, I used to be able to watch tick tock for like a half hour
straight and now some people do longer half hours.
That's a long time for me.
I can't even binge stuff on Netflix.
I just can't sit that long and I couldn't before I especially can't now.
I just have no patience for it.
So instead I, I take long walks and I, uh, fell into a good, a good, uh, I'm
in a good pace.
I didn't think I'd be able to write every week when I got back.
Cause I couldn't write every week before I left.
I was fried, but I can now.
Nice.
Go, go read.
Anyway.
Yeah.
So enough, enough input to it, like write for a time.
Like the best thing about like having this kind of job is getting
more input to write about.
No, what's interesting is vast majority of my newsletters have been
related to something happening at work.
Something comes up.
You know what I'm going to write.
I could help one of the ways I process.
I process a lot just by talking through things, but if I can write about it,
I can figure out what it means to me.
And you'll notice a lot of my, uh, posts recently, I've just been about like
things from the trail that are kind of retrospecting into my life.
Like, oh, this made me think about this thing or this thing on trail.
I'm going to think about this thing or this thing.
I'm going to think about this thing on the trail.
So, um, eventually and probably not very quickly, I'll run out of some of
those ideas and by then I'll probably have a job.
So I guess I'll find some there.
Can I circle back to principle number five really quick because I don't like it.
This is the way this podcast goes.
Even with Brent, we just go in circles and circles and circles.
Tell me what you don't like.
Well, you're supposed to be a good listener, which means you lose your train
of thought, but then it comes back.
So I'm working on being a better listener.
Okay.
So I believe the customer is the best person to judge and evaluate
the quality of your product, but is often not the only one doing that.
And I think that's why so many people don't like that statement.
It's, it's a bit of a hyperbole.
And unless you're doing like, uh, production monitoring is your only testing.
There are other opinions that matter.
Aren't there?
And it seems, and it seems, and it seems easily to dispute, right?
The customer is the only one capable.
No, it isn't like multiple people capable really, but maybe it's the one.
How, how are they?
And, and some might not, but when you say like about security, how
as a customer do I know that the security aspects of the software are
really like as presented, I cannot really, but this doesn't mean the
whole thing is irresponsible.
It's the principle.
It's how you, how you deal with it.
Right.
It's
I'm going to let me push back on that.
I'm not against this and we can have, I'm glad people have a rational conversation,
but who else give me, give me another person, give me another persona that
can evaluate the quality of our product.
I guess as like, as like, maybe not a main expert, but expert
tester, I could find the things that the customer only glancing.
How do they know that the customer, how do they know that the customer
would care about that issue?
I, I don't know.
I'm going to have a soapbox for a second here because some of these folks will
find, I'm going to air quote bugs that no customer would ever care about.
They're very excited about those testers.
Lots of testers get really excited about, Oh, I found this thing.
And, and something Brent said a long time ago is what's, what
is higher quality software?
A software where software where there are no known bugs, but has a hundred users
or software that has dozens of bugs, but used by tens of thousands of users.
Which one brings more value?
It's the second one.
So how do we know that the expert tester is finding bugs
that matter to the customer?
Some of them are obvious.
It crashes every time you started up in every environment.
You don't need to ask the customer, is that bad?
Should we fix it?
I got the sense customer wouldn't see that right.
And, and, and if he wrote the customer would definitely say, yeah, this is shit.
I don't want that.
Yeah.
Well to me and Eric Reese, Eric Reese, Lian startup.
You don't get any value from your engineering effort until
it's in the hands of customers.
You don't know if you've built the right thing to solve their problem.
Obviously.
And, and we can separate testing from quality.
I don't really give a shit about testing anymore.
I care about quality.
Testing has to happen, but it's on the pursuit of quality, which is value
to some person who matters, which I think is the customer.
So if we put it that way, uh, yeah, we're, we're going, if we just are careless.
And I'm going to refer once again to Zen and the art of motorcycle maintenance.
Uh, I'll tell a story about that in a second.
Uh, Robert Piercig basically says quality and care are two sides of the same coin.
So we're going to put care as a developed development team into our
software. Uh, so it doesn't mean we're, we're evaluating quality.
We're going to put care into what we make and craftsmanship into what we make,
but we don't know if it's quality, meaning value to some person
until the customer use it.
Right.
All you know is that it solves some problem you think.
Yeah.
You have a hypothesis that it solves the problem.
So then you can put metrics in telemetry in place to see, are we solving
the problem we're intending to solve with this software, with this
release with this API, whatever.
But the customer, we don't know if it solves that problem until the customer
uses it.
And when you say the quality of our product in that principle,
people aren't thinking the quality product is the one that solves the actual
problem instead of a different problem.
I think they're not even thinking about that at all.
The way that's written.
How would you, well, I've been pushing back on the, the only one,
because I do believe the customer, I still believe the customer.
Ultimately, the, I mean, there's other quality things that can happen,
but I'm, I'm bending a little bit, but I'm not bending.
Cause it doesn't matter if it doesn't solve the problem for the customer.
But how would you, how would you, other than saying the best,
which I don't think I like, I'm going to think about it though.
How would you write that principle?
It's the most important one to judge and evaluate.
I don't know.
I'm going to think about it.
And I would make maybe, maybe at a yes.
And, um, like as we like enable, make our teams more capable.
Our goal could be to make the customers more capable of like, actually deciding if
this is like solving the problem in a good way or not, or like helping them
understand the quality of the product for their needs or whatever.
Um, so it's not irresponsible because we don't just push it to the customer
without any, like without any care, without any quality and without any
feedback, right?
We just, we usually it's good for quality.
If we work close to the customer, get an interaction feedback loop and they,
they judge what we deliver.
I get that.
Yeah.
The feedback loops become critical there.
If you can have a super fast feedback loop.
Um, I think what pushes people's buttons here, and this is probably
partially on purpose is that people read this principle and think, Oh, you're
making the customers test our software, which is true, but not true in the
sense of like, here's your test cases, go enter these bug reports, blah, blah,
blah.
We have telemetry in place to help us understand how it's being used, what
problems are being solved, what errors running into, we're looking into
HTTP error logs.
We have a lot of stuff we monitor to see if it's working as designed
functional correctness and to see if it's solving that problem.
Uh, Brent and I have talked quite a bit about, um, having a hypothesis
for every feature, like we expect that adding this feature will increase,
uh, user acquisition by 20%.
And before even releasing it, talking about the experiment, everyone
think about what are we going to do?
If it does, what are we going to do?
If it doesn't do we double down?
Do we try something different?
Making every feature hypothesis on what's going to change for the customer.
So you can measure that.
You can tell if you're solving a new problem, if it's getting better
for the customer or something is changing, it's a lot of extra work.
Uh, developers, development teams often fall into, wouldn't it be cool
if we did this thing and they, and Microsoft is especially horrible at this.
And I can tell you many stories from my time there.
And, uh, I can, I cannot stand Microsoft products anymore, but it was, it was
just as bad when I was there.
Uh, so how do we make sure we're solving a real customer problem and not
something that we think is cool or something we think will solve a customer
problem, how do you do that about the customer?
I'm seeing faces.
Yeah.
Dog fooding.
I'm going to first, first, first, first, first, first, first, first, first, first,
dog fooding, but then you are your own customer.
Basically that doesn't help really.
Yeah.
And where you can dog food, if you can use your software to
help make your software always awesome.
I, you know, I've done that a ton at Microsoft, but working
on operating systems, especially.
It's a great way.
Cause it's a, uh, it's a proxy, but we're not the customer.
I think it'd be an example from office way back.
It's like office 97, I think a lot.
And this is back in the years of three year ship cycles and lots
and lots of beta testers, lots of feedback, fixed the bugs, better
testers, all super happy.
They ship it.
A bunch of customers are pissed off because I think it was, um, I
think it was, I don't remember exactly.
I think it was lawyers, lawyers use, they didn't have enough
lawyers in the beta testing lawyers use word differently than way.
Everybody else uses word and they were pissed off because
bunches that didn't work right.
So it, and it's the same thing if you do your own testing.
Because your dog fooding is great.
You're finding a lot of the stuff.
It's how I use it.
You don't use it like the customer because the customer will
use your software differently.
You need to think about all the different aspects.
And when you're dealing with a million customers, data telemetry.
So the way you can really do that rather than wait, rather than ship it,
wait for bug reports to come in and then ship patches.
Gross.
Thank thank goodness.
We can, we can ship multiple times a day now and detect these things
and fix these things and, and figure this stuff out.
Last product I worked on was installed at the customer controlled
environments and that was, that was weird.
We didn't ship multiple times a day and it, it, it definitely
felt like a step back, but that, that still happens out there.
Yeah, it does.
It does.
And, and again, I think some of the folks who get angry over any of
these principles, especially five, which we did not expect expect to
be the most controversial, but I think it is.
All of our years consistency.
It's amazing.
Yeah.
Um, I think there is a lot of software that is still shipping yearly.
I don't, I don't ever want to work on that stuff.
I like, it is so much fun ship working on stuff that ships multiple times a day.
I love detecting and fixing errors automatically within minutes.
Uh, I, it's, it's more exciting for me.
Yeah.
So as you do that, we had the podcast reading my posts recruiters.
And then when, when Brian Finster was on, we talked about, and he said this a lot
and he's very active on LinkedIn as well.
I like reading his posts because he's not afraid to engage with people on LinkedIn.
Uh, but Brian said, like the best way to find problems in your team is to
try and do continuous deployment.
Like if I go to, oh, we can't do that because that, okay, we'll fix that.
We still couldn't do it because of, of B we'll go fix B it's, uh, whether
you do continuous deployment or not.
Does it matter?
You don't have to, but if you talk about what it would take to do it, you're
going to find all the bottlenecks and problems in your system.
Yeah.
Cool.
All right.
What else we talk about?
Do I want to talk about that some more?
I can talk all day, as you can tell.
Well, there was just a recent Dora report was coming out, right?
Saying like fewer than once per six months, deployment frequency is at 3.6%
they say here, so based on the,
if you're a recruiter, one of those companies, please do not contact me.
That's the folks that need you most.
I thought maybe I got to think about this.
I kind of, so bringing a team from every six months to, well, there's
stories about this, like, I think Flickr was the one that went from like a very
slow release from multiple times a day.
First, I guess I could, I don't know if that was their desire, if the
desire, there's the difference.
I figured it out.
If it is, I don't want to go from A to A.
If shipping every six months or less is, that's the plan.
That's the forever plan.
Hard pass.
But yeah, if you want to get, if you're shipping once every six months
and you want to ship 10 times a day, hell yeah.
Let's go do that.
I mean, I'm still, I'm trying to figure out my testing past is calling me and
I've kind of stepped away from it completely, but every time I, I talk to
somebody about that topic, like my Spidey senses say, Oh yeah, this is, this is
cool, get into this.
Uh huh.
You know, I'm not going to go do a testing specialist job again, but I really
should tap into that experience.
So, uh, yeah, if I could get, uh, your, your leftovers, Alan, for
transforming an organization or something, I don't know, but I really need to
embrace that and, and help, uh, help companies bridge that gap.
Well, wherever they are in that journey.
Yeah.
But if they're not on a journey, if they're going A to A, yeah.
Uh, I'm not going to be a cog in the wheel.
Exactly.
Same exact boat.
I can't, I can't do that again.
I'm, you know, as I think my LinkedIn profile says this, but
Brent calls me a change agent.
And I, I like, I'm good at helping organizations make changes and figure
out and finding all the things blocking them from doing it.
I, I don't want to go from A to A.
I don't want to hold the status quo.
I don't want to be, you know, you get it.
So, um, the good news is, is I will find a job eventually.
And I know where all the really talented yet unemployed people are.
So I, and I will have open headcount.
So I'll just, I'll just bring y'all along for the ride.
Awesome.
So the jobs you're looking for, Alan, they don't have a
thousand people applying for them.
Do they?
No, they don't, but a couple, a hundred, 200 sometimes.
No, they don't have a hundred people applying for them.
Not the job that you really need.
Um, and it's probably not posted on LinkedIn either.
And I can almost guarantee the job I find won't be on a job board.
It'll come from a network somewhere.
Exactly.
Yeah.
That's, that's really most likely how it's going to happen.
I knew that I see where you're going now, but yeah, I'm, I'm going to
apply because I need to shake the rest off and I'm on an advisory, um, advisory
board for a couple of different tech companies that kind of, that's fun.
It's free consulting.
I have the people reach out for more free consulting.
Um, I'm happy to do that because it kind of tickles my tech
brain and gets my brain working again.
Uh, I became pretty dumb on the trail.
I forgot everything.
It's coming back.
So then back, it's cause all you do is you get up and you walk and you eat
and you shit in the woods and, and
now you get to build that knowledge back up with a better structure than before.
It is an a clear brain.
Uh, I'm super excited because I'm, I know what I'm good at.
I know I can do all the things I do, but, uh, what Zen spy is, is, uh, there's
all this, it kind of kind of built a lot of the therapy I've been on,
been in for years and years, but there's a buzz that happens.
Like just things you're worried about stressors, anxiety, little things.
They're all gone.
They went away.
I mean, they went, they still come back once in a while, but when they're gone,
you can tell it's like, if you're in a room and you think it's silent, then
you turn the lights off and this buzz you didn't even notice goes away.
That's what happened in my head.
And now I can hear when it comes back.
Oh, that's wrong.
Whereas I gotta make that go away and I can make it go away usually pretty
quickly.
So I'm trying to stay in this world where, uh, I'm happy.
I'm confident.
I'm clear on what I want to do.
And I'm not going to do things that take me away from that, which would be
a company that wants to go from a and stay at a forever.
Uh, I am at my most effective when I can be me and push things forward and do
all the wild, crazy things I do while creating engaged teams at kick ass.
So that's, that's my plan.
Um, uh, Zen spy incorporated, maybe, I don't know, Zen spy LLC.
I'm not sure what it's going to look like.
But we'll figure it out.
One little networking tip that I'm finding is, um, it's not necessarily your
really deep connections.
Uh, it's very frequently someone that you you've met maybe twice virtually.
Um, those are the ones that are usually getting me interviews.
So it's those fresh connections, oddly enough are really valuable.
I'm going to keep an eye on that.
I haven't really leveraged my network enough yet on this job search.
And again, cause it's a weird time.
I'll, I'll, I'll reach out to him.
I was, uh, one point I was planning to head down to San Francisco for a bit later
this year, I thought I would network a bunch of my old unity colleagues, uh,
who are both there and not there anymore.
Uh, not just been pushed out a little bit, but I can still contact them virtually.
I have one good thing about unity's massive layoffs is I have former team
members who like me a lot who are spread all over the tech industry.
So, uh, I will, I will begin reaching out to them and see what to have them
keep an ear out for me.
Uh, I've done that a little bit already.
I'll do some more of that, but, uh, yeah, we'll see what I'm not again, not
super worried about it yet.
Um, I can even probably leave the yet off there.
I'm not super worried about it.
Cause I know that I will find a job eventually and I'm not going to settle
for something like, Oh, here's a job.
I'm not going to go work for.
Oh, meta, for example.
Never going to happen.
Not a fan.
Uh, I kind of don't want to work at a super big company again.
I think for me, I would love it.
If I could own engineering in a company had like between 200 and 800 or a thousand
engineers, um, I guess my sweet spot for, for culture change and pushing things
along and not being in a cognitive machine, but having the ability to
change culture and drive things.
But we'll again, we're going to see what happens.
I'm repeating myself, but I think it sounds exactly like the thing that
everybody's telling like freelancers to do, please put it online, put it on
your service page, what kind of packages do we offer?
What kind of shops do you seek?
Um, just get it, get it online.
Somehow that will probably help maybe of like random people stumbling upon
that, right?
Just by you say the organizations that might need you hate you or whatever.
Um, maybe not the person who are like, who wants to take care and
wants to make quality matter might be looking, might stumble just by
Googling upon sub-stack course or whatever.
Right.
We need to start a Slack channel called help Alan help spy find a job.
Spy job.
You can all give me your tips on cause I'm, uh, you know, the newsletters are
on angry weasel.substack.com.
I still have angry weasel.com, uh, five for Friday, which I did for
like three years straight, maybe four.
Uh, uh, I'm, I think I'm going to be done with those.
Oh, wow.
So I don't think so.
I've, I've, I've sort of lost momentum towards the end.
I got, I did him every week, but I got to say it was a highlight of my week
when I showed up in one of them.
Like, oh, now maybe I have to do them again.
I, I am not on the internet that much.
Maybe when I get back to reading, uh, I'm reading, maybe I'm reading
books instead of internet things.
Maybe when I get back into the swing of things a little more, that,
that'll come back.
But then where the question I was getting to is where do I put this
information on angry weasel.com?
It's not on a separate page.
I put it on the sub stack somewhere.
I got to figure, I got to figure out what information I want to share where I
put it and how I get people to find it.
So my, my network, and again, this, this is a fresh contact introduced me to one
person who introduced me to somebody they knew who gave me an opportunity
with her network to be listed as a service provider among startups.
And I'm looking at this form that I fill out to get on this, this list.
And it asks, what do you do?
And I, well, I do a lot of things.
I don't know what to put there because it's got to sound organized and focused,
but it's tough being a generalist.
Damn it.
I think so.
Um, I think I can get pretty specific at what I do.
Uh, and again, maybe starting off at a consultant role or a fractional CTO
fractional VPE is a better path for me.
I haven't, I'm kind of six to one half of those together right now.
I'm my post.
I've always thought I do consulting at some point in my career, whether it's
now and then into full time, whether they do full time and do some, I, even
when I stopped working, um, I can't just go to the gym, play pick a ball
every day, I'll get a little bored.
I need to exercise my brain.
So let's say I get a job I love.
I do it for a couple of years.
Um, and I tend to not just quit jobs.
I can, I, I quit when I'm not needed anymore.
I've worked myself out of almost every job I've been in, except for the last
one where I hiked myself out of it.
And I will probably do that again.
I will find myself, um, in a position where I don't need to be there at
that point, I'll probably go into consulting.
I'm not, I'm not going to do full time work for a lot longer.
Uh, I like it, but I also like traveling and hiking and, uh, playing pick
a ball with the, with the retirees.
And, and I guess technically I'd be a retiree, but I don't know.
I'm I'm I'm a, I'll just say I'm a lot younger than the folks I'm
playing pick a ball with.
Yeah.
I look back over this period.
I've been unemployed and thought, man, if I had known out all of that,
all those efforts to find a job wouldn't have succeeded.
I would have traveled and I thought, wait, traveling costs money.
Dang it.
It does.
Well, it, it, yeah, it does.
It, it, it, it's not free for sure, but there are cheaper places to travel
and, um, you can, you can make it work.
So yeah, then I'll, I don't know.
I'll figure it out.
That was good talking about that though.
And you guys, you know, we'll start some, uh, some slack conversations.
You go to modern testing.org and get a link to our slack group.
One of the three.
And if you want to help me, I'll create a channel, help, you know, spy
jobs and you can all give me tips on how to find the job I'm looking for.
But really, I need, I haven't tried that hard yet, so I'm not terribly
worried about it.
I'd hire you as a consultant in an instant.
So, well, I guess that's what I need somebody who actually has, um,
pocketbooks to tell me.
Yeah.
You can't leave us today without getting a story.
How much can you afford?
I'll let you know when I get the job and the budget.
So help me get a job too.
Yeah.
But yeah, it's fun though.
Alan, you have to tell us, you have to tell us a trail story before you go.
You're, I know you're trying to wrap up.
We have to hear a juicy trail story.
Well, which I there's, there's like 10,000.
It's like when people ask, how was the hike?
It was four and a half months and I walked 2,655 miles, not including side trips.
We'll call it 3000.
How was it?
Uh, that's not what I'm asking.
How was like 10 minutes of that hike?
That was really exciting.
Um, let me, it's all exciting in its own way.
So let me just kind of, I'll give you the overview and then listeners.
If you want to ask, if you want me to dive into any of this, let me know.
This might take a while.
Uh, the Pacific rest trails is, uh, in five sections.
So I'll go one by one.
The desert starts at the Mexican border goes up to, uh, roughly where
the Sierra began in California.
So South of just South of the Bay area.
Uh, blew my mind how beautiful the sunsets were.
I had never seen a desert sunset before.
I never say I don't think I've seen a cactus bloom before.
So I spent, you know, a solid month and a half walking through the desert.
Just, I thought I would hate it.
It was beautiful.
It was incredible.
A great way to not, not huge Hill thought it was great.
Uh, hit the Sierra on may 31st.
Um, and still a lot of snow, a lot of snow.
Uh, I did probably some, some of my dumbest hiking.
I was hiking by myself through the, there's people around.
I didn't hike with people and probably the dumbest thing I did.
And this is, I wrote about this in one of my recent newsletters is I decided
I was going to go say down this Hill, which ended up being solid ice.
It was a dumb, dumb choice.
Um, somebody broke their leg there the day before.
I didn't know that, uh, I managed to, I know what I'm doing.
Instincts took over.
I bailed out.
I was fine.
Uh, but I spent the rest of the day thinking about how
stupid I was to even try that.
So, you know, a week later I am walking across this waste, deep rapids
by myself also, also stupid.
But, um, I had one choice.
One is to either keep going and make it across, which was choice
a or choice B, which was die.
So I chose a, which was good, but you know, probably having a spotter there to call.
I'm not sure what the spotter would have done because I'd
have been washed down the river.
They could have called the SOS and got me dragged out downstream.
I don't know.
Um, but overall fun, a lot of, uh, I mean, incredible beauty, but walking in snow
every day, almost all day for a month was a little, little tiring after a while.
You get, you get to the Sierra and you go, Oh my God, the waterfalls are so
beautiful.
The mountain lakes are so great.
Three weeks later you go, Oh great.
Another lake, another waterfall, more snow.
Uh, Northern California starts around, um, Tahoe up to the Oregon border.
Uh, the worst maintained part of trailer hiking over, it was hot.
It was ashy from, from major forest fires there in the past.
And, uh, that's where I, that's where Zen Spy was born because I got so deep
into my head, did not think about how miserable the trail was that like,
all I solved every single problem.
I didn't even know I had yet in my head.
Um, and then I got to Oregon, took a bunch of days off in Ashland to see some plays.
Uh, and then started trekking through Oregon.
I smashed my ankle on my first day out of Ashland.
So about 15 miles into Oregon, a long story, a rock flipped up and bashed
my ankle, it's still not right yet.
Uh, I woke up the next morning, ankle was swollen.
So I did what any through Hiker does.
I only walked 15 miles that day.
Elevated my leg.
I woke up next morning, it was a little better.
So I only walked 15 miles again.
And then, uh, it kept on getting a little bit.
I did 22 the next day.
I ended up doing my biggest day at all in Oregon hike 33 miles, uh, one day, but
basically went across Oregon in about 20 days, Oregon's a little flatter,
cruised across my ankle healed as I walked on it.
Uh, it's still not healed.
I had it looked at once said, come back.
It doesn't get better if you're not walking on it so much.
I had to go back because even today, just, I went for a little run.
It's like, it's tweaked.
It's screwed up, but Oregon was a blast.
Um, uh, met, um, ended up, uh, met another Hiker and Crater Lake who ended up, we
ended up hiking in the last whole last 800 miles of the trail together.
Incredible persons, still good friends today.
Uh, hit Washington and it's like, Oh my God, I'm home, but it's so far.
Washington is so much harder than Oregon.
The ups and downs are so much.
Uh, but cruise along, uh, my son who we called spike it, uh, is 21 years old,
hiked from so quality past to Stevens, past with us, just 70 miles stretch,
but more up and down per miles than anywhere else on the trail.
I think he was a little beat up, uh, a little, a little complaining towards
the end, but he made it through, pushed him pretty hard and then, uh,
pushed all the way to the border.
And it was a little, that was a little surreal getting to the finishing.
Cause you're just walking every day and all of a sudden you're done, but you're
not totally done because you have to turn around and walk 30 miles backward to get
home because you can't walk into Canada anymore because stuff.
And then it didn't really sit in that I was done.
Um, it's hard to handle.
It is.
And I'll tell you coming back was there is a real thing called post trail
depression, which, um, still comes and goes, but the first week back was
overwhelming.
I went four and a half months where everything I needed to live fit in a
backpack, a small backpack, even if I stayed in a hotel for the night, all my
stuff still fit into a backpack.
And then I come home and there's just all this stuff everywhere.
And I didn't know what to do with it.
I get, I purged a lot of it.
I have more to get rid of.
I can't handle having stuff.
Like even I have like lots of books on testing and leadership and
software development, most of them on leadership.
I don't want them anymore.
Um, I'm like, I, I going to, I, if I knew someone locally who wanted the books,
I just like, if anybody's in the Seattle area, you want a bunch of books on
leadership, let me know.
I'll give them all to you.
I'm a sucker for books.
That's the hardest thing for me to get rid of.
As you can see, I don't want them.
I don't want things.
I don't want my things anymore.
I got a lot of my clothes don't fit anymore because I lost about
25 pounds on the trail.
It's like, but I didn't like him anymore.
I got rid of a bunch of my clothes.
I got rid of a bunch of, um, just stuff.
I continue to purge every day, either throwing stuff away or like I have
no desire at all to have collection.
I don't have any big collections, but I just don't want things.
So that's, that's a little, uh, one thing that really hit home.
And, um, even some, you hear this a lot of times in self-help or
retirement books is you want to have experiences, not things.
And that's become like super true for me since I've been back.
I don't, I don't give a crap about things.
I want to have experiences.
Like I got a note from the, uh, or a friend of mine from trail sent me a note
saying I can get a completion certificate for the PCT and I made a digital one.
I'm printed as a thing.
You guys can see it looks like that.
So, but I'll probably just put this in a look at this, put it in the recycle
bin, cause I don't want it.
I had the experience of hacking the PCT.
My internet's a little freaky.
It'll work out fine.
I had the experience of liking the PCT.
I don't need a thing about it.
Uh, I want to spend my money on travel and, uh, classes or things I can learn and do.
I really don't want to buy cars or books or, I mean, I'll read books on my Kindle.
Um, they're small, but I don't, yeah, I think it's probably pretty common, but
it's, it's weird, it's weird being back, but I'm back now and, um, I will
probably do some, uh, more hiking, um, this summer and I'm going to assume
the recording will work fine here, but my guests are frozen because my network
has puked for some reason.
I hear you, but your video's not moving.
So I will keep talking.
Yeah.
And cause I like to say goodbye to them before we end up here.
You don't hear me.
What's going on?
Danny Andreas.
If you can ever hear me, please say something.
Do you know how to sing the closing riff or maybe he recorded it on his
no, I don't, but, uh, yeah,
you can still hear me.
They're telling me they can still hear me.
Yes.
So, uh, I don't know what's going on and why they're broken.
I'm afraid to refresh my page.
So, oh, that's weird.
Danny can hear things.
Oh, you know what?
Um, off I've actually do a little bit of editing.
If you can hear yourselves, that means you will, your recordings will upload.
So pretend that I can hear you and we can wrap up here.
So, uh, Dan, I, I, I can't ask an open ended question.
So I won't know when you're done.
So I would like to thank both Danny and, uh, Andreas, uh, global, global
warming, um, global verming global warming.
Well, it depends on the German accent.
I want to thank you both for, for being here.
Um, so, uh, let me start with you, Andreas.
Uh, any, any final words?
It was much fun seeing you and, and having a chance to get another episode out.
Love that.
All right.
And how about you, Danny?
Thank you for that.
Oh, this was a thrill.
I've been trying to get on the podcast for a long time.
Not very hard, but finally I tried.
And, um, uh, one thing I'll leave you with, if you go to my blog,
swalchemist.blog, you will actually find, if you scroll long enough,
a picture of a cactus bloom.
So, um, there's that, but you have to do a lot of scrolling to find it.
So thanks everybody really enjoyed it.
All right.
This has been episode two 20 of the AB testing show.
Uh, I am going to chef, seven, the outro post-prob because
career sides still screwing up on my side.
Darn it.
I'll have to do some more editing, but thank you both.
Uh, we'll see you next time on AB testing.