Welcome to AV testing podcast your modern testing podcast your hosts Alan and
Brent will be here to guide you through topics on testing leadership agile and
anything else that comes to mind now on with the show hello Brent how are you
today I'm doing nifty and swell that's great you that's great welcome to
another episode of AV testing where we get together and we talk about nothing
at all how in the effin world do we get to 200 it's our 214 215 I don't even know
I'll count it off later it's a big number we we why do people listen to us this is
215 we are we're basically useless you could you could get a better conversation
just sitting in one of the restaurants near Microsoft actually people go to the
office anymore what's the what's the work situation there oh dude dude dude dude
yeah I went to an off-site on Wednesday was it at Microsoft it was but all of us
work it was a different building so it was off our normal site but there were
people there and we had like a lunch breakout and use the big projector and
talked and laughed and I'm like whoa and you talked about things that weren't
about work sometimes too huh yeah yeah all that stuff that never happens in
their moat role but what's the basic requirement there at Microsoft they ask
people to go to the office is it just pure hybrid go whenever you want is it
is it you'll come to the office couple times a week like what's the latest
there is such instructions the instructions okay let me know when you're
done working that out done okay okay you with manage manager permission you can
self-elect to do any degree of hybrid between zero and a hundred percent okay
okay and I have not met a manager but I assume there's certain there's certain
places at Microsoft where obviously for example if you are one of the folks in
the data center you probably can't do that remotely too many times probably
not right for the most part I'm guessing if there's a manager just being a jerk
and making their employees come to work with they don't need to those employees
are gonna go find the new manager they'll probably try this is the
internal job like it and for in the wayback machine our internal career
started Microsoft used to have like a thousand jobs any one time you can go
apply for across the company is that that getting less now with the it is
cuts and everything it is right with the with the cuts that we just went
through right yeah that's tailored back but to finish you answer your question the
only the only other issue is at Microsoft we have two types of space here
I'm not talking about office or open space but it's designated or
undesolated mm-hmm and you have to work from work at least three business days a
week to to acquire and maintain a designated space that seems fair yeah
that seems like a fair thing if I'm going that often I would want a space
but if I'm just hopping in once in a while I just need a place to sit down
and plug in and hang out and I guess it's not free food it's a weird world
it's just weird so I'm glad I think that's a good way to work I had a
conversation this morning with someone in HR because we have I'm not gonna go
into the details mm-hmm on whether someone new to the junior member new to
the team would have to go to work every day or be remote and if we need to
relocate them and my whole org is remote and if they want to go to an
office they can and I have managers that can make sure they go to the office to
meet them but it's just it is weird and probably similar I guess Satya he gets
it he's an engineering leader it's I live in a world where I'm in a fully
remote org in a company that does not embrace remote work so you get to a
certain level up up the management chain and it's in the office five days a week
as the is the mandate or three days a week I guess would be probably more more
often so it's yeah yeah of course I live nowhere near an office so that would be
a tough commute for me I could go to a Comcast office in Seattle there's I know
of rent in office type places and there's one of them up in Everett I
think there's a ton in Seattle there's a ton of and I think I've shared this
business idea on the podcast before I would actually love to leave my house
sometimes to work I think back when we had an NBC News office downtown I went
there a couple times a week or once a week for a while it was fun just to go
to an office even though there's nobody there even though I didn't and nobody I
work with is there for sure in all the empty office spaces in I'll just pick on
Seattle but in these towns I would not only like more shared workspaces again
not having a dedicated desk place I can go plug in somewhere and just do my work
have a have some meeting rooms that could pop into for meetings but without
paying the full monthly rent rather than pay the full monthly rent of
something like we work or any of the other various clones of that what I
would do to to ensure occupancy and get breadth of people coming in is just go
to all the companies that have a presence in the area or not go to every
corporation and sell like here are by a thousand day passes for the company and
you could dole these out to employees who wanted to wanted an office to go to
just to get like me to get out of the house or something or somebody else is
doing like whatever wants to go work from an office for a while they're not
sitting with people they're working with but they're sitting with other humans and
getting some of that social interaction that's just missing from so
many people with remote work and again you have to do some governance to make
sure not everybody's using their passes on the same day but I think if you did
it wide enough it would even out and maybe you have to get a reservation in
the middle of the week they're gonna they're gonna fill up faster than Monday
or Friday because they like take those days off or two days off to work from
home those days but I want to solve the problem of the empty office buildings
and getting some money going in there but do it in a way that doesn't lock people
into a huge outlet like I can't afford to go pay even more of the local small
places for co-working space it just doesn't make any sense I'm not bringing it
just doesn't make any sense at all and I don't want to go to the office very
often but some days some days I like to get out of the house and work I'd
like to I like there for being an option that work at NBC here's here's 10 10 day
passes to use over the next you know the quarter that'd be great I would I would
use them it to me it would make sense as sort of like a mental health benefit
type of thing right that the thing like the thing I was really excited about
about the off-site is number one hey people okay but number two hey people
having a conversation around things I care about all right and I'm networking
I'm simultaneously socializing networking and getting shit done and and that
killing of multiple birds with one stone really appeals to me yeah let me
talk about something I've done remotely you can get there too there's a sense of
self-accountability you get when you're in an office around other people a bunch
of stuff I want to get done there is a a significant amount of
administrative that's part of my job whether it's submitting contracts or or
filling out forms for vendors it's a lot of stuff I'd rather not do in a
million years also nothing I can really delegate unfortunately so I need to
just force myself to do that stuff one way I've done that in the past remotely
is for a while my leadership team and I we set up like a twice a week I can't
remember what we called it just an hour call we did a slack huddle cuz they're
easier and team sucks even though I worked on it ten years ago we just did
a slack huddle where we're on the call we were muted but we kind of all just
did a quick little dump of what we're gonna work on for the next hour and
there was no accountability from others but it kicked in that self-accountability
I could say okay I'm gonna do expense report approvals and get these three
contracts into our tool and it would by committing to my peers or my team that I
was going to do that I would sit down and work on that and crank that out and
get it done and it felt good to get it done everybody else had similar stuff
they wanted to do I'm just kind of hung out in a quiet study hall remotely
now if I go to an office even with people I don't know the fact of me
going there I'm like honestly in my if I'm at home I'm working from my kitchen
I got man I have to do expense reports I think I'm gonna go make some coffee
first and then maybe a sandwich and then I'm gonna pet the dog and then I'm
gonna go sit there and look at it again and go you know I'm sure there's
some email that needs to be read and deleted first like I don't I don't have
the type of things I hate it's like for me I can't think with all those dirty
dishes in the sink right this house is a mess like how am I gonna efficiently get
this there's something to that though yeah yeah I go I I will do these expense
reports as soon as I wipe off the counters and scrub the sink yeah so I
think getting out and again sometimes I can do it but sometimes it's that it's
not like I don't get the work done from home but sometimes I just need to get out
for like I said it's a mental health thing so I'm not sure how it's gonna work
out long run I think some people can work really well efficiently long term
remotely I think I'm pretty close to that but I'm not that I need to like just
sometimes I go to a coffee shop and get a cup of coffee it's loud and I
can't do meetings from there but I can kind of focus and get stuff done
because I'm not distracted by anything around you know one thing that I have
done in the past that's in alignment it's like okay I need to focus I want to be
near people but it's you know the stuff I don't want to do right so I have to
find a dish a a distraction free environment right and and because I am
really clever like I can find ways to procrastinate the thing that I have to
do really well yeah a secret I've learned is essentially a public library
like I will often go to like the Bellevue library and nowadays it's well the last
time we went there after Covid like friggin ghost town just like everything
else that's a good idea just getting out it's kind of a free long enough to do
meetings because it's kind of a free office space I've done really well my
kid took a motorcycle safety class a month or two ago and it was just far
enough away that I didn't want to drive home so I just kind of hung out but I
would coffee shop didn't work I found I actually did most my work from the car
just headed to my phone just there's nothing else to do I wasn't distracted I
could just do the work anyway interesting ideas I think everybody some
people want to go to the office every day some people never want to go to an
office I think there's a spectrum I live like 95% on the on the remote side
but sometimes and maybe I satisfy that itch the times I do go to the office to
work like I go to New York or LA for a week but it's it's a different vibe
sitting at a desk not that I'm not sitting at a desk right now but this
no you are this desk is filled with my crap I want some random desk with
nothing but a coffee cup on it no there's another problem too right at the
rate the more and more it's hard to belt or hard to how do I used to say this
when COVID happened right I end up amongst multiple different reasons but I
ended up going to work the entire time during COVID because number one work
allowed me to do so of various other reasons but one of the things that I
immediately recognized that I missed was the the the commute the time I spent
yeah thinking about what I was going to do and then and then retrospecting on
the way back yeah I fully agree that was it's that's a transition time yeah when
I first started course now at Unity is different because there was never the
org was not remote there were offices but I was my team was in 17 different
countries so it was always remote but what I found I in not going to the
office I and I lost this somewhere along the way but I had a pretty steady
routine in the morning that would transition me from sleepy time to work
time and especially given my days started at 6 a.m. most mornings I would
you know I would I would not get up it I could not function in that 6 o'clock
meeting if I got up at 545 I would have to get up about 515 530 at the latest
kind of be awake and around and try and you know do the wordle or something to
get mentally sharp and then I could hit that 6 o'clock meeting with the ground
running there was always even though I wasn't going to work this is interesting
sorry if you're all bored out there but I would get up I would shower I would
get you know I get dressed or be that transition there I would you know drink
a bunch of water get the brain ready and then start going usually my first break I
would have coffee sometimes I make coffee right before I don't like to drink
coffee first thing in the morning but I like to have it within like an hour I
think I read somewhere that's the right way to do it but I'm not sure if
that's true or not and that was then somewhere along the way like I just
took a shower today about 45 minutes ago sometimes I don't get to it all five or
six at night I just I just kind of get up and I still get up a half hour before
my first meeting but I kind of get up and I just just sweats in a t-shirt and
I now that I have short hair I splashed some water on it to get lay down from
my bedhead and then I'm off for the day so I wonder if it would help me again I
don't feel like I'm not hitting the ground running with that first meeting I
start a little later my first meeting usually 7 30 or 8 but I wonder if I should
go back to showering and actually putting reasonable clothes on in the
morning anyway we'll let our we'll put that in a poll question our listeners
decide I don't yeah I've I've noticed a similar behavior like Fridays now is a
work-from-home day and I'm still in my pajamas I've only ever seen Brent in
his pajamas like the last three months yeah and and I'm trying to think through
okay when did I just start making that transition like it's I still get the
same amount of work done but for me like just making guesses I'd like okay the joy
I would feel about going in engaging with my team which is a lot more awkward
now it has it has to be more scripted right in some regards right I've it's not
nearly like I love it when my whole team is in town and we all go to work and
lunch and like it's fantastic I'd prefer that above anything else but I'm like oh
well yeah being able to be in my pajamas all day long on Friday and getting work
done right does actually make me happy too not nearly as close as the other
thing but yeah the one thing one thing I have noticed though and I wonder if
you've encountered this as well I ever since I started working solidly two days
a week from home when I am done with work I don't want to come into this room
this room has now become work yes that happened to me during the pandemic
especially in our old house I work from the kitchen a lot here but those two
years working in my office on my old house I could not go into the room after
after work was done I could not return to that room it was wasn't fun for me I
don't know the the the positive or negative reinforcement I don't know what
it's like I absolutely know my subconscious has shifted yeah because I
had to I stopped playing PC games during the pandemic because I didn't
want to be near my PC I started playing Xbox exclusively because I did
not want to go back I didn't want to look at my computer after the end of the
day right because like this setup right in front of me is work yeah and
fortunately this is like I said I work now every so often my son of the time
from this desk most time I'm sitting at the kitchen and for me it's well I'm
mostly doing it here I've I've tried to like take my laptop to the kitchen and
know like the the call of doom scrolling on YouTube off of my TV is just too
enticing so I'm just like no this is my workplace plus I also don't want this
like work aura going wider than this room yeah I get that it's definitely it's
a work-life blend and yeah I'm gonna find your boundaries so anyway that's our
episode on working remotely no that's our that's our intro talk on working
remotely I let me see I had a vacation last week it was great I am recharged
lots going on blah blah blah for someone to be charged like I know don't
sound it right no you sound you sound drained AF we need to we need to like
record go back to recording in the morgue like Friday afternoon I'm fried
at the end of the week you are all lucky that you can even understand my
English or maybe the baby is not English anyway um you know do you want to talk
about something else no I mean I do like that idea right maybe considering going
back to like I still have your bag of crap I know I haven't seen Brent IRL
since 2019 yeah probably fall 20 yeah probably maybe 2020 but no we did not do
any podcast in 2020 I don't think well COVID didn't start till till literally my
birthday 2020 so I like maybe we did something early in 2020 I don't anyway we
may have you may have come to hmm cuz we did a couple recordings at unity was
I there in 2020 where was I yes I was yeah I'm looking at brain fart I've gone
back to 2020 on Spotify riveting podcast material so yeah oh that was a 343 I
missed three three three eight they require effort and we actually have guests
lined up for the show too but those require effort and rescheduling and my
assistant is doesn't exist to go figure that stuff out so as the producer
assistant I've failed I just I just show up here and talk about stuff so I have
found it yeah our last I don't think this was the one because it was episode
116 but our last episode before COVID was titled what's the deal with I stqb I
don't think it was the the fun one where you drop the quiz on me no it's not I
can't remember who knows what that was about that really in the one teens 115
116 oh my god we've done almost as oh my god March 2 2020 yeah Wow we've done a
lot of within a hundred episodes and said okay so I want to talk about some
so I was on vacation last week off the grid I mean I was on the grid I just
didn't turn my computer on okay and except to watch some YouTube shorts you
know they'd be important stuff and apparently well I wasn't paying attention
there was this thing out of China that wasn't COVID it was deep seek deep seek
and here's what I know about deep seek I want you fill in the gaps deep seek is
yet another LLM Gen AI thing what sets it apart is two things one it's
run by China and highly censored and two it apparently runs and one of my
biggest complaints about all this Gen AI crap and the bullshit people are doing
with it is the amount of energy it takes and the amount of environmental
resources it takes to run this stuff apparently deep speak deep speak deep
seek is cost-efficient much more cost efficient with much more resources uses
much less energy I don't know if I believe all that but curious because you
probably pay attention to stuff more than I do can you catch me up on deep
seek and let me ask some dumb question not I still have a lot of open questions
okay because number one it is well known that for things like this for
tech IP the Chinese government will absolutely steal and claim otherwise okay
and I haven't seen there there there are suspicions that the reason why their thing
is so cheap is because they did exactly that they trained it on opening eyes all
I don't I don't we don't know for sure we don't know for sure I don't like to
tend towards conspiracy theory I will hypothesize that it's not oh come on
come on it is as a data scientist I will say from the data that I know I
cannot refute or support that position whatever yeah and I would very much like
to do one or the other okay so getting past any potential conspiracy theories or
lies coming how it works like I have not and will not plan to play with it at
least for now I have not used it once okay so what else you know about it what
what should educate me educate me someone who doesn't like I'm so freaking
burned out on Gen AI and sick of people looking for magic there are a few good
applications coming out which is great but I'm just I'm freaking done I'm tired
of people I had dinner last night was Wednesday night with someone who was going
off on how Gen AI was changing the world and which is a great stance as long
but they knew nothing about Gen AI so I was just kind of annoyed and pissed off
so what should I know about deep-seek whether it's real or not okay in terms
of how they developed like let's just talk about number one they open
sourcing that okay this means Gen AI is going to there's going to be a lot more
competition around Gen AI okay now I am a huge supporter of enabling competition
to bring about innovation and price competition how many layperson
understand what is it they're open sourcing that the LLM the code that
generates the LLM what's actually oh that the chat bot what's open source to
my deep-seek they are so I'm looking at our article right now and again I have
not followed up on this number one all of their models are going to be
available open source okay to use you could argue well GPD does that no it
doesn't right you can do a certain amount of it but then like they're
doing the the freemium model right I have a subscription to open AI and
allows me to do everything I want to but they're going to open source everything
and the article I'm looking at is saying that they're gonna open source
their methodology which is something that I'm gonna want to dig into a lot
further hmm right the because now so they were to they their claim is that
they were able to build something that one tenth of the the that's their claim
yes the price tag and without using GPU okay now in in data science I'm not
using GPUs crazy talk it is I was from the articles that I read they used GPUs
they didn't use they use cheaper ones but still I don't think how do you do
without the floating point speed I think they use GPUs if you're smart
well no no no so I don't know if you're aware of this but it's an export what
is that thing GPUs are in the export restriction thing yes like US is not
allowed to export GPUs and I can tell you for example we operate a government
cloud for China okay not one damn GPU in that club okay now that doesn't block
them they have all kinds of friends that they can go and talk to right to get
access to the compute power of GPU so I just thought just to back up my claim
here and suit to think company claims to train this model for just six million
using 2,000 Nvidia h800 graphics processing units okay is the versus the
80 to 100 million cost GPT for and the 16,000 h100 GPUs required for a mid
is llama 3 so they are using you they're using cheaper GPUs okay so
anyway that's what that's how they got around that but much cheaper and in my
much less energy consumption I don't know how to try guess I guess it's gonna be
open source you could test well you can't test those you're gonna go spend 6
million dollars to go build the LLM and see if it's see if it's right or not I
guess you could model that I don't know anyway what else now so now
basically they've opened the world up the make your own gen AI world to
smaller companies right which which creates disruption which creates
competition which creates innovation right even though I love what the
connection to open AI has done for the Microsoft stock price in the long term
competition is going to bring this stuff down is gonna create a differentiation I
want to take this and maybe leave deep-sake in here and build on the topic
we talked about last time which is the AI apocalypse AI apocalypse industry is
changing and there aren't there are new and again my hypothesis was that we are
not out of different business ideas we there are new businesses that can be
enabled by gen AI which I would really love to see and I see a few pop
up here and there which is actually really cool but I feel like the
basically my conversation I was a stranger on Wednesday night I feel like
maybe I'm in a weird bubble I feel like the general world is still looking at AI
to be magic that does really simple things that could be done without AI
and I'm worried about the ability of those people or okay I'll back up
because I got the majority people I talked to you about gen AI it's
basically magic to them it's gonna solve all their problems that are and
the problems I want to solve are simple problems that could be solved via an
algorithm not gen AI yeah I how do we get people to think differently or just
it's just a time thing when people think differently about this stuff and
begin to innovate like very little innovation on gen AI I think I'm still
waiting for it I think we're gonna find two things okay number one we are
already in a world where gen AI is okay I'm gonna go back to an old speech of
mine back to the s-debt days I thought I'm an engineering tester a term coined
at Microsoft circa 2004 sooner than that I was an s-debt in the 90s dude oh yeah
oh no you had a flash you had a flash it was sde flash T it was not a slash yeah
we took the dash away the one thing that happened on Thursday yesterday Thursday
yesterday for recording time yeah yeah I hit 30 oh well congratulations yeah so I'm
gonna get I'm gonna get a different you can't see it on the camera I'm gonna
give a different version of those yeah I have a couple on my shelf up there but
one that looks all sparkly and fiery Wow you used to be like 30 was like oh my
like didn't 30 used to get in the old days when wouldn't you get like a plaque
in the conference center oh I already know you that sooner I got it at 25 you
have a plaque in the conference enter not a not a plaque but there's a there's
a crystal that has every everyone's name that celebrated 25 and as Microsoft's
gotten older like the font has gotten smaller yeah you can still read my name
without glasses but I don't know not two years after me all right well
congratulations on 30 years I guess if I would have stayed I would be at 30 when
did I start 95 2025 I'd be coming up on 30 years think you started full-time
about six months before I did yeah I I literally joined the company in 94 but
there was weird oddities so my official start date is 75 or yesterday 95 all
right sir back to the topic and well we're good at this but I am so uh let's
not go all the way back to deep-seek we are talking about how I'm just waiting
for people to begin to innovate on AI versus seed as magic is deep-seek gonna
help with that just more fuel to the magic fire it's not gonna be more fuel
to the magic fire so what it will enable direction changes this is why I
was talking about it's gonna enable competition right because other companies
smaller companies that couldn't get into the game of creating models will now
be able to do so assuming everything that we've heard about deep-seek is true
right now in my view if it's chock full of of China you know CCP censorship then
everything I just said is is wrong because like I'm not gonna use this but
if the methodology is open source and and somebody else comes in and trains it
and still maintains that price tag then yeah this is gonna open up to to people
creating their own model generators and in one thing I think that could be
particularly interesting is generating deep topic knowledge instead of how GPT
right now is sort of generalized however we're gonna hit another thing that I
think is gonna be problematic and maybe I brought it up last time there's this new
concept that I bring up AI litter last time no okay I forgot because I'm old
and then I may be but it you know fills a couple more minutes of the podcast
so yeah AI litter so AI letters is concept where essentially because AI is a
hot new thing oh that's where I left off my speech from the old days automation if
you're not careful anything that you build with automation to do good will
also reduce the friction on doing bad like if you're not careful around how
you apply that automation oh yeah right I wrote a I wrote a blog about this got
probably a decade ago where where as you know I have a I have a patent for a test
architecture that that used to be well used at the company and when I left the
team where I build it they took it further and it became a situation where
dev would just barf code and then just said submit it to the automation and go
off to lunch right and they wouldn't they wouldn't code review they would
because they had confidence that the automation would catch anything it
encouraged intellectual laziness and I definitely think that that will happen
here as more and more AI comes out yeah I think it's a good parallel I think
intellectual laziness is being encouraged I totally agree with that
and if it's intellectual laziness around things that we don't care about
I'm cool with it I'm cool with it but what's happening and here's a very
specific case there is now a group of people I believe there's a reddit for
this there's a group of people that have mastered and share their mastery
around how to use Google and force it to the index pre 2023 oh okay why why do you
think that they would want this give me give me some insight because 2023 and
after it is filled with AI litter as in litter like on the internet highway AI is
dumping potato bags and bottles right they so these popular tools are now filled
with AI generated crap yeah right yeah and it is so easy to generate like the
problem right now today is no one has really solved the quality problem right
open AI is like oh yeah GPT-40 can pass the LSAT okay great that's nifty it
can pass the SAT also nifty okay but I don't know about you Ellen I will never
need to pass the LSAT and I only never say the SAT only once well also I had a
friend who's on a fantasy football team volume like 40 40 50 year olds and the
loser of the league had to go take the SAT of a bunch of high school kids so
you may have to take it again I would I'm just saying you never say never I
would never take that back ever so but right it and that's an impressive goal
and a prep and impress a statement but it doesn't necessarily equate to that this
thing is a low friction answer of the of the questions I have for my day-to-day
problems and as a matter of fact it doesn't and there's not really a scalable
way to define the quality I'm looking for let alone how to measure it yeah and
so so people were like well fuck it I can just I can just give it a prompt
generate a graphic and generate a bunch of text like a couple podcasts ago like
you you you did that fake podcast with Google okay that's a fun toy but it's a
toy it would get redundant and boring very quickly right I was that was part of
the argument I had with Gen AI man the other night it can create art I said
yeah not really anyway I don't know that it can create art well it can
create decoration for sure the point is the point I think the majority of people
well probably the majority don't give a crap about or don't know enough about it
the enthusiasts if you look at the cost of Casa crib the enthusiasts all think
it's some magic that's gonna do very basic things for them the people who
can use you does not believe it's I don't know like when I see the people
who say they're really into Gen AI and chat GPT and and and all this stuff all
they're doing is using chat GPT to answer dumb questions I have I think I
might have mentioned this last we're talking about copilot yeah but and this
is the way I describe it it's copilot's great but essentially all it's done is
save time by not making you go to stack overflow to copy and paste that code
there's some subtlety and nuance there it does do better but in the you know four
years ago three years ago the way to program was this is hard
stack overflow well that'll work copy paste into my code yay it works debug
debug today it's let me let me ask copilot or one of the other code gen
tools to help us solve my problem there are there are two things that I have
found Jenny I works really well hey it works more works well for more than two
things but you have to apply some systems thinking critical thinking and add some
skepticism to what it produces that's all I'm saying let me let me change the
scope of my turn right thanks I was thinking in more in general terms if I
don't think like the the Q&A strategy that the most are building off of GPT chat
bots chat bots chat bots I don't think that's a very effective one I don't think
so either people like it though it's a good demonstration of magic the scenarios
and I don't know I I spend a lot of my time thinking about okay what other
scenarios are like this okay the github copilot experience that is phenomenal
right it's so there's one the experience where me and GPT are kind of playing
opposite roles I don't like that it's like I asked it it says something that I
know you're full of shit and then it argues with me in that funny story that
has actually happened my daughter was in the car at the time and she's like dad
you just pissed off the AI right I remember that story okay but where where
essentially GPT is alongside me and pair programming with me that is an experience
I can't live without anymore well why is it you think then if that's the
experience on average if I trust the internet so like 20 to 30 percent of the
suggestions are actually accepted and as we know canonically from that data some
of those still have buggy code so if it's phenomenal why isn't it suggesting
more applicable things more often I think I feel like we talked about this last
probably did but I'm just I'm asking my little feeble mind we did talk about it
but I'll remind you because I remember you argued about it I remember that
discussion I remember winning but go ahead Salesforce it doesn't matter what
actually happened that's what you'll remember the Salesforce actually did an
approach where they measured it okay and and found that their software
engineers were getting a 30% productivity boost and then I went into a
diatribe around no in terms of how Salesforce operates right with a with a
combine and a scrum model is it is actually measurable but anyway I don't
remember where I found this but there was a study that showed that that 30%
increase is common and known when it's an experienced developer using GPT oh yeah
yeah but when it's an inexperienced developer it falls flat and that is
hypothesized to be an experienced developer can look at what was
generated and very quickly go this is a bug or oh great you saved me time
whereas an experience is still constantly learning and doesn't know good or bad
patterns doesn't know good or bad code but um all right fine you're okay I'm
not gonna harp on that so to summarize as we get to the end here deep-seek is
gonna it's gonna bring more LLMs to the masses because it's open source and
runs cheaper it's gonna bring more good and and more bad more of everything yeah
I think that's the way it's gonna bring more all right I hope we get I hope we get
to a point someday or look back and go remember when everybody's all excited
about Gen AI and they're doing shit with it now look what we can do right I'm
waiting to get there I've heard I've seen a couple good examples come out to
like this is a good application of this solving hard problems that you got oh yeah
I would solve this with an all-out so we're getting there I just I don't know
I'm sort of frustrated with where we're I'm frustrated with the pace at which
people are figuring out how to leverage a technology that's far more than a quick
look-up tool I the way I hear you saying it is the killer app that uses
this from Alan Page's point of view does not yet exist correct yeah yeah that's
true that's true and it should do this by now stupid people get out there and
innovate you keep telling us AGI is coming by 20 people are people are too
dumb to get there whatever all right we're gonna we're gonna call that it
thanks for listening to our podcast on remote work and deep-seek and the death
that will come to all of us from AI I am weasel Alan