You have to constantly embrace the new and try new stuff and figure out,
not just dismissing stuff wholeheartedly. I'm just blown away that there are folks in software
development. I see them in software testing. I don't pay attention to other knowledge of work
jobs who are perfectly happy to keep doing things the way they've always done them because there
couldn't possibly be a better way. Welcome to AB Testing Podcast, your modern testing podcast.
Your hosts, Alan and Brent, will be here to guide you through topics on testing, leadership,
agile, and anything else that comes to mind. Now, on with the show. Hey, everybody. It's Alan.
And we're here for episode 187 with an asterisk of the AB Testing Podcast.
There's an asterisk?
There kind of is because I just saw this earlier and I forgot to let you know. Not that I tell
you anything. But if you go to Spotify, remember I did a bunch of those one-off interviews? I still
need to do more of those. I'm happy to do those. But we did the 343. Yeah, the 343.
Yeah, those are fun.
Three questions for one of our three listeners. Apparently, I did about, oh,
12 of those because Spotify says this is our 199th episode.
It's our 199th podcast upload on the AB Testing Feed. But episode 187,
all kinds of milestones coming up. I don't know what we're going to do. We'll figure it out.
I don't think there's going to be a party, but for those of you planning ahead, that's,
yes, we know we've been on the one-a-month podcast. But Brent and I have had lives being
busy to us. And by the way, Brent, you see I'm in my new room here.
I did. I'm noticing.
It's not unpacked. It's a big freaking pigsty in here.
When was the move in?
I don't remember. A couple of weeks ago because I did the Wonderland Trail
right after we moved in. So, yeah.
Are you hanging out in the family room or is this an office?
This is my office. It's just not unpacked yet. I won't do the camera swoop, but sometime I will.
Why not? For the live feed?
For the live feed? Well, I've got the trash back there. There's windows over there.
Oh, I like the windows. The windows are nice.
There's my office door right there.
Okay.
And my closet, which is also my library.
That is some thick-ass molding you have around that door.
No kidding, right? 1906. So, what was I saying? What was I talking about? Podcasts? One-a-month.
We'll get back to two-a-month here shortly, but it's close enough. You can start counting down.
We had hoped to hit 200 right in April at the beginning of our eight-year anniversary,
nine-year anniversary. We're going to be a little behind that, but definitely in 2024,
we're going to hit the 200th episode. We're going to have some listeners on.
I'm not sure how many or which ones or what to do, but we're going to figure it out.
So, all kinds of fanfare coming up, but for today, we're just going to have
Brent and I talking about a topic we have not yet. I'm not going to say decided on. I'm going to say
discovered. Oh, wait. Brent is holding up a topic. Oh, yeah. I do not yet have a TV or a
console hooked up, so I have not yet played the game that I need to be spending a lot of time on
that is called Starfield. Brent, please, all I want to know is, because I know you've put probably
good solid double digit if not triple digit hours in already.
I have not. You'll be surprised actually.
You always surprise me, Brent.
No, no. So, I'll just share here. I'll just say to the listeners, there is a major
life situation happening to me right now that's taking a lot of my time and attention.
It's not at a point where I'm comfortable sharing it on the podcast, but I'll just, to answer
Alan's question, actually, surprisingly, so I started playing it the day before it was publicly
released. You're so cool. Actually, one of my peers said, oh, here's the steps that you have
to do it and you can use money to get in early. I said, oh, that's fantastic. Of course, I think
I talked about it last time. It required me to go buy a whole new Xbox.
We heard all this. We heard all this. All I want to know.
So now let me tell you, I have almost not played it at all.
I need you to play it enough to tell me if it sucks or not.
I am only level seven. I don't think I'm yet at that point.
There are things, so I will tell you, I find myself comparing it to Fallout.
The storyline hasn't captured my attention yet again, but only level seven.
And there are still, when you play Fallout, you go and you craft stuff.
And like crafting, I haven't quite figured that out yet.
And I don't like if crafting is a major part of like,
if I had a little bit of crafting, Fallout 76, a lot more crafting.
I don't really like crafting. I'll do. I like repairing my armor if needed.
Here's the deal. Here's the bottom line.
Yeah.
If I had a choice of never ever playing Starfield, despite the hype or a choice of playing it
and discovering that it's awful, I would choose the former.
That's all. I want to find out. We're going to have a guest on soon.
So let me, without throwing any names out, let me just start this conversation.
If you don't, I probably had something else random to discuss, but let's just start about.
Listeners, you're in for a challenge because we're going to be all over the place.
So there's been some interesting threads on AI.
We're not even about AI, about chat GPT specifically.
We've talked about this before. I want to bring it up again because it's getting
almost embarrassing where some testing experts are writing articles about how
chat GPT is broken and horrible and useless.
My words that paraphrased.
And I hate to be the person to say, but you're using it wrong.
Like you and I, we've had this conversation.
There are so many things that chat GPT is good for and LLMs are good for.
But if you use them wrong, they're not going to be helpful.
Yeah. You and I have said many times, I want to just finish this thought here
because it's then we can see where it goes to.
But you and I have said many times, AI isn't taking away people's jobs, but
people who use AI are or will.
So I was listening. I heard a variation of that.
I'm going to share that. I'm going to shut up because
okay.
But really wants to talk. So I was listening to the Smartless podcast with Kara Swisher.
You know, Kara Swisher is no.
She's awesome. She's written about tech for a long time.
She is super smart. She does a pivot podcast, a couple other podcasts.
Love her.
Oh, no, no, no. I am completely.
I think I'm completely wrong.
I think I do like she's been doing tech for.
Yeah. She used to write with Walt Mossberg back in the day.
Yeah. Okay.
So Kara Swisher is talking about AI with the smart listen.
I've heard her on pivot, talk about it before, but she I like the way she puts it like
AI isn't evil.
People who use AI can be evil.
And I like that as a variation of ours, but she really gets.
It's not going away and it's going to be valuable.
And again, if you want to go back to our audience who is largely not completely,
but largely testers do not shun AI and LLMs and things like GPT because you because somebody
said or you don't think they're helpful.
You will need to more and more over the coming years be able to use and maybe even build and
develop LLMs in order to do your job better.
So if you're going to ignore it, I'm going to go out on a limb and say you will likely be
unemployed because I mean, there'll be a long tail where you don't be.
But anyway, that's my thought.
Let's start there.
Any thoughts on any of that, Mr. Brandt?
Yeah, there's I think there's an analogy.
I think it's spot on.
Right.
The I forget the name of the guy.
So the the super chess champion that that got Bobby Fisher.
No, the one that that got beat by deep blue.
Yeah.
Kasparov.
Yes, that's it.
Thank you.
One of the things that he did is he didn't get frustrated.
What he did is join forces with AI and he called it a centaur, right?
He's he's a centaur part human part.
I guess AI is a horse.
Which part?
Yeah, which part is which I'm confused.
And the drawing.
I'm guessing the human part is the human right.
But maybe not.
I mean, I didn't I didn't come up with a term.
But yeah, the centaur just destroyed deep blue.
Right.
And that's that's what's going to happen.
I do think some of these things there was.
Do you listen to Planet Money?
I do not.
Planet Money NPR show.
So they did a they did a couple of lead up.
It's on, you know, wherever you get your podcast.
Maybe the same place you got the A.B.
testing podcast you're listening to right now.
By the way, give it a rating, write a review,
get us some more listeners.
Anyway, go on, Brett.
Yeah, they had a couple of, you know, set up shows.
And then they finally did a show where literally everything was done by AI.
They even have a host that was AI.
You know what?
It was a lot of work.
It was it did it.
And it only needed the humans really to sort of integrate the pieces and do the final editing
because that's something that I can't do yet.
But it did it.
It's not at a point where they felt their jobs were threatened.
But you could look at the episode and go,
OK, yeah, it just takes a little bit of additional effort.
It's not hard to imagine that that's coming.
And here here's the part that just kind of blows me away.
And again, this is something we've said 50,000 times on here.
But you know, I don't care whether you're coming from software development,
software testing, construction, maybe not construction, actually, maybe construction.
I wonder if we're getting to a point in the evolution of some of the manual labor skills
where construction actually is knowledge work.
I think in some contexts it is, but not all.
But in knowledge work, work that requires discovery to you can go look up Drucker's
definition of work that requires discovery, innovation and making mistakes in order to
learn and get stuff done, which we do.
Software testing is part of that.
Software development is part of that.
Lawyer is part of that.
Cook is part of that.
And I've talked a lot about cooking on the podcast and how it's the same thing.
In knowledge work, you have to constantly embrace the new and try new stuff and figure out,
not just dismissing stuff wholeheartedly.
I'm just blown away that there are folks in software development.
I see them in software testing.
I don't pay attention to other knowledge work jobs who are perfectly happy to keep doing
things the way they've always done them because there couldn't possibly be a better way.
Anything that distracts from the way I've always done it is probably wrong.
So I will put effort into proving that it is and in doing so highlight my dumbness.
I mean, the only thing that's good about that approach,
you'll still be able to sleep at night because you'll know who to blame.
Right.
It's it's oh, it's the AI.
And, you know, last decade, it's agile, agile to blame.
And I'm sorry, it's neither of those.
It's it's you.
All right.
So let me I don't want to dwell on that, but I do want to talk more about AI.
I do want to talk about AI because there's some aspects we haven't talked about.
This is totally not planned.
This is me just letting like Brent and I haven't talked in a month and I'm reflecting on what's
happened in that time and stuff floating in my head in that month.
I took a long hike.
I wrote I wrote a blog post a little bit about it, but I a lot of thinking time.
And one of the things I was thinking about this started off from and I can talk about
my former employer.
I don't think I have any NDA's that say I can't talk about anything.
It's public knowledge.
They they had a food park.
They did some dumb stuff.
And again, I predicted this dumb stuff three years ago.
Let me tell you how they hired an exec who I worked with a Microsoft.
I'm not going to name any names.
And when he got hired, I thought, oh, he makes big dumb mistakes.
He went from Microsoft to Amazon, then to Unity.
And I thought, oh, boy, this guy is not good.
We're going to see what happens.
And he's the one that drove this mistake.
It's you can go read on the Internet about it.
The whole thing about I can talk about this from a public perspective.
One of the things when you're a game development engine and Unity makes a bunch of other
products as well, but their flagship products, the game development engine,
which they sell for free.
That's stupid.
They don't sell for free.
They give it away for free.
If you're enterprise, you pay.
You can pay an enterprise fee for more licenses, etc.
There are some unenforced or not enforceable rules around if you get to a certain revenue,
you should begin to pay for it and just kind of relying on the honor of the system.
So the struggle has been and it always would be with a free thing like this.
How do you monetize it?
At what point do you just hope people once they see value, they feel good about it
and they go pay as actually something I would do if I use free software and I
begin to get a lot of value out of it.
I go and pay for it even if I don't use the paid features.
So yeah, or ads.
It's a struggle to figure out how to monetize that stuff.
And they came up with what I think is the worst possible model for how to make money
and didn't seem well thought out when the users saw it.
The users freaked out, got mad, all kinds of stuff happened.
The Internet was an angry place for a few days.
But what this led me to think about was how much of leadership or running a business
could you drive through generative AI?
For example, you know, judge EPT is very generic.
This trained on literally everything.
What a good portion of everything up until 2021.
Correct.
What if I generated?
And help me with this thought experiment because while I did play a little bit
with building an L, I'll call it a SLM, a small language model.
I ran all 50 of my blog posts or whatever from the last year, just my recent ones.
I think I told you this.
I put it in a blog post something.
And let's say we fed every business book paper from published,
from ignoring copyright issues, just had to assimilate the knowledge,
the vast majority of the knowledge of running businesses that are out there.
Couldn't I just then wouldn't how feasible would it be for me then to ask questions of chat GPT
on how to run my multimillion dollar business?
Could it come up with a better solution for monetizing or better ideas for brainstorming?
Could it tell me how and when to communicate those changes with customers?
And what I'm getting at when I've read articles about which are kind of funny,
but also when I think about it at the end of a long day of hiking,
kind of interesting and scary are, could an AI be a CEO?
It could.
Or more likely, could an AI make a mediocre CEO, a good or an excellent CEO?
So that one, I think is possible, right?
Going back to the Centaur discussion.
Replacing a CEO.
You have to have someone to ask the question.
So replacing is tough, but it's made me think that like the Centaur model is really great.
I think it goes back to AI isn't replacing people, people who know how to use it are.
But I wonder if, so now I'm going to keep thinking.
Well, so let me just finish my thought there is, is yeah, I can see it.
It could certainly play the role of a CEO.
Okay, it's a generative AI.
You ask it to generate things.
It will generate things.
Right?
The thing you got to remember though, is that GPT is not an intelligent system.
It's a parrot.
Correct.
It will be parroting things that it has learned that CEOs say.
Now, whether or not your fictitious business is context sensitive enough for that generative
AI to succeed or not, I don't know.
Let me just explore this because there is a parallel to our first topic.
What I want to do is, I think you're right.
If you follow anyone, whether it's a person, a thought leader, or an AI,
blindly, you are probably not going to make good decisions.
But instead, where people screw up with these models, they ask them for specific things.
Count the verbs in this paragraph.
It's like, shut up, you count them.
But as far as they can help with creativity.
If I'm a CEO, I'm not going to pretend I'm a CEO of Acme chainsaws and bike parts.
And I'm not going to ask it, what should my next marketing email be or business email?
I understand my challenges and I'm going to ask my questions like this.
I'll tell it, I'll give it context.
I'll say my primary challenges are blah and blah.
What are five things you think I should do to...
Again, this is my fictitious LLM based entirely on whole of business knowledge.
What are five things I should consider to solve these problems and move my business forward?
None of them may be the right one, but those may inspire me to make a choice that I haven't
thought of before.
And I could say, well, help me with the marketing email or whatever.
Give me examples.
I've had chat GPT.
I can't remember what I had to do.
I had to write something for me.
It sucked, but it was close enough to to unload some ideas from my head.
So I think that I feel pretty confident that if you're comfortable at getting ideas from
it to feed off your own, you can be really successful.
And the parallel I wanted to draw is where in this scenario, if I was one of those CEOs
who thought I already knew everything, I wouldn't bother asking it.
In fact, I would just try too much time trying to prove it couldn't help me
just as some of these other people are doing with it when they're not using it to their
advantageous to their advantage to learn and grow.
You know what?
I'm going to make a note of that the next time Satya does an AMA, I may just ask that question.
Hi, Satya.
My name's Alan Page.
I have a question for you.
AlanPA at Microsoft.com.
If the mail balances, don't worry.
It is me.
Trust me.
Certainly, I know Scott Guthrie does AMAs all the time.
I don't know if I mentioned it, but that's an ask me anything sort of.
I think that's one.
I think people know what AMAs are.
They happen outside of Microsoft.
So some of the things you certainly can do.
Like I'm on the Bing bot right now, and I just told it that I am a franchise owner for Subway.
And I asked it, who's my biggest competitor?
Jimmy John's?
No, actually.
Burger King?
McDonald's.
Right.
It went.
It said McDonald's, KFC, Burger King, and Wendy's and Starbucks.
Okay.
And now.
Oh, okay.
That makes sense.
Do.
Now I'm going to ask you to do a spot analysis between my business, business, busyness, and Starbucks.
This will be really cool because everybody will hear the key typing as well when you're talking.
Yeah.
Anyway, can you summarize the answer please before I go even farther on my
AI can run our business?
It hasn't generated it yet.
Okay.
While it's thinking.
So going far, there's decision making, but honestly, I think AI, another area where it's
going to help generative AI to be specific is in knowledge discovery.
As you've known me for years, I'm very big on how we acquire knowledge.
You talked about Philip Farmer's five orders of ignorance,
and we need a suitable means to discover what we don't know.
We don't know.
Now imagine, let's talk about Microsoft system because we both know them and we can.
Imagine if you took, are you still using head tracks?
Doesn't matter.
I'll give her a name.
Imagine you take your employee accessible HR data, your employee accessible accounting data,
your employee accessible information about who works on what based on internal, on
documents that exist that people have created.
I want to be able to ask a question like, who besides Brent Jensen's org is working on X?
Actually, I can't say X because X is Twitter.
Who in Brent Jensen's org is working on Z?
I can ask questions like, I need to have a meeting with Brent and his entire team
sometime the week of October 9th needs to be.
And again, rather than me, it's like my assistant.
I have someone else on my calendar, I have for several years.
I love it.
I can never go back, but couldn't AI handle my calendar?
Couldn't.
When a meeting request comes in, I could teach the model that meetings from this person are higher
priority than meetings from this person.
If it got confused, it could ask me.
Yeah, but that's it.
It could actually shuffle my calendar.
So AI can do that and to some degree does.
That type of AI is in or AI like that is in place with Outlook and Exchange, some of it.
I would call that more of an algorithm than AI.
But it's not LLM, it's traditional data science.
Yes, you get the point though.
I think we can, for example, I want to set up a meeting next week for three to five people
who spend a significant amount of their time working on some technology from looking at docs
and I don't want to say looking at emails, maybe looking at public emails,
emails that go to DLs.
It should if enough data is in there, it should be able to say,
here are six people and three of them are available next Tuesday at 11 o'clock.
Yeah, an AGI will absolutely do what you want to do.
And AI is not, no AI is going to do that without some of.
Sure, sure.
I'm not talking about what we can do today or tomorrow, but eventually because
you know that these are blockers.
Things get slowed because we can't get the right players in the room to figure something out.
If we can accelerate that, if we can accelerate the ability to discover knowledge, to discover
the people we need to talk to, to identify problems and move forward,
a lot of huge, cool, good things.
Yeah, you know, the things that are, I was just thinking, even when I get the people in the room,
like I'm not going to mention on the air, but there's a situation I'm dealing with where
for the last three months, there's this team I've talked to, I've shown them,
I've shown them some pretty cool AI that my team is doing that's LLM based.
It's also a really cool problem.
When I show it to them, they're like, oh my God, that's awesome.
And they go, oh, we're going to set up time to go through planning and formalize this.
And we now do semester planning.
Today is the last day of the old semester.
Monday, we start the new semester.
They've not come and talked to me, even though I brought it up every time I met with them.
So now I'm at a point where basically their value proposition to me is that they have
UI Dev Talent that I would love to be able to leverage.
I don't have UI Dev Talent that I have developers, but their skill sets are more back end stuff.
And I'm like, you know what?
I'm just going to sell it around because right now the customers I have for this particular product,
they're huge fans.
And okay, great.
Would you like to?
Oh, you run a dev team.
Hey, do you.
So you can lead a horse to water.
You can't make them drink.
And AI is not going to help with the drinking part,
but you can get the horses to the water way faster.
And if worse comes to worse, if my team needs to invest and build its own AI,
I don't know if you've coded yet with the GPT co-pilot.
I have not.
Oh, you need to do that.
You need to experience that.
If nothing else, do it when the advent coding thing pops up.
Oh yeah.
At advent of codes going to be really interesting this year.
That thing is a game changer.
It's a game changer coding with this thing as your co-pilot.
And I'm like, all right.
So I can do coding now.
I haven't yet figured out a good way to get it to define like an OOP architecture,
but you can do things like write a base class, add properties, and it doesn't matter the language.
Like it's things you know that can be done, but you don't know how to do it in this language.
My worry with a co-pilot is going to lead people to
run and rely on code they may not fully understand.
Oh, it is most assuredly.
Most assuredly.
But the nice thing as well, like, you know what?
My current favorite thing to do with the Coding Code Pilot, right?
As we know on the podcast, Dev does not like testing.
Yeah, it is really good at analyzing my interfaces and coming up with unit tests.
Yeah, I'm like, yeah, baby, keep going.
Oh, no, that one was dumb.
All right.
Let's then I go to my comment.
I say, this unit test does this, this, this, and that.
Then I hit enter and boom, there's the code.
I scan it.
I'm like, oh, this is making me so happy.
I do have the SWOT analysis between Subway.
Yeah.
Oh, yeah.
For those of you who stick around this long.
So what is your business plan, Mr. Manager of Subway?
Well, you know it's SWOT analysis.
Wait, I'm sorry.
Are you a manager or regional manager, assistant, regional manager,
assistant to the regional manager?
What do you do?
No, in this fictitious example, I am the franchise owner.
So, so Subway, Subway is very famous for being the cheapest of all the fast food
franchising companies.
Right.
I think it's like 12K gets you a franchise.
SWOT analysis is a basic MBA analysis.
SWOT stands for strengths weaknesses, opportunities, threats.
And I said, all right.
You told me earlier that Starbucks is one of my big competitors.
Tell me, you know, what, what's a pro and con here.
The strength of Subway.
Great degree of sub customization.
It's the largest fast food restaurant chain in the world by count, which is good.
Right.
A good brand out there.
And apparently they have good marketing strategies.
The interior design looks cheap, turns people off.
And I'll say, I kind of agree with that.
One thing I wasn't aware of, it has a high employee turnover.
And this is one of the problems with franchising.
Services may not be consistent from store to store.
Starbucks though has really mastered that.
That's if I go order a triple Americano anywhere in the world,
it tastes pretty much exactly the same.
The biggest challenge with franchising is getting consistency.
Because yeah, that consistency is what makes your brand threats.
It's saturated, right?
The fast food market is saturated like crazy.
Other people are kind of moving more towards healthy, healthier eating.
And even though fast food or Subway is kind of trying to change its brand on that front.
I'm sure it'll list some opportunities around that.
Keep it up.
And local fast food chains, right?
People were like, Starbucks, let's try something local.
Now it says strength of Starbucks.
Strong brand recognition.
Are we still on strengths?
You got to go a little faster, man.
No, no, I went through all of the SWAT.
Oh, no, no, I didn't.
I went to, I missed opportunities.
And there's one opportunity in here that I'm just like, oh, this is fantastic.
Home meal delivery.
And I'm like, really?
The Starbucks not have a deal with DoorDash.
Every freaking one of the else does.
But introduction of drive-through.
I'm like, I have not seen a Subway with drive-through.
Why?
I mean, that's a good idea.
Why is it?
You think?
And this is where, Roger, with your everything on here, but this is why I think AI can help
because even if it's a bad idea, it can help you think of things you haven't.
And it could be the customization is too complex for drive-through to be efficient.
I don't know.
You and I would both pilot that and make a, we would make a impromptu drive-through with
sandbags in the parking lot and get permission for that and see if it worked.
And it wouldn't even be, it wouldn't even accept the intercom.
It'd be somebody to take your order standing outside.
We would do the pure concierge MVP and see if it was feasible.
Well, so Chick-fil-A.
It'll give you ideas.
Chick-fil-A does that.
Do you?
They don't have the customization.
No, but they do have the poor teenagers sitting outside in the cold and rain.
And I'm like, I feel bad for those folks whenever I see them out.
Well, you know, when Starbucks, they don't, I haven't seen this in years,
but when the line would get long, somebody would come out and take your order while you were in line.
And it turned, and that's, you know, efficient, but it turns out that's also
psychologically keeps you from giving up and leaving because you've already given your order,
even though you haven't paid yet, but you feel like you've given your order.
Now you have to wait it out through the line.
Right.
But if you're in, if you're in a line in the Chick-fil-A drive-through,
you're not changing.
I mean, you're there because there's someone in front of you and someone behind you.
You're going nowhere.
But again, again, let me just pause here and go back to the original statement.
If you are trying to improve your business, oh, Brent, by the way,
what is principle number one of the modern testing principles?
Oh, it's, it's.
I couldn't have set you up better, you dumbass.
Our priority is, is improving the business.
Thank you.
Yes, that's that's it.
So if hearing here, based on my statements, this is
if you want to improve your business, you should use whatever tools you have,
whether it's actual software tools, LLMs, books, knowledge, seminars, discussions,
to try and get better at it.
I think, uh, again, going back to our first topic about these experts dissing on
LLMs, it's not like there's a lot of things wrong with chat GPT.
I can pick on it, but they come from a point of arrogance where this thing
couldn't possibly no more than me.
Let me prove it.
When I look at businesses, whether it's an software organization,
it seems like your team at Microsoft or a large scale corporation,
you have to run them from a place of humility where you know there's more
to learn.
You know, you have to experiment.
You know, you have to try new things and you know, you need to get new ideas.
People make fun of me at my last job and at this job because I drop book references,
like change out of my pocket.
That's a horrible metaphor, but all the time and, and someone that works to be
this week to me like, how do you read so many books?
You know, so many book titles, but I have such imposter syndrome.
I feel like I need to read a couple books a month
just to get enough ideas to hold my head above water.
So I have things to try.
I have things to think about.
I have things to help me try and get better.
And I think and I use it for this.
We've talked about this.
I use chat GPT a lot for that.
Give me ideas.
I'm thinking of doing X.
I'm not putting in, you know, company secrets because we all heard the Samsung story,
but I'm putting in like I want to do X.
I've considered A and B. What else should I consider?
And in those cases, it's super helpful for me.
The moment I assume I know everything I need to do
is probably about two weeks before I get fired.
Well, hopefully.
Right.
The, the, the only reason why it wouldn't be is, is if people are afraid to fire you.
If you, if you've done a good job on making sure that they're screwed because you're the
bottleneck.
There's all kinds of dysfunctional ways.
Doing that.
Sure.
But as you know, I don't believe it.
No, and I know.
And the one thing I will too echo all of the people like you are.
Um, uh, a hungry reader.
I've known that for years.
I'll say the thing that I'm most impressed by is that you actually remember.
Um, you remember sources.
Authors.
And, and the book title.
Just the good ones.
Yeah.
No, I mean, I, at times I'm like, okay, I know Daniel pinks my hero, but what's the
top three books that he's done?
I'm like drive whole new mind.
And I don't know what you'd do for number.
Drives the only one that came to mind, my mind.
And then like, well, right.
And, um, like I wonder how long it'll take before I forget, uh,
Nicole's book name, probably forever because it's because the word of her book
is the first thing in our, in, in, in the end are the modern testing, um, motto.
Right.
And it's like that one's going to take forever for me to forget.
You don't remember that.
Okay.
Well, it's, uh, it's about that time.
And, uh, I hope, I hope you all enjoyed our little walkthrough AI.
We're going to, um, on our next, one of our next couple podcasts, uh, there has
been someone, uh, engaging with folks on trial.
And he fully believes that like Brett and I do, but much more detail, much more
knowledge that testers can learn a lot from AI and taking on these experts who are.
I hate this.
I hate to think of, I feel like I sound like Steve Jobs saying your
iPhone wasn't working cause you're holding it wrong, but, you know,
generative AI and GPT is very much garbage in garbage out.
And if you're not getting out of it, what you think you should be, you should
look at what you're asking it.
So anyway, someone, uh, gonna have a guest on talk about that and go a little deeper.
That'll be fun.
A little bit more about AI.
It'll be fun, fun, fun.
Any closing words from you, Mr.
You're just Brent today.
No, I forget what your weird name was last time.
I don't care.
Don't repeat it.
Yeah, no, we're good.
All right, man.
Okay.
Well, this has been episode 187 of the AB testing podcast.
I am Alan.
I'm Brent and we'll see you next time.