So it depends on which challenge you want.
They're both hard.
They're both fulfilling.
It really depends on which challenge you want, given the context of the team and the product.
Welcome to AB testing podcast, your modern testing podcast.
Your hosts, Alan and Brent will be here to guide you through topics on testing,
leadership, agile and anything else that comes to mind.
Now on with the show.
Hey, everyone.
I'm Angry Weasel.
And I'm Colonel Stinky Bottom.
To the Weasel and Bottom podcast.
Weasel and Stinky podcast.
Oh, I should get stinky weasel dot com.
Oh, yeah.
So the reason I bring that up and you can go to angry weasel dot com and see the history
behind Angry Weasel.
When we're logged into Zencaster, which is working for now,
we have to put in a username and mine is I logged in as Angry Weasel and Brent
logged in while he cleans his room while I talk as Colonel Stinky Bottom.
So could you, um, the story of Angry Weasel is well known on the internet.
Could you please tell the internet, the story of Colonel Stinky Bottom?
Actually, it came from my roommate in college.
He and I played a game and he actually went by general Stinky Bottom.
And I thought that was the funniest game playing handle.
So college kids do dumb things.
And I can tell you because my daughter is gone, left the state, practically left the
country. She has moved into her dorm.
So far, she hasn't done dumb things, but I'm going to say it's inevitable.
That just started, right?
Yeah, yeah.
She starts school on the sixth.
She was able to move in a day early.
So she moved in yesterday, but she's kind of getting unpacked.
And I don't know where she's going to fit all her crap because as I told you, not
only is she moving out, we're boarding up this house and getting out of it.
So she's like, everything gone.
No, the fact that I'm in a weird audio config today, it's essentially, I'm
hearing myself, but sometimes I'm like a three to five second delay.
Oh, well, you're going to have to figure that out.
Milliseconds.
Both are annoying.
Yeah.
Brent has like one speaker that's working on one computer and one
microphone working on the other computer.
It's confusing.
And somehow Zencaster is handling it.
This is our last podcast from from this room.
I am moving on the 11th.
And then after that, I'm on the 14th.
I'm going to leave and go do the Wonderland Trail.
So we'll figure it out.
We'll figure out.
Maybe we'll do one next week.
I don't know what's going on.
It's the A.B.
Testing podcast.
You haven't figured it out.
My AKA angry weasel Allen and he is AKA Colonel Stinky Bottom Brent.
And we're going to do a podcast where we talk about random stuff and hope that we
make sense to at least one of our three listeners.
So like a plan to you, Brent.
It does.
All right.
I have the first topic.
You do.
I do.
It's now Brent topic one.
Go.
Okay.
Do you know what this is?
That is a box.
It is a box.
It is an X box.
I don't know which camera it's an X box, man.
It is a box with an X box.
Correct.
In a box and Xbox X.
I have an Xbox X.
Do you?
I do.
I do, too.
Yeah, I got one in a while back.
A little while because because Starfield that came out.
Yesterday.
Oh, it did just for the pre-release.
Right.
For everyone.
Yes.
But if you are an ultimate game, I am, I am, but I have a problem.
And you bought the premium upgrade and you have one of these and you were
a friend of mine.
You can call me last night and tell me how awesome the game is.
All right.
I can't.
So we have my daughter left, but we do have two teenagers living in our house
right now, long story, and they're living in the room with the Xbox.
So I have it.
I'm not able to play the Xbox for just a little bit longer.
Move the next box.
I got to pack my freaking house.
I'm going to get to it.
I'm going to get to Starfield about a month after you.
So you can ask me.
So it better live up to one half of the hype.
So that's all I can say.
If it is half as good as being hyped, I'll be happy.
But I'm worried.
I'm actually worried that the amount of hype makes me think it's going to suck
and nothing would make me sadder.
It's advertised as made by the Alan makers of Alan's two favorite games of all time.
Fallout 4 and Skyrim.
I was like, yes, yes.
Give me, give me, give me.
If it sucks, I am going to go off.
There's no way there is.
Did you play Fallout 76?
There's a way I did.
And I did twice.
And I will tell you the first time it does suck it.
But the second time I've completed all of the missions.
I was amused by the game.
But now I'm just sort of wandering around upgrading my house.
Like, all right, cool.
I'm not as much into the crafting part.
So I like to fall out for.
Hey, so should we talk about our mailbag questions or other stuff we got to discuss?
What's going on, man? What's the plan?
Do we have a plan?
Yeah, let's do the agenda.
Let's go. We got two mailbag questions.
Mailbag.
And the question is, it's from Aaron.
Aaron Flynn, thank you for being one of the three in our Slack group.
And if you would like to be one of the three, you can go to modern testing.
Org and find the link to join our Slack group.
And if the link doesn't work, you can send me an email.
The address is on there and you can get me to fix it, which I just did this week.
All right. But Aaron asks, I'm interested in the circumstances or reasons people
made a transition from I see to non I see roles.
I see being individual contributor, a non I see, a K.A. a manager.
What makes you go back and forth?
This is editorial comment.
He didn't write this.
He's better at English than I am.
What are reasons for going back and forth between being a manager and a non manager?
What made you do it?
When do you encourage people you manage?
Since I read the question, I'm going to let you I have a I just want to keep on
talking for like 20 minutes on this, but I think it would be better if we got your
insights first, Mr. Stinky Bottom.
Do we think that's the question he meant to ask?
When do you encourage people you manage?
Well, I'm going to switch it like, well, it is about like I'm going to talk about
that, like when people should when I encourage people on my team to become
managers or not.
But I want to tell my stories about going back and forth.
Oh, do you think that's what it was?
Because I'm reading it literally.
When do you encourage the people you're
a manager like all the time?
No, no, no.
It's about making the switch.
How do you coach people on when to do it?
How do you choose when to do it?
And even if that's not the question, this is the question we're going to answer
because this is the better question.
Okay.
I have always been promoted to manager literally every job I've had, even including
when I started at 16 and Carl's Junior flipping burgers.
For me, it's the work ethic that kind of always brings me there.
Managers.
Because I see don't work hard or have a good work ethic.
I'm going to let you finish.
No, but I have some comments.
They do.
It's just I've always been in a position where I was in the upper runs as an IC.
Right.
It's like I'm here to do the right thing, make customers happy, etc.
Try to bounce stuff on your desk while you're talking because I can't edit
that out.
I believe you're selling yourself short.
Please continue.
Think you bottom.
I was always someone who is striving towards perfection as in terms of how I
was being judged.
It since has been revealed to me through my counselor.
This is this is one of the aspects of how I grew up.
And that's all the detail.
I'm going to go on the podcast, but not great.
So what you're saying is your environment growing up has led you to wanting to be
and being more comfortable in managerial roles.
We'll do that.
You will do that.
Okay.
Summarize.
It's one of my powers.
When I look at my strengths, we've talked about strength finders stuff on here.
Right.
I'm really good at seeing what makes each individual really special and helping
them to carve the Michelangelo out of their own marble columns.
Cool.
Early on, it was just because sometime around 20 years ago, what I was
about five years into my career, there's a bit of wisdom that I realized as a
manager, no one's ever going to remember the projects we worked on and what we
shipped the tech, although that's not entirely true, unexpectedly.
Perseus, as we've talked about before, is still in use.
And surprisingly, that thing we built in 1996.
How you how you treat your employees, the employees that love you and the ones that
hate you, they're going to remember you forever.
And I think about that legacy and I'm kind of blending into the second question.
Well, let's not get there because I had a whole bunch of rebuttal and questions
for you for our first question.
Sure.
Are you ready for me?
Yes.
So I want to go all the way back to one thing you said and be very clear on it.
And that thing is you mentioned being promoted into management, which I don't
like that terminology because it's not a promotion.
I'm sure at some companies when you move into management, you absolutely did.
And I will now elevate the volume on you saying that and editing because I can.
I have always been promoted to manager, been promoted, been promoted, been promoted.
It is a career change.
It's a different job moved into management.
Yes.
So let me tell you a little bit about what I've done.
I have gone my entire career bouncing between an IC and a manager and for a
reason and for good reasons every time I talk about those.
One thing really cool is on our Slack group merit has done the same thing.
She has bounced back and forth between being an IC and being a manager.
Some of its contextual and not everybody can do that.
But let me talk about my reasons and see if they help Aaron at all and
understanding.
So I started at Microsoft as an IC 95.
Here's how I became a manager at Microsoft for the first time.
I was working on Windows and it was a
I call Windows ME Windows marketing edition because it was really about
having a ship vehicle for a whole bunch of applications.
So it was a small team and they kind of just put something together.
Pretty small team doing an OS.
We did some I don't want to go into all the details what we did, but I was
working on debugging the nightly stress runs working on the kernel and working
on enhancing and debugging the debug version of Windows and I was
underwater like one of the only times in my life I've gone to my manager
said I'm having a hard time getting all this done.
There's lots of context switching cognitive load and he says, hey, I think
we have a new hire starting next week.
Let's have them work for you.
And I said great.
I have someone to delegate crap to and so I had a direct report.
And he came in.
He's so funny.
I won't call Yawn out by name shit, but he overslept his first day and showed
up around noon.
It was hilarious.
This is what he felt so horrible.
But it was so funny.
I didn't care.
Anyway, Yawn helped me out a lot and they ended up sliding a few more
people into my org for for consistency, the people who ran stress, etc.
So I had a small org after that piece of crap shipped.
I worked over on Windows CE where they grew a larger team around me
because I knew a lot how Colonel and drivers work.
They put all the testers Estet's in charge of tool development,
driver development, kernel development, all of my org.
The name of graphics over and before I knew it, I had this team of
about 50 people.
I was very much and here's probably where I made my first mistake.
My learning as a manager.
I had crappy mentoring as a manager.
I think Microsoft didn't really care as much about managing people
just having people on teams at the time and I was so hands-off today.
My philosophy is give people a framework they can work in and then
get out of their way.
I didn't really give my team a framework.
Fortunately, I had a lot of really good performers on the team and
the team got a lot of crap done.
But then I just didn't like it at the time.
Part of it was I thought the whole I mentioned just mentioned
a minute ago at a team that was performing really well, but we
had the whole stack ranking thing going on which I thought was
dumb and I have to go into these meetings twice a year and go
here's my lowest performer.
Here's what they're doing.
Tell me I'm going to give them a 2.5.
So yeah, we'll do the hand wave and we'll figure something
out. Maybe they get to three.
I said bullshit.
So I just didn't like the way Microsoft made you manage people
about the same time.
Thoma invented this test architect role and my manager said
well, you should be a test architect.
I said, okay.
I don't know what that is.
And so I jettisoned everyone except for the tool development
team at first and eventually jettisoned everyone else back
to an IC.
So I turned to that time.
It's sort of the IC that's the right hand person if whoever
is in charge of stuff and I love that role.
I have someone who works for me in that role now and it's
great.
I love doing that.
I did that.
I went over to the engine XO thing and whatever and did
that for a link.
I left there.
I went over and did that for Xbox.
I worked as a IC reporting to our whatever Chris was director.
He wasn't a VP.
He was a partner director, but I just figured out what needed
to get done and did it.
I've always enjoyed influencing without authority and helping
people.
I've never had a problem with that.
I have no problem having an opinion and helping people get
stuff done and I did not like how Microsoft wanted managers
to behave.
I had studied enough at that point about management.
I got into studying management a lot when I argued with our
learning and development team over the differences between
leadership and management.
I said a lot of things you're teaching managers are good
for people in leadership positions.
So their answer to that was to send me to a bunch of our
management training.
And so I learned a lot there.
This is where I started reading so many damn books about
leadership and management.
I stuck with an IC when I joined Chris's team on Xbox.
I was offered a role of running the tools team for Xbox
and I said that noise because not only did I not really
want to be a manager at Microsoft, but I had been around
a long enough to know that folks who worked on internal tools
got shafted in reviews across the board.
So there's just no way I said, you know what put me in
charge of it.
Don't give me any direct reports.
We're going to run the whole damn thing like a virtual
team open source and and we did and I wrote more code
in those two years.
Like my joke always is my two years on Xbox one were the
best five years of my career and weed and a bunch of
that stuff still being used as well.
Not like famous like the Perseus test case management
system after Xbox one shipped.
I worked on that stupid science project for a while
still as an IC doing whatever I wanted.
I went over to teams as an IC at first and then eventually
grew a team around me and that's where those things
were a little better than the Satya effect was coming
around and it was a little easier to be a manager.
They weren't making us do dumb things.
I found with all my experience influence that authority
and with like the things we talked about on the podcast
and studying agile and agile leadership.
I felt pretty good about it.
I enjoyed management.
In fact, I think I remember at the time we're around
then talking to you and go hey man, should I go
back into a management role?
And you're so in your hell.
Yeah, you do it.
You may not remember that I do know I do.
I totally remember it and and probably over over lunch
at that Vietnamese place, but or somewhere.
Anyway, no, no, no, I do remember it because it was also
the same time we went to I went to Din Tai Fung
for the first time and like everything about like
Din Tai Fung friggin fantastic.
Oh, no doubt.
And that was my first time and I remember everything
about that.
I if I knew the Japanese names, I think I could tell
you what you ate let alone what I ate.
Yeah, Din Tai Fung is Chinese.
Yes, I know.
I realize that I was dumbass again.
Yeah, I remember that and I also remember you were like
the team you were leaving was not great.
Much of what you were saying kind of resonates like one
of the things I realized as you were talking about you
switching back before between a manager and an IC is
kind of what I do between M1 and M2.
I often get pushed into M2 is kind of kind of what I think
is on track right now in my job.
And what's interesting is I love that I have grown to
love that M2 role.
Why how to teach me?
I immediately miss being useful.
I get a lot out of helping leaders become better leaders.
It's really motivating for me in the five levels of leadership
by Maxwell.
He talks about and I love this the levels in the book.
Some of the book is a little weird but talks about you're
putting a position of leadership and then people give
you permission to lead them as a gift to build trust on
that team.
But eventually your job is to build more leaders in the
org and I like that.
I do not want to manage the details of what my team is doing.
I very much want to help go back to Legione.
I'm a galvanizer and a discerner.
I'm going to help them figure out what is the right thing
to work on?
What is the direction?
Let me put a nice framework around what you need to get
done and then let you ride your bike and I'll watch
from the edge of the cul-de-sac and see how you do.
You can ask me for questions, but I really like helping
people become better leaders.
I'm a very good leader in the business.
It is what I will do for the rest of my career.
I'm managing a much smaller team at NBC that did a
previous job, but I'm still managing a group of leaders.
I have my right hand I see and three other director
plus level folks and my job is to give them a framework
where they can be successful and coach them.
I just went through the just very quickly the five
levels of leadership.
I got to imagine this is something you talked about
before but I'm looking at it now and I'm like, I don't
remember ever thinking the thoughts I'm currently
thinking.
Right.
These five levels is fantastic.
I wonder does the book go through and and argue why
that's the leveling very much so.
Okay, Amazon.com.
Yeah, so let me go ahead and finish my story because
I kept on bouncing around.
I went to unity as a manager direct and as we discussed
on here and as I've done many times in my career, I
worked myself out of a job.
I got to a point where I had moved all of my team into
either quality coach roles into Dev roles into DevOps
roles platform engineering whatever you want to call
them and all of a sudden I was an IC without a team.
So I went over if you recall and worked as an IC on
our ad system running program management, which was
a good learning experience for me and I learned a
whole crap ton about delivery in just having an
opinion there moving forward that I still apply
when I went back to leadership.
So I I am comfortable but I am comfortable being an
IC who tries to influence hundreds or thousands of
employees as I am leading a team of 50 100 200 500.
I am beyond the point in my career where writing code
all day is going to be my job or even where writing
code half the day is going to be my job.
I miss it, but I'm just not as good at it as my
employees are but I feel like I am I enjoy it and
I feel like I do a good job influencing and leading
large numbers of people with a M and IC or a manager.
So will you comment on that?
I'm gonna go back to the whole like how do I
make that choice?
I'm thinking yeah, you're right on for me.
I know I and I'm wondering if that's one of the
if that's my next thing right now, right?
Similar to you your career since you and I've
met you've kind of changed what you do and how
you're doing it every two to three years if not faster,
right?
I used to argue through on that but you're exactly
right.
You did and then I think I don't know.
I feel like I may have pointed out the pattern
because I remember one time you did try to argue
with me and I'm like dude, I know I take it back.
I was wrong.
I'm like it's on fucking LinkedIn.
Let's go look right now.
Yeah, I'm thinking I really still get a lot of
joy. It's not so much of the coding stuff as much
anymore. I'm spending a lot more time focus on
teaching my my employees.
It's almost out of self-defense.
I run a team of data scientists and very very
clearly the trend is that a science is going to
be a specialization in death.
It's it's absolutely clearly a trend in my mind
that's ever increasing and so I'm like, okay,
these guys got a code and I don't think a single
person other than me on my team really has a good
sense for example of design patterns or TDD or any
of these sort of modern development principles.
That's not true.
Actually, I have two people one has a one was
trained collegiately as a CS right up to Masters,
but the other one has has industry.
I mean your story makes sense.
Do we use that you have more things to go?
Oh, I think that was I just saw how I make the
choices. You know, I don't think I'm going back
to being an IC and it really if I go back to
the points where I've made that choice, it's
taking the opportunities where I thought I could
learn the most and being a manager isn't for
everyone. In fact, one of the things I do I did
this at Unity.
I'm doing it right now in my current job is when
someone wants to be a lead like someone thinks
I'm thinking of going into management and in my
head first off a conversation with them and I'll
explain to him that's a career change and by
the way Camille Fornier's book called The
Manager's Path excellent walkthrough on how
like she's really thought through this.
I think it's an excellent book.
I'm a big fan of hers, but I have a conversation
with them first to figure out like this is a
career change is different.
It's not a promotion.
It's not easier.
It's just different.
It's a different job and if they tell me yeah,
I want to try it.
I make them a provisional lead which means that
they I don't move the people over but they act
like the lead of the team and they and they
function as the manager.
I treat them as a manager.
They're invited to my leadership meetings and
I like to do that for about three months and
what happens in that time is they figure out if
management's for them and I will tell you 25%
of the time maybe a little less 20 to 25%
of the time people have gone through those
three months and said you know what this was
fun, but I'd like to go back to being in I see
and because it is a dip.
It's a career change and I want to give people
the opportunity to try it in a safe environment.
And if it doesn't work out, it doesn't work out.
No, no feelings lost.
They got a chance to do it in a safe environment.
Lesson learned.
How did you bootstrap that that sort of process
within your team like the first time.
Hey, this person is going to be an active manager
without any reports like how do they learn how
to manage in that regard?
Well, I talk about with the team about what
the provisional lead role is like.
I say I explain this is anything I explained
to you to the team.
When we have opportunities for someone to move
into a lead position and someone's interested.
I explained that will put them in this provisional
role. I explain what it means.
It means they're going to manage the team.
We're not going to we're not going to make the
HR changes, but we're going to have them manage
the team for around three months.
I like from two both sides to try before you
buy it's a very safe way to do that.
I don't know how it is.
I know since the big flattening at Microsoft
is all these people that were had been leads
forever. All of a sudden weren't leads and when
I would open a lead position, I would get 10,000
internal applicants for that position, but I had
an opposite challenge on my previous team where
I don't know enough yet about the current team
where people did not want to be leads.
They thought that seems hard.
I don't want to do that versus all that seems
easy. I want to do that, but I want to give
them the opportunity to do it in a way.
That's not scary.
I just talk about it.
I socialize it.
I like that strategy in some regards.
I'm kind of doing this more informally with
with my team.
I have two IC level principles on my team
and I really want them to understand business
leadership in my organization is something
that I believe for a very long time.
I do know my senior VP agrees with me on this
principle level.
I sees they need to be more owning a small part
of the whole business like they own the KPI.
They got to move.
They own the strategy to get there.
They own that business and it's a real struggle
for people going from senior to to principle
right because they what do you mean?
What got me here isn't going to get me there.
Did you have a difficulty making that shift?
I know I did.
I said at 64 for I think seven years because
I was just like and then I realized I went and
actually talked to the right set of people and
they're like there's no such thing as as a level
60 at that point a level 65 test architect.
That was sort of what they were saying.
Now, I know that got to be true, but they're like
they may have that title, but they're a business owner.
They're not just the next level up test architect type
book and for non-Microsoft people that's sort of
that where the principle level begins the principle
engineer. Yeah, it was really hard at that time.
I think it's important to a lot at that level.
It's important to align yourself with a manager
who understands what should come out of that role.
I think it's important as a principal engineer 65
plus for Microsoft folks to have an opinion that
matters that you can sell.
I guess the big difference like at 64 you could
just crank out really good work all day, but at
65 plus you're expected to be an influencer and
and help drive big things and get them done, which
I enjoyed so I probably I must have been I don't
really remember when I got promoted 65.
I know I think I was still in Windows CE.
I was because I think I made it to 66 in Windows
CE the mid-principal level and eventually got to 67
when I worked in engineering excellence.
The short answer is and we're not going to get
to the second mailbag question, but the short
answer is to I see your manager is I would say
understand that it's a career change and be in
the place where you can both learn the most and
have the most impact and I honestly be engaged
the most I wouldn't take a manager position just
to take a manager position if I didn't want to do
it. If I didn't care about growing people and
increasing engagement to me, I think the most
important thing a manager can do is drive engagement
for their team, which means building a healthy
org, which means autonomy mastery and purpose make
sure people understand that they're what they're
doing and why it's important have the skills in
order to do that and the autonomy in the framework
they can work in and then get their work done as
a manager. You want to build that culture for your
team to be successful. This is true for a line
manager as well as a manager and managers take
that management role. If you want to not have the
burden of that and get a bunch of stuff done
that impacts maybe even a larger part of the orgs,
I think those high-level ICS can often or I think
65 plus going back to principal engineers.
They're having influence not only in their
manager's org, but in their manager's peers
organization. So it depends on which challenge
you want. They're both hard. They're both
fulfilling. It really depends on which challenge
you want given the context of the team in the
product completely. I mean, I think the trick
is take on the one that's more important and
then train up your people and have them help
you shoulder the burden on the other. Yes. Work
yourself out of a job. Yes. We've said that
mission repeatedly on the cast and I will say
it is still the right thing. Absolutely. And did
you see my my sub stack post like two weeks ago?
What was the title? I don't know some Taylor
Swift song. I read something recently. I don't
know if it's the one. Why don't you make the
it was a real story about us talking to someone
who were talking to their husband and their
husband said they couldn't take a vacation
because their team needed them. Oh, I did read
that one. And that's a true story that made me
think so much like that is absolutely wrong. So
every manager I've ever worked for I've all I've
taken a bit of their style and made it part of
my own right. The bad managers like the thing
I took it from the from their style is like,
yeah, I am never going to do that. But there
was one manager that told me early on in my
career that at Microsoft there is never a good
time to take a vacation. Therefore any time is
just as good. I think that's true for any job.
Yeah. And we need to learn from Europe. I don't
care what's going on. I'm gone for four weeks.
I don't know if that's we need to learn. It's
tough for Merk tough for Americans. No. So one
of the issues one of the issues that contradicts
that which is there's still like at Microsoft
and I don't know how how wide it is. There's
still this sort of emphasis around specialists.
Hey Alan, what's your project right. And I'm
like yeah I don't want Alan to own a project
and I certainly do not want my manager talking
to him about the project he owns because that
contradicts the T shape people I'm trying
to build in this organization. But with that
with that sort of ownership model it has a we've
talked about this a million times. Right. A
specialist is on this podcast is known as
what a bottleneck. Right. Right. And you know
what you may not actually your team may not
actually need you or may actually need you
if you're a manager I'm going to just straight
up tell you if your team needs you you're up.
Yeah. Now it may be situational like there are
times where that happens but I sure as hell
hope that you are as Alan said I think like
six times on the podcast working yourself out
of a job one million percent. All right with
that violent agreement I think there are some
chunks in there that maybe someone finds
valuable we'll find out let us know. Yeah let
us know could join our slack community give us
high ratings tell people listen to the podcast
send us we don't need any money. Send us don't
send us anything save money. All right let's cut
there. I am angry weasel Alan and I'm I'm just
right now. Okay that's cool. We'll see you
next time everyone. Bye.