And to be clear, when I was in college, I worked at a grocery store and I was a checker.
Welcome to AB Testing Podcast, your modern testing podcast. Your hosts, Alan and Brent,
will be here to guide you through topics on testing, leadership, Agile, and anything else
that comes to mind. Now, on with the show. Hey, hey, everybody. Hey, hey, hey.
Hey, it's AB Testing. It's AAB Testing. I was thinking Fat Albert.
We're doing a podcast and did you know we're doing a podcast? Are you aware of this fact?
Are you aware that we have a podcast? I just call in. What are we on? 167.
So we've been doing this podcast. Here is the question of the day, a little podcast trivia,
and you can play along at home. Just open your favorite podcast app and put in this code.
What was the date that we posted episode one of AAB Testing?
Wasn't that April? April something April 1st?
What year? Oh, God, I have no idea.
April 13th, 2014. Okay.
We are coming up, you know, we're six months away from our nine year anniversary.
Not too bad for two people who started a podcast for really almost on a dare from Michael Hunter,
right? Yeah. I don't know if it was a dare. You guys should make a podcast. We're dumb enough to go.
Sure. I interpreted it a little bit differently.
He could have said you guys should stick your finger in a light socket. We would have gone.
Yeah, sounds great. You might have.
So I might have because I'm not particularly bright, but what's interesting.
And I want to do a little meta and talk about the podcast a little bit here today.
I was in a meeting today with some folks, external to unity and with some folks internal to unity and
and almost all the time I'm finding more and more stalkers and you know who you are.
It's like the podcast was a different thing when everybody who listened was an anonymous
human being. We didn't know. Remember when we had three listeners and like Jim Moore would come up
and say, Hey, I'm one of your three listeners. And Steve would say, I'm one of your three
listeners and we only have three listeners, but yeah. Okay, good. Anyway, the point I was getting
to was as you type away on your fucking keyboard is that these folks in this meeting are like,
Oh, hey, man, you know, Alan is a podcast. They listen to the podcast. So hi,
Wyatt. Hi, John. Hi, Steven. I and anybody else is listening. It's not a very good podcast.
I guess it is an excellent example of the, this is no 98% invisible.
Malcolm Gladwell. Stop. This is an excellent example of a podcast for the genre we invented.
What's the genre? I'm leaving that for the listeners. Oh,
you know, actually we are the number one podcast of all time in our genre as well.
Absolutely. I completely agree. I'm picking up what you're laying down. So I switched
to anchor FM for hosting, which has been really good. And this I'm not, I could do ads for anchor
and they pay us, but I don't, you know, uh, but anchor has been pretty good. There's your ad
anchor if you're grepping text in our podcast, but they keep stats much better than my previous
platforms I used. Do you know? So it's been less than a year. It was last January. I changed
everything over to anchor and screwed up everybody's feeds and got it all correct again.
Guess how many another Japanese question. Another is on your quiz app. Everybody
guess how many people in that last year have gone back to listen to episode number one and
and made it through the vast majority of it. Three. Oh, that what's weird. It could,
it could be the same three people each doing it 254 times because we have 700 or two
wrong math. You know, we have 712 listens of episode one in that last year. I don't know what
you people are doing. That is, uh, even though even its debut episode was still the top of our genre.
It was not even meh. It was, it was Brenton Allen trying to figure out how equipment to work,
trying to figure out what to talk about, which is kind of what we're doing here.
Eight and a half years later. Yeah. You know, when you, when you master a skill,
you make it part of the environment and we'll call it the dark genre as well.
But we've made it very clear on this podcast and specializing generalists that I'm really a master
of nothing. My secret skill is I can learn enough of anything to be super effective,
but I'm not a master of anything. I will say your secret power in this context.
And I do not, I do think that this phrase very well captures it and I do not in any way, shape,
or form mean any offense. This is nothing but praise, right? You are the master of fake it till
you make it. Oh, I, 100% that is, you know, maybe that's how we work together. So I was thinking
about how different you and I are. Like I was making, um, they're asking about the podcast and
someone brought up the fact we're talking about politics sometimes. I said, yeah, Brent's one of
those stupid libertarian to let his political views get in the way of actually making progress
in the country. But we'll get, we'll get back to that later. But, um, but also in this context,
you know, Brent's saying you're number one, number, number one of my genre. That's great.
So, uh, you have, you are a deeper expert in the areas where you need to be like, you were deep in
test automation and wrote a, a very good and probably one of the best test automation
harnesses used at Microsoft. Um, both a praise and a dig. Also what you're doing now with data
science and it's, it's super deep, what you know, and I'm more of a, I mean, you've seen me,
I can get around in the data science world and, uh, but I faked everything, but it's,
it's even before I got into tech, that was my thing. Uh, I played in high school, I played
clarinet and saxophone. I did not want to bring my nice saxophone outside to play in the marching
band. So I, I learned how to play drums well enough to make the drum line in my high school.
So then I played drums and drum core, I played drums in college, college marching band. I even,
I, I, I did not know that. So here's the funny part. Uh, not only did I do that,
and then I played, I played percussion. I made the top jazz band playing vibraphone, uh, vibes.
If those are, is that the cool thing that they use to make the, the Star Trek sound?
It's like, no, no, no, that's a theremin. It's like a xylophone, but metal wider keys, uh,
two octaves or one octave below often use in jazz. So a big fan of Gary Burton for those you want to
dig in there. So I, I wanted to do it. It was actually easier path. There was an easier path to
me to get in the top touring jazz band playing mallet percussion than it was for me to get in
the long, long line of saxophones. So I did that for a while. And then here's the funny part. I went
out enough. Everybody knows this that I taught school for four years after I graduated. I came
back to graduate school.