I get what you're saying.
It's all true.
I'm not sure if we're actually getting any deeper on this or actually I'm not sure where
we're going with this is my point.
So welcome to AB testing podcast, your modern testing podcast.
Your hosts, Alan and Brent will be here to guide you through topics on testing leadership,
agile and anything else that comes to mind.
Now on with the show.
Zencaster, you're my.
Yes, I got to witness it.
The long hard fought battle Alan had against the inanimate objects.
Now I got to be nice here.
Because remember last time Zencaster died on me in the middle and I was upset, but it's
okay.
This time I'm trying to be very nice to it.
I know how to caress it.
The audio was coming out the wrong speaker.
So what you do to trick Zencaster into loving you again, because that's what we want to
do.
Want to trick it into loving us again.
That's all about relationship building.
You change the audio setting to something else, save that and then go back to the one
that it said it was doing before and it will suddenly work.
Feels like a bug to me.
Now Zencaster and I love each other and we're going to love each other for about
the next 45 minutes.
And we're going to together when a man and his software love each other very much.
They come up with a podcast.
This is nearing creep.
Creepy.
Yeah, I know.
Yes.
And I don't.
I don't want to raise alarms.
But in terms of the little audio signal, I see yours.
No, no, no.
I don't see mine.
I see yours.
It's good.
Yeah.
So I see it.
It's a lot of editing and post-pros where I go bleep out the stuff.
I get rid of me.
I try and make myself sound smarter and Brent less dumb.
It's a lot of work, but it's fun.
What I want to kick off with here is really extending a little bit on our last podcast
with Dagna, but just really taking the elephant in the room and hugging it with both arms.
Yeah, that that was that was a bit coincidental, huh?
Well, you know, from my position, I, you know, I was I've been working on, you know, unfortunately,
the layoffs we had at Unity for several months.
So I knew that was going on while we were talking about that.
But you know, the industry overall, there's a lot of a lot of folks we work with Jim Moore,
one of the three after 26 years of Microsoft was laid off.
I was not aware of that.
As well as did you ever work with David Klein on Xbox?
No.
It just is the new for a long time.
I mentioned him for a while, just really, really cool kid.
I call him the kids younger than me, but he's probably your age.
Anyway, he was laid off also after 31 years.
It kind of blows me away.
And then I noticed your your name on our Zengcaster session, but still love you.
Zengcaster is still employed.
Yep.
I have lots of thoughts and takeaways and some comments, but but how are you doing?
I mean, it's it's weird.
A lot of a lot of folks are no longer your coworkers.
What's that like?
Well, so it's first and foremost, it's it's horrible, right?
There's there are a lot of mentees, old, old friends, like rumors going around.
Anxiety is high.
I didn't know about Jim.
I'm still kind of reacting to that.
I want to tell a Jim story here in a little bit.
Remind me.
Jim is in one of the two two groups that I am aware basically got hammered.
And there's another group that I've heard of.
But one of my buddies in that group, I still see that they are very much online.
So one of the things that's tough for me and we should talk about about you as well.
Right.
One of the things that's tough for me is I have I have a relatively large team for a frontline
manager.
I have a relatively large team and that's something that they want to talk about.
Right.
Like, well, how is this decided at this point in time?
It's it's not clear to me.
Right.
Well, is it all done at this point in time?
It's not clear to me.
I have worked with my team long enough to know for them to know that I'm going to be
transparent.
I may not.
For example, I do know something and I cannot share.
I will tell them, look, I know something that's related to that and I cannot share.
It'll be a different version of that.
But credibility is my currency and I'm not going to violate that.
And so I actually had a very long conversation with one of my employees yesterday and I said,
it's fun having a conversation around layoffs with a data science team.
Right.
Because I can go in to use data science terms.
I'm like, look, what you're asking me to do is build a predictive model where I I not
I not only do not know the the the label for the golden set, I don't know the features
for the golden set and I don't know the rules for the golden set.
So if I were to build a predictive model, like what you're what you're asking me to do
is is tell you, Britt, what's the probability that that I'm going to get laid off?
Literally is some number between zero and 100.
I am.
Ask chat GPT.
Yeah.
And I said, and I'll be I'll be very honest with you, Alan.
For me, that's a little uncomfortable because all the other prior layoffs, I've been pretty
well connected to the communication network.
Right.
I've been able to learn or glean more of what must be going on.
Pretty good at inferring from, oh, that team's doing making this decision.
This of the team over here is doing that decision.
Oh, OK.
The overlords must have been going down this path.
Right now, I don't I don't know the policy here.
And I said, there's two things.
Number one, this is a model that's in terms of predictive model.
This is a model that is 100 percent uncertainty.
Yes.
Number two, in my view, the absolute worst thing I can do with my employees is give
them false hope.
Let me just build on a lot of what you said there.
So involved in building part of our model this time, it is not a repeatable model.
You would never use the same model for selection for two layoffs in a row.
So that even furthers the unpredictability problem you talked about.
And inevitably, all models are wrong.
Some are useful.
I make sure I got that quote right.
Make sure.
But it's true.
The model is wrong.
This is what is hard for me is one.
There's a couple of things that are hard for me.
One is the model is wrong.
I got it wrong, but it's impossible to get right.
I tried to get it as less as least wrong as I could.
And I know I didn't get it right.
And even if I go back in time and do it again, I would do something different.
I would get it wrong again.
It's impossible to get right.
There's a lot of guilt that goes with that.
And then when you've heard me talk about how psychological safety is just so
important on my teams and trust.
And then when things like this happen, it's my role to be the messenger for the team and
talk about why it happens and to share as much as I can.
But it's hard for me because I try and be ultra transparent.
There are legal reasons around this that make me I can't be as transparent as I want
to in everything that went into this, which is hard.
And then also just the fact that it happens resets that trust level on the team.
I have worked to go do again.
And that's hard also.
So yeah, it's rough.
I reread and I've been rereading the book I mentioned in our podcast with DAGNA, this
book called Healing the Wounds, Overcoming the Trauma of Layoffs and Revitalizing Downsized
Organizations because it talks a little bit about the layoff process, but it talks a lot
about a lot more.
The bulk of the book, and you should read it too, is about what you and I are experiencing
is how to deal with being the survivor of a layoff because it feels fucking weird.
To me, my superpower that has helped me for so long in terms of surviving the company
is been fairly accurate around what sort of skills are going to be needed in the next
three to five years and making sure that I'm developing myself in that direction.
Learning what's important.
There's this old book I read years ago.
My dad was a director of program management and he was a big fan of books by an author
named Harvey McKay.
And I read, it was all about perspective setting.
We have seen all sorts of studies that employee engagement is a real important thing to build
within your team.
Yep, the most important thing actually.
It is.
The Lentione studies and research shows that engagement with work has a massively hard
correlation with the predictability and quality of what your organization produces, regardless
of whether it's software, widgets, sandwiches, whatever.
Engagement critical.
Yes, totally.
As you and I work very strong to make our teams feel like our families away from our
families.
One thing.
Let me interrupt you there because it's tough to even hear those words because when companies
do things like this, it's cogs in a machine.
It's reusable pieces.
It's hard.
That's what I was saying.
For me, a lesson I learned a long ago is that you absolutely should do that, but you should
also put in constant reminders that this is a business and that business decisions will
be made based off of business KPIs.
When I go into this, it's like, okay, what kind of a business would you like to work in?
One that feels like a family or one that doesn't?
Well, obviously, duh.
A very simple answer.
Just like all great things that can be overdone.
As you do that, you can't lose sight that it's a business.
And that is part of it that can ease the sting because what's happened a lot
of places, it's a shocking reminder.
Going back to the book, there's a bit of advice that he gave.
The single best way to assure you are not impacted by layoffs is to make sure you're
on the decision committee.
And it sounds like a tautology, but to me, it's direction setting.
Going back to modern testing principles.
Principle number one is not key just for testers.
It is key for everything you are doing in your career life.
And the slightly revised version that we have floating around.
Right.
It is in your corporate world, every decision you make should be around if you want to minimize
the probability and this is no guarantee.
But the only wisdom I have learned, if you want to minimize the probability of you being
impacted by a shocking layoff, you need to pursue what makes you happy.
That's obviously true.
But you need to, within those constraints around your motivations, your skill sets, or whatever,
you need to optimize all decisions you make around business impact.
I'm thinking right now, I'm a data scientist.
Well, there's a very few of us.
Right now, that's a good optimization.
I am in Azure Core, which is a key.
It's not only the cloud is a key business of Microsoft, but I'm in Azure Core, which
is the key business unit of Azure.
I am having strategic impact across all of Azure.
These are all things that increase that probability of me providing business impact.
I get it.
And pushing back just a little bit.
I'm surprised.
I want to go back just a little bit, because I want to go back to engagement.
And the point is, I don't want to optimize what I do around making sure I don't get fired
because that's not engaging.
Engagement comes from three things.
Research shows us three things.
You have to care about the work you're doing.
That's the matter to you.
Yes.
You need to know your manager cares about what you do.
Research shows this, and you need feedback.
Now that first one's really critical.
This is just kind of a technology as well.
If you like your work, you do better work.
Mastery, autonomy, and purpose.
Yes, going back to Dan Pink.
This is the purpose part.
God, I can't even think straight through all this.
What I worry about, and what you just said, is, is your purpose to not get fired?
No.
Because you made it sound like that a little, and that's where my pushback comes from.
I am going to restate what I said.
Every decision you make should be around optimizing business impact.
And I said that purposely.
It says the absolute worst thing you could do is take a defensive strategy.
I am going to do everything I can to avoid fill in the blank, painful thing.
That nearly always fails.
No, I get that.
What you want to do is create a positive impactful mission with one that would ideally also avoid
the thing that you're afraid of.
I used to tell people back in Microsoft, if you remember when we did the scoring system,
and you and I went through both of them.
I got 4.5 once.
Right.
And now my question is, okay, and which model was that?
Where 4.5 was good or bad?
It was good.
Right.
It's one of the best you could get was a five, but I never knew anyone that got a
five.
So I have gotten four O's in both models.
The end when you get that negative message, the absolute worst thing you could do is
respond out of fear and say, I got to do everything I can to avoid a four O next time.
Because I've heard of this rule.
If I get too many of these in a row, I'm fired or whatever.
Right.
And that's the wrong thing to do.
So let's say a five O is the best, best thing.
And you got a two.
Right.
You do not try to avoid the two.
What you do is you have a conversation with your manager and say, yeah, that was a
sucky speed bump, but now let's have a coaching conversation around the reality
of what am I going to do to get a four?
Sure.
And this goes back to purpose and it goes back to making sure you're valuable,
being, you know, it's your, you're valuable.
But in the end, as I discussed before, the model is unpredictable.
It is.
So you can do all that stuff and still lose your job.
Absolutely.
So, so even for me, even for me, like as I told you what I told my employees,
the model, do I feel safe right now?
No.
Right.
I am beginning to hear rumors of the next set of dates when the next hammer is
likely to fall.
Is that going to impact me?
At that I can say yes, because either it's going to impact me directly or it's
going to impact me indirectly.
The only thing I can do about it now is any sort of safeguards that I might put
in play.
If you don't have a backup plan, yeah, maybe, maybe it's worthwhile spending a
few moments thinking up what that strategy might be, but don't over pivot
on it.
That's, that's number one.
And number two, what I am finding right now is that I'm finding that this
phenomenon is making me live in the present more than anything else.
It's like, yep, I, my career may die tomorrow.
So what I'm going to do, because I know that if it does, there's nothing
I can do about it right now.
There's no VP.
I could go argue, plead, beg.
There's nothing I can do about it right now, but it also seems some, my
pointless seems unwise for me to go ahead and book that $30,000 vacation
in the summertime.
Of course, of course.
So I think we're, I get what you're saying.
It's all true.
I'm not sure if we're actually getting any deeper on this or actually, I'm not
sure where we're going with this is my point.
So yet, yet try and keep your job, losing your job sucks.
And it's one thing, it's a little harder for me this time around with, I have
the people laid off my order.
For example, I know people like at Microsoft, you know, Jim and David, we
brought up before who are, you know, they're good.
They're really good at what they do.
But the challenge is now there's a hundred thousand software engineers out there
looking for jobs at the same time.
So I worry a little bit about the market.
Well, and they just take a little longer for them to find their next gig.
And here is the, here is the thing that you haven't thought about yet.
I think the people who, who at Microsoft, because again, I'm hearing
rumors that that there's, that there's multiple decision dates coming.
Right.
It's all going to close by, by March, but there's more events, right?
Well, guess what?
The people who got hit first, they have the advantage.
They have a headstart.
Right.
And yeah, it, I think I may have brought it up.
No, I have had, I brought it up in other conversations.
It reminds me of Moneyball, right?
Where there's one scene in the movie Moneyball where the guys, uh, the
guy says you have a decision, there's nothing you can do about it.
You're going to die tomorrow.
But the decision is how you can take a one bullet to the head or five to the
stomach and bleed to death.
That's, that's your only choices.
For me, that choice is clear, right?
If, if, if it's not avoidable, then make it as painless as possible.
Okay.
And please clue me into the metaphor.
No.
So if the issue is this is the first time where I've seen potentially big layoffs
throughout the company that has multiple dates and, and there was a big thing that
happened a couple or last week and people are like, okay, well, is the decision
closed?
Am I safe now?
And maybe it's, so it's, it's kind of.
For those of us currently, for those of us currently surviving and are
gonna get hit the next time, that's sort of been shot in the stomach, right?
So you're not only making it, you're not only killing them, but you're right.
They're anxious right now.
Right.
Yeah.
And that's something worth, worth talking about.
I don't think that's right.
No, I don't think it's right either.
But again, I can't recommend this book enough to explain like what you're going
through and the impact of layoffs.
So yeah, the anxiety of am I next?
Even if there aren't rumors, even if there aren't rumors, even if you've been
assured by your manager that your team won't be targeted for layoffs, you can't
help, but feel anxious about that.
You can't help, but worry about that.
And it affects your productivity.
It affects your engagement.
It affects your morale.
It accelerates the oncoming of burnout and many other things.
It's a traumatic experience.
And I don't think I use that word lightly there.
It is, it is a form of trauma to have to go through all this and there's deep
emotional effects on the, on everyone involved in things like this.
And it's tough.
Yeah.
And even, even surviving is not all that great, right?
No, it's not that, right.
That's the point.
That's exactly what I'm saying.
Because you still, you still have all this work that has to be done, but now
you have X percent people to do it with.
Yeah.
Let me talk about that for a second and read you a quick story from the book.
We can go back to the family metaphor of, of is your team a family or not?
So imagine a family, a father and a mother and four children.
The family has been together for a long time, living in a loving,
nurturing, trusting environments.
So I thought my org to be on my org to be.
The parents take care of the children who reciprocate by being good.
Every morning they have breakfast together, which is a bonding experience for them.
It's kind of like an organizational staff meeting.
One morning, the children sense that something is wrong.
The parents exchange furtive glances, appear nervous.
And after a painful silence, the mother speaks father and I have reviewed
the family budget, she says, looking down at her plate, avoiding eye contact.
And we just don't have enough money to make ends meet.
She forces herself to look around the table and continues as much
as we would like to.
We just can't afford to feed and clothe all four of you.
After another silence, she points a finger.
You too must go.
It's nothing personal, explains the father as he passes out a sheet of paper.
Each of the children, as you can see by the numbers in front of you,
it's simply an economic decision.
We really have no choice.
We have arranged for your aunt and uncle to help you get
settled to aid in your transition.
There's more.
The next morning, the two remaining children are greeted by a table
on which only four places have been set.
Two chairs have been removed.
All physical evidence of the other two children have vanished.
The emotional evidence is suppressed and ignored.
No one talks about the two who are no longer there.
The parents emphasize to the two remaining children, the survivors,
that they should be grateful since after all, you've been allowed
to remain in the family to show their gratitude.
The remaining children will be expected to work harder on the family chores.
The father explains that the workload remains the same, even though
there are too few of you.
The mother reassures them that this will make us a closer family.
Eat your breakfast children and treats the father.
After all, food costs money.
Oh, that's amusing.
It's it's amazing because it's sad.
Well, it's.
There's there's some there's some real parallels there.
You know, I had to deliver one of these layoff messages myself and it sucked.
Right.
That the reason why your story you just shared actually works.
And the one thing that's the one thing that's missing from really the story
is right, the fear that the mother and father have around
uncle or our cousin, Bob,
or the two children leaving and suing them.
So it's not just a business reality, but a lot of the constraints that happen
is because we live in a litigious society
and you just can't you can't be real
because that could make things even worse.
100 percent, 100 percent.
I that that's I.
Yeah, absolutely true.
So it's a mess and it's again, you have anxiety because you've heard rumors
of things coming up and it's hard because, you know, I think we need to read
everything we've talked about.
It's just the aftermath.
And here's what bugs me.
Here's what bugs me.
I didn't look this up ahead of time, but there is data and articles
I've seen that show that layoffs make a very
they should ask chat GPT about this, but they make a very minimal to zero impact
on revenue and and margin, meaning
the effect of come on with the productivity hit
and everything else involved.
You don't really save the company save much less money than they think they do.
VLF. Yeah, I would.
I would want to see that.
I saw one article.
I only glanced at it.
But so anyway, maybe that's not true.
I don't know.
I mean, one of our readers will dig that up.
So we talked a lot about layoffs.
Yep. We talked a little bit about like the aftermath of I worry with myself
and especially reflecting on our conversation with Dagna again on burnout.
It's like I am like myself.
I am angry more often.
I have less tolerance for
less tolerance in general.
I I have a good guess for the missing the fill in the blank word,
but I won't share it.
Yeah, I want it to be great to have if Jim, if you're listening,
you want to be on the podcast sometime, just get on here.
We'll get you get you to tell them stories.
But I'm going to tell a story about Jim,
because it goes back to once in a while in this podcast,
I talked to one of my employees this week,
one of my original employees at Unity, and we talk all the time and and a
rasmus and he was talking about the fact that we never talk about testing
on this podcast anymore. So that's all right.
We were talking about the right stuff.
Talk about what's relevant.
If there are things you want us to talk about,
what you do is you join our Slack group and you can get there by going to
modern testing dot org, clicking on the link,
and then you can join it and go to the mailbag channel and tell us what to
talk about or general or anywhere.
It just it's a hodgepodge.
We do take a lot of input from that community and we'll talk about things.
We'll talk about them.
Otherwise, we're going to talk about whatever we want.
I don't know what Brent is showing me, but it is showing me a picture that he drew.
I don't know what's going on.
This is so weird.
My number one memory of Jimbo.
Jim, yeah, we had these cameras, two Jim stories.
We had these really kind of interesting roundtable cameras.
What did we use them with?
I guess we must have used Link or Office Communicator.
And what it was was this camera that sat in the middle of the table
with this little circle on top, and it would detect who was talking
and change the camera to point you at who was talking.
And Jim didn't like that.
So we hung a little sticky face, a little sticky note in front of it
with a drawing of a face.
So every time he talked, it showed this little sticky note.
That's what Brent showing to the camera right now.
But that was the story I was going to tell.
Microsoft, they may still have this, but it's all self-serve
creating a new distribution list, a new group equivalent of a Google group.
You go to this tool that looks like it was written in 1989.
Is it still the same tool, Brent?
What tool?
The tool to create a new, I forget what it's called.
The tool to create an auto group, the tool to create a new mailing list.
Oh, no, that's that's probably changed like four times.
Oh, OK. But really early on,
Jim created because anyone could create a group.
I've created thousands of Microsoft, probably.
I'm sorry for my email sins of the past.
But Jim created a group called Null.
It was just him and a couple of people at least used it to,
you know, kind of a joke, Dev Null.
And just it was just a group called Null Forever until it wasn't.
One day when Jim was working on Xbox, he's it came.
He was looking a little white.
He came out and told us that all of a sudden he was getting random emails
not addressed to him all over the from all over the company
with some of them, some private and sensitive information.
Oh, geez.
What what bug did he take advantage?
No, let me out.
Was it called null or was it called the null string?
No, it was called null and you L.L. the string.
OK, so Jim is so ethically responsible.
He blows me away.
He immediately created a folder for all these things to go to contacted
exchange like a VP in exchange is on the phone with him in like five minutes
going, what what is going on?
And they changed something.
It started sending a bunch of random mails.
I don't know. I don't know what the bug was, but it was hilarious.
So the reason I thought of it recently was Jim.
The reason I found out Jim was laid off is he you know, LinkedIn
is an awkward place to go now because 80 percent of the posts
are people saying I was laid off for my job looking for work.
Yeah, Jim went to post.
He posted. It's really funny.
He went to fill out like I don't know,
he showed a little picture of the form and where you put your company name.
They put like ex like, for example, ex Microsoft.
I thought it's funny because it's like ex Microsoft.
I replied to him.
I said, Jim, knowing you, you have to make your company name null
and see what happens.
Yeah, it's a bummer.
So I I also feel bad because I screwed up Jim's life.
I I made Jim come to work on my team.
Jim worked on teams for a while.
Yeah, I made him come work for me on teams because I wanted to do
because Jim does awesome work and I wanted to bring his energy there.
And he didn't want to come to downtown Bellevue, but I convinced him to do it.
And then he came and then I and then I quit.
But he went back to Internet Explorer after that, where he where he worked
for a long time.
I hope Jim's doing well, but I love that null story.
It took this is great.
This is like as a tester, you may go, I'm going to try null as a group name.
OK, nothing weird happens.
It's fine. It's it's the long, slow hunch.
It took like six, seven, 10 years for that null distribution list
to become a bug.
There are similar things.
So there was this old tool that I built to back back.
This was back in the raid days.
Do you remember raid?
Raid kills bugs dead. Yeah. Yeah.
So raid was one of the raid stories to raid was one of the first
bug database management systems Microsoft had. Right.
And it was a piece of crap, but it worked.
It was better than whatever was before.
I don't know that I don't know that product studio ended up being better than.
Right. But no, but I finish your story.
I'll tell a raid story. OK.
So I had an auto mailer.
This is back in the early days of the exchange, which much like every
early product team, the stupid vanity metrics was the only thing that mattered.
Right. And we are trying to ship and we had too many
resolved bugs that weren't closed.
Right. So my boss asked me to create a an auto nagger.
I would have just closed all the bugs, but whatever.
That's what I would do today.
And I've had conversations.
I literally have had conversations with my senior executive.
I'm like, look, I will look you straight in the eye and just tell you straight up.
I think this is the most efficient thing to handle it right now.
If it hasn't been touched in two years, just close them all
because if it's important and still relevant, it will come back.
Yes. Oh, my God.
What this thing did.
So if you remember, if it wasn't assigned to anybody,
you would assign it to active.
Yes, I remember this now. Remember that?
OK. My thing would look OK.
Let's take out everything that's not assigned to active.
And I will I will send it to whoever.
No problem. Well, then I discovered
that with an exchange, it was very common to assign it to DCR.
Well, I remember DCR design change review or something.
Design change request. OK. Right.
This is how they they hacked that.
It's not a bug. It's actually somebody filing a future work item.
And I didn't change my code because it turned out all those mails bounced.
Therefore, it's no big deal.
And tell some poor dude joined Microsoft
who got the email address DCR.
And you and you completely filled his inbox.
I'm freaking day one.
I hammered the crap out of the guy.
He's like, why, why, why are you doing this to me?
And I'm like, oh, crap.
Yeah, you may want to talk for multiple other reasons.
You may want to talk to I.T.
about changing your email before you get too used to it,
because you're going to get every bad, badly designed
auto nagger sending crap to you.
So, by the way, sometimes you should look and see if Microsoft
has given Alan P.A. to anybody else yet.
My raid story is when I first started.
Let's go look right now.
I can't remember the version numbers and I wanted to find like a
I wanted to find the app for a screenshot for how we test off Microsoft.
Even then, it was too old.
But whatever the version, this is just classic hacking.
Whatever version of raid it was when I joined Microsoft,
it had a database limit of around 30,000.
It would just stop working once you got like 31,000 bugs in it,
which sounds like a lot, but Windows 95 was a shit show
and with a bunch of customer reported bugs in there, too,
that end up being like grouped into one bug.
So there was a lot of a lot of stuff in there.
I think two or three times during the Windows 95 cycle,
we had to do this migration where you take
all of the resolved and only resolved and active bugs
and at the lock raid, all is resolved and active
and move into the new database.
And then you start from there.
So you start with, you know, 5000 and build up again.
Yeah, I've just hilarious.
I executed multiple DB migrations.
I'm extremely grateful that every single time
it went off smoothly without error at all.
I actually wrote a bug tracking tool at Mittysoft.
So I was there before Microsoft.
I didn't know what I was doing about once.
I mean, I really nothing.
I knew nothing about what I was doing.
It worked until it didn't.
So at least once a day, I had to had to run an auto
repair on the database and restart.
And it's just I was bad.
I like it was it was horrible.
I could do much better today.
I think I wrote it.
I think I wrote it in Visual Basic.
Right. But with some access database,
we've talked about this before.
Well, perhaps we have the bug database today
is for me is very simple.
It's my count.
It's by Kanban board and the number of bugs on
listed on the board is no more than 10.
And they're all gone in 48 hours.
And maybe real quickly, it's worth mentioning is
the last thing on LinkedIn there with someone posted around
having a zero bug backlog.
And what was interesting is there a bunch of comments
from the traditional testers, I'll call them like, well,
let's talk about what bugs are and maybe it's OK.
It's like you guys don't get it.
What it means is deal with it or deal with it now or close it.
No, that's it's deal with it now.
Yeah, right. Either way. Right.
And they miss the point on it, but I just thought it was interesting.
Like they zero having zero bugs is a good thing.
And the thing I pointed out that kind of quieted people
or they just ignored me because they get mad at me
because I have weird ideas like not having testers on on development teams.
And I just pointed out that how much time do teams waste
re-reviewing resolved bugs or re-reviewing bugs
and deciding not to do anything with them?
Just close them. Either just deal with them.
Deal with them. Do something with them.
Don't let them sit around.
So anyway, we got there from there, from there, which was fun.
We should probably close for today.
We got things to do. Get back on track.
Brent is eating during the last 10 minutes of the podcast here.
So I will try and edit out the lip smacking.
And and you cannot imagine the pain it is to be the A in A.B. testing.
Anything to say for yourself, Brent?
I can imagine the pain.
And now. Oh, wait, wait.
Now he's talking into his hand.
I'm looking at the agenda.
You had a question about analytics.
Now, Brent, I don't have time to talk about analytics.
We'll talk about analytics next.
Well, then do the question as a cliffhanger.
I don't know what the question is. I've forgotten.
Oh, all right.
Okay, then.
The cliffhanger is this, this.
I have never been a fan of movies or TV series based on video game
because they always screw them up.
I have changed my mind.
Go watch The Last of Us on HBO.
New series on new shows on Sundays.
It is amazing.
What is that based off of?
The Last of Us.
I have not played or seen post apocalyptic zombies.
Oh, I did the what was the infected by infected by mushrooms.
Yeah, I don't know how this is going to make you feel,
but I hear rumors of a studio making a feature film based off of Fallout.
Don't like it. It's going to suck.
But then that said, Starfield coming someday soon.
I know I'm watching for Starfield.
It's from the makers of my two favorite games ever.
Fallout and Skyrim.
I can't wait.
And and I'll close on one Fallout update last.
Sometime ago, I think I I don't know if I spent a little podcast or told you,
but I've gotten back into Fallout 76.
I had I had a lot.
I just basically wiped my old character and start again back at level one.
I am now back to the same level I was previously.
And I will say I am enjoying the game.
It's nowhere as near as good as four or five, but I am joining the game
way better than I should go play it again.
I've played a little bit.
I've been so much for ending on time.
I bought a switch and I've been playing Mario Odyssey all the time.
Oh, I heard about that.
I haven't played it yet.
It's we have two switches.
All right. This is a good place to.
All right, everybody.
Thank you for hanging out with us on the E.B.
testing podcast.
I'm a I'm not.