to have the same mindset that you need to be a tester because a software engineer
has to have that same what could go wrong. I've carried a pager for 20 years. I guarantee you,
I can think like a tester. There's nothing that gives you a quality mindset like not having to
wake up at three o'clock in the morning. Welcome to AVE Testing Podcast, your modern testing
podcast. Your hosts, Alan and Brent, will be here to guide you through topics on testing,
leadership, agile, and anything else that comes to mind. Now, on with the show. Hey everybody,
welcome back to the AVE Testing Podcast. Happy new year. I am here. I'm Alan. We have Brent.
Hello.
This is I.
We also have Brian Finster. Brian, say hi.
Hi, I'm Brian.
I am excited to have you here for a bunch of reasons that will emerge. What I want to do
first is give a little context on why Brian's here. This is both for our listeners who may not
have seen. We talk about you on our Slack. If you want to go to join our Slack group,
you can go to moderntesting.org, click on the link, join right away. We've talked a little
bit about some of your LinkedIn posts. Good stuff. We're not talking dirty behind your back or
anything. But I imagine Brian being much more of an internet celebrity than Brent and our three
listeners. There's people coming to listen to our podcast going, why is Brian hanging out with these
two half-baked people trying to make a podcast for eight years?
Dude, I'm seriously half-baked. I don't understand.
Yeah, okay. Between all of us, we are one and a half-baked.
And this is also a context for you, Brian, to know why did these guys invite me here?
So once upon a time, about eight years ago, Brent and I were both in testing roles at Microsoft.
I led a few cross-company test-related groups, and Brent and I had such a good rapport in there.
And we've been giving each other crap like this now going on 10 years that someone,
I think it was Michael Hunter said, you can start a podcast. What was that, Brent?
It's been longer than 10 years. I met you when I joined the TLT, right? So it's been longer than
that. That was the test leadership team at Microsoft. And I'm going to assume it's the
same for all of you. I have now lost my ability to track how many years have gone by.
There was a blurry few years in there that are still blurry. But anyway, we started a podcast.
And we're going to figure this out as we go. And we talked about doing a podcast. But
one thing happened very early on as we very early on, the conversation shifted to something
prominent. And it was that Brent and I were both seeing that software delivery was changing.
It was changing definitely before then, but Microsoft is usually the last to know about
changes and how software is made. Dude, I came from Walmart, so.
There is the clip that goes on the beginning. Dude, I came from Walmart.
So we saw this world where fast feedback loops wouldn't need armies of testers because they would
get in the way. And we could reach higher quality by focusing on feedback loops, data,
and adaptability. So we talked about that because we were seeing it. We weren't trying to invent
anything. We were talking about what we were seeing. So we talked about that on the podcast
with the goal of helping testers navigate these changes that were going on because things are
changing. Things are still changing in some ways. Things are still the same. They're a
little bit different. Fast forward a bit. We came up with these modern testing principles,
which were the idea was to try and like, what are the principles behind what we've been
talking about for a few years now? And they're not modern and they're not about testing,
but we wrote them as sort of the, not the antidote, but the growth, like the traditional
test as a gatekeeper type of testing to modern testing where things are different.
They're really modern delivery, but we're keeping them. We still call them the modern testing
principles. We, if I may interject, we call them that mostly because to resonate with the audience,
we were trying to target. We saw two movements. It's super important. I mean, you have to do that.
In Alan's story, all of that is true. One of the things though,
that at least I experienced. So I spent a good amount of my career in middle management in QA.
And Alan very similarly, while he was at Microsoft, he avoided management, but
he still had very high scoped roles with large reach, large impact. And so when we both started
talking while he was still at Microsoft, and this was before Microsoft did his big switch,
when to sort of dramatically reduce the number of testers, we both had at that point in time
experienced around, Oh, this is what happens. This is why this works. Because back then Agile was,
was like crazy sauce, right? They're like, what do things without a hundred page document?
That's crazy. Alan and I were not only, not only did we see that it was coming,
but at that point in time, we were one of the few that wholeheartedly defended that that is the way
we should be going. Which I don't know about Alan, he's far more charismatic than I am, but it
did cause some sacrifice to some friendships on that front. What? You're deserting. How can you?
The creator. Exactly. And based on, based on LinkedIn comments, I'm guessing Brian, that that is a
phenomenon you're familiar with. I did give Brent some pre reading to kind of get familiar with it.
So this is interesting because I really want to talk to about the history about how I came
came to this. Yeah. Because I've been a software developer doing product development since 1996.
I've been doing it for awhile. Honestly, did it the way that I know a lot of people still do it,
which is I code something and then I go and manually test it and I go deploy it and hope
it doesn't blow up for years and years and years. You know, if you, and this before I,
before I worked at Walmart, but you know, Walmart, we went through a whole bunch of Agile
transformations as one does, which right after they sent us to PMI training, by the way,
which was really interesting. You know, I, I was one test away from being a project manager,
like fully certified by PMI. But we got to the point where we'd stabilized. I worked in
logistics at the time and I was working in warehouse management systems. And, you know,
the primary system I worked on was, I mean, oh my God, it made windows look small. I'm pretty sure.
I mean, it's, it's just a nightmare of old, it was like four different warehouse management
systems all banged together with a common database that we'd applied after this modernization effort.
But we were delivering that thing almost four times a year. Now this is also a period of time
when Walmart was going through a lot of acquisitions. So we're getting a lot of other markets,
you know, South Africa and Central America and all these, all these different markets.
And, you know, we need them to be on a common logistics system. We don't want to be integrating
all their legacy logistics systems. And, you know, we're delivering change every
three to four times a year. We did a value stream map one time and it was,
took us 12 months from a business request to deliver it to production. Right. I mean,
it was a nightmare. And every single time we did a deploy, so at the time, so I'm talking
about when we're just at the cusp of doing things correctly, they put me in charge of the team
responsible for integrating all of the feature branches every quarter for the quarterly release.
Right. I talked to, it sounds like a fun job. It was a fun job. Now they, it was very entertaining.
They, they gave me this job because I've been really looking into how other organizations
were doing source management. And I thought we could do it better. And they gave me the
mandate of making the team obsolete, making the team go away. Right. So it was an improvement
effort. And I was like, I'm all over that. I don't want to sit here. Let's make things better.
And I talked to Gene Kim about this after when he, he said we had drafted unicorn project and
he was talking about merge day for the Phoenix project. It was like 350 branches. I was like,
that's nothing. Hold my beer. Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait,
Brian, are you the real Brent? No, no, I'm not. But I am the sad that had to integrate 400 branches
every quarter, you know? And so you integrate 400 plus branches every quarter. And, you know,
then you deal with the merge conflicts and then you're six weeks late and then you go and deploy
and you've got scheduled war rooms for like scheduled here's the schedule for the next
week. Who's going to be working which part of the 24 hours seven day a week shift to support and
stabilize the system after this delivery for just the initial part of the stabilization. Okay.
So I mean, I did it's just a nightmare. And it was just normal, right? I mean,
it's not a nightmare because that's just how you work. And then SVP said, Hey, look,
we need to do this every two weeks because we can't meet our business goals by delivering
this slowly. And so what do they do? Of course, what they did was they hired McKinsey and Bain
and brought in no, no, no, no, no, actually, Randy, Randy, the SVP at the time, Randy Salley,
love that guy still have beer with him. Randy presented this as an engineering problem to us
senior engineers in logistics and said, Hey, I need you to fix this. Right? So one of my
teammates got a copy of continuous delivery. We read it. We knew about Conway's law.
We I read like the domain driven design for dummies. And we put together a plan for leadership
about how we can go to more frequent delivery. And in fact, when Patrick and I were working through
this, we had a, there was project manager assigned to this project. And Patrick and I said, okay,
look, we think there were two weeks isn't aggressive enough. We need to go for daily.
If we go for daily, we might go for weekly. If we go for over two weeks, we might be hit every month.
So let's go for daily. And the project manager said, well, they asked for over two weeks. We
don't care. We're going for daily. So will I quit? If you guys are going to do that,
like we don't need you because we're doing this for two decades. We're fine on our own things.
And we drove for daily, but just so, but imagine the situation we're in. We are a bunch
of developers who we have a QA area. Who's been doing all the testing for us, mostly manual.
None of the developers in the area actually know how to test at all. Okay. We're not going to go
for daily production delivery. So today's code goes to production today. That was our goal.
Now we had an ops area too, because they'd gone through the whole matrix organization fat and
split off support from product from development where we used to run what we brung. They pulled
that away for developer productivity, which just destroyed quality even further. But they, the ops
SLA was that you had to be stable for 90 days before they'd take it over, but we're delivering
every single day. So we'll never get it to them. So that means we're going to get ops back,
which made me incredibly happy. Honestly, I wanted ops back, but that also means we're going to be
delivering untested code every single day to production. None of the work. So we have to
dig into testing. And so I started taking testing very, very seriously. And I started working
through this problem, just going backwards from I need to deploy every single day.
It has to be validated that it's ready for production every single day. The way all this
testing is being done right now will not work. So we have to reinvent all of testing.
I had to get the QA lead that was assigned to us on board. We had to, as the pilot teams,
learn how to test from scratch. I've got a copy of XUnit test patterns. It was like 900 pages
long. I was pouring through that. I was pouring through everything I can find. I was interviewing
developers about why they were struggling with testing. It was like, Oh, well, because the
requirements are crap. So I discovered, I found the behavior driven development. We learned to do
that. So we could get clean requirements so that we would know what to test. And we were doing
all this upfront work so that we can write testing code, do real continuous integration,
and push testing code to production. And so what my takeaway from this journey was the continuous
delivery is a quality initiative that it stress-tested your quality process and that you must
focus on quality if you're going to be good at this. Later on, I went to the lady who used to be
my senior director. She moved to be the senior director of QE because I rebranded QA to QE and
told her she needed to hire me to drive CD across the organization because CD was a quality
initiative, not a development initiative. And every since then, test architecture,
how do I get from idea to production with fewer handoffs, fewer, less reworked,
faster feedback at every single step. There was a, early on in this process, QA put on this
whole quality conference. And I was one of the keynote speakers, not in QA, talking about how
testing, you test everything. You test meetings. You don't go to a meeting list. You have an agenda
that you can assert against. That's an interesting angle.
It's like if you don't have an agenda for a meeting, don't show up because you have nothing
to assert against to find out if you got value from the meeting. I said we're testing for value,
not for adherence to spec. Yes. So much yes.
And people say, well, how do you test the test? You ship it. The test is just prod.
You don't. That's how you test the test. You don't. I love that phrase. I'm writing it down.
You test for value. I wrote a blog post recently called the three wrongs. And this is something
I, you know, just like an epiphany I had several years ago that the whole, the reason for all this
agile nonsense is everything is wrong all the time. The problem with classic testing process where you
have product owner or BA or somebody creating requirements, handing them to the development
team and then handing them to a testing team to automate the tests or do manual testing
is that it's missing the foundational principle that the requirements probably wrong in the
first place. And on top of that, we're going to misunderstand them because of the handoff.
And then when you hand them to a development team and a testing team, you double the chance
misunderstanding. And I've measured this in real life on development teams with value stream maps
and interviews when we were, when I was running the dojo. I've seen this in reality where the
testing team misunderstood the requirements differently from the product team. And they
both misunderstood the requirements for what the product owner meant. And the product owner
actually misunderstood the need. And I have documented that in value stream maps.
I think it's Crosby. I think it's Crosby. Now I'm taking this myself who said,
quality is conformance to requirements. And I've modified that before you cringe and go,
I believe it. It's true. Quality is conformance to requirements, but only the customer can define
requirements. I gave it there was a talk. Oh, even further, the customers, customer themselves
may not actually know the requirements. No, they don't until they see it and then they can edit it.
Yeah. Right. Right. But the, there's a talk I used to give. So the last role I held at Walmart
was I led the DevOps Studio at Walmart. And our job was to, we were using continuous delivery
as a forcing function or to improve engineering excellence and business delivery across the
organization. We were building a platform that was optimized for that. If you weren't using a CD
workflow, the platform was hard. It fought you on purpose. Like we need Gitflow. Yeah. No,
we're Gitflows on our roadmap. And I was asked to create a dojo where you use immersive learning
to help teams learn continuous delivery. We're like hands on, we join your team as engineers,
not freaking agile coaches, and pair with you while you learn CD in your context with your work.
And I used to give these talks about testing and one of the talks I gave about testing,
I always started off with this definition of quality. And I had an image of the 2017 MacBook
Pro. Now do you guys remember the 2017 MacBook Pro? Oh, that's the one with the touch bar. They
added the touch bar. They removed the escape key. They removed MagSafe charging. They removed all
the ports and just use USB C. It was the highest quality piece of crap you could buy. And I had
a picture of this and I was talking about how I'm a photographer. They took away my SD card
reader. So now I have to go down over SD card reader. I have dogs, large dogs. So they run past
the coffee table, trip on the cord, right? When they ripped the computer off the coffee table
instead of just some MagSafe cable detaching. I'm a software developer who focuses on Unix.
I need my escape key. How am I going to get out of VI? And I'm like, when that computer came out,
I bought a refurbished of my personal machine. I needed a new one. I bought a refurbished 2016
instead of a new 2017 because it was garbage. And then I was starting to say, this is what
quality means. Quality means it meets the user's need. Not that it meets the spec.
I have a whole other thing about why I don't do that. But this is the core fundamental thing
is that everything we do is wrong until we can get it to the front of the end user
and find out what's wrong so that we can adjust. And that the reason I focus so hard on continuous
delivery is because of the joy that we felt when we were able to deliver multiple times a day
to the end user, get feedback directly from that end user, adjust, give them feedback the next day,
they were happy. We were happy. Morale was high. Quality was high. Everybody should work that way,
but it requires rethinking all the things that you think you know are true.
Yeah. A million percent. Yes. Every once in a while I joined a new team and somebody doesn't
get it. And I remember at my last company, I joined the new team or talking about delivery.
I said I would rather ship 10 times a day than once a week. And the SVP just, I don't get why
you would say that. It's fine. It's fine. We're not going to go into it. But I convinced him.
It took me a few years, but he was on board. It's just a different way of thinking.
Well, you get terrified of size, right? Once you do it, you get terrified. It's like,
what do you mean 500 lines of code? Are you kidding me?
No. Well, so part of it is like in the transformation. And I think you're right.
Right. In my own journey on shifting to agile, like for me,
I've told this multiple times on the podcast, but I'll do it. I'll do the short version for Brian.
Everyone else can press the skip 30 seconds.
I went to Scrum. We executed it poorly. A two week Scrum ended up taking three months for us to
unscrew up. And then we shifted to a Kanban model where basically a small little thing ships
independently. And in order to execute that, you had to make certain changes. You had to make smaller
changes. You had to cover the entire test suite, as you called out just a second ago.
But where the magic went in is one day, one of my people submitted something and everything was on
the floor. Now that sounds like a bad story. However, because it was just one change that went
in that put everything on the floor, it took seconds for us to back it out, took seconds for
us to repair it. The guy knew instantly what he did wrong and get it out. I had to multiple times
go forward and try to do the same conversations you did. And that Alan just talked about
convincing others to take the risk on my team, we're going to execute this way. And to your
point, this is the point I resonate with. When they think, oh, we're going to ship once a week,
they have the size in their head. And then when we say we're going to do it 10 times a day,
they don't automatically shift that size in their head. How are you going to do that 10 times a day?
Well, it's actually we're not we're shifting to small batch.
Yeah, it takes a lot of practice. And I've been having the last couple of days, I've been having
some really intense discussions with people who are trying to redefine continuous integration,
so they can feel better about not doing it. And but here's the thing, okay, is that that
driving down that batch size is not the goal, it's the forcing function to the goal.
Yes. Okay. And I'll give you another example that you reminded me of is that of something saving
our ass, because we took CD seriously. Okay, I had the when we've been going on for a while,
and one of the other teams have been focusing on working this way. And I had a direct dependency on
them. They were the they were my downstream service that I needed a lot of information from.
I worked very closely with the tech lead. We were doing contract driven development.
Anytime we needed a contract, anytime we needed to change between the two of us,
we were coordinating through our contracts, we can deploy independently, because that was the
other thing we put rules in place when we started this, every team delivers in any sequence,
asynchronously from anybody else, which meant we had to focus on really good API management.
Well, there was a test that we had to run, where we would, and this is logistics, we get a
purchase order come in, it would process through their system. And then we would do something
to validate that we were actually could receive freight, and create inventory. And that was the
test took four hours to run that test. I can't do CD that way. And so it's Walmart. We didn't
have a lot of external information, all works very inwardly facing, we independently invented
virtual services. We submitted a pull request to my colleague's team, to give them a contract mock
of their API. And then created a process where we would send a test, a test header.
And they would get they would serve the mock instead of actually hitting their actual
logic. And so now this integration test between the two teams went from four hours to microseconds.
So the way but but Brian, you're testing the mock. Yep. We also get contract tests to test the mock
against the actual response so that we can validate the mock. Anytime you're doing a contract test.
So when you're doing integration tests with mocks, you also have to have a contract test to validate
the mock. Sure. Right. So we did both. Okay. But the result of that, though, is that they
made it when we were going live in the distribution center, and they had us in a distribution center
with really terrible network latency and all sorts of other problems. Because of course they did.
We're we're going live. And we're making changes rapidly as because there's always the things that
you didn't know about until you actually try to use the system for real. They broke their contract.
And we discovered it instantly when we ran our test the next time before anything deployed.
And before anything could have broken anything in production. Because they're just just that broke
the test immediately. Right. But the only reason that that test existed that way is because you
can't do CD with the way we were doing integration testing before. Right. Right. It's the driving
down to focusing on speed of feedback. Driving down that batch size forces you to solve these problems.
And it makes you safer. It removes drama. It makes the work suck less.
You know, this is something that I've started to do with my junior. So years ago,
I shifted away from QA, went to dev. And now, and then little after that, I became a data scientist.
And now I actually run a sort of a dev team that's producing data science driven services.
One of the things that that energizes your ICs is closing the loop between the customer value
proposition and their actual work. Oh, dude, dude. So I gave a talk with my teammate in
2017 at DevOps Enterprise Summit. Because I'd gone to the conference the first time in 2015.
And I saw all these executives talking about all these things we're doing and how it impacts the
enterprise. Like bullshit. How's an enterprise? We need to tell everybody how it impacts the teams.
And we had a slide that talked about how it made us love developing it.
We were beating animated heart on the slide. And it just made us love development again because of
that. Because we got to see our work being used instantly. We got feedback. I talked to somebody
at the conference that year who was a platform developer for Exxon. And he said, it seems like
all the best developers get a platform because it can be closer to the customer. And I just moved
to Walmart platform and the people I worked with, I was like, oh yeah, I agree.
That makes sense. People are motivated by progress.
And Dan, you've gotten there. But one thing, if I can, I'm going to change just,
not even a change of gear, a little bit of a veer here. Your journey on discovering testing,
I think is pretty unique. But maybe not. I don't know. I see the pockets, everything we're talking
about, things we're seeing happen all over the place. But there's still a lot of people
doing the old way. When I spent a chunk of my career teaching developers how to test and having
very good luck with it and realizing that developers actually could be very good testers.
And I tried to accelerate that via, sometimes on one project, I did a lot of it just by doing a
whole lot of code reviews. And what I found is, one, developers can be very good testers.
And two, not surprisingly, when developers knew testing was part of what they were delivering,
they began to design better code in the first place because they started to think about testability
as they were creating the code. And they go, well, I'm going to test this. They would think
ahead. You discovered a lot of devs without, may not think of that contract testing solution.
Well, that's amazing how they didn't know this exists. So there's a curiosity. I'm curious,
one question is, how did you discover some of the nuance? And then the other end of that,
I know you've written on LinkedIn a little bit about this before. I want to talk about it a
little bit. But there's this whole developers can't test thing, which we know is bullshit.
And I'm just curious on why you think people think that as well. So first question,
how did you get so good at testing without a great coach like me? And two,
Brent, I'm muting himself just to laugh. And then two, what do you think it'll take to get
more people to figure out that devs can actually do really good testing?
So, you know, I found mentors. Liz Keo has no idea who I am. Okay, I have talked to her on
Twitter occasionally. If I ever meet her, she gets so much beer or whiskey or whatever her favorite
drink is, because she was my behavior driven development mentor. I consumed everything that
she had to say about that. I went out and found people. I'm spanking on the name, the guy who
wrote cucumber and cheese. I was finding these resources out there. I found the Xunip
webpage and I was pulling from that. It was my job to discover how we can do this. And then
to spread that knowledge, because we had to solve the problem of continuous delivery. Patrick,
my colleague, he was working on the automation. I was working on how to use the automation.
And so that was, I had to, it was my eval. And then also binding other people,
if you don't know how to test, we can't do CD. I needed everybody to do CD. Even before we,
this is why, even before we started using continuous delivery as an enterprise
improvement strategy, I knew that if we didn't spread the disease of continuous delivery to
other areas, it would be easy to kill. All we'd do is take one leadership change at a low level,
CD's dead, and we'd go back to the old terrible way of delivering the software. I didn't want that.
And so I was going out to the end. So if you understand at the time, I didn't talk to people.
I was, I'm an introvert, but I was an actively not talking to people introvert.
But I needed this to happen for my quality of life. Right. And so I was going out to other teams
and explaining to what we're doing in behavior driven development. It's the, I was giving
presentations about it. Just, Hey, you want to have a, what's your team to have a presentation
with BDD. I was finding other people who were coming in from other organizations and who had
a test collaborating with them. Hey, let's, how do we do this better? Later on, when I moved to
platform, we hired Villa Sverigraven in the platform, uh, as the he's, he was working at QA
at Netflix. And I said, village, you're not my testing mentor and bounced ideas hard and
passed off of him and challenged. You know, I was like, I have this idea and he'd come up and I was
like, that doesn't feel right to me. And I didn't just accept what Villa said, even though
it was my mentor, I would challenge him because it just didn't seem to align with continuous
delivery. And so it was steel on steel, trying to get better at this stuff. It all came down to how
do I deliver workable software every single day? Right. It's just, how do I solve this problem?
So there's a characteristic here that I've been going to sound briefly. Like I'm blowing
smoke up your ass, but as a manager, there's a correlation. You don't have someone study.
I'm, I'm, I'm, uh, well, let me just finish my thought because I think there's a correlation.
There's a curiosity and drive in you. Like you had, you could have gone to your manager and said,
we need to hire testers. We'll, we'll just make them move faster or whatever. Or you could have
said there are many ways you could have given up and gone a different path, but you didn't. And
that curiosity to go discover, I think it's any knowledge work, being curious and wanting to learn
more and continually trying to discover what you don't know and what you don't know, you don't know
is absolutely a key to success. So there's a story in there as well.
Full disclosure. When we were making the shift, we also changed tech stacks and the new tech stack.
I was not good at, and I was, uh, you know, it's very difficult to be a senior engineer
where the thing that this tech stack, your senior at no longer exists in your area.
You need to become an expert at something quick.
So I became an expert at how do we deliver better while I'm learning the new tech stack.
Way back when Brent and I were both in test and he was, I think,
I think we were still doing like kind of old school tile testing, but not the gatekeeper.
Brent came up with this mission. Like, you know, testing's role is to accelerate the
achievement of shippable quality. And there's something there too. Like you,
you wanted stuff to go faster for good reasons. And then, I don't know, I think there's,
I like the story there.
Yeah. I mean, and going back to some of the core motivations I have, I've always,
I've not been a developer who's number one software, something hobby.
Okay. I code because I need a tool. I have other hobbies, photographer, motorcycles,
I build models. I don't solve, I don't code for a hobby. I could solve business problems.
I care about the business problem. I push back really hard on developers who say our
job is algorithms and data structures. Our job is to be business experts solving business problems
with code. It's fascinating.
Modern testing principle number one, our priority is improving the business.
Yes. And everything, you know, I talked to people, how do you get people to buy into continuous
delivery? I don't. I get them to buy into how do we deliver better business value at lower
cost with less variability and less, you know, drama, right? You know, it's...
But Brian, I am a database expert and I don't care about all of that. I want to add the next
feature to my database.
Okay. Well, go work for a database company.
That is...
But, you know, and then that's a valuable attitude to have. But, you know, going back to your
question about why people think developers can't test. Well, it's because they can't,
right? It's not because that... Well, it's not because they can't, it's because they have no
idea how, because you... What's the main entry point for software development?
It's a computer science degree. We don't need freaking computer scientists.
We need software engineers and that's completely different thing. And so people go to
university, they get a CS degree, they might be taught the basics of how to structure code.
You know, they come into the workforce mostly illiterate and then we have to train them. And
if they wind up in the wrong organization, they won't get taught how to test. And then
they'll think that's just the right way to do it. And those organizations will have testing teams
and the testing teams will say, well, developers can't test. That's my job. Only I have the
mindset to think about what could go wrong. Right? It's like, apparently software is the
only discipline where only somebody other than the engineer of doing the work of designing the
thing can think about, you know, only somebody else can think about what can go wrong.
I mean, that's why we have QA teams looking at bridges to decide how that can go wrong
while you have bridge engineers, you know, civil engineers only doing happy paths, right?
But they're not taught how to test. And, you know, you'll see me on LinkedIn having
these heated discussions with people who I'm looking at a point, they're looking at
a developer, so I had to test only I have the skills, I need to be the one testing
and explaining to developers what they're doing wrong. And it has to be an adversarial
relationship because that's how quality is done. And I'm looking at going, I'm a value stream
architect. You are a constraint in the value stream. That constraint is driving it backsize.
The larger batch we deliver, the more wrong we are because the idea is fundamentally flawed in
the first place. That can't work. You need to teach the developers how to test and you need
to work on giving them better tools to get that done with. You need to don't grant, right? You
cannot be the person doing. If you're an expert, I value you for sharing your expertise and elevating
others. If you try to implement your expertise, I hate your guts because you're harming my quality
of life. We are on record. Absolutely in agreement. We view like, Alan, what is what's a synonym for
specialists on this podcast? Bottleneck. Yeah, you're gumming up the works. You are blocking
the business from achieving its value. Absolutely. In the dojo, the process we went through in the
dojo, like I said, it was immersive learning. And we would go and work with the team for six weeks.
It was not unusual for many of the teams to have either an external QA team testing their code
independently or to have test automators on the team whose job was to write end-to-end tests.
By the way, god damn it, BDD does not mean using cucumber to write end-to-end tests after the
coding is done. Okay, Jesus Christ. BDD, TDD does not mean anything tests after coding is done.
But what we would do is we go into the team. And so we have to change the entire way this team
works to go from the way they're working to continuous delivery. And we also could not have
those testers doing what they were doing. People always thought that I hated test that I hate
testers. I mean, I get accused of this all the time. I elevate testers when we did this.
We go into the team and say, look, what you're doing right now, not only is it constrained,
but it's a waste of your talent. And whether they had the skill or not, we always granted
the skill because we knew that if we challenged them that they would elevate or sort themselves
out. Okay. You're the quality expert on the team. The team doesn't have the muscle built.
You need to help them build the muscle. You need to be the coach for this
and stop doing what you're doing now. Stop testing, start being a quality engineer,
help these guys learn how to test better. Talk about test design, share your knowledge,
share the mindset, share how to think evil, evil ways. And we had so many
ex-test automators who were just massive fans of the dojo because we made their lives better
because we gave them more important jobs. Oh, when I mentioned when I first went to dev,
one of the things that Microsoft famously did is actually collapsed the test team.
And every new dev team was part dev part test. Okay. What I actually found was those old test
automators. It was a lot easier for them to start writing code, which felt like a reward to them,
but they still kept, they out delivered all of the old school dev experts.
I'm not surprised. We used to tell the, what we would tell this test automator is just like,
hey, and if you get bored, pick up a feature because that'll also give you a deeper insight
into the challenges that developers are having with testing. You know, pick up a feature.
Now, and so this is, this is the big problem though, what we have in the industry and why,
you know, one of the, they've, they've hardly released modern software engineering a few years ago.
And he sent me a pre-release of that book and I started reading it and I was like, oh my God,
that's this, this is the book because it explains to you what you're doing wrong as a
software developer. It challenge you to be a software engineer, to take the job seriously,
to apply engineering principles, to, to have the same mindset that you need to be a tester because
a software engineer has to have that same, what could go wrong? You know, I've carried a pager
for 20 years. I guarantee you, I can think like a tester. There's nothing that gives you a quality
mindset, like not having to wake up at three o'clock in the morning.
And well, once you realize it's in your control.
But, but here, this is the other thing, because having a, it's not enough to have a quality,
you know, a testing mindset and focus on quality if your feedback loops are truncated.
Unfortunately, so many organizations design the system of delivery to make quality very,
very hard to deliver. Okay. This, this concept of run what you've rung doesn't mean that,
that you own all of the infrastructure and everything to deliver your software. What it
does mean is that if you build something that when it breaks, you're the person responsible
for fixing it. Right. And that is a primary, very important quality feedback loop that
when, when we had an, you know, an ops team whose job it was to do level one, level two support,
so many defects were getting hidden until they became emergencies where it could have been,
if we'd found out about it early on, number one, we wouldn't have been keep building on top of
quicksand on top of something that's already unstable. They're patching together, not letting
us know about, but we could have killed it and nipped it in the bud before we got very,
very angry people yelling at us and, and, and, and gotten better at our quality process up front.
And so to anybody out there who's in leadership who thinks it's a great idea to have a support
team support, supporting software that a development team is writing, you're wrong.
You're harming your customer. Stop it. Move ops into the team, start a page, your rotation,
create an L one support team whose job it is, is to do triage, but not to fix anything
and wake people up. Your quality will improve. Yeah. That's exactly what did it. My last
company we had eventually we got to a place where we had the L one pagers and they took
care of everything that had run books like you need to bug anybody. We'll work around
the clock at distance and we'll make sure stuff gets filed. So it gets improved because
a lot of the run book stuff is stuff that's just going to go wrong. Yeah. And then,
yeah, but then people were, if something happened, they were brought in quickly and they owned it.
And I love that. That's the way it's, to me, it's the way it should work.
When, when they went through this maintenance, they called it project harvest, by the way,
this matrixing of the organization, we, we called it project Reaper because it just
absolutely destroyed our culture. But when they did that, you'd have, you know,
number one, we had no way to train new developers on support because it was only L three and it
was only in the middle of the night because we never got day calls at all ever. And number two,
by the time we got on, instead of having somebody who was mildly annoyed because their job was kind
of getting disrupted a little bit, we were an hour and a half into the problem. And now
we're waking up trying to orient to what the issue is, probably have a VP on the line.
Got a very angry person who, you know, in the UK or Mexico or someplace screaming at us.
That's the best way to try to resolve an issue.
Yeah, for sure. You know, I've been, you remind me in your talk there, I've been
about eight years ago or so, maybe nine years ago, sort of found myself into managing platform teams or
whatever you want to call them infrastructure teams. I don't like calling them DevOps teams,
but you know, I'm talking to you. Please don't call them DevOps.
Yeah, I'm not going to. I'm just trying to appeal to the wider audience. But
so what I found in doing that, like very early on, because I had spent
seven in the industry, 30 years, about 20 years in mostly in test related roles,
maybe the last year that sort of more of a test coach, a little bit of a dev in the middle.
Anyway, I realized six months into managing a platform team that, oh my God, I have more
control over quality in this role than I ever did at any time of my career, because I was building
tools to help make it easier for the developers to deliver as fast as they wanted.
Yeah, no, I work for a company that does platform work for the government right now,
and it's a really important job. I can't think of anything better for any developer to do
than to work on platform if they take it seriously, if their role, if their goal
is to help other developers live better lives.
Yeah, for sure. And one thing I want to talk more about, we're almost out of time, but one
thing I've noticed in being in this role and then talking to folks in similar teams and
other organizations is often this platform team is kind of treated like the ops team. Like they do
the, they do the CI for another team. It's like another pattern. Don't do that.
They get, you got to, you got to build what you run or what do you say?
Run what you run, run what you brung, run what you brung. Yeah, I love that. And that's,
I want to, that's it. I want to enable teams to do that. Should be the goal of that platform team.
Yeah. I mean, the platform at Walmart, we didn't build pipelines for anybody.
No, no.
Easy for people to build pipelines themselves. How can we build a, we don't know your quality
process. Exactly.
That pipeline defines your quality process. All we can do is give you tools to make
that as easy as possible. Absolutely.
And the whole concept of, oh, that's the DevOps team building pipelines for somebody else
is the most bankrupt version of, you know, misunderstood DevOps that I can think of.
Yep. It's like, if you can think of anything more diametrically opposed to DevOps.
It is. Yeah. Yeah. Especially DevOps is about everything the opposite of that.
I gave a talk at QCon where I talked about the journey we went on
and how we replaced a scale agile framework with engineering and logistics at Walmart.
And I talked about this concept of, you know, owning the pipeline. And then I asked if anybody
in the room was a DevOps engineer and built pipelines for people. And I had several people
raise their hands and say, please stop doing that.
Yeah. That's what I tell them. Knock it off. Knock it off.
We are just about out of time here. Man, it is so cool to get to hear these stories
and kind of your journey. It's just really impressive. People don't read the lighter
notes, the show notes. So if you want to, I know you have your blog.
Yeah.
Other, oh, and you have your DevOps podcast on YouTube.
Sort of give us the rundown how people can get deeper into the world of Brian Finster.
Well, I have a blog, the five minute DevOps blog on Medium. There's a reason why it's called that,
but we don't have enough time to go into it. If you go to blog.brianfinster.com,
you'll get there or rant.brianfinster.com will also get you there.
Also, there's an open source project that we started a DevOps enterprise summit
several years ago called minimumcd.org. And the goal of that is to create, number one,
a minimum set of if you are doing these behaviors, this is the minimums to be doing
continuous delivery. If you do that, you will see these benefits. You won't see these benefits,
unless you're doing at least these behaviors. And they're the minimum set of behaviors that exist
in any context, air gapped, cloud, cat videos, metal and distribution centers. I don't care.
We worked on these really hard. Dave Farley was one of the early signatories on that. He thought
it was good. We keep expanding on the knowledge base there, but it's just we learned a lot of
hard lessons and different, you know, the core team from multiple organizations, all of us have
learned hard lessons around CD. We're trying to make it easy for other people. And just,
I want to leave this with people again. You can't do continuous delivery unless you try.
Trying to do continuous delivery will uncover so much organizational dysfunction,
so many skill gaps that if you just try to do it and just relentlessly fix those things,
you will wind up better off, even if you never get to real CD.
That is also my experience. Brian, thank you very much. I do want to personally thank you.
Like it was great hearing the story. I had not ever heard sort of the journey.
So you sort of landed in the same place, Alan and I are. And when it comes to the
mentality around how to do development, lifecycle management. But coming up through dev and coming
to that place is a unique perspective that I had not heard before. So thank you for joining
the podcast. Thanks for telling your story. Really appreciate it. I appreciate the opportunity
to share. Hopefully it helps somebody. Yeah, that's all we can hope for.
Any one of our three listeners to grab a nugget and go, I can grow from that.
Yeah. All right. Well, thanks everyone for listening. I'm Alan. I'm Brian.
We'll see you next time.