You and I do not have the mental capacity to combine the number of ideas that this
freaking bot already has done.
Welcome to AV testing podcast, your modern testing podcast. Your hosts, Alan and Brent,
will be here to guide you through topics on testing, leadership, Agile, and anything else
that comes to mind. Now on with the show. Hey, everyone. I am Alan Page and I am here with
my colleague, Jensen. That's right. I don't know what I'm doing. I wasn't expecting the
I wasn't either, but through miracles and miracles, we got Zencaster to work and gets you that three,
two, one. As a risk repeating myself, I'm not going to do on the whole rant I did last time,
but I want to like Zencaster. And I feel like this is what's frustrating is if I start off with
buggy software and it gets better and better, I fall in love with it more. But when you have
software that works and then stops working, it's really annoying, really not or the experience gets
worse. It is frustrating. But anyway, I think we're working. We have a backup going in place.
I have the sounds coming in the right holes and out the right holes. I figure like it's a
good place to do our last A.B. testing podcast of the year 2022 2022. That's the year. Yeah, good job.
Not so do you remember a year ago, like what we're going to do today, the usual end of year,
we're going to reflect on the year a little bit and we're going to look ahead a little bit into
the year. And that's going to take about 40 minutes. I'm sorry to say. So if you don't care
about that, then you can just wait till January for 172. Yes. But, you know, listen on.
Yeah. You do never, never know what you're going to find out. So did you go back and listen to
whatever episode it was, the last one from last year?
No, I do recall that I did a shit job on predictions.
Here's what I did. I did not go back and listen to it. It's like 159 or something.
But here's what I did do. I got to tell you, and you know this, I'm going to repeat it for our
listeners who may have forgotten. So since I left Microsoft, the only Microsoft software I use is
my Xbox and Visual Studio Code. And I think that's it, except for one exception, which I do
once a year. And that is to load. I don't want to bother installing all of Office, but I load up
Word for web, whatever it's called, into my browser. And then I go to the dictation thing and import
and I import the MP3 of the podcast from a year ago, our predictions episode. And I let the
translate function auto translate it from the MP3. Oh, does that do a good job? You're saying we
not a really very good job at all, but close enough. I can give you some context.
You're saying we could have been doing crappy transcriptions forever then, huh?
Yeah, it would just take so much editing to get it right. So I know, and I get there's a,
I didn't highlight, there's a couple of really funny ones in there.
But you can kind of get the gist of it scrolling through pretty quickly. I get much
faster than listening. I can just scroll, blah, blah, blah. But some stuff is surprisingly accurate.
Do you want to, let's, maybe before we go into our predictions from last year,
like how was your 2022? What was it like? What did you get done? Can you remember back to January?
Do, is it all a blur to you like it is for me?
This year was mostly a blur. There's, there's nothing I can look back on.
And go, you had 2022. I guess the only thing would be, would be the D, the partial D COVID occasion
of society. I mean, that was great. I mean, a lot of the news reports coming out now kind of
ticked me off, but the fact that things kind of going back to normal ish ish.
We just had a discussion with some of the leadership for our local office to talk about. We've,
I'm not going to rehash this because we've talked about this a few episodes ago.
How do we get more people to go back to the office? So my, my view on that is changing.
My view on how do we get more people to go back is changing a little bit. It's more of,
why don't we just give up? Why don't we just have a smaller office? I think for a lot of
tech companies, especially in places like here in San Francisco, where, uh, here in a lot of
your breathing there, especially places like here in San Francisco, where people are commuting from
a lot farther away, even for you. How long is your commute from where you live to the Microsoft
office? It'll be between 15 minutes and 30 minutes. Okay. Your system, I thought you're a
little farther north there by make a difference, but you come in pretty early. So mine's about 25
from where I live to downtown Bellevue. I'm good with that. But a lot of people,
especially folks that haven't lived here as long and they just live an hour away.
Cause that's where they can afford to get a house. And it takes a big chunk of commuting time.
I'm kind of wondering at this stage of the pandemic, it's not over by any means,
but we're at a stage where we're just learning and we're getting towards where it's endemic,
I guess, where we're learning to live with it. I never anymore have a time when I don't know
anybody that has COVID like any day of the week, you could ask me, Alan, do you know anybody that
has COVID right now? And I can tell you names of people. That's what it's like. And I don't,
I'm not that social. I don't know a lot of people. I always seem to know people who have COVID.
Yeah. I don't know anyone right now. I mean, I guess we're not taking a poll there.
Well, so anyway, the, the, the point I was going to get to is I think a lot of companies,
I'm not saying my company or Microsoft or any other companies. We should just make co,
like our co-working places, like, which is kind of what our offices are now, just make some smaller
offices. Like my office typically has 30 to 50 people there a day. The office holds 200 to 250.
If we had an office that held 75 or a hundred, it would at least feel like an office. It would
feel like there would be some of that buzz and, and some conversations happening that weren't just
about work. But anyway, uh, 2022 I can share. So on that, on that front, for example, I can share.
So we're here at Microsoft and I don't know if I've shared this, but I am often involved in like
office moves. I'm, I'm particularly good at figuring out who goes where type of thing. I even,
uh, this year I did something I've been doing. I've been wanting to do forever. I actually wrote an AI
to, to do it and figure it out. You had mentioned that before. That's cool.
Now, the thing that is interesting right now is we're, we're in this,
Microsoft officially is in this weird place. We, we are simultaneously do not have enough offices
and have too, too many offices. I can't wait to, I can't wait to hear you explain this. Well, um,
so when you were here, if, if you recall there, there were rules on like space and moves,
right? Seniority rules, for example, if you've been here 80,000 years, you get, you get the
corner office. Exactly. And over years things have changed. Uh, for example, every move that
I've done in the last, I don't know, 10 years, uh, if you're doubled, you get a window office.
If you are a single or a manager or for whatever reason you get your own office, usually that'll
be an inside office, right? They kind of, kind of appeals to a little bit of a balance to make
it work. Gotcha. Right. Right. And of course, Microsoft being one of the only companies where
employees have offices, but go on. And even that's changing. Right. But even in the open space,
right? If you have seniority, then you get, you get the one desk where your back's against the
wall and in a, in a corner next to the window, whatever. Right. So what's going to be right now
is a lot of those rules are still in place. And so there's a lot of people taking up
space because they have seniority who are then not coming in. Aha. And I have a story about that.
Like w w there's a break. Right. And then new hires are automatically being told, sorry,
you will be working from home because there's no space here. Now, weird. I can't imagine that. Okay.
This is weird. That it's a, it's a weird thing. And lastly, someone did some bad scan. Um, you
know, we, you have a, you have to scan a badge and approximately 11% of our populace are coming in
into the actual office. It's all weird. And Microsoft leases a bunch of buildings and,
and found out that we're going to give up the lease on one of the buildings and everyone's
all freaking out where are we going to fit all the people? I'm just like, yeah, you got rules from
1998 that are making it difficult for you to figure out this problem. So for example, one of the,
the things that I did for my manager's recent move, I went to, I, I did a data science way. I said,
okay, based off, I did a poll has bunch of people. Okay. Seriously though, you know, in the next
hundred days, how many times do you think you're going to come in? And they answered honestly,
and I guaranteed that they'll have a desk. And then I rearranged people based off of the
probability that they're going to be in. And so then you could say, all right,
the, the probability this office is going to have at least one person in, in a particular day is
going to be 0.8. Right. Anyway, you take that, you rebalance it and you end up with everybody
being able to be guaranteed a desk, not, not, not having to turn it away. Like if I were to show you
right now, you'll see that even I am, I am currently doubled up with a desk. This is a coworker,
a coworker of mine who comes in maybe once a month. Okay. You know, there's a couple of things I want
to share here. One is just sort of in the regular world, the non-Microsoft world and more open
spaces, the idea of hot desking is just a lot easier. And you know, you were telling me a while
back, maybe even a year ago that Microsoft was moving towards away from desktop workstations
and more towards high-end laptops to work from. Did that ever become a thing?
Hasn't become a thing yet. It hasn't become a thing.
We're, you know, we have of course some parts of our, go ahead, Brent.
It is still so, not only high-end laptops, but an AVD instance, an Azure virtual desktop
instance for everyone as well. So we would all have pretty beefy VMs in the cloud. And that to
me all makes perfect sense. And they announced this, God, nearly a year ago.
Yeah.
I probably should dive in.
The way it works for us is we just have a desk reservation system and all the desks are reservable,
either ongoing permanently or for a one-off. And it's just first come, first serve for the most
case, the few exceptions. And you just reserve your desk, you show up, you plug, there's monitors
there. You plug your laptop in. We have lockers there where I keep my portable Bluetooth
mechanical keyboard and mouse. And yeah, I just sit wherever. But I've been sitting in one seat
regularly now, which is non-reservable because we have, I won't even name any names,
but we have one person who's a senior vice president reports to our CEO who has a permanent desk
in a very nice spot. And I know he never comes to work. So I moved all of his stuff into a file
cabinet. I've been sitting at that desk.
Because I like that.
So I always have a desk that I just work there. And then a lot of times I go in and I'm in,
you know, Zoom meetings all day. But anyway, the laptop works well.
Just as an aside, does the senior VP know you're homesteading his desk?
Maybe. I told him that I may just take his desk over. He didn't say anything
once on a call. He's one of these folks who splits his time between Seattle and California.
And I think he's been mostly on the California side in a while. So yeah, that's where we're at.
So anyway, we talked last year a little about the pandemic and COVID. Do you remember a conversation?
We've had multiple of those conversations.
I'm going to go back to the specific episode 151 and talk about some of our predictions last
year before we begin looking forward to the next year. So one of the things was that I said that
I wasn't planning to go to the office at all in 2022. That ended up changing. I got bored of
working here probably the last three months I've been going to the office two to three times a
week. So I was wrong. You also mentioned that Bill Gates had mentioned that the pandemic would be
over in 2022. And I don't think we dove enough into the definition of air quote over. Like I,
it's not over unless you could say it's a standemic. I don't think we're quite too endemic yet. So
I think it's not over. I think there still is a COVID pandemic. So Bill Gates was wrong.
He was wrong to hire me too. You know, even though it's several levels of indirection, but whatever.
I don't know who has the authority to declare it over, but our president stated it was over
on September 21st of this year. Well, he was wrong. He was wrong. Just, you know, yeah,
he was wrong, but at least he didn't come out with his own line of trading card NFTs
of him dressed as a superhero. Yeah. Who knows what his son's doing.
Yeah. So a year ago, we were talking a little bit about your art. Are you still painting?
No, I haven't. I haven't. So what happened? What happened? Usually you're showing me stuff. Like
what happened to your up and coming painting career? So I'm going to restart it. Actually,
I had a conversation with my daughter when I dropped her off today. There is this cool
online class that costs, I guess, like $400 that I can make Microsoft pay for with that
random benefit that I think came into play when you were still here.
Yeah. Some sort of education benefit. That what it is. Might've happened after I left. It's all
right. No, they took when they changed it such that you had options other than the pro club.
You could sign up for a pro club or you could get X amount of dollars back for whatever the
hell you want. Right. That's what I did. I did that for the last couple of years. So yeah.
Yeah. And at that point in time, the whatever hell you wanted had to be something fitness
related, but they've since changed that and it can kind of be whatever the hell you want.
Oh, that's cool. But yeah, I asked my daughter if that would be something she would want to do
with me. She's like, as long as we're doing it together. And I'm like,
oh, wow. She's about to turn 13 and she still wants to do things with dad.
Yeah. That's nice.
I'm in. He's like, who knows how long that's going to last? So yeah. No, I painted. I painted one thing
this year and I hated how it came out. I never actually finished it and shredded it.
It is one of those things where the nice thing about painting, particularly like oil paints,
you screw something up. It's very like anyone who's watched Bob Ross, right? Happy little
accidents. You could easily fix it. Watercolor, it soaks into the paper and it's a lot
harder to do that. And then when you stare at something and you go, oh, I see mistakes
everywhere as part of my QA training, right? It still sticks with you. You see negativity
everywhere. And then I go, and it's beyond my capability of fixing it. So I can either keep
it here until I find a way to fix it or I'm going to shred it, which is what I did because I'm like,
I can't stand looking at it because it frustrates me. It's broken and I can't fix it.
I'm glad you're getting back into it. Actually, I want to look forward yet. So I want to look back
on our predictions from last year and add some few notes in there. One thing I did in 2020, so
here's weird, something I've done the last six months that everybody else did at the beginning
of the pandemic is I grew my own sourdough starter and have been making sourdough bread.
It's been coming out better every time. Are you still using the, you're using the same
refrigerator? I made my own mother. That's so cool. So it's just, you get the whole wheat flour and
get the pulling yeast from the air, which is generally including at least some yeast from my
body. So it is literally out. It's like made from me. Made with love. So I did that. So we spent
some time last year talking about streaming services and what we've been watching. And
we just, my wife and I just wrapped up watching Wednesday last night and this is where it gets
blur. I can't remember what I watched this year versus last year. I did two years ago. You
recommended what was it with the masked singer, which I still don't like. And I told you that last
year and you said you liked it, but whatever. So I watched the Reacher series on Amazon was
really good this year. I've read all the books and or is, is, I think the best start in my
discussion to have here and, or I think maybe the best star Wars series on Disney.
Now, interesting. I just finished and or I, this week, like I think Tuesday and I was surprised with
the end of the episode, right? I'm like, what? What that or it's season, whether that's the end
of the season, but what's he going to pick? We kind of know. Spoiler. We kind of know by the smile.
What's going to be chosen? I thought I don't know. I don't like I felt that like a good deal of the
Star Wars mythos was, I don't know, neglected. I don't it felt it felt like a like they had taken
a template of some form of similar script and just mapped it to the Star Wars.
I mean, it is kind of maybe that's why I liked it. It was definitely a more mature show.
There's no baby Yoda in this thing. It was dark and serious all the way through.
Maybe Mandalorian Mandalorian. I like Mandalorian. I guess that was last year,
but I like Mandalorian so much more. I mean, the Roku character could get me. Who cares? But
the Mandalorian character, that character was awesome. I know, but it's lighter. And maybe
it's just me and I like the darker stuff. But what else? What else was good this year?
What did you see on the Oh, did you watch the one on Hulu? Do you have Hulu? The one where
I really like it. It's the chef in Chicago, who's like a decorated chef who goes back and it's a
drama, not a reality show restaurant. I the bear, the bear, the bear. That's it. That was really good.
The bear, the bear as in growly thing. Yes. OK. I love cooking themed things of all sorts. I
have not. You should check that out. But you know what? I've been watching this
a show on Netflix called Drink Masters. It's like a food cooking show,
but they're making mixed drinks and it's delicious to watch. I no longer have Netflix and it took
forever. It took forever to finally let go of it. It's not coming back. It's not coming back.
It can stay gone. So did what did Netflix do to hurt you?
It it had it essentially cancelled Iron Fist. That's what finally pissed me off. I'm like, OK.
Well, that wasn't that good of a show. And I had I was a big big Marvel fan.
I had the entire 15 issues of the Iron Fist run. But it's a big Iron Fist fan. That wasn't
a great show. They didn't do a great job with it. They ended it horribly. But I think because
they got cut. Yeah, they said, could we please finish it badly with ten dollars in a piece of
guy. And then with with the main hero having cheap powered guns. What the hell is this?
It got weird. Yeah. So anything else could you be watching? I have watched
everything Marvel on Disney Plus now, like literally everything you go, even like the stupid
like five minute clips about I've watched those two. Yep. I finished about three weeks ago.
I finished. I hadn't watched all of Agents of S.H.I.E.L.D. That is now over.
Yeah, I watched I watched those when they were on network TV.
All right. Like I said, literally everything on Disney Plus Marvel I have seen.
That's a very good series from beginning to end. Lots of fun.
Yeah. Although the agents of S.H.I.E.L.D. series, the last season, this is so weird,
but it was clear they were just trying to tie things up 100 percent.
Similarly, I have H.B.L. Maxx, so I'm similarly almost through the D.C. stuff.
I have tried to get into like the Teen Titans in those series on there and I just can't.
Oh, Titans, I've gotten through. Oh, oh, and the episode one of series four,
a season four of Doom Patrol came out this week.
I haven't tried watching Doom Patrol yet.
If you haven't watched Doom Patrol, oh, my God, it is.
It is in my view, it is absolutely the best thing D.C. has made ever.
Well, it's not a high bar.
Flash is pretty good. The C.W. Flash.
Yeah, that was good. I did watch a season of that.
It's kind of like I don't know if because my childhood was 98 percent Marvel and two percent D.C.,
that's kind of what my it's hard for me to get into the D.C. shows, but I'll give it a shot.
I'm going to put Doom Patrol on my list.
Doom Patrol is way better than Masked Singer.
I got it again.
Low bar.
And then the other one I am up to date on is The Boys on Amazon.
Yeah, I couldn't I did not like that at all.
I and actually I was just going to get mad at you for recommending it,
but I see other people say they think it's awesome, but I just it didn't click for me at all.
Uh, maybe maybe you just didn't get through enough of it.
All right. Well, maybe I'll try it again.
I'm going to put it here.
I may give it a shot again sometime.
I have a whole crap ton of work to do, but I have those weeks off.
Maybe I'll do some streaming.
Check those out.
So anything else from the streaming world worth mentioning for our fans who want to get that?
We don't have fans, people that tolerate us.
Speaking of people that tolerate us without looking, I would like you to guess
how many people were in our Slack group a year ago versus today.
This is one of the three dot slack dot com.
You can go to modern testing dot org, click on the link and join.
Sometimes it comes back and says the link is invalid.
Just try it again because it just does that.
It's a slack thing.
I am going to guess last year around 500 and this year around the thousand.
Well, you're wrong on both sides.
So we didn't grow a lot this year.
Last year we had 742 members of our wonderful Slack community, which is it's vibrant.
People ask questions about modern tests.
It's not like Brent and I have to go answering.
People just talk about stuff and some great conversations, some simulations of chat,
GPT, having an ABI testing podcast, which are kind of hilarious.
Yeah, we added.
We added 122 members to our Slack over the last year, which is all right.
So it was from 742 to 864.
If we do another hundred and I mean, we're on that pace, ramped up a little bit.
We should finally get to a thousand next year, which is a peer vanity metric.
But well, it means nothing on our way to a million.
It's not like we don't have hypothesis.
Brent, I think if we talk about the boys on the podcast, we'll add 10 more people to our Slack
community. We should have a channel because channels are free in Slack.
Why don't we have a channel in our Slack to discuss what is good on streaming television?
Why does that not exist?
That's a very good point.
Somebody will do it now.
Thank you.
Thank you. Whoever created that channel.
Please invite me and I will put links to everything I've watched.
Why doesn't Netflix give me a year interview recap like Spotify?
Why can it not tell me where I binged my time or same thing for Peacock or Hulu or Paramount Plus or
oh, Ted Lasso.
Ted Lasso also very good if you have Apple TV Plus.
Oh, you probably don't have Apple TV because Microsoft ignores the existence of a company
called Apple. Apple TV has a show called Severance, which is utterly fantastic.
Maybe the best thing I watched this year.
It's a show. Let me give you the premise of this show just for you.
Everybody else has seen it, Brent, but I will tell you literally everyone else has seen it
except for Microsoft employees because they don't believe in Apple because ever since
bomber smashed that phone, it's like it's like it's erased from the brain.
Anyway, the premise of the show is this idea that your work life and your home life are
severed, meaning when you're at work, you have no recollection of who you are in the real world.
And then when you leave work, you have no idea what you do for a living.
Just just just know where you work.
Oh, that would be so.
And the moral implications of such an arrangement and ethical.
And then what happened to someone decides they let me give you one little gist of a thing.
Doesn't give anything away. No spoilers.
What would happen if someone at work decided, you know what?
I don't like this anymore. I don't want to do it.
And then they tell their boss that in their bosses, okay, let's talk about it tomorrow.
And they come talk about it tomorrow.
And there's a recording of the home person of that home version of that person,
meaning themselves and they left work saying, no matter what, I do not want to quit.
I'm staying in this position. So you're arguing with yourself.
Yeah, no, I was from two different lives.
I was seeing all sorts of.
Right. You could be a PI in your job and be hired to investigate yourself.
I know it really good. Really good. You should watch it.
You just get like, I'm sure it may be pirated somewhere or yourself like a trial of Apple TV
to watch that. You could like binge that and Ted Lasso and have a wonderful week.
Okay. The last thing you said that I recalled from the translated notes,
which I would like you to expand on, then we can look forward to 2023 a bit is you said,
which I think is true, but I want you to talk about it.
Modern testing principles will safely die to some degree.
Well, safely. Wow. That was generic.
That's how you get the I said it was right. It didn't say it was good.
Yeah, it's. That's weird, because in some angles,
it's it's it's hotter. Well, it's no longer a fad topic, I would say, like when when we came out
with it, right, it was a bunch of people. I don't get a lot of people arguing against it with
white knuckles like we used to. Yeah. And also the point to bring up was again to talk about
what's the next evolution of those that isn't just tester focused. So that way they empty
principles are dead. Long live empty. And we got to a point where said modern testing is about testing
and it is modern. Right. Right. In terms of like the A.B. testing, which is interesting because we've
had a few of our if we had a few of our listeners go, please, please don't go down that route around
user studies and A.B. testing. I did a I just like the rest of human society.
I I am been fascinated with chat GPT as as a knowledge, a knowledge graph, a knowledge mining tool
along these lines. I asked it. I asked it two questions today, and I didn't save the other one,
which was more relevant. You know who Christopher Alexander is? Of course you do.
Of course I do. Yeah. And I asked chat B.T. to describe software quality in the spirit
of Christopher Alexander. I also asked it in the spirit of James Bach. Oh, God.
Does it know who James Bach is? It does. That's cool. And I didn't pace the James Bach one,
but obviously you would read it and go, yeah, it did an excellent job doing that. Right.
What I find fascinating, though, is combining Christopher Alexander did not talk about software
quality at all. Right. Right. He talked about quality directly. Not directly. He talked about
quality and design patterns invented by him were for the express purpose of delivering quality.
And and I thought it did a very good job at this as well. Right. The very first concept,
it is a holistic concept that considers the overall functionality, usability and value of
the software, as well as how it fits into the larger system. That phrase or something like
that wasn't in the chat GPT's expression around James. And if I've read Christopher Alexander,
I'm like, yeah, that's totally him. Right. And then it continued on talking about
the user and the well-being and satisfaction of the person using it. Right. And I'm just like, okay,
this right. Clearly, I go back, winding it back to modern testing principles. I go back and I think
about what was in my mind. And it's it's more of that that point of view that Christopher Alexander
or Weinberg or a myriad of people that that we have talked to and talked about on the show.
And it's it's around the human and how the human is going to to use the thing to bring
to make their life better, easier, stronger, faster, whatever. I completely forgot why,
how I got on this tangent. Nobody knows. Yeah.
So we were going to talk about modern testing principles dying or not dying. Oh, we got here.
So wrap this up. So we have to start making predictions. Yeah. Yeah. I think in some regards,
I'm going to say it is in its it's in its midlife. It's no longer bored and exciting, but it's it's
not dead yet. It kind of, you know, kind of like you and me. It just is around. Yeah. So speaking
of not dead before we go on to predictions. And this is kind of again, another snapshot of the
world. I was thumbing through my RSS feeds. There was a time when I caught up on my RSS feeds
every day. Now it's every couple of weeks I go see what do people write about? So I quickly go
through and I saw someone somewhere say something around. What do I it was one of these like Cora
type posts. What do I do as a tester? What do I do when a manager asked me why I didn't find a bug?
So today I tweeted, what do I do when management asks a tester? Why didn't you find this bug?
And my answer, of course, is first thing is that I get back in my time machine and get the fuck
out of 1997. And then of course, there's going to be a few people who say things like,
this seems like a legitimate question for management to ask. No, it's just this idea of, I mean, it's
a good, it's a, to me, it's a straw man argument that I mean, I, I think largely it's a straw man,
because most companies don't function like that. How can that be largely a straw man?
And it's blatantly a strong man. I, well, I would say blatantly a straw man, except for,
I'm guessing that some places blaming testers for bugs in the wild is still the way they operate.
I think it's completely idiotic. I think it's the fact that someone, anyway, I'm just, oh, Lord.
So anyway, there's a little bit of a reference to the future. Let's talk about the future
where I already talked about the fact we're going to get to a thousand people in our slack
group. At some point it's going to snowball. No more in trouble. The other thing you almost got
right was I asked you what would be the last episode of 2023, 2022. And you said 170 and this
is one, two, three, four, five, 171. So you're off by one. Sorry, man. And we'll probably get to some,
we'll probably get to one 90, one 90, one 91 next year, one 92 somewhere in there.
I'm predicting one 92. Okay. I say one 91 and I have control over that. So I'm probably going to
win, which means here's the good news is that we're going to get to 200 in 2024.
If we both live that long, but we predicted that. And we did, we did. Okay. So what else is going
to happen in 2023? I wrote down two things in 2023 for sure. Do you want to share those things?
Oh, and we didn't, we didn't talk. Uh, what was your favorite episode this last year?
Oh, I don't know. According to Spotify, uh, 155. The, when we had, uh, Anne Marie on for.
Oh yeah. That was fun. And she's popular. She's more popular than us. So
she brought in some listeners for us. Gotcha. Mine was, uh, was, was the one with Al. Um,
cause you like Al. Well, it's so weird to think that was this year.
It was, it was January 10th. So it was barely this year. And we have, I'm not gonna, I'm not
gonna, just gonna hint at it. Our first recording of 2023, we have a guest who is going to be
fantastic. Awesome. That's my prediction. All right. My prediction. Number one,
hybrid will finally actually work. They're about hybrid work or hybrid cars. Hybrid work.
Hybrid cars. I don't know. Okay. Hybrid work. Um, again, can you, do you want to define
work a little bit? I think like anything works with the right air quotes around it.
Ah, yeah, that's true. Cause you're going to hold this against me next year. So I better be more
specific. I think the, the, the creativity of humanity and or the knowledge of, of chat GPT
will work together to come up with a solution for dealing with individual as well as corporate
preferences, right? The, hopefully with, well, we'll see. Never. I will never underestimate the
power of short sighted thinking. Um, so that will certainly throw a wrench in it. Uh, the,
the prediction I am absolutely the most confident in is GPT three, which is the AI basis for things
like chat GPT will be the fastest service online ever in humanity to bring in 1 billion revenue.
What's the revenue model? Uh, I don't even think they have one right now.
I want to ask chat GPT, what is the revenue model for GPT three? Okay. Well, that'll be that,
that one is good. I dig that one. Oh, I think, I think they'll go from zero to a billion next
year and it'll be the fastest service ever in humanity's lifetime to do that. And once that is
done, uh, bets are off. All predictions are off because that is a massive accelerant.
So do you think it's through, I want to talk about this a little bit. Is it just,
you know, microtransactions on API calls to use that to solve all the myriad of problems?
Cause I would, that would be useful. Yeah. Yeah. That's exactly what I think it'll be.
Yep. Okay. That's what I would do if I was them, I would, again, for the hobbyist,
it would be nothing pennies to play with it. And for a corporation wanting to, like,
we can go back and look at this whole thing of 15 years ago, target using data science,
air quotes to predict, uh, to know based on what somebody was buying if they were pregnant.
Now this is accelerating that this is accelerating things like that,
even for companies, cause it's natural language based NLP as Brett likes to put it.
This makes data science like that accessible for any company. There's some API calls and your prediction
from three years ago, where you're saying that data science as a role or discipline is going away
become accelerated potentially by GPT three. Oh, uh, yeah. Yeah. Like my, my team focuses on
natural language processing. And I'm like, okay, maybe I need to lead the way here and guide my
team away from that and start being one of the first to actually, you know, make the calls into
GPT three. Matter of fact, just before our podcast started, um, uh, one of my peers set up a,
a meeting in the new year to, to, to discuss GPT three and, uh, a system my team owns
code named wayfinder. So I'm just thinking through this. And I think if you, you are
hauntingly going to be correct on this because you, as it is today, uh, GPT has its learning model
is based on your login and what you've entered. So if you could have a learning model in a service,
you say based on the data, these thousand transactions, what is the next step for block?
I mean, it could fricking do that. It could, it could be decision. There's the creativity involved,
which talk about last time, but the decision matrix is yeah, I'm, I'm on board with that.
I support that prediction. So I have taken GPT three or chat GPT, like one of our threads on,
on our Slack channel where you talk about the modern testing principles version two and
a whole bunch of the three came in and commented. Yep. They did. They did. I, uh, did not read all
of those comments. It was a very long reply chain, but I did copy and paste it into chat B,
GPT three and said, generate rewrite the modern testing principles in a way that makes everyone happy.
Would you like to hear them? One million percent? Yes.
Number one, our priority is improving the business. It did not change that one. Nobody's mad.
Number two, we identify, prioritize and mitigate bottlenecks in the system to accelerate the team.
Okay. All right. One of the, that took the feedback. It took the feedback for those
you're not in the Slack channel. Some people did not like, thought it was too
prescriptive to mention theory of constraints and things like that. So,
well, and the other thing too was someone also said they didn't like that accelerate was removed
in V2. Number three, we are a force for continuous improvement and adapt and optimize
our practices to succeed. To me, that feels kind of vague and hand wavy, but it's still got the,
the right thing across. Number four, we care about the skills and professionalism of our team
and work to foster a culture of excellence. That's better than what we wrote.
Number five, I kind of don't know the controversial, but not controversial. Number five.
Well, and, but it did exactly what I asked. Number five, the customer five deleted.
Nope. The customer is the ultimate judge of the quality of our product.
That's actually not horrible, not a horrible reinterpretation.
It's correct, but, and it's written in a way that no one would disagree, but it did so.
No, but you're right. It softened it where we see the only one capable,
meaning stop pretending like you're the customer. And I told you,
I read Melissa Perry's book on, which is freaking excellent called the build trap on
outcome driven software development. And she talks about product manager,
product management saying some product managers say they are the voice of quality,
which is, which is kind of funny from the, because testers always say we're the voice of quality,
but she follows it up and says that, but we're not used to use the fricking data.
All right. Number six. It did not change. Number six at all. Okay.
I guess data extensively to deeply understand customer usage, then close the gap between
product hypothesis and business impact. Apparently I wrote that one like a robot.
Now it did change. Number seven. It's still expected. It was because that one,
that one makes people mad too. Okay. We strive to expand abilities and knowledge across the team,
aiming to eliminate dependency on specialists and consciously choosing specialties that the team
can consume as a service when necessary. Oh, cause that was in the discussion. I forget. I don't
know about that, but I mean, I get it. I get the, I get the origin story of these updated things
and probably the ones that didn't change because nobody argued about them.
If I would have put in that thread, but nobody mentioned lemon pie, lemon pie would show up in
one of these things. We should, but now, now think of, this is a, I mean, it was a lot of comments,
but, but think of applying this across a much larger sample set. Boy, it's like I said last
week, there are creative things I do. And I don't think very much of my job can be automated,
automated away by chat GPT, but also maybe it can, maybe there are some things like leadership
principles and things I think about around alignment that I could get written better as
a result of some, some discussion. No, it's so here is the thing, right? Where do ideas come from?
It come from old ideas getting together, right? You and I do not have the mental capacity
to combine the number of ideas that this freaking bot already has done. There are some very common
detractors of modern testing principles. I'm wondering if I could, if I could get,
if I could get this thing to rewrite it in the style of our detractors.
And I think my prediction also is we will eventually have an episode of AB testing in
2023 where chat GPT or GPT three do not, but worth it for today.
Maybe towards the end of next year.
My predictions are not for 2023. I do have a prediction for this weekend.
I believe that Argentina will beat France on Sunday in the World Cup final.
That's what I got. I don't think I had time to think of very many other ones.
We will see. I'll see if I can write some into the show notes of it. They can be before
the weekend, but it was fun to look back. Fun to look forward a little bit.
We will see what happens. I'm looking forward to, we're both kind of in that
20 ish episodes for 2023. That seems like a good pace. That means we go every other week,
skip a few, make it all work out. Every year I predict all get the guts to act,
get Nicole forage going to come onto the podcast. So maybe I'll just throw that one out there again.
That may happen, may not. We will continue to do guests from time to time.
That's all I got. I'm excited about the GPT three stuff. We'll make that happen.
So anything else from you, Brent Meister?
No. Happy holidays, everyone.
Yeah. Happy holidays. Have a good new year. We'll see you in January 2023 with a new
episode sometime. I'm Alan. I'm Brett.
And we'll see you next time on the AB testing podcast.