Maybe the tooling we need around this is the tooling that stops people from being fucking idiots
Welcome to a be testing podcast your modern testing podcast
Your hosts Alan and Brent will be here to guide you through topics on testing
Leadership agile and anything else that comes to mind now on with the show. We're back for another a be testing
It's just me
Alan wait what just you sorry. I just mean Alan comma Alan. Sorry try that again. It's me Alan and me
Brit and we're here together. Nobody no guess nobody else. My dog is asleep on the floor. Yeah my cat
empty
Your cat's empty. What no, so I I get it. Did I get I get it? Okay, I the cat bed. No cat did I
Already show you I did I did last episode. Yeah, yeah
It's been fantastic. She no longer jumps tries to jump on my keyboard
She's just happy being within arms reach
I am getting over a cold. I am going to edit out all of the
coughing that I may do
but I'm hoping that for the listeners it gives my voice a
Texture
That will draw you in to the important things I have to talk about
Or not or fast-forward you're actually I already sound higher pitched
Than I do normally because you are listening to this at 1.5 speed. I'm doing swell
I'm eager for the weekend within minutes
my of this
Podcasts being done my daughter and I
despite the damn
liquid sunshine today
We're gonna go out geocaching and we oh cool. You're both excited about it
I did that with my kids a long time ago. It's kind of fun
Yeah, hey, but speaking of going out have you seen Dune new Dune?
Dune 2 no Dune 2 you got to go see Dune 2 in IMAX. I have not seen doing one yet
So much better than the Dune we grew up with
Yeah
That probably won't take much. I
Am going to play Xbox this weekend for the first time literally in months. I got to tell you about
my
Struggle with starfield
Okay is I am in a place now where I do not have enough health nor ammo
To get out alive of this building. I'm in but I have to kind of walk my way out of
So I think I'm gonna have to go back to a save point well before the building is kind of start a whole big
Quest over because there's just no way out
I have scoured the building and all I find are more bad guys and no ammo and it's been kind of frustrating
I think if I'm a game designer, I would not put myself in that but put my players in that position
So I'm gonna give it a shot again
It's been long enough now that if I have to go do the whole quest again
I won't be mad because I'll forgotten most of it. It's kind of not a great experience. So I'm gonna go fix I
In starfield got myself into that situation I
Refused to do what you did and I just you know died reload died reload
Have already done done that 300 times and I did it enough to manage to squeak through
Okay, I will probably try another 50 times before I give up just for the record, but I probably I don't feel confident
I am now roughly
I haven't played it in a couple of months. I am I think around level 35 the last time I checked in
I was I'm at 12. I think it was around 7 but my
My birthday was last week in my Oh Happy Birthday Brett Brett's 25 now
25 going on 12 and
My eldest gave me
Baldur's Gate. Oh, I've been playing that too. That's a fun game, too
And that's the other I play three games on my Xbox. I play
Starfield Baldur's Gate and FIFA
Okay, I thought I felt I was I only am doing to matter of fact
I think I told you I went out and bought a whole new Xbox
Just to be able to play starfield and
Currently that Xbox has exactly two games installed upon it. I
Picked up an X. I think last summer
It has my whole library on it because why not? I don't have my other one plugged in anywhere
I I thought about plugging one of them. I have so many of them now. Anyway, lots of Xboxes. I'm gonna do that this weekend. Oh
Oh, I want to talk about how forgetful I am
Okay
So I had an idea for a podcast topic and Brent has a better one. Thankfully
But longtime listeners will know that I often
vet
articles or
our
Presentations on the podcast is talking about something that I'm thinking about for a presentation but kind of work through it
I'm giving a presentation at another company in May
Which is coming rather quickly and it's a it's a company that invited me up to give them a talk
pre-pandemic I supposed to give the talk in April or May of
Bad time to travel around the world. I'm finally gonna go back and give some talks and I was gonna talk through them
But I heard back from them today
asking me for some information about my talk and blah blah blah and blah blah blah and
I realized I do not have a copy of the abstract. I sent them anywhere
I don't know exactly what my talk is about. So I'm not gonna vet that here on the podcast because
Because I'm frankly old and dumb. Well, it feels like a good a good hour or two on the
Podcast you and I could just chat GPT it out. Yeah. Oh
And we're gonna get to chat GPT in a minute. But speaking of old and dumb
This is episode 197 of the AB testing podcast
So we are coming up on not only the 200th episode
Not all but more but more we're coming up on the 10th anniversary of the very first AB testing podcast
Do not listen to it
if we were
now I have been thinking hard about how we get to
200 to be released on that day and what it means is we got to get
197 198 and
199 out quickly. I think we decided this is 187, right? This is 197
Okay, and I'm Alan and that's Brent and this has been episode 197 of the AB testing podcast. All right
Now now let's do 198, okay
We're gonna figure it out, I don't know I got time let me know let me know if you want to do we could release
Episode one as a recap. Oh
No, we could do episode one with like director commentary. Oh
for 198
Okay, and and by the way like who invented this rule that episode
200 has to be done after
198 199
Right, right. We could just we could just skip some you're right
But I like the idea of MST 3k in our first episode that actually would be fun
I haven't listened to it in a long I gotta figure out I am pretty sure I can figure out how to just pipe that in
To us and we can listen and pause as we go along. That would be fun
Let's actually let's do that. Let's figure out how to make that 199
Okay, actually we'll do that. We get your calendar out figure out how we're gonna shove those in I will make it work
If you want to just pick a night, I got nothing going on. Let me know
So listeners don't know that Brent tonight we don't talk in between we got it we don't plan
We don't have a good things to do
Yeah, we should get a we should get an assistant assistant producer that would figure all this out. Just tell us what to do
Okay, we don't pay I think we can make this happen
All right, the hard part will be
We will have to do
episode 200
Morning our time if we want to do it on that day
Okay
We should
You know what because that one I probably won't edit so we could
If we're going to do it live with guests, I probably won't edit it
Uh, i'm going to talk to alan about this
Outside of the cast so
And if you all want to offer input
One of the three slack calm is our slack channel
But the way if you're not already there you can go to modern testing org
And click the link and joiny joiny joiny and get in there
And we're going to do our best to make it all happen and we want lots of guests
We're going to have for episode 200 whenever that is we're going to have people join
And there's going to be a chat gallery. We can have people just i'll figure it out. We can have lots of people on
It's going to be a big party without all the fear of covid and that stuff
All right
We have done some planning some
Gnashing of teeth and fingers and and things and we're going to do the best to make it work
But we have more to figure out but our assistant will step in and help out there
and let's talk about
Something brant you had an idea for a topic and it was five minutes ago. So I forgot what it was. So yeah, so go ahead alan
You and I have stop sharing your screen
Yeah, all right. I'm gonna try pushing this stop button and see what happens
It worked. Okay, great. Yeah, it didn't kill the recording. We're good. Yeah. I'm like, why is it called stop?
It should be called unshare. What's gonna happen if I push this button?
Whitaker
recently wrote a post
uh
Alan if he remembers will link to it
And it is called the resurrection of software testing
And I thought it might be fun
for us to review slash
Comment on it
What this is this the same james whitaker who said test is dead?
He did
He's claiming he's giving credit to his colleague at the time alberto
Um, but I heard it for the first time from him
Yeah, and a lot of people misinterpreted this
Merritt had a great post this week that I mentioned in five for friday talks about people
who
Reference things in their talk that they have not fact checked it on the full research on so test conferences in my experience are famous for this
People telling stories about things that are half true
And a lot of the stories about test is dead
Missed the point
A lot of the test is dead about the same things brent and I have been talking about because your data is there to help us
Uh testing as it's been known
This is I think that was 10 years ago, right?
15 years ago 14 and 2011 so 13 years ago
First gave the test is dead talk
Stuff was changing
So it was a fair talk to give I think a lot of people lose a lot of the context or haven't looked into why
and again as we talked about with um
with cat a few episodes ago, it is
surprising to me
How many testers who tout themselves on critical thinking fail to apply critical thinking when evaluating things they don't agree with but anyway
So that all happened. There was some reaction a lot of it misconstrued and then james who is
Trying to remain relevant in the world. Sorry james
Comes out with an article called the resurrection of software testing where he says, you know what?
Maybe it's not quite so dead
All right. Yeah
The ending of it is software testing may well have died in 2011
But its mindset needs to be resurrected in 2024
The world needs the skills of testers more than ever and researchers need to step up
To create similar tools processes and training they did for software so long ago
And what's interesting that we're going to actually spend a half hour talking about this post but
The first it's not a very long post and the first three quarters of it. All they do is recap albert's test is dead talk
And then he says oh ai and then gives uh brent's
Paragraph and I think there's a lot of truth to that
No, I think there's some truth to what james is saying
because
ai is
Changing the way software development can work
A lot of people think of ai as magic
Yeah
A lot of people blindly use the suggestions from ai without reading them remember my prediction show I talked about
As mentioned in the sense then at least twice
The ability to read code critically is going to become very important because you have to figure out
What's actually happening with this generated code?
And if that's and maybe that's a tester mindset
In a sense like brent's making a face like he's about to go to town on this really this one paragraph article
No, you just said
When the way you said the tester mindset
triggered
Negative thoughts from old podcasts. I get it right
When I read this
That didn't trigger. So so you you bring in loading that into the brain at the same time. I'm like, oh
I'm gonna
Cute a little now. Um
And I as an aside i'm like, hey, do you have arvin's?
Uh phone number on on speed dial like maybe we should pause and call him into this right now because I'd love
I think this would be a topic of interest to you. I'll go grab me living in my basement. Oh second living
He did something very hand wavy like
James super hand wavy. It's canonical with james
like he's the master at
What's a nice way of saying authoring clickbait titles rhetoric
No, like the resurrection of software testing like oh, yeah. Yeah
Yeah, and and to be clear we both love james a great friend. He's a funny guy and he's and it's obvious to me what he's
Doing here, but he's actually in his and he will tell you
That he is not being, you know facetious or clickbaity. He really means it but
On the other and he is actually correct. I want to go into why he's correct
But there's not enough there there
To actually get a full opinion. I think hopefully there's more coming
I thought it was funny james posted like this is right from three weeks ago two weeks ago. He posted
Any testers on the east side want to get together and chat?
And of course, he's going to invite them to his bar where they can buy his beer, right?
But he's like get together and I I just replied hey, dude test is dead
Did you I did I did I think you replied i'm talking about testers not test
words are important
so yeah, well, no, it's interesting because I
I think we would argue
That tester is more dead than test
Yeah, I would
I'm not going to write the article with that headline but
I'm like, you know because I read this line the world needs the skills of testers more than ever
So he never he says the resurrection of software testing
And I don't know I I don't think he's what what evokes for me
is
Bringing back right the the singular discipline
Bringing I hope not
And I want to talk about what what my interpretation of that is and it's kind of riff on that for a second
But I do want to bring up a tangent. Oh, no a tangent never
Tangent tangent. I happen to be we needed a theme song for tangent except we just I'd run out of copyright money
I uh was talking to a internet colleague today
Just talking about job searches and giving some generic advice knowing nothing about the person but super nice guy. I think he'll do well
I think
None of that's important if you're listening
And we talk today friday. I actually really think you're gonna do well, but
The thing we talked about is something i've noticed because I just
I do a lot of free consulting not as an employee of my company just because people say hey
Do you got 10 minutes or 15 minutes talk about a thing?
And I say as long as you're not trying to sell me something i'd be happy to talk to you
The industry has been very nice to me. The best thing I can do is talk to folks who asked for it
so
What I've noticed and I told him this what i've noticed in having these conversations over the past few months is actually
The bubble is moving
The bubble is moving on what testing is doing. We'll even put our conversation with brian finster from the podcast into this bucket
People are beginning to see that testers on good teams
When they exist exist to help developers do their job better
And that can be coaching or frameworks things are not there to do the vast majority of testing
They may do a little bit of testing because they're really good at it
But they're doing it in a way that makes people around them better
And I want to come back to that put a pin in that for a conversation on ai
And I also talked to a company
Uh, a test leader at a large company brent wrote a tangent song and chat gpt. This is great
I talked to a manager at a large company who has a test team
And my little alarm bells went off. Oh, you have a qa team. Mike also the qa team
I said, what do they do?
And what he basically he described that I won't use the words
But basically they accelerate the achievement of quality. They exist to help make to help with feedback loops
Help with the testing part of feedback loops. They can go faster
They there was a few cases where they did a little bit of
A little bit more than I thought they would but they are actively working on removing that from what they do
Okay, so this is a large company's probably had testers for 20 30 years. I am seeing the changes happening
I think these changes apply
To ai we do not need dedicated ai testers testing ai now. It's funny because
Arbin said you and I would one or both of us would both be in qa roles by the end of the year
But I have not been interested at all in any of these folks
Jobs or positions what i'm interested in learning kind of their journey so I can
Try and get stuff a stick in my head
I think we need people like and go back to the ai problem
It is a parrot as we discussed. It is not magic. I watch self-proclaimed test experts
use chat gpt for things or
Test chat gpt on things that an llm and generative ai would never be able to do
And they point their fingers and say you can't trust this stuff. It's broke and it doesn't work
We need people we need critical thinkers who understand how this stuff works
So they can one stop those people in their tracks
So when somebody it wants to use generative ai to manage their nuclear power plant
That's someone steps in so that's not a great application here the right things is good for
That's kind of what's been missing and we can go on the little ethics and ai thing
We don't necessarily need ai tested
We need people who really understand how it works
To explain to the rest of us one last thing i'm gonna get off my soapbox because I went to a talk
from someone
Virtually, of course, I don't leave my house because when I do I get sick
I went to a talk
Virtually from someone giving a talk on ai or llms or both people don't get the difference and yet neither to this person
They were on one hand
Ranting about how much they knew and how deep their talk was and while I was watching thinking oh my god, this is all wrong
So it's really missing from the industry today to sum up my ted talk what's really missing from the industry today?
Is people who understand how llms work?
Explaining and hand holding the people who are using them so they use it in the way that's most effective
And they don't use it for the things that it's not designed for and complaining
You're not going to get me to disagree with that i'm more curious around
Like the synops of of the one talk that you talked about
Like what was a key thing that this person was wrong on? I can look I probably have notes somewhere. I can look it up
They were actually wrong in a couple things
Partially right, but also in some places very wrong. No, it was it was
So high level that it didn't matter
And the low level stuff, but no it went deep because the speaker was very adamant about saying how deep they went
But the stuff they went on deep on it was obvious. They did not understand
Okay
They had no idea what a rag model was but they talked about it like they did but then they described it
It was obvious. They did not know what it was
for example
Anyway, I don't I'm I'm not here to throw internet people under the bus
What i'm here to do is say this is an example of where we need i don't even want to call it testing
It's an example of where we need
critical thinking applied to how
AI is used
Brent showing me a paper on his desk about how to filter content for retrieval augmented. Yeah
I literally just printed it out and just pulled it out of my paper my printer
The issue that we're battling is the same thing we've been battling
for a long time, you know
Ignorance the intellectually lazy is what i'm gonna call them. Yeah. Yeah
That's it
I don't know how we fix that like honestly lom quite honestly is probably going the other direction
Correct, right? It's like oh
Oh, we need a jingle
We need a little theme song for when we go to the start up the tangent segment. Oh chat gpt
Hey, it rhymes cool. Let me show it to allen, right? I spent
No time reading it most of my time going what's the prompt?
right, uh it
theme
That's the other thing
At work. I play the role that you
just
Talk through. Oh, maybe you're gonna be a
Uh, uh, ai qa
Uh, no
Yeah, exactly. Yeah, no
No, because number one that would make arban correct, uh, and I refuse to let that happen
I
On a daily basis the last
I have had random
ICs come to me and they're like hey
I have this awesome idea for how to use llm great sit down walk me through it
And they're like, oh, yes perfect except for
You know the parts where I actually use llm it keeps coming back with weird stuff
And then I sit down and I tell them
how
to use
the system
With with the endeavors that you do
You actually do it
Nearly optimal for what is what it excels at right? It's
If it's something that's a creative endeavor
Oh, yeah, I mean it's it's gonna knock things out like
Just as an example today. I have
my team has a
python package that we had built on top of llm to make our lives easier on a lot of aspects and
I
One of my ICs had created a unit test that had dependencies
And I don't like unit tests having dependencies. So I nor should you
So I did depend as sized it
And I had some sample content that I use in other things where it's it's quotes
quotes from yoda and quotes from mark twain
And I just I just said hey
Create three new quotes from a fictitious author
That simultaneously speaks like twain
and like yoda
And then write a story that includes those quotes
and
I better did all right. It did fantastic. Like the the quotes were
I'm like, yeah, that's like that's literally mark twain and yoda
the story was a little chintzy because
It invented a story about a little girl that lived in the village and she found a quote book
And she opened the first page and read the first quote and are they cheated? Yeah, i'm like, okay
Well, you did what I asked for but that's a boring story. That's what they do. That's what they do
But some tester now, here's the here's the difference
Some tester will ask you to write that story but write exactly five paragraphs and each paragraph should have 27 words
And it's not going to be able to do that
It doesn't get that it's not going to do that and they're going to say it's broken
We need people because they don't understand how llms and gen ai work, right?
So what i'm saying we need in testing is and you like I said llms
They are here for now gone for later. We're going to have something else something different with agis or whatever
now each different thing that we call ai and even even gen ai is
Is it really ai is it really intelligent? Maybe not
Right. Absolutely not
So what we need for every single iteration of ai I was given our listeners the benefit of the dot to jump in there
We need somebody who understands how it works
To help figure out how it should be used what we've lost with chat gpt is nobody ever did that
Here's a thing you could ask these questions and then 90 of the people use it in a way
It wasn't designed and are frustrated with it. I don't understand because it's not hard to go figure out
It's it's intellectual laziness as you've called it and it's going to happen because
The speed of innovation this area is going to crank like hell
And people are not going to be able to keep up if they do not take some time to learn how these things
Work before deciding they know how they work
There is a couple of things when I when I think about this like
I
Right as you and I talked about james and james wrote this very hand wavy in my view your view as well
And he left it with the final paragraph
And and we both know him well enough. He did this on purpose. He left it. We do. Yeah
And and what he's going to do is we know james and actually I like the way james does research
He's going to pull people in on this. They're going to give him a bunch of feedback
He's going to get a bunch of ideas and then he's going to con one of them into writing a book with his name on it
Or
Yeah, and you get and you'll get to write the forward
right, you know
He's got an equation that works and i'm not going to fault him for it. I just quite no, no me neither me neither
Nothing, but respect because he does he does know his shit and he knows what he's doing
100 unlike some other folks in the industry who just whatever anyway, yeah
unicorns and rainbows unicorns and rainbows
He says the skills of testers. Okay, i'm not certain what the skills of testers he's talking about here
What are what are skills of testers brent?
um
I guess it would be in this like the ones I would say are are the ability to critically understand what's going on
It's not fine bugs
okay, it's
Tie and connect the dots between the customer's needs
And the product I definitely
Oh, wow
There was a day a day
Decades ago where I would have cited. Oh, it's matching to the
Requirements spec like you know, i'm long past that
It's around connecting to the needs of the customer to this now. I will tell you
one
Really big I was I was
I was in a very high level
llm meeting within my company
just
yesterday
um
Not yesterday
Tuesday, whatever this week. I raised the question
Hey
Has anyone found a way to?
to quantify
the number of times
a particular
qualities
uh situation that occurs in llm has occurred
And like no, but if you find something I need it
And then it went down the line every data science. No, if you find something I need it the biggest challenge
Are you familiar with the book? Uh, what is it? Systematics?
No, okay. It's it's like one of the primers on systems theory. Okay
and
In there he has something he calls the law of systematics
And that law is the number of problems in the universe
Is constant right and you've mentioned this before I didn't I forgot I didn't know what book it was from. So yeah
Yeah, and so the problem with llm when you're trying to do it in a non-creative space
You have to figure out. Okay. What does it do? Well, i'll tell you
It does
conformance well
Like let's say you have five different help docs written by different people
And there's a format a language choices that you like from from on one. Yeah, you just say hey
Take this style rewrite these ones
It'll do that just fine
Well, actually that's a again. It goes back to my I think we need
AI
Guides what's a fancy word for a guide?
guide
Okay
What a docent near an AI docent to kind of walk organizations through how to use it because
time and time again
Organizations think that AI is magic
And people go. Oh, this is a really hard problem. Let's use let's use magic to solve it and someone needs to say
Not only stop them
But I actually look at the org and say here are some areas where we really could use AI
And make sure it's happening someone who understands
You know some companies may call it an AI architect. That's the wrong word too, but somebody
It would be more effective if someone made it work correctly. I want to go back to james
Arden. I want to hold on. I want to go back to that because I don't actually uh
I think the principles of testing that we have been talking about that testers need to serve as a guide
Is the way to do it? It's not AI coach. It's an AI. There's the words. It's an AI
That's what i'm looking for. AI coach an LLM coach
Like someone who can pass on and sprit and spread like seeds to the wind
What works what doesn't work?
I was gonna say I fully agree and when james says
While testing may well have died in 2011. It's the mindset needs to be resurrected in 2024
Testing may well have died in 2011. We need a different kind of person
to be doing
evaluation coaching testing on AI in 2024 and beyond
When the might
No, here's the thing and actually this is one of the things with this statement that I I will
Adjectly like if you were here, I would look him in the eyes and say james. This is bullshit
Because while software testing may have died in 2011
The mindset that was necessary to build software did not still exists
And is thriving
It's just now we spent the last 13 years
Getting devs to understand it better
right, it's
to me i'm like
No, I don't think this
I wish I could disentangle with skills attesters when he says researchers need to step up and create similar tools and process and training
That part I probably agree with and I think we're probably talking about that. I don't know if it's researchers, but it's
there
It's not only
The guides like you talk about the docent or like coach
What this says say is people like me
Who who do understand a lot of things about this and by no means do I?
I understand more than the common people and I understand that there's a lot more people who understand way more than me
What the world needs is a set of in this space a set of tools that make the sticky harder problem
clearer
Make it avoidable
like don't
You know what? Here's a tool
It's a front end that sits on top of chat gpt
And does some nlp on your input prompt
To let you to give you a score
On the shittiness i'm sorry the quality of your prompt like I could write this I could figure out if this is a question that I think
chat gpt
will answer
Really well or answer like you're asking it something stupid that you'll never get a good answer on
You and I use critical thinking to figure that out, but I can quantify that
How how would you quantify it?
I'm going to use a language model that looks like there. So I know what chat gpt is good at it's good at
parroting text and finding similarities and the style of somebody
All those things but that's it's not but all those things is a big
No, I want to flag the things. I know it's bad at so maybe i'm just going to do it simply
from
A keyword input file of things like similar it's going to look for words like count or rhyme
Or any of the multiplication symbols or all of those things. I know it's bad at and I know it's probably a quantifiable list
Uh and use those to help maybe it's harder than I think it is but it's possible
It is absolutely harder than you think it is. It's just software
Uh, but but here's one of the things that I don't know if you've ever done this
um
I I told you i've been talking to
Employees just about every day for the last two weeks. Okay, one of them is
Is is actually a rock star who reports to me, but he's still kind of unfamiliar with llm
He's familiar with with neural net. So the other day I was walking him through and I generated a prompt
And it gave me an answer and literally what I was asking it to do
Is I asked it to write code
And I said I want a comment that describes the purpose of this code
after the curly brace
It kept on putting it before the curly brace
And I wanted it after so then I chided it and I said no
You put the comment before I want it after
And then it says oh, okay, and then it
fixes it
Then I went back and I did the thing that blew my employees mind and I said
Okay
Now tell me how I should have
Prompted you such that you had gotten it right the first time. I just asked it
Tell me what the prompt should have been so that you would not have made this mistake
Now oftentimes it gives you advice. It's wrong
But nine times out of ten, maybe not nine times seven times out of ten
It works
Yeah, I wonder if there's a way to use chat gpt maybe because you can modify the prompt
Yeah, not in the commercial, but if you just like to open ai
Maybe you can work that into the prompt like you can actually
If you've worked on the back end of it, you know that you can
Change the prompt to make sure it does not give it does not
chat gpt as
It exists on the web for most people it will always give you an answer even if it doesn't know
So it could be confidently wrong, right? You can prompt it to not do that
If you don't know tell you don't know no, but that's changing the answer
But that you're exactly right though, right? It's essentially
So you talked about it's a parrot and i'm glad that that
I wonder if because I haven't played with this what I want to know is can I use that same prompt?
Can I use some prompt engineering on the sort of in the middle layer like you can do with?
Oh, you know if like azure openai can I muck with the prompt there give additional prompts?
That would have it
Great like rather than confidently give an answer to some math that it can't do
If it could reply back and say this isn't something i'm good at
Or I don't have a cop my or my confidence level on my answer
I don't know now. It's so in my but these are the these are the research tools
I want these fancy researchers wittaker speaks of to write
yeah, my
That for me that one would be a difficult one to do
Because and I love difficult because oh it's fine, but the the thing is
llm
Like I know all it is and I know you know this but i'm gonna remind everyone on in the audience, right?
All it does is it given a string of text?
It produces the next character
Right and then given that new string of text. What's the next character?
Repeat until bored. Okay, but I I realized what i'm doing is something I get mad at companies for doing all the time
remember when uh
One of the iphones like the seven or something it didn't work and steve job said it's because you're holding it wrong
Because the antenna was in a weird place, right? I remember that
So in a way, I am telling people they're holding their phone wrong. People are using chat gpt
They're getting asked. They don't like it's broken
And here I am saying it's because you're holding your phone wrong. You're doing it wrong
So what I want the tool to do if you're doing it wrong is to tell you you're doing it wrong because maybe that's easier
Than have every company having an ai coach to help them from stop being stupid
Maybe the tooling we need around this is the tooling that stops people from being
idiots
gpt
And now we're aboard. I just want to be super clear
Gpt will never ever ever ever ever do what you just want. However, that doesn't mean
That just means no one should be using gpt directly. It should be going through a different endpoint
Gpt is just a front end on top of a
Really really big llm. Yes, exactly aboard happiness
But I look at this and i'm like
Yeah
To me it it's the same thing if you are building
software or a solution that relies on llm
then
the the developers of it
They need to be thinking about
What is the quality of this solution? How will will it solve the problems?
It'd be interesting to bring
Nicole
Forsgren on and say
Hey, did the principles of your thing? Do you have any opinion?
To me, it seems like the very same principles that you're talking about for code
Would also apply to prompt engineering. I know you may or may not have studied that but what's your intuition?
I'd love to hear her answer to that
Because i'm just I have a question for you. Yeah
So we've been doing we've been doing a little book club on accelerate at work
Have you and we just did chapter three and four today and three is the one on culture
And talk about westerum's model, which is super cool
I wonder if
And you can talk we can both talk about this from a microsoft
I wonder if the advent of chat gpt is
Re-encouraging the hero mindset
Because somebody wants to go solve everyone's problem with the magic of gpt. I haven't seen that
I haven't seen that but there is something there is something very relevant that I have seen
in that timeline
okay, and that is the
the
proactive claim of duplication of effort in order to
Make sure everyone is aware that I have licked the cookie. This is mine
right in the the
Alan i'm concerned that you're duplicating my team's effort
Right. That's just a political ploy
Oh sure. Yeah
Particularly like i've been getting it a lot lately because I run a data science team that specializes in the nlp
And the other team that quote unquote is competing with me is a dev team
Right from a knowledge point of view. They're not going to beat my team
The only way they win is from a if it turns into an api problem, which
Right gpt is an api
But it's the quality output of it that matters. So here's my thought so, you know remember back in the day I work with
Folks on the microsoft research team on a lot of software engineering studies, but here's the study I want to see
It's almost too early to do it. It's way too hard for me to do but I want to find something around the
The effect of generative AI on organizational culture
Or organizational health either one of those i'll call it organizational health like how is chat we talk a lot because we're adjacent to it
About chat gpt helping programmers and helping make software
As you know when we've discussed chat gpt and generative AI isn't just for developers
That's some pretty good pluses for us and I talk about how I use it in writing and thinking through things
But what is that's the thing ai is for everyone gen ii is for everyone
What is the effect of that? What what is happening to organizations who embrace?
Gen ai who play with gen ai like what is happening there? Are they getting healthier?
Are they getting less healthy? There can't be no impact. Oh, there's gonna be impact
But I want I don't I actually don't have an opinion of what that's gonna be but it's worth measuring i'll i'll give you
I'll give you some thoughts. I have enough thoughts already
Here's a few more
Okay, i'll squeeze them in number one. Remember what I just said about systematics. Okay. Yes
The key thing is that the number of problems in the universe is constant
Okay, and when I talk about
This this law
I talk about like okay when email happened
Right when I remember I remember when email was invented
Why was it cool?
Because we could talk to our friends anywhere in the world
And not have to pay for stamps and not have to wait
For free, right?
As long as we paid our computer lab fee and
Then what negative what problem was constructed because we created email a couple problems, okay
One big one is you couldn't infer tone or or anything from the email
We also created spam emails
We also created and again, maybe it goes with the first one with we created internet anonymity where
You could be a dick to someone because you're more likely to be a dick to someone because you were you had never met them
You'd have a relationship with them. You're talking to people
You don't know as much now over email because it's free right and and actually even
even
More and some may view this as a positive or negative but even if you just talk of you know, limit it to friends and family
Right. What did you do?
You increase the friction or decrease the friction
For you know grandma to send you you know the chain letter that will save
Even allies would still will send you crap now
right
My uncle I have an uncle that every time his pc dies
And you've encountered this i'm sure
Right. Oh call brent. He works for microsoft. He can be your oh god. Yes
Well before email there's no way he would ever have like sent me a letter asking me for that right?
Automation
reduces friction
It doesn't just reduce friction on the bad things it reduces friction
So the good things become a lot easier to do but the bad things do too
like junk junk mail spam the ability at scale for
the nigerian prince to
Ask you for help, right? Yep
The same thing's gonna happen here and the intellectual lazy are gonna get caught by it
They're gonna get creamed one of the issues is
Okay, so ai can at scale
review let's say
Bug reports, right?
AI can at scale review it
But now you have to review what it reviewed
Right. How do you how do you know?
Because you know enough that it's a generative AI
How do you how do you know it's doing the right thing?
And here's the well, isn't that similar to who tests the tests?
Yeah
Except when it's who tests the tests
Uh in the past it's been a human being that you can kind of go. All right. Well
Karma will eventually hit the tester who wrote a billion bogus test cases
Right. No, I I get what you're saying
AI is skynet happens when we begin trusting the AI for everything
Well, yeah, and if we if we are about to get even more flooded with AI generated content
Right. It's that flood that's going to lead to trust because I just don't have the time to read it. Otherwise
100 million percent. Yep. All right. We should we should cut it there. Yep
That was actually a fun conversation. I got a little bit more passionate about it than I thought I would so super exciting
Thank you. James Whitaker for your contributions today
What was it 197 197? All right. We'll see you next time. I'm Alan. I'm brain
order of law
I'll peter say