Welcome to AV testing podcast your modern testing podcast your hosts Alan and
Brent will be here to guide you through topics on testing leadership agile and
anything else that comes to mind now on with the show hey Brent yeah how's it
going what's up man that's a hard question just chillin just chillin hey
so I want to apologize in front of all of our fans we don't have any fans the
people that somehow listen to us while they're cleaning their toilets we skipped
a week because I was out hiking last weekend and I forgot to let Brent know
so sorry about that no we're gonna pick it up here gonna go out again next
weekend I did a little trip I was gonna do like 75 miles through the cascades
but my water filter broke and it was hot and there weren't enough people for
me to mooch water off of so I ended up bailing about halfway through probably
the right choice still kind of bum but I will get out and do it again but you
know so the trip we did you respond to my texts while you were out in the middle
of nowhere no I was I was actually on my way back from being being extracted I
left on Wednesday but Friday afternoon I said you know what the smart thing to
do the responsible thing to do is for me to get myself out of the danger
zone so I did yeah and that's we did that so Brent's got a fancy new
microphone yes and so we're hoping came with so let us let us know in the copious
amounts of fan mail we get what you all think of that and here we are again yeah
I'm wearing a little Japanese motorcycle shirt and Brent's wearing a better shirt
a mighty Thor says the mighty dad but it's Thor and I'm not Thor not Liam
heans were Hemsworth Thor Thor for like the old comic book and now he's
awkwardly rubbing his chest I'm not really into it anymore it's impressive
that you could tell immediately that it was Thor and not you know because most
look at you go wow how narcissist are you because it's you on your yeah an
image of my double game yeah I'm like no it's actually Thor yeah well all right
well anyway that's going on Wow
the heat it was hot it was hot and the hot was really bad this week I've been
working this is the first time I've worked in my office like in a while
because I've been working downstairs because downstairs is about 10 degrees
cooler but it's fine it's comfortable in here it's yeah but it's such minors all
winter long right it's cold it's wet it's rainy and then oh it's hot your
your your background is different today I just now know that cuz I'm still in my
I'm still in my office I'm sitting I have a avenue poster I got a poster of
the Pacific Crest Trail yeah I was like California on that I mean that's yeah
as California Oregon and Washington yeah so yeah okay I got a couple topics today
but anything else is super exciting you want to share but if I said super exciting
like three times now I'm kind of freaking myself out what do you got I
didn't know that I was supposed to become no nothing exciting all right okay
boring AF since the last time the I have a larger topic but I found the
new topic to talk about I kind of need to bounce off of you there was an article
just came out in August type pickers today about open AI and their plans to
build Skynet as you know about this so you we've talked on the podcast before
about AGI's and how we're perhaps slightly excited and slightly afraid of
this phenomenon happening there's this Bloomberg list of the open AI's five
stages of artificial intelligence which are chatbots which we have today
those are nice those are fun nice little partners talked about them level two are
reasoners human level solving problem solving which they equate to a doctorate
level person without all the tools to go get access to just like a doctorate level
smartness for reasoning level three are agents and systems that can take
actions level four our innovators AI that can aid an invention and level
five our organizations AI that can do the work of an organization aka Skynet so
what they're saying is reports say that they have level two kind of on the edge
of existing oh it's gonna it's gonna snowball from there that's that's both
the exciting and the scary part how do you feel about that oh I I despise it
immensely what do we what's what's the the ethical action we should all take
as this quest towards pure AI despite everything we've seen in the movies
continues I don't know what we can take like the only thing we can do anything I
can think of like the EU is doing regulation on this one right it and that
is something that needs to be solved well before it flips over to that bar you
mentioned on level two yeah right so level one is what AI a chatbots okay
level two are the human problem solvers the doctorate level people and then it
goes to level three agents and systems that can take actions for our AI that
can aid an invention and five is AI that can do the work of an organization okay so
when I look at these these levels I'm trying to sort of take my knowledge and
kind of reverse engineer like each of the faces because I've given these
stories and like I don't know if I mentioned that on podcast I recently went
to my daughter's middle school and and talked about AI and the stuff and the
way I talk about AI in particular is it's it's essentially it memorized it has it
has things memorized right it can learn it but it memorizes it doesn't know
anything LLM right can pass the Turing test but it doesn't know anything when I
look at and that's kind of what they're saying level one is right except it
right level one in this case is doesn't know anything but passes the
Turing test like you can't tell the difference that's sort of kind of
right level two means a basic problem-solving ability that would be
comparable to a PhD level I look at that and I go okay are they gonna further when
problem-solving is a very generic term right it doesn't necessarily mean math it
means sort of the ability to apply tools and part of me goes okay that's kind of
my definition of a of an AGI right there but it could still be just
memorization right it it's more right you can see if you know how all of them
work today you can kind of see the evolution here right what I'm worried
about is one ethically the crap that can happen I'm worried about the power
the compute power required for these different levels of things until these
things start inventing like we need the the AI is to begin to invent faster
computing so they can actually run and when they do they get scarier but level
on a level three right that just means it's memorized you right
person personalization right the the practical point I want to get to I'm
curious on your opinion on in this and don't worry listeners not spending the
whole podcast on this we're gonna make a 180 here in a moment or maybe a was
three 540 we're gonna spin all the way around get a little dizzy and come back
practically people are spending millions and probably billions of dollars
across the software industry investing in air quote AI solutions to solve their
problems do a lot of those problems become obsolete or easier to solve or
solve in completely better ways once you graduate from one level to another
every single time you know the problems become different like if we look at like
when I look at their levels and I'm reading your article and it says open
AI has previously defined AGI is a highly adamant system that can outperform
humans on a majority of economically valuable tasks like I don't know that
the economically valuable task thing is important but I look at their levels
and what they define as level five I mean that's that that to me is well
beyond AGI that is nearing ASI um which so there's AGI ASI we're all gonna die
that the right order yeah if an ASI exists we don't know if we're all gonna
die but the way I simplify right an AI is a parrot an AGI is kind of like a human
and an ASI is God okay and we're all gonna die well if God is benign no we
won't God's a computer powered by Nvidia well more than one computer and
certainly more than one Nvidia chip yeah it's all a computer the yeah this is
level four these the system can create new innovations right that definitely is
AGI in my definition but if they make because the the one thing that humans can
do they quote-unquote the AI's can't is create right until they can right and
yeah if I I look at this and quite honestly I'll just look you straight in
the eyes and say thank God the two like these are this is a phrase I rarely say
right but in this case thank God the two of us are old as fuck because so we
can let the ASI's rule over our children well no no I mean we still have to do
something about that but should we fail right yeah the like can outperform the
work of entire organizations right the the competitive environment the world
competitive environment the even within the United States right yeah the number
one cost to any business is payroll and that'll change the number one cost will
be compute right it'll be compute but here is the weird thing because a lot of
people we don't have a self-perpetuating engine right the AI that
they're talking about here like why do we even need CEOs with with this type of AI
oh we don't need CEOs okay we don't need we don't honestly look we don't need CEOs
with chat GPT chat GPT is not the great greatest I'm being I'm being slightly
facetious sure sure but I look at this and I go okay so with an AGI people will
be able to perform the work of entirely of entire in organizations like all white
color work in that world is is automated why not right it's it's automated and
then that level four they can create new innovations okay because because the
other thing is okay well something has to tell it what to automate well no no it
can do that itself it can but you can think let's look at the adjacent possible
here let's not spend too much time on this but if you look I mean where humans
can really help out is figuring out there's some judgment we can put into
looking at the data sources and and maybe some pattern matching but I'm
beginning to doubt because even LLMs are very good at pattern matching they're
very good if you if you look at you know let's pick a popular Microsoft
application that probably couldn't get any worse the Microsoft Office suite and
massive amounts of customer telemetry they know what the customer problems are
they know from the internet what works and what doesn't work well and what
features people want and what they what they enjoy they know everything about all
the users why couldn't a sufficiently advanced AI look at all that look at the
code base and figure out what the right improvements and bug fixes were to make
going forward to continually to continually evolve that and even add
more telemetry where it didn't exist to learn more the question why couldn't
Microsoft Office be a self a self-growing software suite it could but
here's the thing like if AI is doing all this who's it doing it for the four
people that use Microsoft Office the the testers the four testers you know
downstream from the AI no I don't know I mean but like why if AI takes over the
world of what color work like I don't need Excel anymore I'm not looking at
it what's the point of me building a spreadsheet well the consumer then is of
course other AI's right but why would they go through office suite right they
would they would build up a rich microservice framework that that we would
like now I'm gonna go down the path of friggin Skynet that's where we're going
that's exactly where I'm leading you yeah Skynet and so the only other thing is
right um self-perpetuation right it still doesn't have sentience but with
with a general intelligence like it's gonna pass all it's gonna pass all of
our tests of sentience that we've ever developed and then I will ask you you
and I have both worked in tech for a very long time I have known people who
would not pass sentience tests Brent almost lost coffee but it's true
squirted out coffee on my brand new mic because what because when I said that
you visualize people you've worked with well I did but but then I realized no
they had sentience they were just socially inept the so much so that you
could not tell them apart from a non-human that's my point all right so
yeah I don't know I don't know how we stop this because here's the thing about
human condition number one they will absolutely be highly intelligent bad
people getting access to this and doing harm of course right number two
universally on all of these type of technologies the following phrase is
true the road to hell is paved with good intentions right also true right we go
oh it can create new innovations hey we finally have a system and his PhD level
we finally have a system that can cop cure cancer you know things bipolar
things that haven't been curable before it will be able to do that because it
can it will be able to look over the data rapidly iterate design appropriate
experiments right yay cancer right but if it has the ability to do that then in
the hands of hacker it's gonna have the ability to do the opposite hey let's
just kill everybody in Washington DC well well now now we got flagged nice work
but yeah I think it's very again going back to Skynet why isn't the path that
decides that humans are inefficient they should get out of the way well so the
thing that we can't guess here is what it's good what's gonna be its goal right
the only thing that the only thing in my mind when they talk about level five
right so literally level five again is it's an AI system so the way it's
worded level five involves the step to achieve a GI an AI system that can
perform the work of an entire organization to me that's just nothing
more than one you know a bunch of a eyes working together towards a common
goal like it's around okay we've created these AI's that can replace a human now
let's scale it okay that's not in my mind quite the same thing as an AGI
although AG an AG or sorry it's past AGI AGI means like it it can rationalize to
the same level as a typical human however scaling it doesn't quite mean
it's an ASI yet right and the one key thing here is what's its incentive
what's its goal an ASI there have been papers already published on it it's well
known in research that if an ASI ever exists we will not be able to control it
so if it does exist what's gonna be its motivation you said okay you're gonna
find out the humans are inefficient right it will quote-unquote know that it as a
system only exists as a bunch of physical hardware that wears out now nicely
distributed across the world right um it will have to figure out a way to
assemble it like I guess the one linchpin that it will have is the
robotics have caught up by that yeah lots of things to think about Wow I want
to think about the opposite for a minute okay so here goes our is gonna be a 180
but a full spin ahead of the 180 so 540 see how to how to move to Alaska and
homestead maybe maybe maybe the maybe my all my hiking here by myself is
preparing for a life off the grid where I hide from these things but I we talk a
lot here about the knowledge worker and how the knowledge worker is different
from the the factory worker from the past and think talks about them in a whole new
world but the determine around a lot longer one of the things we've talked
about and I talked about a lot in my blog post with my team is the human
aspect of leadership and teams and and how you have to create engagement by
making sure people understand why their job is important and giving them
feedback and making sure you know you care about them those are the top three
contributors to engagement in the workplace we know from studies that work
that engagement contributes to better software products quality etc so what I
I'm curious about I have some other questions on this is what do you think
AI means to the like as these things come in and begin to do and again
people worry they can do jobs for this and I think for the short term even
with level two we're still controlling these things how do we keep track how do
we continue to focus on the human aspect of of team management and software
delivery and just not teams of knowledge workers while basically while
the computers are taken over or does it matter do it do we do we give up on
that the human aspect is absolutely critical to me from from an ethics
standpoint right to me this the closest analogy to me is the nuclear bomb right
um I was watching a YouTube thing the other day and right now on how to make
a nuclear bomb no good because that that would get flagged as well um no the
we were talking about so right now the United States has something like 4,800
nukes and because in this is down from like an incredible high where at some
point in time like back in the 80s we had things in the high five digits nukes
and so we're dramatically lowered from that but you know what it as we've seen
with from from the fallout series right it doesn't take a lot of it doesn't take
nearly many of those to just completely destroy the yeah why do you need 4,800
when 12 is plenty well in case you know six of them miss sir sorry and so now
the thing that happened though historically do you do you know what
really drove the the god damn it what really drove the the ramp down of
military might what was it a large number of historians and this is one that I kind
of tend to agree with like some will say it was garbage off and Reagan and you
know I was gonna say that I thought maybe I figured it was wrong it's wrong
what really drove it was the movie the day after what yeah tell me so the day
after went global and it freaked everybody out did you see that movie I
remember it which one was that there was a lot of those end-of-the-world type
movies in the in like the early 20 yachts 2010s which one was that the
thing got icy no this was sorry for the clicking came out 1983 is this the one
where they the US and the end of the movie spoiler alert they end up blowing
up New York themselves as a like as a thing I don't inception okay oh because
I read that book a long time ago I thought it was before well before 83 but
it could be the same thing is but it's like an accidental nuclear strike no oh
then I don't know no no no this this ends up being a full-on nuclear exchange
between us and Russia but the thing that that it's called the day after and I
picked the wrong window because we're seeing infinity yeah AB AB testing
inception yeah so as you can see here I'm looking at the day after on
Wikipedia for the listeners right the thing that this did is it had massive
effects on policymakers both here and in Russia because what it showed was a
view of what human life was the day after okay and okay I never did see this I did
I did it came out 1983 I was 13 and there are two movies that I remember when
they came out I couldn't sleep for weeks this was this was one of them and the
other one as as you know I was born and raised in California the other one was
called the big one talking about the the earthquake that that is due to hit
California someday and basically destroy more than half of it just as a quick
check in here remind me how we got here from the human aspect of software
delivery the human aspect of software development so the human side of this is
going to be forgotten if the humans itself don't step up okay the up until
the when the big one came out or the day after sorry came out people are like
yeah nukes they got nukes everyone's got nukes and then they went around their
lives okay it wasn't until something like this came out and showed everyone a
realistic view not a science fiction thing like we talked about Skynet we
could also talk about the matrix like both of those are science fiction both
of those are fantasy both of those might be nearing possible but because it
everyone's used to it from science fiction they're not afraid of it when
this one came out people were like holy crap that would suck we need to do
something to curtail it right because the road the hell is paid with good
intentions and because it's going to be super clear both from a government
standpoint as well from a corporate standpoint that those who get on this
level 5 AI system is going to have a critical competitive advantage right that
compete it's gonna like oh no we got to do this or else we're dead right so that
is I like there's going to be data scientists like me not me but like me
going no we got to help corporate you know our company get onto this because
if we don't this other company who is working on it is gonna win the market and
they will destroy us like the first thing that will probably happen is this will
be a monopoly creator yeah it's like the first one to the AGI wins because it
would you be able to crush your competition it could react to your
competition faster than human good for sure for sure um and it could probably
negotiate because the functions at the acts of organizations perhaps it
could even negotiate a merger right and unless there is a an AI owned by the
government that's going to be able to take the place of the Supreme Court
right like the the world will be over before it's even begun to go through
say our current laws on monopolistic behavior so the going back to the
knowledge worker and and pink's book famously talks about the feature of the
future is going to be paved by these right-brain creative thinkers as we move
away from the widget makers in the factory and have this more creative
people leading our way towards the future does that change it with with the
advances in AI's do tech workers eventually shift to being more of the
factory workers are we going to so I just thought of this now but do if if
the compute is doing the heavy lifting on creating and inventing and figuring
out the future then is software development essentially factory work
potentially that's that's an interesting swing and then I wonder what the swing is
and then like what are the things like I was thinking the other day watching
watching yet another YouTube thing we spoke about this just a little while
ago open AI can generate STL files okay sure for 3d printing okay it's not great
but it can it can generate it could create physical objects absolutely yeah I
could see that now you know taking it off of the base plate I don't know how AI
does that like sure you can generate and print it but but but but that's
essentially factory workers it's not right it's it's it's not creative work
taking it off the plate and putting it into its application right we would be
like as we said before until robotics kicks in even stronger than it is now
and some of the some of the robotics stuff I've seen is it's not that far
away yeah we're just we'll be manual humans will be there in order to move
things from point a to point B yeah and and or maybe not that's that's robots on
my point before was maybe maybe what we're doing today which is largely
creative work eventually becomes factory work because the computer is doing the
heavy lifting but I think something else will emerge that rate that that
requires that creative thinking hopefully humans will still be needed to
cook although you can 3d print food wait a quick story about 3d printing we
have as you know old house and we have an old lock and on the front door and
it's really nice big brass thing didn't want to replace it with the of course we
hate carrying keys around because live in the 21st century and why would you but
we didn't want to replace it with like a keypad entry because it wouldn't fit the
the the jive of the door so anyway you need a thing called level lock it just
replaces the deadbolt it's a Bluetooth it's super handy except we put it in
our door it was too big it fit in but you couldn't get the mechanism back on so it
turns out there's a thing called a lock collar you can buy a little piece of
round metal for $50 from Amazon it's ridiculous or or you can 3d print one
in about 15 minutes and that was super handy and so now we have a 3d you can't
even tell because we printed it in black and it's kind of a brass black brass on
the door and yeah there's a little there's a little little collar on there
and we got a little little level lock to work so three prints are great got to
use some creative stuff I didn't my wife didn't she's better with those things
than I am but yeah I wonder I think for my I mean like you said before we're
old I don't have none of this stuff is gonna happen before I go off and live
in the old folks home but someday you know software engineering is it's gonna
be it's gonna be factory work it's gonna be just you know plugging in data into
the computers and letting them do letting them do the fun stuff well so I
would foresee sort of two industries like I remember way back in the day Bill Gates
wrote it wrote a book on this topic right and he predicted that
essentially entertainment is going to be the only work yeah and if you count
food as entertainment I'm all in I would love to I would love to get on
that problem is I would do it today it doesn't pay as well as unless you're real
unless you're in the elite elite it just doesn't pay as well as as software
you know I used to say that when I retired from from Microsoft I would go
to culinary school and I don't care what age I don't know as I get older
I'm just like yeah maybe I you know just find a small place off the grid in
Bali and yes yes former software engineers of Bali unite right the it's
like the the thing I think about is what keeps the economy going right the other
thing I could see of in terms of factory work is yeah humans band up and start
startup munitions work again right because I remember so one of the things I
when I was talking about with the middle school kids the AI AGI ASI they're like
they were puzzled they're like old guy why are you afraid of ASI right we can
just turn it off and I'm like oh no I hope there's not too many kids who have
that belief like oh yeah right we just keep taking advantage of it until it
gets overboard and then we just turn it off that that tells me you didn't
explain it well enough oh yeah it was told it made it very clear to me at that
point in time I'm like okay somebody just missed something this was this was
so I did the same presentation the sixth seventh and eighth graders the sixth
graders this that's where this question came from the eighth graders were
appropriately scared they're like what there we go what um yeah I don't know
what what happens between just those you know two years but um yeah there's no
just turning it off now it it will have to like there is physical labor necessary
electricity is necessary like there's costs but like a lot of like who who are
these organizations selling to if the human race if white-collar work is
eliminated who's buying the products and services right and so there's there is
there is that that loop that I'm worried about and quite honestly I think
something like this if it's not curtailed right it's it's gonna result in a
dramatic reduction in the populace yeah and systems thinking is a good skill to
have here to understand how all the pieces fit together but you know what's
really good at systems thinking and understanding how all the pieces of it
together of AGI yeah yeah but again and again the oh I got I got the answer you
asked the he told the AGI list all the bad things that could happen what you're
about to do that instruct it not to do any of them done in a way that doesn't do
and I know I've talked about about the genie in a way that doesn't invoke the
genie in a negative way like I want to be a world-class swimmer boom you're a
shark right I don't need the AI equivalent of that metaphor right um yeah
but there's also have you ever read as a moth many many years ago okay right the
again with the theme Road to Hell good intentions thing right the as a mobs laws
of robotics you take each one and you you program them straight into the AI make
them key but because humans are flawed they don't each one on itself looks fine
but when you combine them together right the only way to protect the spoiler for
those who haven't read as moth right the only way to protect the human race
the only way to fulfill all three laws is to completely remove all freedoms from
the human race because they have to be controlled in order to honor the three
laws right and the thing in my mind the one key thing that was a flaw in the
laws because the laws basically say what it can't allow the harm if the
laws have been potentially I'm gonna do this as my own thought experiment
avoiding harm doesn't mean happiness and the three laws are all about the robots
are to prevent harm to themselves or to others and it is a priority order what
would be better I think is a laws around pursuit and so if the first law basically
said you need to better humanity of course we could brainstorm this because
then then bettering humanity right gets eerily close to means just to find the
ends type of shit yes right and and Adolf Hitler type of shit and so yeah we would
need an ASI to work through that particular problem and get get through all
the kinks but why would it because what's its motivation I don't I don't
know yeah thanks for that you're welcome man and I hope our listeners aren't too
freaked out but or mad or whatever but you get what you get on the AI testing
podcast well we are here to kind of inform people yeah and you know would be
cool right things like this but I look at this and I go you know what traditional
testing topics is not gonna friggin matter in this world oh my god no it's not but
no it's not yet yeah somebody on linkedin some tester on linkedin will be mad
because AGI won't alphabetize a list for them I'll say nah it's nothing so um
but we are right we do want to give people things to think about we do want
to describe what we're seeing and where we think we're going we're not inventing
anything as usual as we've never been done but we want to get people thinking
about things that maybe they haven't thought about before so hopefully we've
done that the cool thing is this is actually not Alan and Brent this
entire podcast has been generated via AI prove me wrong it's not gonna be able to
all right well I did no I did put a picture of us I posted a screenshot into
our slack one of the three dot slack calm you can get invitation there by going
to modern testing org and yeah you can come in join the conversation always
good stuff going on there lots of people way better than us both as humans and
in testing and in leadership and in software posting their thoughts there
we're just kind of there as honorary guests so it's a great place to hang out
should you want to have a place to communicate can we do a live stream yeah
we get one of the last no I'm like a full AI generated livestream what not not
with the current technology as you know the video generation isn't as good as
something with but you know you already know our voices can oh yeah that's easy
and you know the internet knows our topics so it could be possible you have
to like avatars in place of our video other than that we don't need to be here
already at today's level of AI we don't need to do this live as people we do it
because we're old people and this is actually this is easier for now for now
for now it's easier damn it I wonder how many uses of my new microphone I'm
gonna get not very many yeah and I'd also like to think our guest today Brent's
cat you might have heard him in the background in the background I did I did
that again yeah so she does yell her opinion out once in a while which is nice
and yeah I think that's it any final words Brent nope all right I'm I'm I'm
nope number one he's nope number two and we'll see you next time on our AI
testing podcast