Thank you. It is a little my daughter
Welcome to a be testing podcast your modern testing podcast
Your hosts Alan and Brent will be here to guide you through topics on testing
Leadership agile and anything else that comes to mind now on with the show
Could we be?
any more
Pathetic old men is it possible? Are we the most pathetic old men that exist on the internet?
No
Yeah, there's something we can strive for for sure
So as many of our readers know I gave up on grooming part way into the pandemic and grew my hair super long
And and my beard super long. I have since recently
partially
Groomed to myself. I have a beard looks
Defuzzed
It's shorter than Brent's but one thing I didn't realize still Brent was looking at his cat is that
We both are holding on like I I couldn't cut all my hair off
I can still do the little man bun ponytail thing and Brent has one too
And I realized looking at his how much I need to cut more of my hair off because I realized
How bad I must look no you look great actually
like thank you, but you don't have
You don't have the little hair island up here that looks stupid
More out so that the whole damn thing
Like now I have a little
You're not the target demographic. I'm trying to make my hair look good for it before just you know
Oh, just so you know sure you know
Just just know now you got the whole sexy salt and pepper look going on. That's that's that's that's what my t-shirt says
We are back for episode this is 212 I believe that's on right to you
Sure, right 212 212 is an even number not a prime number to even number
Also the area code of Manhattan in New York City. That's a fun fact. I didn't also also a palindrome to undo
Many good things. I can't think anything else about about 212, but that's that's up to five
All right, and that's the end of our podcast today. Thanks everyone for listening
How's it going? What's new tell me something exciting about what's happening in your world?
Uh, well, it's been a while like we haven't talked the election at all. Oh
Wait, there was an election I missed out. I
Understand why you might be repressing it
I mean, I'm embarrassed but anyway go on
I'm embarrassed
you know
49% of the people who voted voted for a
Convicted rapist and felon and all-around fraud
Not good human being that's who we are as a country. I'm embarrassed
Okay, so I've said on the podcast before I I did not like
Biden or Trump
Kamala the we haven't talked about her at all and that is actually part of the reason why
She lost I don't think Trump won. I think she lost
I think I I call that correct. I am mad at the Democrats
They did not call out the misinformation around the border of the economy, etc. Etc. They thought they could just yeah
They didn't wait again their strategy and we can just simplify it because we're not a political podcast
Not their strategy was a complete and total utter clusterfuck. Yes
Yeah, yeah, and we will deeply pay the price for that
That's where we're at. So anyway other than that moving on from the election. What else has been going on?
We had a huge storm here in Seattle
Area we did we had a bomb cycle and did you have power you're on the east side you have power
Yeah, no, I live in
neck of the woods that
all of our wires are are underground so
We do get power outages, but the tree has to fall directly on the transformer like the probability
So yeah, we've been fine. Yeah ours flickered a few times. We have been solid
We have a couple more storms coming in over the weekend. So good times. Yeah, there's supposed to be something today
Yeah, so anyway, I've been traveling a lot. I was in New York last week
I was home for about a week in between I was in Montana taking care of
Just
Family stuff before that I was in New York for 10 days again before that it's been a lot you have family stuff related to Montana
I didn't know this. Yeah. Yeah
Okay
So I haven't been moving on I haven't been home much. It's good to be home
And I kind of just trying to catch up on shit. Yeah
So anyway, yeah, I never let you answer your question. What else is new?
What's new other than the power outage that you didn't have storm bomb cyclone?
You missed the whole connect season. We talked about remember last time we talked about
The the how performance reviews are done horribly like 99% of the company has talked about how I try and come back
Episode 211 that's one back in your history. You can hear a lot more about that
there is
Something sort of new popping up at Microsoft that I think is an interesting
topic
Maybe I'll throw it out. How about that? Can you tell me? All right. I'm ready the
Nothing could surprise me. No, so it goes back to
to AI again
However, you remember remember way back
MS. Poll I do remember MS. Poll
And the engagement survey and this poll is gone. It's replaced by a new system a new engagement survey. Okay. Yep
and
one of the current questions is
I
know how
It's I'm screwed it up and I know how to use AI and my day-to-day life
Oh interesting. I bet that number is pretty low. It is certainly
Well in my organization, it's not shock
But
Overall, it's it's it's generally viewed as lower than
Than people would like I'm not certain I've not had any conversations with him. Like what's the right number?
But I do think it's interesting that that showed up
Well kudos to the HR team for adding that question
Right. Yeah, why?
Because I agree but why because it's not normally they're focused on engagement and how they look on the Gallup polls blah blah blah
Here's a actual question you can ask you kind of know the answer
But you want to confirm it because you can do something about it. You can actually do something
This is common. I would bet every company that asked this whether you're Microsoft or you know
Walmart
Nobody answers that question as positive
No group of employees answered that question as positively as you'd like because you and I know there are many
advantages to productivity to efficiency to decision-making that can happen if you use AI effectively and
It's just it's just good data to have to point out that we're not taking advantage of what's there and I'm going the whole
Gen AI isn't really AI but whatever it's helpful no matter what and I don't think most people
Know how to make it helpful
Yeah, yeah, no, I think number one
The fact that they are asking that question
Right. What does it do? It asks that question every manager in the company gets a score against that question and
Then they immediately take action like this is this is
just
a fantastic way to motivate a behavior change in a direction and just
like ridiculously
Yes. Yes, but also because there you can correlate that question against things like
I have ample time to learn new topics helping with my job
So I imagine that's low that could be low too or maybe it isn't and it's high but they're spending their time learning other things
There are other questions in engagements
It's like the whole advantage these things is not the way people sorry on soapbox
The way people screw up surveys is they just treat every question individually. You have to do analysis to find
Correlations and find out to helps answer questions on why things are the way they are and once you do that with that question
You're gonna find some interesting insights
Yeah, unfortunately, I mean you can and if you're if you're the team doing
Analysis that has everything in the clear. You probably can do a lot more. Obviously. I only have
my team scores and
only in aggregation and without commentary
So I just look at him go neat vanity number. I have to get for me that sucks
I don't I don't know who runs HR at Microsoft anymore. It's a revolving door there. That's fine
It's probably somebody better given you know, it's probably somebody good
That's not the point. The point is I would be willing to bet you know
I pick on Microsoft a lot, but I'd be willing to bet that a company like Microsoft are
Taking a data analysis approach to the survey stuff and looking for correlations and trying to find not just oh
Let's give people some AI training. They're gonna find some
behavioral things and management and team structure that are going to help influence that I
will
Join you in your optimism. I
Like in my little neck of the woods like I run a data science team. Yeah, that's what we do
But again, the debt is not sufficient. I have no visibility to
to
Matter of fact other teams have come in and said hey, can you data science our scores?
Data science your scores. I kind of believe they'd say that
Some do
Some do that the the ones I like working with do
the
Right gives a figure they go. Okay, I don't I don't have the skill the thing
I wanted to drive with this that I think is potentially interesting because this one question
has
like I as I mentioned has
encouraged a behavior amongst in particular Dev and PM and
and the Dev and PM managers are
basically going
late
WTF what the hell am I supposed to do here? Right and and
Meaning even those managers don't have enough understanding of
of AI and
There's now it just event
Carefully because I love my company and that is honest. That's me just saying it but
There is a
There are two things that one thing that's bad
That's happened here is is there's a lot of discussions I'm having with people. Oh
And I call it AI and magic same thing
And then the another discussion is AI and LLM same thing and as we both know
These are both false
But that's how they are approaching it with me and so I go, okay, how do I engage here? How do I help them?
move forward like p.m.
Hit me this week and I spent a lot of time with death because that's easier for me to understand
I'm like look look at any place in your architecture where you need to automate decision-making where your devs have made up numbers
Like if made up number equals another made up number then do thing
Timeouts as a very simple example
PM is a new one and they're like, well, what am I supposed to do here? I don't like well two things
that were very obvious to me is
Look at the part of the job that's that's
tiresome and
See if if AI can can help you like I find good success in terms of I don't like
using LLM
to write my slide decks
But I do like it in terms of writing
the the outline of the deck
Do you have you used LLM to do death work? I have it doesn't mean it hasn't been great
But it's been helped this bit. It's again. It's a collaboration partner. It gives me some ideas and I go well that sucks
But I can build on that say something. Hello. Oh you sound maybe
Welcome back Brent to the AB testing podcast
Thank you 12 even number
Blah blah blah question on the engagement survey, although it has a different name on on
Using AI appropriately people come to you to talk about whether AI is magic or
Whether LLMs and AI are the same thing. I think pretty common across the industry. I hear those same problems all the time
where I am, so
Do you remember where you were on that journey or should I just take off in a different direction?
You can go wherever you want. No
Fully agree and we've talked about it a lot the fact that people don't know how to use AI effectively
They don't know how to use and it's it's fine. They're going to learn it. I
Think there's extremes where they think it's like we get the folks on LinkedIn saying oh, it can't count ours in strawberry
It's stupid, but you're an idiot because it actually is very powerful to help and I think
Blah blah blah so if I said before I want to talk about you're gonna get
back in the AI stuff, but
one thing
No company as a collective has ever done really well that I've worked out in 30 years is actually
Do I've never seen a company do the right things with those engagement service?
It's almost like they do them. Okay. We have to do an engagement survey. It'll tell us whatever
but
It's actually used right. It's a really powerful tool. I know Microsoft used to do like let's do a morale event
Let's all go to a movie or a bowling the day before we fill the survey out to make people feel a little bit better
Absolutely idiotic and stupid
there is a little bit of a day of a snapshot of the day that comes into fact comes into play with those surveys, but
I think I'm taking this different direction because actually something I've thought about a lot and I went to a
leadership session when I was in New York last week and I was talking to the guy that runs it I think my
retirement job may be to run
Like leadership programs or talent and leadership things like that's I think I'm at some point
I'm gonna get out of software completely because it's killing me and I'm gonna do something to help people become better leaders
So anyway, a lot of folks look at their survey results and they'll either pat themselves on the back or not
They'll look at the low stuff
Often what happens you look at like what sucked you? Are you?
Okay sharing what what like sucked in your your team on your thing
You can
Holy crap, did you know this is going
You know one thing about record we need to cover recording studio so don't have all this bullshit, okay
Dropped your tablet and blah blah blah and slightly crippled. Okay fair enough fair enough
This is gonna show up on my podcast
Alan does things like that. All right, let's see what happens here. Okay. Now. Anyway, we're we were you're told
Oh my god, where the hell were we what sucked on your engagement survey?
Super you for you on mine
One of them that I remember is
Compensation, okay, and what can you Brent personally do about that?
Jack all you can't do anything. No, that's false. Oh, tell me okay
I was I was actually hoping you'd agree with me so I could disagree with you. Tell me more. Oh
Sorry. Yeah, you're right. What am I gonna do? I'm not
Authority on that
No, actually, I'm one of the rare people at Microsoft that believe that if you if you approach it the right way
Every one of these things the frontline manager can take action
Yes, right
So there's and that gets into two big mistakes people make in looking at their engagement survey results one is
They look at things that are negative and say I can't do anything about that employees see they need more comp
They need more money. Sorry the same thing with any more education whatever employees go. Well, it's not my job
I can't do that which is a big chunk of BS. You can affect that go back to Dan pink
maybe it's not money maybe it's autonomy and purpose and mastery or
Maybe there are things you can do about money. You can make a difference there
Other thing is no and actually even further and again, it's Dan pink. But the other thing further
Yeah, I I have my scores up my lowest is
I have a good deal at my company
right, that's the lowest one and
and
There's a reasonable balance between what I contribute and what I get in return
That one most managers will interpret it as money
But that's not what it says. It says I have a good deal
Yep
right and
People go after as Dan pink points out
people go after
money
as
the plan not even be but
CDef
Right people are more engaged
By by being in the environment where they're energized by it. They feel like they have a purpose
They have some sort of autonomy
right
those
matter far
more
Than the money once the money is at
a
basic level right
Right, that's for the majority people there's there's always the others who are like comparing themselves to their cousins or you know things like that
right
um
So okay, so you're absolutely right. So the mistakes people make is
They either throw stuff away say I can't do anything about that
Or they only focus on the low thing say a low thing
Say okay, I say give people more money more money and that it'll be great
You also have to focus on like what's your highest thing?
What are you best? What is your what is your team say as far as engagement goes your best at manager respect?
okay, so
Um, what's gonna happen if you focus on getting people more money?
But you sacrifice manager respect
You're gonna play engagement survey whack-a-mole the the the the point is that's a bad example
That would be hard. But but yeah, you're right if you focus
If you don't focus on the whole system
Exactly, and that is the mistake people make they don't focus on the whole system
So again in my in my future job where i'm doing this full time
I would make sure every leader of a certain size team has a coach to help them
Evaluate what it means help them figure out the actual behaviors. They are doing that they should continue and behaviors
They could be doing to help improve things
You're not trying to
Play whack-a-mole with the small things and ignore the things the low things and ignore the things you're doing well at
You have to figure out what you can adjust in the system to make these numbers are a rough reflection
Of how the org feels about coming to work for you
So you have to attack it as a system and you have to look at
It's a reflection everything happening at once so you understand
Uh what you what behaviors need to change? There's no leader out there who's perfect every single one including myself including you
Can do some things better?
We can do some things better that help our teams focus on their work and be more productive
And I think a lot of managers are just freaking lazy and don't bother
That pisses me off lazy managers piss me off lazy leaders piss me off
There's a lot of these assets when I think about
right the new system
like they have
There's a lot
That they can do
to make it more actionable
Like even someone like me like I have spent an hour trying to reverse and successfully reverse engineer how they
How all the data flows?
Because I was trying to figure out how to drive action with this
um
They've dumped it down to a point where i'm like, yeah, I wouldn't be surprised if so many people
Okay, what if?
Can I walk you through a thought exercise?
Yeah
Okay
We have the engagement service those can be different every company you can add questions like the ai question is great
What if there was a separate survey for leaders you can say people managers or or people at a certain level?
I would say people at a certain certain size organization
That asked you maybe even in free form text about behaviors that you employ as a leader
things like I make I focus on making sure every person on my team gets feedback at least once a week or
What form or short answer what forms of feedback do you get?
Um, how do you motivate your team or question? They can be they can be uh bullet points, you know multiple choice or they can be
um
Short answer so we're giving all the leaders of a say more than 20 people all these questions to kind capture their behaviors
now
Can I take the results? I haven't thought about this yet. Can I take the results of that?
Correlate them with the results of the survey
Put it into an llm and put a chat bot on it and ask it
Here are my survey scores. What are some things I can do to?
uh balance these numbers higher across my organization or whatever the question is because I should be able to see
I would think
uh those because behavior drives motivation and I would think from those behaviors from again at microsoft size from
Hundreds or a thousand other managers and and they're correlated with their
Engagement survey scores. I would hope I could find some common ground
It's a it's a kind of a cheap way to learn from each other on how to
How to treat those that survey like a system
Yes
I actually think
What what you inspired for me when you as you're talking through that?
um
is
strength finders
We we've talked about this and I this isn't a a tangent to go deep into strength fighters, but
if you read when you go take the strength finders test you you get a
A pamphlet
That talks about each of your strengths and it gives you a little paragraph. You you recall what i'm talking about. Yep. I do. Okay now
If you read that paragraph versus going to the strength finders book and reading the paragraph there
You'll notice that there's similarities
That that the theme is similar like uh, for example me one of my strengths was restorative
I go and read it in the book. It'll say a bunch of things and I go read it in my own
PDF and it's it's it's in the same ballpark, but it's different and that is because
Gallup has the ability
to
Because the strengths aren't independent they play off of each other
so my other strengths
pivot around how I use my restorative it's not the
Not the pure restorative that you would find in the the book, but it's one that's
Aligned by the other ones and for me, it would be absolutely that would be an llm tool worth
building
where it takes
As long as this was done in a absolute psychologically safe. Yeah environment because
What i'm about to propose
Could absolutely be used for evil
Right. It would be handy if I could go to a tool
Give it access to my email
Give it my scores and say
Hey
what are the
Here's an example question. What?
What are the
top five high roi proposals
You have for me
right
look at my patterns
because
If I try to take make a program out of each of these
It's going to be a challenge
and with
Uh, I think there's like 30 40 questions
and so trying to do
Me sitting down and building a system out of that
Is going to be very complex and time consuming
Well, let's go
And I have an ego so i'm gonna go right? Oh, no, this wasn't me
This was the top down bullshit thing that I had no choice over right?
I want to meta even more because
Why don't I there's a challenge with a lot of leaders is they
There's uh unconscious incompetence. They don't realize how much they don't know they don't know
Uh, most leaders i'm not one of them would say they don't need a coach or a mentor
Uh, and I think most leaders actually do I don't think most leaders are as good at doing their job as they think they are
So that's that's a problem. I can't necessarily solve however
Why doesn't ai just look at not just email but other communications I do
Even even to my meetings since most meetings for me at least are online and can be if they're not recorded can be analyzed
Why don't I get coaching tips weekly or daily on things?
I could do differently or like when I talk about feedback
I like to give continue feedback or improve feedback like you great
I like I like the way you listen while i'm talking and makes you feel like i'm listening to thanks for doing that
Please keep doing that. I don't have to think of a new thing you've done, but I want to reinforce the things you do well
and then
Uh and this ai can do this as well. Hey you you
In the it's the meeting you were able to get everyone in the meetings to talk and that was great
Keep doing that. I want the ai to tell me that the ai can be changed can be trained on not just the
The literature out there, but the literature out there
Like there's a lot of literature out there that is based on interpretation of facts accelerates the same thing
It has an interpretation of the facts. It's pretty good. It's pretty objective in the way it does it
a lot of leadership books in the same way what I wanted to do is take the
the canon of
of known solid leadership principles from gallup from strength spiners who's based on data
Correlate that with how I behave at work in a way that can be observed by ai and then give me
Coaching feedback in small chunks on a regular basis
And I think the cat wants to talk apparently, but that's what that's what I want and that's doable today, right?
That is doable today someone could build that now. Here's the question and it's
I love it when she does is she's like i'm right here pet me. Um
I've had multiple cats use the only one that's ever done this the cat was batting brent on the arm while I was talking
Yeah, she was like hey, I want your attention pet me now
what you just said
mate
Is interesting
In let me let me do something with you
Let's see how well it plays out. All right. Okay. I was like I have on my android phone
the microsoft
Co-pilot app. Okay. Okay. I don't know if you have android. It says brent is great to see you
I do have an android phone with no sim in it that I use for
Watching tick tock there is a neat button
Right there. All right
Okay, i'm going to turn up the volume
And this what does the button do? Hey, brent. What can I do for you?
Hey, can we go back to a previous conversation?
For sure
What were we chatting about? How do you feel?
about voice driven
ai bots with a personality
Speaking strictly from experience. I think they're an interesting tool
They can make interactions more engaging and personalized. It's like having a conversation with a knowledgeable friend
Of course, it's all about finding the right balance between personality and popis
Too much personality could be distracting but the right amount makes it more relatable
What do you think?
Well, I think it's interesting that you did not bring up the primary detractor
What would you say that is?
Probably the risk of over-reliance on these bots. They're a great aid, but shouldn't replace human interaction entirely
They can also sometimes unintentionally reinforce biases or lead to privacy concerns
It's kind of like wielding a double-edged sword you get the good stuff, but you need to watch out for the sharp edges
I think you we should be stronger. We shouldn't just be having to watch out for the sharp edges
um
Like do you have any concern around?
human beings
Falling in love with ai and how that may impact society
That's a complex topic for sure while it's understandable people may form
Attachments or emotional bonds with their ai companions
It raises questions about how those relationships might impact real-life connections
It could blur the lines between genuine human interaction and artificial ones potentially affecting how people perceive relationships
It's a nuanced conversation with ethical emotional and societal implications
Any specific part of that intrigues you?
Yeah, the ethical concerns and how we're gonna how we're going to prevent the ethical concerns
Before they happen. It sounds like you feel you're sounds like you're okay with us taking a reactive approach
Not really
I think we should definitely be proactive about ethical concerns
Especially when it comes to rapidly evolving technologies like ai setting strong ethical guidelines
Fostering transparency and ensuring accountability are crucial steps to minimize risks
It's about anticipating challenges and having robust frameworks in place before things get okay. Thank you. I gotta go back to a podcast. Bye
Sure thing brent. Enjoy your podcast. Oh my god
So that's weird. Um
And yeah, but how did you feel about that? Like the first time I did that I was with my daughter in the car
And I don't know how I let it do it
But basically if I were to go to a different screen and I would show you
that
is all
llm
Like everything that they it was llm running
And it was just the voice ai
Outputting it there's a couple takeaways I have from that one is
I no longer need you on the podcast. I can just as have an ai to talk to
Let's see if I can figure out how to do that. No, don't do not do not stop that
I think I think the key thing is is yeah, we we all saw her
Was it her or she her?
Who my ai the movie the movie with the guy fall in love with the ai. So
Oh, I haven't seen that one. I'm not talking about you know
Focusing on the ai, but the ai I think even the way I use chad gpd today. It's a coach. It's a collaborator
So why don't given in general how bad leaders are across the industry and how much data we have on how?
On on what it takes to be a good leader and what it takes to lead it to to make a team successful
Why don't we why why can't we take those conversations from all the ways we interact with people?
And have an ai become our coach to help help these leaders learn how to behave better and improve
That's the question because so now we're going back like okay brent that neat tangent
But why the hell did we go that way? Right? And so what I walked away with okay
And I I don't think this is what you're saying
But what I walked away with wouldn't it be great if we could have an ai watch what we do and give us little affirmations
But affirmations corrections course corrections tell us to do things that we're not doing okay. It's of course corrections. I love that
towards
What goal what correction and who gets to define that?
Okay, i'm gonna go off data here research shows that highly engaged teams deliver
Uh faster
With quality and there are facts on what creates highly engaged teams
They need to know why their job is important. They need to learn manager cares about them
They have to they have to get feedback are the biggest thing
And and and then those those dive into
I feel like you're missing my point because you're mentioning all the things that you know, I already agree with I I know but I think
I think if you look a lot of managers, you'll ask them for example. Hey, do you give feedback team?
Yeah, I give my team a lot of feedback and then because it's not observed because it happens behind closed doors and closed meetings
We don't know if that's true or not
What I want to have is the ai to tell me if i'm doing the things that create highly engaged teams
Or maybe I tell the coach here is what I want to get better at
I want to get better at making a closer connection with my employees and get so they'll so that
I can give them strong feedback without feeling like without them feeling like i'm attacking them
Now we're on the same page and and then having some
So we're on the same page having something doing Pavlovian experiments with me
without
my conscious awareness
I'm I'm just like
In the beginning I have to have the ai help me figure out what the goal is because if i'm your typical
mediocre to worst manager or leader
I don't know what those things are I need to do because i've never done as good as I was as a software developer
I've done jack squat on learning anything about leadership and growing people. I completely get that you are essentially
What you are done is trying to create
a
fourth order of ignorant solution
Yes, I want to use ai to help people discover what they don't know they don't know right you are correct and all i'm saying
And i'm aboard on that one, but it's got to be
ethical af
It does. It does have to be ethical af but I think it can be I think it can be and and
I would be surprised because i've never had an idea that wasn't already invented or already on the market
I would not be surprised if one of these companies like fellow or whoever who focus on
These managers, excuse me manager employee interactions
Haven't already thought about this or building this in some way. This is I think it's critical. I think
I don't like like you just heard what what bing is. Yeah, like it's not far off
I don't I personally
Like I think I told you
The first time I did this I I did a different voice
and
My daughter was in the car and she's like
dad
Because the way it responded dad the ai hates you
and
Because of the way they responded i'm like, yeah, I totally get what she's saying
And i'm like, this is why I don't like anyway, i'm not going to kick that horse any further
I absolutely believe it's unethical to put personality into ai
because of
The yeah the problem because because people
Number one, it's well known
People are very easily manipulated and an ai could do that and a friendly ai could absolutely do that
Super well
Anyway, yeah
No, okay. I agree. So I also don't like the personality
I think it's a nice little parlor trick they've done to make it a little scary to to creep towards uncanny valley
I do not like it either, but I think there's a huge
opportunity there and I think we're yeah, you're right. I want to find a cure for fourth order of ignorance
Yes
And I I agree. There's a way to do it
I just as i've mentioned before
right, it's
The fact that there's so few systems thinkers in this space
Ah
is problematic
This is why like if you get down to it, we don't need
And this is why people can't coming, you know looping back
This is why people come to you and can't differentiate between ai and magic or llm's and ai
I think the need for systems thinking in the new world we're growing into is becoming
Uh more than critical, um, like like vital. Yeah vital
like I like
Near existential I don't use that word very often because it's so buzzwordy now, but near existential
Yeah, I agree. I think
it has to change or
I mean
It has to change because we'll never take full advantage of the tech the advances into technology until we do
Yes, so yeah
All right, then well, uh
I'll I will be a combination
prompt engineer. I hate that term a prompt engineer and a
Talent coach in my future life not not
But I think there's there's something there and I yeah, I think mostly
like
Rather than look at ai as magic. I look at what I see are big problems and one big problem as I see is that
Oh god, I could tell stories probably get fired for them, but I see
uh
There's just a lot of flaws across the industry here
There's some other folks as well in how people lead teams and they fail to see how important it is
to
Focus on those things as a leader the critical thing. So I wish they would get the coaching they need
They don't know they need it. They're never going to see it. They think they're fine. Whatever whatever whatever like
Let me give you one more example
We can close to the day
But you and I'll go back to microsoft in the old days when it was toxic microsoft and the way to get to the top
Was to leave bodies in the wake
You know you you and I both saw people who got promoted for being complete assholes and tearing people apart
and
What happens that happened? Did they get whatever whatever level it is at a higher level? Um
What it does is it reinforces that behavior so they do more of it so they continue to grow
Yeah, and what it does is it tears apart teams and makes good people leave to go find different things
The great thing about microsoft if there's one
Is just teasing is that uh, like I survived there because I as you know, I changed jobs every 18 months
Because if if I got bored on the job or I didn't like the manager there was another place I could go work
That would be better for a while
Yes completely agree
That the no it and there's unknown
you get more of
For any organization that you probably know this better. You can probably cite this better than I can
but in any organization you get more of the
Personality as derived by their actions
Of the leader
Right first and foremost like leaders will say oh we need to do this
But if their actions say differently
It's their actions that you're going to get more of whatever is the principle that drives those actions
Right if it's charge the hill you're going to get charged the hill if it's going to be steamroll your
your
Your office neighbor. That's what you're going to get
now
Those are bad. But the other extremes in my view are bad as well
right like
No one ever talks about what is collaboration taken to the nth degree
Right. That's that's the consensus committee bureaucracy
Model where you get in the meeting and you can't move forward because everyone has to agree and no one does
So there's
Balance
Balance is what's key it is it is all right
Well with a few breaks for audio and technical issues as happens
The cat's fine
Brent you got you got to leave the ponytail man. No, I love it. Okay. All right. I'm gonna grow my hair out even further
All right, um a quick story then we're gonna go I should do this at the beginning but uh,
I
Had a week
but on monday
Um, you know, I haven't uh as some longtime listeners will know at one point. I was somewhat of a musician
I auditioned for a band on monday night. Did you really I did so I that is awesome
And uh, so I got a note back there auditioning a few more people, but i'm definitely in the running
I will know more I won't know more for it till the like the end of the year
Because they have some other gigs coming up with subs and things. But anyway a lot of fun. It was fun
Playing with other people for the first time that was great. I also I forgot my neck strap for my zaxophone
And so I had to use like a string like a referee string and it pulled on my neck so hard
But I was having so much fun. I didn't notice like it completely wrecked my shoulders and back like
Uh, I could finally get my arms above my head. I couldn't get my arms with my head for a couple days
so well, I was actually more worried that because you said
Because the surface area is much smaller and i'm like, okay
What's he so into it that he was actually starting to slice into his no
No, there was a line in my neck for about 12 hours, but it went away. I'm good. I'm recovered. I'm recovered
Okay, and I will never ever forget my neck strap again. What kind of band?
A ska band. Oh awesome. Awesome
All right. I will let you know if I get into the band we'll know by the end of the year
uh
All right, man
I think i'm we'll figure out the next recording. We got probably one maybe two more before the end of the year i've got our uh,
Predictions episode in reflection on the last year all that stuff
All right. Well, uh, i'm alan i'm brit. We'll see you next time