Welcome to AV testing podcast, your modern testing podcast.
Your hosts, Alan and Brent will be here to guide you through topics on testing, leadership,
agile, and anything else that comes to mind.
Now on with the show.
I have pressed record.
I have pressed the intro.
I have not yet pressed Brent.
Brent, how are you doing today?
I'm doing super.
Super like super man, super dog.
I am emotionally positive.
I am physically drained, as you know.
So we got delayed a week for the podcast.
So I know what is it?
Jason gets ticked off when we're late.
Well, you get what you pay for, right?
Although even if he had paid for it, we would have still been late.
I was last week suffering through my second bout of the COVID.
I officially was negative yesterday.
So a little longer than 10 days.
How was it this time?
I know- Oh, this one sucked.
Oh, really?
Because I know somebody who just got it for the first time.
And it was kind of mellow for them.
I hate them.
But I'm still one and done.
It's inevitable.
It's inevitable that I'll get it sometime and I don't walk to you.
But the darn thing's never going away.
And it's just going to become the new 10 day flu.
It's horrible.
For me, no.
So both times, it was the first day that sucked.
But last time, I just felt tired and miserable.
This time, like, no, nausea, full on fever, pain out
of every nerve in my body, it sucked.
But it only sucked for about 36 hours.
Not bad.
So the rest of it was, I mean, I just worked from home.
The first day, I'm like, yeah, I'm not working.
But after that, worked from home.
My daughter also got COVID.
I'm pretty certain that's who I got it from.
She was showing- Did you kick her out of the house?
No.
But we both sort of hung out in our own room.
We had just flown back from Florida.
I just came back from a- That's where you got it.
Pretty certain, actually.
Yeah.
And my son sat in between us on the whole plane trip.
And he managed to not get it at all.
So what's up with that?
I don't know.
It's a weird thing.
Maybe your son's a robot.
Who knows?
He might be.
All right.
I don't know if I- I just got back from LA.
Went down there for a couple of days, hung out with the team.
It's weird to have a meeting in a meeting room.
One, it's massively productive.
But two, I couldn't figure out how to make the-
I mean, eventually, I did figure it out.
But I was intimidated by the room control
to plug in my laptop or we all joined the meeting together.
That's something I haven't dealt with in many years.
That was a little while ago.
I don't know if I did that.
Anyway, fun stuff.
It's weird.
Good times.
There is one in-person meeting that I have on my calendar.
And I regularly attend it.
It's weird pre-COVID versus post-COVID.
It's sort of a status-recording meeting.
The things before COVID, I would avoid the plague.
I regularly attend this one, and I look forward to it
because it's like novel to do an in-person meeting, even now,
today.
Yeah.
It's weird.
I don't know.
But it was- it's great.
It's such an accelerant to get folks together.
It was beneficial in so many hundreds of ways.
But it's different and weird.
Long days, too.
I ended up meeting with the team all day and then dinner at night
with a lot of 14-hour days of sort of on, which is for us INTPs
or us eyes, especially, it's pretty exhausting.
I think we've begun to forget the degree to which
in-person collaboration is an accelerant.
Absolutely.
We talk about Async all the time.
But I'll tell you, number one, in comparison to you,
particularly the way you told the story at Unity,
my team has not figured out Async even remotely close
to how you described it at UN.
We were pretty good there.
And we were before.
The difference is if you're in 10 time zones,
literally, I mean more actually, but 10
that I'm working with very closely,
you have to figure it out.
And the thing I've been thinking a lot more
about this remote work, and it's not all Async.
You have to figure how to work both synchronously
and asynchronously.
And it's hard with you and I because we're
working remote at a company that isn't fully remote.
Like fully remote companies have because they're not
paying any rent, have all kinds of budget for travel
and getting these teams together.
And of course, Microsoft, everybody
gets a million dollars for travel for their budget.
So it's a little different.
No.
Not the last several years, no.
Yeah, but I'm being facetious.
Even at Microsoft, it's hard to mean for,
I get where Satya's coming from.
I'm already paying for how many buildings on campus
that are 25% full.
I can't up the travel budget just because people who are remote
aren't getting together.
And I know a lot of folks at Microsoft are in the area,
but I know they don't go to the office, they could.
But you've been hiring more remotely as well
because it's a better way to hire good people.
So it's weird and it's good to get people together.
And I think it's necessary.
And I think we're still, I mean,
work changed in the last couple of years.
And we haven't quite adapted to the involvement yet.
And we're gonna have to figure that shit out.
I completely agree.
All right.
Okay, let's get into,
dun dun dun, little transition thing past the,
is there are people, do you hear that?
No.
Good, I'm gonna turn off that app.
I have an app, it's giving me some notifications.
If that was in the thing, I'd be all kinds of,
ah, stop it.
Okay, we got a couple ideas for a topic.
Do you wanna start with number one or number two?
Uh, there is a third that I just saw.
A what?
Yeah.
Like is like breaking news somewhere?
Oh my God, is it crouch track again?
No, here, I will.
Breaking news on the A.B. testing podcast.
Do I have a breaking news sound effect?
I need more sound effects in my thing.
How many, have you populated them off?
No, I can upload as many as I want.
I just haven't bothered because I didn't know
we're gonna have like things, you have to warn me.
You have to warn me, Brent.
I don't.
Okay, Brent has shared with me.
Oh.
You know what, I forgot about this one.
Do you wanna talk about that one?
We can talk about that one.
This is live, live here on the A.B. testing podcast.
So does that count as a mailbag?
Or is it just a question?
It feels like a mailbag.
I don't know if I need to press the button or not, Brent.
Yeah, go ahead.
I mean, it's in general, but go ahead.
Let's call the mailbag.
All right, we have a mailbag.
I think just because the amount of joy
you push in that button brings me,
I think if it's ambiguous, it's a mailbag.
I want to press more buttons.
And it's my fault for not having more.
I should be adding all kinds of quirky little sound effects
because that's what's gonna get us
downloads and clicks.
That's how we get from three to four listeners, right?
So I did read this article a few days ago
and the article someone sent to us
and who sent it to us?
It was not Brent.
Brent, that's not you.
It was sent by, sorry, someone on our,
oh, from our, what do you call it?
Our Slacker group, one of the three.slack.com.
Walmart, is that the full name we have here?
Walmart, that's the name we know now.
Nice looking guy.
Sent us a blog post from Stack Overflow
and would love to hear our opinion.
And the title is called,
Generative AI is Not Going to Build
Your Engineering Team for You.
Subtitle, it's easy to generate code,
but not so easy to generate good code.
Do we just say correct and move on
or do you want to talk about more?
Yeah, it's interesting.
I want to talk about more.
All right, then we'll continue.
Yeah, there is, like I do hear rumblings.
Like it's interesting.
Like number one, I'm gonna share my intern
that I had this last summer, okay?
He, it was not a CS degree.
He, we hired him, he was a cybersecurity.
He was going for a cybersecurity doctorate.
And one day I asked him to,
hey, I need you to do this and do this
and do this analysis, okay?
He did all of that the next day.
But then showed me a working,
highly interactive website
that he had just put together
that also allowed you to drill into the analysis.
And I will tell you, no one on my,
like I run a data science team
that has a lot of development talent,
but no one on my team is skilled at UI.
And he showed me something that was like,
holy crap, I'm like, how did you do that?
And he's like, oh, yeah, I don't know how to build UI either.
I just had chat GPT write it for me.
And I'm like, oh, whoa.
So I had, he's unfortunately gone.
I wanted him to sit down and show me.
And did his code break the day after he left?
No, no, that thing's still running.
And I'm like, okay.
I'm like, all right,
this thing is capable of doing things
that even I hadn't dreamed up yet.
And I still kind of want it.
I may call him just to check in and see how he's doing.
Like he was a fantastic intern.
All right, so what's interesting for me in this article,
and it brings us back on topic here.
I think you're a little bit on topic,
but I'll put a link to it in the show notes
that if you read those,
did I mention go to the one of the three.slack.com
or to go to moderntest.org to get a link there,
you can sign up.
So the subtitle to me is odd,
it's not the key point of the article.
They do discuss it.
And we all know this, anybody who's dealt with co-pilot
or asking chat GPT to code,
yeah, it can do code that solves problems.
It can even fix the errors that it creates
and eventually you can come up with something that works.
Is it good code?
No, you need to look at it
and you need to be able to read code.
Again, going to back to my prediction
from eight months ago in the beginning of the year,
being a good code reader and reviewer
is going to grow as a valuable skill more than writing it
because chat GPT or I'll say Gen AI can get you started.
So there's some talking on that,
but I wanna, I don't know if you read the whole article,
but that is a good point.
And I think it's been discussed quite a bit,
but also the article ends up being a lot about
advocating for hiring junior engineers.
Right.
And like head nod, like whiplash head nod from me.
And I think it's interesting to tie that
into the overall story, but to me that was,
I'm curious in your takeaway,
so I wanna dive into that, but first,
did you see that too with the,
for you was the article more about writing good code
or more about why hiring junior engineers
is helpful in growing them to some engineers, et cetera.
I think the article was written
to try to put a statement around there
that does appear to be something companies are doing.
The, like, okay.
And that is cutting back on their payroll,
not lowering the rate at which we hire
junior engineers because the quote unquote,
Gen AI can automate their jobs.
Right.
And I think they're basically saying no.
And that kind of, so in some regards, like what,
to me, it is, no, we should not stop hiring
junior engineers.
Well, I mean, nobody advocated for that.
I will tell you a lot of the people making decisions
to cut back on their payroll
because of the existence of Gen AI.
I think you're taking a massive risk
because they're kind of putting their finger in the air
and going, oh, this is where we're going.
So let's just go there now.
Right. Yeah. Absolutely stupid.
This is equivalent to teams that said,
like when we talk about in modern testing,
like the tourniquet and Band-Aid story,
but the companies that fired all their testers
because they saw some other company didn't have testers.
They thought that would improve their quality
when there's a few missing pieces in there.
Now, maybe it's similar.
So what, I'm gonna draw a couple lines here together.
Where do you get good senior engineers?
Joel Spolsky wrote an article about this 20 years ago.
Can't you just now order them from amazon.com?
I think.
Because I think actually Amazon is one of the companies
that is cutting back on payroll.
You have to go to the dark web for those,
but Spolsky wrote an article
about where all the good senior engineers,
something like this.
And the point was that if you're a good senior staff engineer,
you have a job that you like and you're well compensated.
And if you decide you want to change jobs,
usually it's because you've been poached
and you have an offer and you're never on the market,
or you're on the market for about a second.
Like even in this economy,
the good engineers, there's gonna be some exceptions,
but generally they're not on the market for a long.
We've been a little lucky, not lucky, unlucky,
depending on your point of view.
There's been a few good months, Rob.
But generally, they stay employed and gainfully employed.
The best way to get senior engineers for me
is to hire the junior engineers when they're hungry
and get them to grow.
But more importantly, more importantly,
when I look at diversity,
and not just diversity in race or sex,
but diversity in ideas,
diversity in different ways to solve a problem,
diversity in curiosity about how problems can be solved,
diversity in people thinking about what's possible
given their unique background,
that comes from my junior engineers.
A lot of the senior folks,
they get used to solving problems a certain way
because they've been very good at it,
but they end up using their same toolbox a lot.
They're very good at that toolbox.
They deserve to be senior.
But the reason I like to hire a lot of junior folks
is they bring new ideas and new ways of thinking.
And if you replace them all with Gen AI,
how many different ways does Gen AI have
to think about solving problems?
Exactly zero.
Well, it has the LLM that was based on one idea.
I'll give it one.
Right, well, and it's because you said the word think.
Oh, okay, you're correct.
So I think you lose a lot of that.
You lose the creativity in problem solving.
Article also points out that writing code is the easy part.
In software development it is.
The people is really hard.
Also, in thinking how the system works together really hard,
there's all kinds of things that are super difficult
that aren't part of just spitting out
the method or the function.
And that's the most here.
Yeah, I...
I think writing code is easy.
Writing code is easy.
The thing...
The art that's dying if it's not already dead
that I still actively use,
and because I actively use it,
I basically out produce any of my staff.
And now that said, most of my staff,
only a couple of them have ever been in development.
But that's design patterns.
And, you know, the art of refactoring your code
such that there is just one line of code
that does the thing you need it to do
versus sort of copy paste, right?
I don't know that co-pilot can really do the design side of it.
I'm looking at research right now.
I was...
I just quickly looked because I...
There's a lot of things out there like researchers saying
and forecasters saying,
oh yeah, it has the potential to reduce,
blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
I'm like, great, I don't care about your opinion.
Has anyone done a study?
Like has anyone attempted to quantify it?
And I do find one, which I'm like, hmm.
So I'll just read this.
A field experiment involved would be nearly 2,000
developers at Microsoft and Accenture.
For those who don't know,
Accenture is one of the largest companies
that will do coding for hire.
Coding mercenaries.
Yeah, sure.
Show the developers using co-pilot
completed 13 to 22% more poll requests per week
at Microsoft and seven and a half to eight
and a half percent at Accenture.
Now, how do we feel about that frigging vanity metric?
I don't think it tells us anything by itself.
No, more doesn't mean better, right?
But it's really hard to measure.
Well, productivity is essentially the rate at which
you get more widgets out the door.
So in some regards, okay, maybe poll requests
is the closest thing to productivity.
I know for me, in some regards, it has sped me up.
But in other regards, it has encouraged intellectual laziness.
I have used that term extensively this week.
So that's odd that you bring it up.
Yeah, intellectual laziness, big bang for me.
Oh, it absolutely is for me as well,
there's like simple things like I'm in Python
all of the time.
I use the pandas data frame all of the time.
And now I have noticed just this week
because I come back from vacation on coding again.
And I'm like, oh, I got to convert this data frame
to a dictionary.
By now I should have this memorized, but I don't.
So I went to get a pilot and wrote a comment,
convert this to a dictionary.
And I realized, oh, I am never going to memorize it again
because it gets that one right.
And I have memorized that I don't have to memorize this.
You know, how do I feel about this?
A story I've told for, actually I think it's good
and I'm a parallel hero story I've told
for over 20 years now.
As I began to like people ask me like,
Alan, you're a composer, I just learned to write code.
And I said, writing code's fricking easy.
But there's a lot of parallels.
There's some creativity.
Creativity is the design pattern.
It's how am I going to solve this problem?
Because that's what chat GPT can't figure out.
There's something here or co-pilot, JED AI.
They're all interchangeably sometimes.
Okay, so there's some creativity involved.
How do I got to figure it?
Same with melody, what voice I want,
what dynamics are on what's this kind of the story
I want to tell.
There's a creativity part.
There's an infinite number of ways to do that.
And then once you get that figured out,
there's a whole bunch of rote work.
There's voicings and chords and progressions
and blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
It's really rote work based on math and formulas.
Sounds a lot like programming.
So as a composer, why, I mean,
I'm sure these things already exist
and in the composition tools, as they say,
if I figure out like the base I want to do,
I sketch in some chords,
I give it a few instructions on voicings and depth
and timbres I want and kabing, all my rote work is done.
It's the same as having you add that to addiction,
convert that to a dictionary.
It's the same damn thing.
And I think it's okay.
And actually I'm looking at another study right now,
which is right along with what you're saying.
Quote, so this is another one of the things
so this is another study done by McKenzie
and it seems much better.
Good, finish it up.
Cause I'm kind of getting excited about something.
So take it there.
Quote, developers using generative AI best tools
were more than twice as likely to report
overall happiness fulfillment in a state of flow.
Yes.
They attributed this to the tools ability
to automate grunt work that kept them
from more satisfying tasks.
And it puts information at their fingertips
faster than a search for a solution across online platforms.
Right.
And that for me in those two sentences, that's 100% true.
Yeah.
So let me tie this back.
So before Dan Pink wrote drive,
he wrote this book called a whole new mind,
which is how right brainers, creative people,
we're gonna take over knowledge work.
And yeah, creative work is so much more,
for me at least, a right brainer,
it's so much more enjoyable for me.
It gives me energy when I can create things.
And then I'm distracted when I have to do it.
Like I almost go to a different part of my brain
and shift when I go to do the rote work.
Da da da da da da da da da da da da da da da da da da.
And if I can basically automate the part
I subconsciously don't wanna do
and spend more time doing the fun part
that's a little harder, that stretches my brain
and makes me kind of think.
God, I'm fricking happy.
And you know, if I'm happy doing my job,
if I love my job, do I create great work
or do I create shitty work?
I create great work.
Yeah.
It's proven.
There's studies on this.
If I'm happy and engaged in my job, I do great work.
Happy people are productive people.
Right.
And I remember years ago,
I had a had an argument with my executive
because he had it backwards.
Why does so many dumb people get to be executive?
Because they get shit done.
I mean, he was like-
It should be how you get it done.
I agree.
It should be what kind of person you are.
And I go back to Maxwell's levels of leadership.
You are a leader because people want to follow you.
Yeah, et cetera.
I'm just kind of mad.
I'm gonna rewind.
Go ahead and talk.
He is, let's see, is he still there?
He's still at Microsoft.
When are you gonna, like,
things are changing there.
Things are getting better.
Can you get rid of the cruft?
He's no longer an executive.
He's only a partner.
Well, keep on-
I mean, that's still-
Still arresting, investing.
They didn't take his stock away.
Still there.
Yeah, but he's not making executive money.
So this is actually really interesting.
Now, based on what I just said though,
and I would do this as a composer also,
I'm gonna imagine I have co-pilot for composing.
And this thing may exist.
I haven't played with these tools in a long time.
But I've written my melody kind of thing,
and I've used the AI, the Gen AI
to help me do some of the rote work.
I still need to review it.
I still, like, I can't just go,
oh, I'm gonna bring this down to the studio
and have the orchestra play it.
No, I'll get, there's, I gotta listen to it
and tweak it and do some hand massaging
to make sure it's what I want,
that it fulfills my creative intent.
And you have to do the same thing with code.
Yes.
So, it's, yeah, that, again, yes,
because I'm getting back to the article here
that says that it generates code but not good code.
And what I'm saying is we do the creative part,
it does the hard part, then we have to go,
again, I think that's creative
to take what's been generated for us
and to turn it into something we like.
Now, and here's the thing,
like when it's circled back to the idea of,
we still need junior developers, right?
Even with the stats, like,
if we take the stats that I see, all right,
and from the two studies, I'll say,
okay, it does seem to be a, let's say,
a minimum of a 10% productivity boost.
Okay, well, I know for a fact that students
at many colleges right now
are learning coding alongside chat CPT.
The coding programs are including-
And that's wonderful, I think they should.
Yeah, they absolutely should.
Like the next set of junior people,
now, hopefully, they don't just learn how to gen AI code,
they are learning, again, human and machine
working together towards a common goal
and not encouraging intellectual laziness
in the way that we both would disapprove of.
But, go ahead, Fish.
But, so if that 10% is real, right?
Yeah, maybe you don't need the 10 heads
you wanted to hire, you only need nine.
But you still need that nine
and this is under the assumption
that these guys are skilled at using this
as a tool to get their stuff done.
And this is what I think we can teach.
And going back to, I love universities have this,
I wanna steal their curriculum
and give it to the engineers we have today.
Because what's missing today
in how people are using CoPilot
and we give people CoPilot to use
is they, we need like an exercise,
like a couple exercises,
a set of exercises they go through
where they have to find practice,
finding the shortcomings of what it delivers
and how to iterate on that
and turn it into something that's efficient and effective.
I think, like I have,
well, the stats are published overall,
they're similar to what I've looked at at our company.
There's a percentage of,
of suggestions that are accepted
that's pretty consistent industry-wide.
But there's a lot to learn there.
But I just,
I think even the engineers employed today
need to do that.
I do love that college students are using,
there are like professors are acknowledging,
and I hope they're doing this in other courses as well,
is using Gen AI as a tool.
It's not a cheating tool.
It should be an accelerant for work, for creative work.
So I don't know, I'm kind of excited.
I'm curious to see what it does
to the industry down the road,
but all these stupid stories about people thinking Gen AI
is going to flat out replace a bunch of engineers is dumb.
It's gonna make some engineers more effective
so you need a few fewer.
And as we've said before, for over a year now,
Gen AI is not going to take away jobs.
No, Gen AI won't.
It's people who don't,
well, people who understand how to leverage Gen AI may.
Because yeah, a team of nine people
that know how to use Gen AI effectively
could probably effectively do the work
that 10 people could do two years ago.
Or today.
Sure.
I was going back before chat GPT came out,
but yeah, whatever.
Oh, fair.
Yeah, and it's interesting,
like I had a conversation on this exact scenario
just today with a brand new mentee.
And it was interesting,
his approach to using Azure Co-Pilot was different than mine.
And I'm like, oh, that's fascinating.
Tell me more about it.
He, like for me, I will do the whole comment thing.
I assume you know what I'm talking about,
where you type in a comment and then it writes out the code.
He likes using the side panel
and he'll instead ask it questions.
Okay, good.
One of the things that is one of my new favorite things
with Co-Pilot is if I had the exception in my code, right?
I can just say, oh,
depending on what I want it to do, right?
I'm a big believer and you don't use exceptions
for flow control.
So I go, oh yeah, that's missing an assert.
You know, please add that assert
and throw if that's missing.
Or if it is an exception,
like some of the calls will time out and I'm like, okay,
yeah, there's no way I can proactively guess
how long it's gonna take.
So let me put exception handling around that.
I hate writing exception handling code.
I hate it.
It's boring AF.
And the fact that this thing can do it
is fantastic.
Now, it never, when I do exception handling,
I like to use the concrete class
and I have not gotten the GitHub pilot, Co-Pilot
to put in the correct concrete class yet.
But you know what?
It taps things out.
It gets the exception structure right.
And sure, I spend three more seconds
to get the right class under.
So yeah, I do like that aspect of it.
Just like that last article I mentioned,
is it gonna take it away not anytime soon?
Gen AI won't do that.
When or if the AGI comes into play,
and I don't know if we've talking about this.
Open AI is on record thinking that an AGI
will exist within 10 years.
Yeah, we did talk about this briefly.
It's, yeah, this I think is probably the lead in
maybe to the, we're all gonna die episode of A-B testing.
We're talking about AI.
Can't remember, but we did mention this.
Yeah, the, so winding back to...
Yeah, I mean, I think we,
anything else in the article you wanna hit like any,
he asked for any comments and there they are.
It's the article has a lot of good points.
It's a head-naught or hire junior engineers,
grow them into senior engineers,
create a good, like here's the deal.
I guess the thing is, it's easy.
Like, I guess my comment around,
it's easy to generate code,
but not so easy to generate good code.
I kind of think that that's kind of a bullshit subtext.
I, yeah.
Right, it's no.
That's hard without Gen AI.
And that statement is true without Gen AI.
Right.
And it also operates under the assumption
that that's really what you're trying to do.
Now, the pointy-haired managers at certain companies,
you know what, they might be, right?
Again, I have seen, I've seen evidence of companies
even at Amazon.
I try to remember where I saw this.
It was a news report where, oh no,
the CEO came out basically at some thing saying,
hey, the Gen AI is coming to take your jobs away.
And oddly, he meant it as sort of an inspirational message.
Oh, Lord.
Or he obviously didn't frame it right,
so he freaked out his entire dev staff.
But it does make the stupid stuff go away.
Whether or not, maybe that could be a fun exercise
to do one day.
Maybe you and I, we could do a series of and go,
all right, I've seen Planet Money do a series
of using Gen AI to create a whole episode.
Maybe it'll be interesting.
You and I.
We could have it, I mean, I could have it
create a script for us that we just read.
No, well, and with their voice stuff, we could go beyond that.
No, no, I was saying it might be a fun experiment
to say, all right, let's dream up a service
and let's see how far we can get Gen AI to design it.
No, it might be good for, like if we're gonna,
we need to do that one as a cast
and put it on YouTube or something,
because people need to see some screens along with that.
I'm wondering how long is it until one of us
can do the podcast without the other one?
Oh, I think.
Like, cause it's there.
So you kind of tried to do that and you're like,
oh no, without Brent, they call bullshit on me.
This is boring.
Well, again, but if I, look, if I need someone
to be confidently incorrect, I can use you or chat GPT.
Sure, sure.
I mean, I guess you just, you spend another couple hours
this weekend and come up with the right prompts.
No, I'm not gonna do that.
Okay, point is, read the article.
There are our thoughts.
We think that Gen AI isn't taking away jobs.
You should hire junior engineers.
You should have a diverse culture that you should,
like focus on, I was gonna say earlier
before you interrupted, like you gotta build good teams
and good teams will make good software
and they'll make it efficiently.
You don't have enough people on the team
to get done what you need to get done
and they're gonna figure out,
like I'm full of tautologies here,
but if you build a good team and you focus
on their engagement and joy of their job,
they're going to produce great software quickly
and yet everybody wins.
Woo hoo.
There is one last thing I'll say on this.
Okay, fine.
One last thing.
And we'll see.
Does it have to do with unicorns?
No, cannibals.
No, cannibals?
Cannibals.
Cannibals, gross.
The section header is we need to stop cannibalizing
our own future.
Ooh, that sounds harsh.
And the very last paragraph.
All of this speaks a deep misunderstanding
about what engineers actually do.
By not hiring and training up junior engineers,
we are cannibalizing our own future.
We need to stop doing that.
Now, before you comment,
I will tell you this reeks of several of the messages
I heard when test was imploding.
People proactively holding on to the old world
with white knuckles.
I don't know if that's their intent.
I'm going to choose to sort of be balanced,
but I think this whole article,
at least in terms of my own view of thinking
about the future and balancing human with the machine,
this article would have been much better
without this whole section.
Because I'm just like, oh, it reeks of that protectionist.
The way we've always done it,
it's the way we should do it that I don't like.
Yeah, I get it.
I get it.
To me, I take it a little bit differently.
I want to get into a couple of code of things here
before we end it for the day.
But really, it's reading my LinkedIn DMs.
I thought would be a fun segment
that I forgot I wanted to do.
But I think what he's saying is
if we only focus on hiring seniors,
eventually we aren't going to have anybody
to grow into senior positions.
And that's how we cannibalize ourselves.
We have to hire the people that grow into those positions.
So I don't have a sound effect for this,
but I don't know what your LinkedIn DMs are.
I reply to if I know you, I reply.
So I don't want people who know me,
who send me DMs to feel like they can't send me DMs.
Of course I'll reply to them.
But I get DMs all over the place
from people who have glanced,
well, they haven't even looked at my profile.
What they've done is had an algorithm,
I don't call it AI,
something has scoured my profile
and found deep in the dark roots of my past,
the word test or the word estet.
And then I get messages like this.
And tell me what your answer would be.
I'm not going to reply.
Alan, I'm building a...
Fuck no, I'm thinking what my answer is.
Let me finish.
Alan, I want to give you $10 million.
No, I didn't say that.
Alan, I'm building a company
to help my customers achieve test automation
using their manual testers six times faster than Estet.
I'm seeking blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
Is he coming to you for venture capital?
No, he wants insights,
but I don't want to talk about testing.
At least he's not trying to sell it to me.
But I don't want to talk about,
like I'm tired of it because nobody gets it.
I don't want to teach my manual testers to write code,
to write code, test code.
I want my developers to write test code.
Yes, that's exactly where I was going.
I refuse to be part of that system.
I'm like, it's not the answer.
A bunch of testers writing Selenium all day
is not the answer.
Teaching my manual testers air quote to write automation.
I don't care how many, look,
I'm sure your company is great.
And I'm sure you have a market for people you can use,
but it's not for me.
It's not for me.
Teach your manual testers to write test automation
and dev code better than your Estets.
And all right, I'm in.
Let's talk about that.
And again, you get the mountain I'm on.
We have studies showing,
studies not just my anecdotes, which are absolutely valid.
We have studies showing that tests owned by developers
have a higher correlation with quality than other tests.
Yet we pay these test teams to write automation,
like an unhealthy amount of UI automation
for the development team.
And I just,
the inability of people to learn and adapt to,
and grow, like, I don't know, like Dan Pink was right.
The future is right brain, creative people.
If you are a fixed mindset and you don't want to learn,
and you don't want to do new things,
and you don't want to be creative in your job,
you're useless.
In software, in software,
you are, you have plenty of other jobs you could do.
Go work in a button factory.
Uh, go work at anything that's assembly line work.
Yeah.
Right?
Button factory, door knob factory.
Yeah, I don't.
I just, I'm blown away.
I was talking to, I was talking to a former employee of mine
who I moved to enroll in another team.
And well, it didn't go well.
Today was their last day.
And I was talking to them and they said,
they're just blown away the fact that
there are people in the software industry who like,
like there is so many new things to learn.
Like, Brent, you and I have been in this,
like, like a combined 150 years.
And every day, every week we find new things to learn,
and we're excited about those things.
And it's that learning and new things that keep us motivated.
And there are people that I just,
I just don't get why there are people who don't want to learn.
So anyway, backing up to this thing.
Uh, I know, I, sure.
I believe in you.
I just want to be no part of having testers learn,
like having manual, like I,
tell me how you're going to help developers
write better tests.
Tell me how you're going to accelerate software development.
Tell me how you are going to speed up the feedback loop.
And I will talk to you any day of the week, any time.
Right. And, and to me, okay.
So you can make manual testers faster than Estes, right?
For me, it's okay.
How can you use that same tech to turn the Estes
into better developers?
Like, um, it is still something that I have,
I've mentioned on the podcast a billion times.
When you take someone who's in suit,
who is competent at testing and move them into a dev role,
they become the developer.
They're the modern developer.
Yeah.
It's, um, they are just simply, uh,
better in all ways that I can think of measuring.
Uh, and if there's a strategy along those lines,
great, I'm a board, right?
In terms of like the one line pitch that you just talked
about, yeah, it's fine.
They, they meant, they meant well, but their demographics
is just screwed up.
They absolutely targeted the wrong person.
Yeah. Yeah, I get it.
All right. Well, that is AB testing for today.
I remain right. Blaine Allen.
And I'm.