Welcome to AVE testing podcast your modern testing podcast your hosts Alan and Brent will be here to guide you through
Topics on testing leadership agile and anything else that comes to mind now on with the show
We are back. Yeah, how are you man?
Hey, it's summer
Depending on you know what depending on the table
depending on
Guess where you're at. It's either summer now or summer yesterday
Yeah, it's by the time you hear this it's summer for everyone. It was summer a day or three ago for everyone
Yeah, I was yeah, so that's our weather forecast. That's the weather forecast section
So many stories on I have lots of feedback about the podcast. I want to share. Okay
You ready? I so I don't know where to start
I was gonna let's do that first and then I'll talk about what I did and then I'll talk about what we're doing
And then we'll weave in some AI and by that time we'll have done nothing for 45 minutes and we'll end the podcast
It'll be great
so
Seems like we should have a theme song for feedback like we
We know it
You know what we embrace it and here's the deal. I was talking with my ever supportive family this week, okay, and
None of which who have my wife accidentally listened to part of an A B testing pod. Oh
Let her know that nobody else has heard
Sorry of an A B testing podcast and we're talking about it with my son at dinner the other night
And you know, I have friend I have friends that listen and they like it. My wife says like my son asked
I think my wife said you knew dad has over 200 episodes on his podcast
Because that's great. What's the podcast about and she looks at me and I look back at her
I said, it's kind of hard to tell
It says it right in the intro
Whatever comes to mind that's what happens if you skip past there
And whatever comes to mind it is kind of what we do
but the reason is and she's not listening to this one so and
Anybody that's already given up on us isn't listening also. So just to satisfy my own ego
the reason
We discuss stuff like this is because in these discussions as where the nuggets come out
Brent and I did not start this podcast ten years ago and start
building modern testing principles and talk about how delivery was changing over time and try and
Find ways again. We don't event we find ways to talk about what's going on in
In those discussions
We have to have the back and forth and me making fun of Brent and Brent calling me names and show me
I'm number one and in that we find the nuggets that are worth listening to and finding out that we can build on for the
Next recording so this is all for us
because we're good at kind of balance and stuff with each other and figuring stuff out and going from there and
Eventually coming up with some ideas that some people
kind of like
Brent disagrees no
We go wrong this is the last episode of the A.B. Testing podcast we're breaking up
B for that
A will be Sam for ADHD and B will be I guess random brainstorming with whoever Alan finds
The yeah, no, I agree with everything you said just got on smart then just without the heavy
tinge of like self-esteem issues like
No, dude, have you is it your first time meeting me? Oh
Wait, no, just podcast podcast Alan not have self-esteem issues. I
Did I let the other Alan leak in I do not
Apologize in any way shape or form for what we are like that's I mean it is what it is
No, and it is what it is on purpose and I would fully understand it would be it
it's gonna be a hard podcast for some people to listen to and
I'm speaking to what's the opposite of the choir cuz I'm speaking to the people who are not
Listening to this episode because they chose to opt out at some point and that's totally cool opposite of a choir
Like preaching to the choir or what's the opposite? Well, so if your patients acquire
Right, I guess not
Because it's not preaching to the people in the pew because they're still listening
it's kind of like when the when the
One kid gets is really rowdy in class and gets sent to the principal's office
Then the teacher punishes the rest of the class
Or when somebody's late for work and everybody gets in trouble those sorts of things like it's the wrong. It's the con
Anyway, I have to do the podcast and doesn't matter
It's not a captive audience. Okay, you're correct. Yeah, you're correct. The
Point is that I wonder if my little pop filter worked on that
I will fall find out in the recording now that I don't really edit anymore
The point is that we have to
Discuss and meander because if we don't do that, we'll never find the great ideas now
We could you and I could just talk not recording for
Hours upon hours and then eventually like once every four months collect our nuggets into one
Into one little thing nuggets are diary
Yeah
So that's that and let's move on to a new topic. I had something else to talk about. Oh, do you ever write?
Just stupid code because it like yes, of course you do because you're like me and you hate an efficiency
Can't resolve the idea of stupid code. I know I
Give you an example. I'll give you an example of the kinds of things I do because they're kind of fun
well, one thing I do at work is I
Probably shouldn't be writing code in my position
But sometimes I like doing some little things like querying github API to find some things out because I know I know
Python and graph qls that are etc. I
Don't know if I told the story on the podcast before but
My son is very anti big company refuses to have a Google ID on his computer
Does not want the tracking him and yet we need a way for him to
View and add to our family calendar
Now I can give him a link that allows him to view what's in it read only
But I don't have a great way for him to add things to our calendar without a Google account. Okay, you follow him
I am and
so
Huh, I got an answer. So Google has this thing there
It'll probably shut it off at some day because it can only lose money. Are you familiar with?
Google app script. No
So Google has this app script thing that integrates with their apps and you can just write stuff and have it run basically as a
Cron job or on a trigger to do stuff and I wrote one that looks for
Males coming in sent you I could give the address but an angry weasel comm address and when they come in there
Can they come in as calendar invites or they're rejected when they come in?
They're parsed and added to the shared calendar. Okay, so pretty easy to do works out great
He can just put as far as calendar he invites this address and it shows up
It's great and it just I just got an error. It just started failing which means that Google changed something in there in their app script
Api, so I have to go fix that I was just fixing that when you showed up
So anyway, I write so many little things like this
Like I kind of enjoy it because I don't get to really write code as part of my job anymore
And I'm far enough removed. I probably shouldn't but I do like little hacks like this
So do you have any little fun little hacks like that, Brent? I
spend a lot of time writing
Code, but I make sure
Like the difference I guess I make sure the difference between the two of us in this case
Right, um is I can still make sure that the code that I'm writing
I'm not critical path
Right. Yeah, there is a lot of
So like in my particular team, I think I've made some this before and my team's improving
Rapidly, but I mostly have a team of data scientists
But we are a full stack data science team meaning
We build our models, but we also build the services and and ship those services that use those models
right, and so that means
Unfortunately most data science programs
Don't train on oop don't train on
Hell don't even train on C. See anything C sharp C flat C
anything
So and in I have
Spent time in dev so a lot of the times
Like I'm spending time
refactoring code
Which I enjoy because I I
absolutely love fixing broken things I
was telling one of my my
ICs today who who got so inspired that he went back to he's got his PhD in
I
Forget the official title, but it's essentially in supply chain management
So he's well trained as a data scientist, but that doesn't teach him coding and he's decided
He's gone back to
Illinois
University to get a masters in in
In computer science and I'm like right on
Anyway, I was telling him one of the one of my measures of a good versus great dev
Have we ever talked about this? No a good developer writes code a great developer
Deletes it. Oh, maybe you've held that before. Yeah, but that's that's not universally true
There's some nuance in that answer. Yeah, it's I mean
No of all developers write code
Like my to me a great developer does delete code
I completely agree with that one and it is hyperbole but just because you're right good doesn't mean you're a good developer
Like that's the only part of that little cliche thing. But the whole point the punchline is
Deleting code is a bigger art form in my view than writing it
And I think it's knowing which code to delete. It's understanding. There's a lot that goes into that. Yeah, that's
There's some missing parts of the story. We all get what you're saying
There's it's about refactoring the designs of the things are cleaner like number
More often than not the things I'm deleting are duplicated code or oh if they had designed it this way
Then this whole other function wouldn't have been needed right up. But yeah, I'm not doing
So I do a lot of refactoring after the teams got going and I use that as educational moments
But yeah, yeah, yeah way back when I worked on teams, I did a little bit of
hands-on stuff
But I always pick what I always described it as do the important because nobody wants to do unimportant work do the important
but not critical work and
if it ever becomes critical and I haven't finished it note that in advance and
Pass it off, right?
Right, which I've had to do a couple times. I can probably do on Xbox once give your heads up to to the victim
to be
Yeah, and we had a pretty good collaborative team there. And again, I always create I
Somehow I create little utopias of folks that work within chaos and we did that there
so it wasn't really an issue there is one of my old employees by the way, we keep on connecting and
They said we should get together and we go to get together and then kind of the our message dies and he never follows up
So Dan if you're listening, we're supposed to hang out sometime
Something else I was gonna tell you Oh
Have you heard of modern testing?
modern
Right you're such a
So I
Know one of our listeners
Asked me to give a talk at a Leon asked me to give a talk to their company just remotely
We had a the Juneteenth holiday here. So Wednesday morning
I gave a little webinar to a bunch of folks at his company in England. I talked about now it was interesting. I
Don't like I don't give that many talks anymore. And I don't know what to talk about anymore because
I don't know in a way. I'm tired of modern testing principles, but I'm not tired of them and I want to get to that
So this podcast is looking for a topic. It's modern testing principles. So it's really nice
He gave me like it'd be go for our company to hear about these three principles three and
three three of the seven Oh three three of the seven principles. Yeah, and
When I kind of put it together, I realized they went together
Kind of well, and it was principal one are which is Brent
Businesses everything. I mean I'm paraphrasing
Yeah, yeah, this is everything so our priority is improving the business. Yes
I believe it was then pretty which one is the acceleration principle we accelerate the teams now. I don't even know three
three and then
six we use data to
to help to
We should memorize these we use data, you know data that good
Brand either. Yeah, we use data extensively to deeply understand customer usage and close the gaps between product hypothesis and business impact
Yes, you with me now one is already
Continuously accelerate. There is no accelerate. So can you do some for me? I think is what you're talking about because accelerate. Yeah
Yeah, so what I found when I put these together
was that
They're all kind of about you know, we improve focus on improving the business
We work on it and we can't do enough there. So work on accelerating the team so they can move faster and then data for decisions
It really comes down to those three principles by themselves are a lot about the feedback loops
Yeah, lean thinking and theory of constraints especially are about they build on improving the business and we're trying to
Increase the feedback or increase decrease the length of the feedback loop increase the efficiency of the feedback loop
And then when you're able to use data to understand
how
That gives you the way to quickly like super quickly understand because you deploy a little bit of a bit of a thing and then
You can get feedback right away if that thing's working for a customer. Yeah, it's it's
It's interesting you just bringing it the three and I'm looking at this and I'm like, okay
And now looking at NTP with a totally different light, right? I'm like, okay
Like if we just had those three
Right. Let's say monetize some vegetables were just those three
Now I'll tell you I'll tell you what happens when that happens, but you go ahead and with your thought. Oh, okay
No, just tell me because
well, right once
once the police officer and
Oh
Do you hear the sign? Yeah, I'm being arrested
so what I found when I was going I did those three and talked about them and then I realized I was putting together my
presentation is
you know, we had
somebody pointed out many many years ago that
The principals were very close to or had a lot of overlap with the three ways of DevOps from Jean Kim
Don't know if you remember those at all, but no it those three especially
But I talked about the modern testing principles being not that modern not that much about testing their delivery principles and they're very good delivery
Principles, but the three ways of DevOps from Jean Kim's I think it was in his first book on DevOps
Probably I think it predates
Us I think it's 2012 2013 that came out. But the first way is systems thinking
Which is seeing in his case seeing
Development and operations as one big thing not as separate things being thrown over the wall
The whole idea behind DevOps was get rid of the wall between Dev and ops
It's all about delivering value to the customer. So system thinking see the whole thing right in there
And this was the key thing because like the the wise guy
The sorry, I don't want to say that way the guru in Phoenix project kept on talking about oh
You've just figured out the first way
Yeah, and because same author same is it's a way of putting that in there right and then
The the second way is to amplify the feedback loops
Make sure that they're apparent and obvious and we're trying to learn we deployed ops we learn comes back to dev
We learn more we give it to ops to learn more and give it back to dev learning and cycling
And then the third way is a culture of continual experimentation and learning. Mm-hmm
And I just found it interesting
How well those those lined up with especially principles two and six it's a lot about let's make sure well one
Systems thinking is we focus on improving the business the business is the system
Three whichever one or yeah three continuous improvement
That's amplifying the feedback loops and six is a way for us to enable continual experimentation
It is hard to do continual experimentation if you don't have the speed of using data for your feedback loop, right?
In the know there I might with you like like it even says in in
Principle like close the gaps of being product hypotheses if you mention the word hypotheses like you're
You're thinking about experimentation
Yeah, yeah
And so anyway it I it popped into my head when I was working on the presentation
because I haven't looked at it in a while and I looked at it and was kind of
Pleasantly surprised maybe blown away is too hard, but very interesting to see how those line up
So there is a nugget of takeaway
That you all can take who are looking for valuable content in the EAB testing podcast. Yeah, it's interesting before you vote
Jean Kim I was thinking of our near to right and
And you could take the same three
and
In kind of plug-in right here and said but the thing is actually I guess that shouldn't be a surprise
right because
angel and lean
It had a lot of different folks with different voices in a different view points all very much
In alignment with each other but different language around how they explained
What it was about right? Um
right, Brennierdson
Is fantastic like he was very quantified like I nearly got his his chapter around small batching
Memorized like that was like how he described why you do small batches
Which in my view is is in alignment with continual learning?
Yeah, his whole book is around flow and systems thinking like he he would be a massive
Yeah, it all fits together and what it comes down to
Dear listener is
remember Brent and I
Don't really have many original thoughts
But we bring in all what we know and kind of regurgitate it in a way
We think makes sense to our audience
So the number of the other four there's two things I'm thinking about now with MTP, okay, I
Kind of wish we had this insight that you just shared like what is it seven years ago?
Because now I kind of want to find a way to slightly rewrite principle one
Dude, we can rewrite anything we want. No, I know I know that like it's ours
You wish you would you wish you would have gone back in time kind of like in Deadpool 2 and
When Ryan Reynolds goes backs and fixes the whole Green Lantern crap. Yeah
No, I'll start thinking about this because I like our priorities improving the business like when we originally wrote that at least
What was in my head was?
We need to get testers
Thinking about the system
not about their small part like
If you got if anyone listening to this podcast still believes
That it's testers job to provide information. I really have to wonder at this point in time
Why you still listen number one number two?
Like you got to realize that that point of view is now
Absolutely. No longer mainstream. Well the things we were trying to remember going back to the context on this
It's probably good to go over this once in a while is that
We were trying to help testers at the time navigate into this new world
And we were clearly saying if you keep doing what you're doing now
If you were your jobs at risk, it's not
Unless you keep on doing exactly what you're doing now and hope it to keep working
Testers have always been good at systems thinking so these were not reaches these weren't like here's your career change
These are things you're capable of doing now
If you do them you you are safe your job is secure. You will stay employed
systems thinking super important and I get and I have been
Messaged in and a little passive aggression from the world that I've talked about it before is I bring a principle one
That's that's ridiculous. We can't improve the business. All we can do is provide information
It's like maybe in 1994, but thank you very much
And you know what if I knew what I knew if if I knew back then what I knew now
I think I would have fought that too. I think so too, but
There were different constraints right there was a lot more things we had to do proactive the feedback loop was a lot slower
but
You know, I honestly believe that the role of Q of QA being information providers
was always wrong it is
Absolutely wrong today. I think you know, I used to talk about this and just felt very
Passive and the way it always felt to me. I want to get deep in this people people really feel this way
those people don't listen to the podcast so it's fine, but it's
It's like and then what like that's really all that's I mean, okay
has always been my feedback on that even going back to
Lessons learned in software testing which honestly has some good nuggets in it. It's a little repetitive
It's kind of funny in some places purposely I give them full credit for that but
providing information
now
No, no, no
It's never been correct. It's never been correct like
My very first podcast like not podcast but blog was around now our job is to remove risks from the system
Right. It's not but we don't own the decisions
Then what's wrong with you own the decisions
Like we we we've agreed we shouldn't be owning the decision to stop ship or not
But it is our job to remove to remove risk from the system
Yeah, why can't why can't why are we where people trying to be information providers?
Why can't you be part of the decision making progress? How come like I would feel so
Unempowered if my job was say Brent. Here's everything I know and I
I'm not I don't I don't have an opinion because it's not my job. Please make my choice for me
It's probably that and I'm sure you have the term
Memorized but that that bullshit was a cognitive distance or whatever the hell it is. Oh
Critical this is yes, this is why developers can't test they don't have critical distance. Well, I'm being sarcastic
It's also probably why we're just information providers because no we can't make the decisions around
What's good for the business? No?
Anyway before we get to like right now I'm thinking
Principle number one somehow needs to term systems thinking in it. Oh
Yeah, okay, right I like you want to take up like right well, let's do it later like right sure
I'm like it's short and sweet. It's the only one of the damn thing that's sweet. So like
Adding systems thinking is probably gonna triple the number of words
But I wish it were there
Yeah, but when we look at
When we look at how these work today, so make these are
apply these to the team like we wrote these as
the
Tester trying to figure out what to do is your audience
Today, they're kind of a message for the team
This is how you deliver in a way that won't get you all the way back to
So it's the team's priorities improving the business
now if you consider yourself to be in this separate little silo of testing and
Even then you should have an opinion but the team like can everyone on the team have good systems thinking
Yes, I would hope so
Why don't they?
I do believe systems thinking is trainable
But I do also think
But from my experience
there there's there's kind of the forest people in the tree people like the people who kind of see the forest and people who see the
trees and
And I do think we need both
I don't think one's better than the other because I like if I keep this awkward metaphor going the tree people are very good at the details
Whereas the the forest people are good at the abstract and the strategy but suck at the details like for me
Devils in the details is the bane of my existence. Yep. Me too. It drives me crazy
we're doing but as I were doing budgets right now and
they're in Excel and
It's an absolute madhouse of chaos and I look at it and I just cry I
Curl up in a ball and I decide to try it again another day that I understand
The other thing you might try is
drugs delegation
That that also works as well
There's such a you may know so there's I can say this fairly there's a lot of
hierarchical
Non-transparency so some of this stuff I cannot delegate because
I'm told not to delegate it because there's fear that someone may see something that I'm supposed to in the budget and
So yes, but normally absolutely delegate. This is right. This is what managers do and
Once again, the podcast goes all over the place. I'm gonna reel it back in in a second
But we I mean any manager like you delegate the stuff that not just you don't want to do
But the stuff that'll help somebody grow and that they could actually do better than you
I have a couple directs who do some things
Made most of my directs do so many things
So well that are things I can't do. I'm very very fortunate. I
To me this is the lesson of strength finders that I walked away with right? It's essentially
I'll tell a very quick story. I probably have already told it before one of the strength chapter 27
One of the one of the strengths is one called communication
Okay, and I was once on the team that we had did every manager had to
send a
Weekly status report. Okay, I
Would rather shoot myself on the head then sit down and write status reports, right?
Because the are I am so this is one of the things that lean and agile has done to me
I am so ROI focused
Unlike no one reads these I'm just invest I'm just investing in it. I'm doing it because I've been told I have to
The only thing that I can tell from the past experience is that the only thing is done with the status reports is that
My management chain knows who's done it or not like there's some tracking system in place. Okay, and so
One of my IC had communication
And I this was early on in my my journey and strengths and I read it but the book what communications about
and I
Connected the dots because that's one of my strengths is connecting dots and I said hey
according to this
This guy might be good at it. Number one and number two love doing it
Okay, whereas I have always like the other thing I do
Is I take on the bullshit work that has to be done that no one really wants to do
So like I okay, I could delegate the status report
But I hate it and I'm not gonna pass on shit work to my people who's trying to do things that they're proud of
But yeah, I wouldn't talk to him. I'll finish the story. I wouldn't talk
No, good. I have a follow-up story as we continue our trip to tangentown. I
Wait to him and I said
Hey, his name was Renee Renee. I hate doing this. I do it because I'm told to do it
Would you like to take it over I didn't delegate it to him I asked him would you like to take it over and
I even explained to him why
And he looked at me
like I
Just offered him the best
Sweetest candy that could ever be given to anybody ever
Okay, and he's like
He no thought process about it. Yes. I want it
Okay
He started taking it over and it is the only time in my career
Where I had external teams that I had never heard of before
Asked to sign up for my goddamn status report
That is the stupidest damn story in the world no I get it I get it and I don't really like them I think
But I have an interesting story. I want to share as an alternative
A lot of my team just post some recaps end of week recaps in slack which I can catch up on
I don't require them to I have Jira. I talked to them. I could figure out what's going on
I can get answers everything. I need to know it's it's it seems more like
Box checking than anything else one thing my last manager did at Unity which was actually fun
you know, I blog every week and I like to write and
What he asked me to do and I'll I save the doc I'll scroll back I have a hundred page doc here
I didn't write all at once
but
He just asked me to write
Once a week
Send me what you're thinking
and
like organized like I called him my my org name organizational notes and it was
Sometimes about things going on on the team some things about something on our leadership team thoughts. I had about
strategy or
Whether it's organizational strategy or product strategy
But I just every week I would write a list of top-of-mind topics and he would read it
Every week and sometimes it'd be often but not always we stuff that would be discussing our one-on-ones go a little deeper into
But it was more about it was less about
Well, I think the difference is it's fair to say this now that we know that I have a job
that's a little weird, but okay is I was in much more of a leadership position there and a little bit more of a
management position here if that makes sense and so a lot of our discussions around the
Moving the company and how can we do this and how should we work here should be what what?
What organizational changes should we make across the org? What products should be billed?
What things should we go invest in potentially buying or I bounce head like when I had org change ideas
I could bounce them off of them. We'd have discussions. It was a good way for him to kind of know
Just it was like we had a 20 minute
Hallway conversation about something that I thought was super interesting during that week
and that sort of thing I like doing I hate status reports and I
Don't like them. I don't ask my team for them
But I do like the idea of I haven't asked my team for these either. I'm kind of more
Making sure the work gets done. But this idea of organizational notes was
was pretty
I
Could just finish what one last thing before I forget is as I mentioned before just kind of capital up here
It's one of the docks I saved when I left
It's I just added to the same dock every week so I could keep my progression
so I have little like this hundred pages of of notes that I sent him and
It's it's I just kind of scrolled through our talking. I forgot about it. And it's
You know, it's it's interesting. It's how I you know, you know, my leadership style of planting seeds
It's how I'd plant seeds with them here. Here's the way I'm thinking about reorganizing the team
I won't mention this again for another two months. But now it's not now it's it's in a cell in the back of your brain
anyway, go
No, so I like that. I don't know that I could do that with
my manager because
It depends on the manager a lot of what they want
They don't want a wall of text like I'll and Steve. Hello Steve. Steve wants to be on the podcast sometime
I'll let you guys talk but Steve does not want a wall of text
Steve wants Steve wants little nuggets and that's fine. So you have to do it Luke at unity
He wanted a wall of text. He was a thinker and he was not that Steve you're not a thinker
People people want their information in different ways. I'm gonna shut up. Go ahead
I'm more of an alignment. I think with Steve on this one with with my reports. I don't want a wall of text
What I want to know is that you've thought about the agenda in that we have something useful
interesting and or important to talk about like for me it's around
Getting my people to be proactive around how they want to use their time with me
I don't want to read at the point of a 101 is to talk through it and have an interaction and
Part of it is for me to be a mentor part of it's me to be a manager part of like status
Like I've I've explicitly told them like I don't want status reports. I don't
want
them even in the our 101s
right because we have a daily stand-up I have a
Separately scheduled office hours with with my team like status that I need to know about I'll know about
But I like this idea of
What's on your mind now the thing the thing I would like to do
Because if I were to say it that vaguely
They would probably think of it as again agenda items for our 101
It depends it depends on the manager in the relationship and it's gonna be different because on both people
It's gonna be different in every single case
I know Luke asked for this of all of his directs and I'm probably the only one that did it regularly
I know that a lot of people
Luke would send them to me to show them minds they get some ideas
So it's just I like writing and I like writing in paragraphs and prose far more than bullet points
So it worked out really well for me. Yeah, and so that worked it was the right combination and
You're always adjusting
It's like it is a how the hell do we get from modern testing principles all the way to manager employee relationships?
But here we are, but there is a lot that's important and just you just have to figure out what each other want to move forward
And that's it's an art but we everybody does it 20 or 30 times in their career and it's fine
Just recognize that people are different strengths finders people are different. They want different things. They're motivated by different things
They enjoy different things and they hate different things
Don't as long as you don't think immediately assume this is where Myers-Briggs versus well
just don't assume that everyone's exactly the same and
You'll be fine and I can even tie that back to make a big loop and get back to AI which we haven't talked about
It's been 45 minutes. Oh my god. If you can get all the back to AI
That's the problem when you have AI right pros AI. There's no human element. It's like you're
It's it's good. It's kind of good. It's accurate
But it kind of doesn't look like something a human would write yet
I don't know if I agree with I do agree you do I do you do agree with your own statement?
Because I use well, you know, we use chat GPT and the thing I wanted and I want to add a whole thing
I asked before I'll just shut up in a minute here
But I was trying to weave it back to AI but it's far too late
We have to close up in a few minutes
But the the people are coming in from the street to figure out what's going on. I
Asked chat GPT before we started I did I use the Allen bot that Jason Arbin made. Thanks Jason and
I can't find the window anymore. I have so many tabs open and I asked it for some topics
So what are some new and interesting topics Alan and Brent should discuss?
On the A B testing podcast and we're gonna do this next time and then I'll get all your thoughts because I've used like
80% of the
recording time on this podcast
It said given the wealth and experience and evolving perspectives of Alan Brent in the field of software quality a fun new and relevant
topic for the A B testing podcast could be
Worth the drumroll sound effect. Good. It's good. The role of AI in modern testing hype or hope
It which is a discussion and a talk I would never give we haven't done that
I do I do want I think there is
strong potential for AI in testing and the strong potential is in none of the things people are talking about and
How's that for a teaser?
Brent what's on your mind?
What topics can you remember from this podcast?
AI
The one from 30 seconds ago nice nice work. Give me one second. I'm trying something out right now
Brent is
Well, we're talking before well, he's trying that we were talking before the podcast started and I Brent stood up to go get the door
He's wearing pajama pants cuz it's Friday, you know, it's we're working from home
Friday and I'm wearing shorts because I took a little break to go to the gym later and
I
Learned a phrase. I think I might have shared this before we're sharing again
For those of us that work from home and we wear shorts and sweats all the time and then we decide we're gonna go out
In public we have to put on our hard pants
That I completely understand and everybody knows what it means as soon as you say it even though it's a made-up board
I love it. I gotta go grab some hard pants. I'll be ready in a minute. I
often
Forgo that just to be quite honest. I'm like, you know what all of the naughty bits are hidden. I'm going outside screw it
You know, I'm trying to look good
Hey, if you I do have one thing I want to mention at the end here once you're done here with your little chat
GPT thing which is providing no value right now. What's the thing you want to mention Brent? Oh
Okay
No, you you so I'm an ideater like the strength stuff, right?
Am
You're an idea monkey
Which means I connect the dots between things and when Alan says oh
I can't write it like a human being and we we had just briefly talked about Myers-brakes. I'm like, oh I have never tried
But what I just did is I said, all right summarize AI and testing and it wrote a bunch of words
And I don't really care. Okay, but then I said now rewrite it as an ENFP
Okay, and now actually rewrite as
I am
TP that's both of us. Oh, yeah
Riveting
Now what would be interesting in pattern matching and maybe I don't know if a gen AI could do this or some some graph paper
But take all of things strengths finders working genius
insights
Myers-briggs plot them all because we're different we're the same on a Myers-brake but different everywhere else kind of map
the the
Communication work what and what Alan enjoys DNA
So I
Whoa
That's getting another homework assignment. No, no, that just registered like for me like
so
You've made fun of me on this in the past like straight. I have Myers-brakes
I think in a general sense is actually really good
Strike finders as you know, I think it's a lot better, right?
What was the the the big big five big six is another one? Yeah, right and I'm like
What fun for for me on this one is?
Okay, if I had Alan
Take all of these tests and then I betcha
I don't even need to feed the data on it because I bet you open AI already knows
I'm like, whoa
What could I do with that? Yeah, it knows it like
So now I have your test. I just
Narration what it knows is Brent types in what is ideation and it kind of explained it in the whole Strix finders way
Can I go? Yeah
Like the fact that it knew I didn't tell its strengths when it pulled it up like it knows what I'm talking about
well, except it's a
Anyway
Ideation kicked in I haven't gotten to the end result
but my
Ethicometer just triggered. I'm like, oh shit if I had that plus open AI I
Bet you I could do a lot of really cool, but also a lot of really dangerous things
Well, there's some there's again there's power in knowing
What how that people are different from you and how to work with them and what motivates them
There's a bunch of different tools that let you figure that out
Some tools are about figuring out what you're good at
Which is also what gives you energy some are purely about what sorts of activities
Give you energy or are difficult for you to do about figuring out what you what's in your wheelhouse dial it in as a manager
It becomes a cool orchestration device. So all good stuff. We've talked about this stuff before we're running out of time
We did not we got to get out of here Brent. This is all good stuff
We forgot to mention last time and we will not do another recording in June
But I did want to call from a be testing a happy pride month everyone. Oh, yeah
Yep, I think I
Can cut this Brent if you want, but I think it's no for Brent and I we both have gay children and we're
We love them just as much and they're awesome
And I'm happy we live in a little bubble of a part of the world where they're they're safe doing that
It's not that way everywhere in the US or in the world. So
Just get out there support your support your community get out there for your pride parades. We have a
block party up on the hill just just treat people fairly and be nice and and
Just everybody's different, but they're all awesome. Well, they're not all awesome
I know a couple people who aren't but most people are awesome
Most all people are awesome in their correct environment
Yeah, sometimes in prison right? You know that anyway, I think this has been episode
200 and whatever 200. Well, it doesn't matter because they're all the same. We'll see you later. I'm out
I want to know your name