Welcome to AV testing podcast, your modern testing podcast.
Your hosts, Alan and Brent will be here to guide you through topics on testing
leadership, agile, and anything else that comes to mind.
Now on with the show.
Hello everyone.
Welcome to the AV testing podcast.
I'm Alan.
He's Brent and this is episode 200 and something.
That correct?
What do you think?
17.
We are once again, so prepared.
I want to know your name too.
And we are the name episode 217 and it is, it's Brent.
Yeah.
There we go.
All right.
Well, here we are again.
We've been, uh, you know, doing our thing, which we've done forever,
which really has no point.
It's just two guys sitting around drinking beer, virtual beer,
because I don't have a beer in front of me.
And we're talking about software leadership, whatever comes to mind.
And sometimes it's, um, video games, streaming television, but Brent,
how you been, man?
What's up?
Oh, doing all right.
Let me show you something that I can't wait.
Just recently.
I'm just saying it's a clock.
It's a ceiling vent.
It's, oh, it's this 25 year crystal thing.
That's my 25 year right next to my 30 year.
Oh, mother of God.
Yeah.
When did I start at Microsoft?
So I started, I would be coming up on year 30 if I was there, but I'm not there.
You're not.
That's true.
I have gone on to different things since then and learned a lot, which if you're
a long time listener, you will know because we've been doing this podcast for 150 years.
I wasn't even born yet when we started this podcast.
No.
And then I came like what, 10 years after that.
Yeah, somewhere.
Yeah.
All right.
Well, congratulations.
Thank you.
Can you get a huge cash prize of that?
Or they still give you like 30 shares of stock with that?
No, you only get stock with the 10.
That's it.
I can't remember.
I forgotten all the awards.
Um, five.
Do you still use head track 10, 15?
Shut up.
Do you still use head tracks?
Um, has it been changed?
Same thing that existed 30 years ago.
Uh, here, I'll try it out right now.
You don't have to try it right now.
No, it makes for great podcast material.
No, it doesn't.
What I found is when I refer to HR systems, I still find myself saying head tracks
once in a while and, uh, yeah, head tracks is this old.
Yeah, it's still running.
All right.
Good for that.
Hasn't been migrated to the cloud.
It's still like running internal.
Of course it is.
Um, yeah, of course it is.
All right.
That's fun.
Well, here we are.
We're back again.
Um, any, I don't think I have anything exciting to tell yet.
Maybe later in the podcast.
Uh, we'll do the pre-roll filler in the middle.
So did you have anything before we got into our first topic for the day?
I may, I have a couple of things that are not nearly as interesting.
Tell us, tell us, tell us, uh, just three days ago, I turned double nickel.
All right.
And that's old.
It is.
And it, but it also means, um, Oh, I don't know what
the color of the work, but I hit tenure or whatever that magic thing is.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
You can, you can, you can leave and you get to keep your invested options,
which is really cool.
I did not stay that long either.
I blew it.
I'm my financial planning.
Um, actually my, my, my mental health surpassed my financial planning.
I will be much better off if I stayed, but I probably also be dead.
So, you know, and then the other thing on, on just totally like, um, just slight
proof that I don't entirely lack of life.
Oh, it's going to be huge.
It's for me, it's major.
Um, I think we're waiting.
So myself, my daughter and one of her better friends on, um, Slurpee day
seven 11 will be seeing, uh, some yacht rock band.
I know it is.
MCR and violent films.
Oh, cool.
MCR for those who aren't total geezers.
Uh, no, actually it's the total geezers.
I don't know what MCR is my chemical romance.
I, I, that's a good, I knew what you're talking about.
And it'll be like my first concert.
My, it'll be her, my daughter's first concert ever.
It'll be my first concert.
Last time we went to a concert was before kids.
Oh my God.
Yeah.
Um, I go fairly often.
Um, not super often, but I love live shows.
I'm going to see a band you never heard of the kids.
No, I'm going to see the Linda Linda's next week, week after next at the showbox.
I do know one of my favorite bands because you mentioned it as one of your
favorite bands, like three or four.
Oh, very cool.
They're, they're fun.
Just garage punk ish pop punkish.
I don't know.
Okay, cool.
Anything so nice.
Nice to be out of a life.
Um, cool.
Anything else?
No, I went to New York last week.
That was fun.
Didn't do anything exciting.
All right.
Let's let's talk about your topic.
Okay.
Here we go.
So is it a mailbag from Brent?
Should I play the mailbag sound?
If you're going to answer it entirely.
Sure.
Let's talk about, cause you brought it up.
So in our pure, 100% professional planning, Brent said, I think I have something to
talk about and he said, do you have an answer to this thing?
I said, no, but I'll talk about it.
He said, cool.
It's on the show.
You liar.
You told me you had an answer to it.
The answer is trying.
Oh my God.
You're just like every PM I work with vaporware vaporware.
You're like, Oh, how dare you?
If you, if we were still at the same room, fighting words, I'd be throwing
markers and erasers at you.
All right.
Um, one of the challenges that, that I am currently facing.
Okay.
And this has to do with it's a downstream impact of COVID.
So there's a lot of these things, but, um, before COVID, right.
Hardly any remote work being done after COVID, um, like my company realized,
Oh, wait a minute.
If we allow hybrid, we could save a butt load on, on leases.
Right.
Move.
Yep.
The, however, what is there is a wacky combination of hybrid
so, uh, most of my team, I would say, so I managed a team of, of, uh, 10 now.
So 10 plus me is 11.
Thank you.
And four of them are remote.
Okay.
And all in my four remote people, they're in, they're in the US, but all of them
are in different states, like multiple hours apart.
And one of the things that's, that's, that's happening is the benefits, the,
the energy around people working together.
Um, I'm just not seeing it like I did prior to COVID.
Right.
And so now we have, it's very difficult to, Oh, and it's not just teamwork.
Cause the, you've, you've seen my, my presentation of how I walk people through
agile and, and what this has a tendency of doing is creating strong collaborative
connections that begin to extend beyond the professional, like they, they
start creating friends now.
Excuse me.
So, okay, dude, I don't edit anymore.
So just, just, you have, you have to be good at this 217 episodes, actually
216 for you because we skipped you on one, but come on, man.
Let's go.
Yeah.
Okay.
Sorry.
I muted so I could cough my, um, lungs out the gap.
Now from management, the teamwork obviously has positive goals
cause the teams that collaborate together get more productive.
Okay.
Sure.
But the thing that I had really well prior to COVID, um, and I don't know
why it's taking me so long to realize, yeah, it's not coming back unless I take
action, um, the teamwork was a huge source of employee engagement.
Yeah.
Right.
And it reminded me, I was sharing this, uh, with a mentee just yesterday.
And I paused and I'm like, Oh, I have a topic for my podcast this week.
Anyway, um, Gallup did a poll years ago around employee engagement.
And one of the things that they found was a, just a massive predictor of.
Do you have high engagement at your, in your business or your work?
Right.
And it was just simply this, do you have a best friend at work?
That question answering yes is a high predictor.
That's interesting because I've spent a lot of time looking at the Gallup data.
And I did not see that one.
Um, most of the research shows that the biggest predictors or
engagement are three things.
Does your manager care about you?
Do you know why your job's important?
Are you getting feedback?
Actionable feedback.
Those, those things are drivers.
If you, if you nail those things, you have engaged people and the engagement
is measured more directly by things like, would you recommend this as a great place
to work, but I haven't heard the best friend one yet because, um,
well, actually, so I'm, um, I don't know how long ago that study was.
Um, cause it was, I saw a long list of, they would ask, I think 12 or 20 questions.
I don't remember, but does your manager care about you?
I think it's very similar to that best friend thing.
Okay.
Sure.
Right.
You want, you want to feel like you're taking care of it.
It goes, it plays with a hierarchy of needs.
Sure.
Um, and my folks that are remote, right.
That really, the manager cares about you is really the closest I can get to helping
those employees answered.
Do you have a best friend at work?
So let me, I want to start to answer this because it's a common thing.
And even before COVID, my team was in seven, seven different countries all over
the place.
So I thought about this a lot and it, uh, it's really up to you.
This is on the manager because you have to create an environment where
collaboration can happen.
And there's a bunch of things you can do for this.
It takes like, I would say 90% of the managers in tech, okay, maybe 80 are
just fricking lazy.
They don't do enough to take care of their employees and drive that
engagement we were just talking about.
Uh, so with remote workers or workers not in the same office, as a lot of
companies have, it takes a lot of effort from the manager because one, you
need to create opportunities for collaboration.
So what if, you know, entropy would say that in a, or where everyone's
remote people, people would tend to work siloed.
I bet those is a good chance that those four people who work completely
remote tend to get siloed into areas of expertise, um, air areas of things
they do by the things they're really good at.
So they just do autonomously and independently far away.
Now, as you know, bottlenecks are bad.
You know, your specialization is a career limiting factor.
But also career growth stagnates because those folks, if they're just
doing their thing and they're doing it in a little, little teeny silo,
their career growth stagnates too.
It's a, and that is also your responsibility as a manager.
So, uh, a couple of things you need to do, and these aren't answers here,
but I think it's a new world and we need managers who can constantly
experiment in trying to solve this stuff.
So part of it is collaboration.
So I know in your rituals, you're getting them involved in, you know, the teams.
I'm sorry, Microsoft, you have to use teams.
Uh, but I'm, there's teams calls are on, they're working on stuff together,
but, and I know you encourage pairing and, you know, pairing these folks
different, you know, get them to know other people through pairing.
Um, one thing that I did, I kind of fell off my radar and the current job,
I did at unity a lot, especially during the pandemic was I wanted to recreate,
um, like you're talking about friends and the problem with being on teams all the
time with every meeting is on teams and not in person is all you ever talk about
as work, nothing else.
And with as many meetings as people have on their calendar, the last thing you
want to do is let's put a meeting on the calendar where we shoot the shit.
I tried to do like a Friday brain break meeting, uh, at the current job.
Did you ever get that to work ever?
What?
That that, so we've done that.
Like, no, no, let me, let me finish.
Let me finish.
So I tried like a Friday brain break here.
Let's let's let's have everybody get here and we'll play games for a half hour,
45 minutes on Friday.
People like, no, I don't, I have too much to do.
I don't have the time to socialize.
So you're in meetings.
People over talk about work.
They never get a chance to know each other.
They don't find their common interests without common interests.
They don't discover people they're friendly with, let alone friends or
best friends.
So a couple of things.
The easiest one is, and you probably do this when you're having one of your
ritual meetings, take not, not even five, two minutes, ask people with it
another weekend, find out who cooked.
What's the weirdest food you ate this weekend?
What's the most, what's the weirdest food you've ever eaten?
Just ask them questions like that.
Get them talking a little bit and then get onto the work.
But more importantly, because people, sometimes people are awkward there.
They just go, I just want to go over my status branch.
Don't make me be weird.
I'm introverted.
The thing I did at Unity that was super effective in my brain at least,
was I started a question of the day channel.
It was in Slack because we were a superior company to Microsoft.
You can use Teams as well.
And I just made this public question of the day channel and every day I would
ask a question and the question could be something who is your favorite
manager ever, or it could be what's the weirdest food you've ever eaten?
Or what video games are you playing right now?
Or I like a huge video game.
Or I like a huge long list.
I just, it was easy to come up with them.
I asked a new one every day.
I invited my team to the channel to start, but by the time I left there
about four or 500 people in this channel with, you know, a hundred
people actively answering every day and people, a bunch of lurkers watching.
So what that created was the water cooler, the kitchen, the coffee machine.
So instead of it, it was async, which was nice.
It generated a way for people to learn about each other, which was nice.
And it didn't add to their schedule.
They could look at it.
And we had, again, where I'm across every time zone in this team.
I had everybody all the way from Singapore to Helsinki.
So it let people answer at a time that was convenient to them.
And then people would connect.
There'd be discussions.
Oh, Hey, I love that movie too.
And people would connect and get to know each other.
And then when they had to work together, it was a lot easier for them
to develop trust to work with each other because they already knew
a little bit about each other.
It, it like any community.
And you know, Brett, I did this because I'm a community builder.
Like any community, it took a lot of nurturing and prompting.
Like I would ask people on my team, Hey, go answer this question.
So we get a couple of answers in here and you have to really cultivate.
But it was self-sustaining when I left.
I don't know if it still exists today, but a year after I left that
question of the day channel still existed.
And it's a great way to get people talking.
Who asks, did you ever hand that off?
I did.
I actually looked for volunteers sometimes for vacations or whatever, but it took me
a grand total of six minutes a week to come up and ask, come up with and
ask the questions every day.
So I just did it.
I had a little reminder every morning to post a question.
I forgot maybe once or twice the whole time, but it was pretty easy to do.
It was part of my routine, but it was one way to get people to learn from
about each other, because you have to find with remote teams, you have to foster
ways for them to connect where they're not just talking about work.
And then leverage that to find ways for them to work together.
You can't let your remote employees just do a thing in a silo.
You got to get them working with each other.
I want you two to go work on this.
I want you to review this or whatever.
Again, part of the manager's job is to sort of guide people to
orchestrate the team, not just give them work, but orchestrate and say,
this will work better if you two work together on this or this thing
that you're doing, Frank, maybe Sally should do that.
So you can work on this thing that Greg is doing.
And you just have to do a lot more of that.
To me, it requires a lot more deliberate management in order to get this to work.
And I know you can do it.
And I just worry, what I worry about not talking to you because you'll try
all this stuff and you'll figure out what works, what really bugs me about
remote teams is that so many managers are just managing the work.
They're not managing the people.
And I think managing the people takes 10 times more effort on remote teams.
And we're going towards the end of tech here.
We are a bunch of folks are managed in a way where they have no career growth,
no, no friends at work.
Engagement will drop to the ground and they'll just go work
at Starbucks or whatever.
I don't think Starbucks is a bad place.
No, I don't think so either.
I just, I just, I just threw it out.
Sorry.
Yeah.
If I offended anyone from Starbucks, I'm very, very sorry.
Well, both of our animals are yelling at each other.
Yeah.
They're both doing their own versions of whining.
You know, that's my soapbox on that.
It's not, there's no blueprint for this.
No, I don't know the, the, the thing that you just mentioned, uh, which I find
fascinating, right?
It's essentially now you can do the same thing, but instead of just allowing random
chance when everyone was working in the same building, you didn't have to do it
deliberately because random chance, right?
But there's no way for random chance to kick in.
So you have to create environments where that can happen.
Now, if you go back to where, um, we're good ideas come from the,
the Steven Johnson book, he talks about the fact that when coffee house has
became prevalent in the whatever center that was, sorry, my history, innovation
accelerated cause people got together and talked, uh, we need to create
virtual coffee houses environment.
People can just talk about things where ideas can, you know, ideas
come from other ideas.
You need to create as a manager, you got to create environments where people can
bounce ideas of each other in a safe way.
And then the good ideas can come out of that.
If you're not doing that, just those ideas, we stay there.
We're going to go back to the middle ages of tech.
Uh, and I think there's still very much a risk of that, unfortunately.
Right.
The, the, um, where movements are going in tech right now.
We'll see what happens, but, uh, we've, we have talked about this before drink.
Um, I think it is entirely possible.
Just like, like what caused us to start this podcast, right?
The, the, the collapse of the test discipline.
Right.
Um, and now the collapse of the dev discipline next up.
Well, I don't even like it's tech.
Like if, if dev goes, what do we need PM for?
Well, I want to tell you, I want to go back to our prediction
episode year before last.
So 16 months ago, when I said the key skill for the future is the
is going to be the ability to read and evaluate code.
And I think that is becoming more and more true as the engine start
generating more and more code for us, which is better and better.
In fact, you remember, and we've had both had interviews where we had
to write code at a whiteboard.
I think that's a stupid question now.
That question is absolutely idiotic now because AI Gen AI can create that for me.
I want, but Brent, but for you, would it be what's wrong with this
design or find the book?
I'm getting there.
What if I gave you a page of code virtually or remote and I asked you first question,
what does this code do?
And you should be, no matter how bad it's written, anybody has
to be able to figure that out.
So what problems, as long as it's not one of those lead code, no, you know what I
mean.
Yeah, I know.
I know what you mean.
You generate the right thing.
It's like, well, you don't ask somebody again.
It's the stupid of all the chess moves on a chess table wants to figure out the
ones where the night could visit the most squares in 14 moves, you know, blow me.
No, but give somebody some code that makes sense.
Make sure that you should, again, it could be different, different levels.
She built to explain what it does.
And you ask, uh, what problems could exist?
And again, Gen AI code may have problems, input, validation, et cetera, et cetera.
You can call those things out and you can say, how would you improve this code?
And one of the things, you know, in the accept accept accept world of AI generated
code, uh, I want people to take the code and then where it's confusing, it could be
a comment, it could be, I'm actually going to change the way this works.
And I think it'll work better like this, but you can like, I think the program or
the future can take that Gen AI code, understand what it does, even though they
just asked what it did, tweak it as needed, make it more readable, both for
humans and Gen AI, and then, then check in that code to solve customer problems.
But the ability to generate algorithms from scratch, who the hell cares about that anymore?
That's stupid.
That was so 1997.
Now, uh, I'm actually, um, this is something I have been thinking about.
And that is all right.
It's, it's interesting that we've moved to Gen AI and I, and I don't want
to go off topic because I've kind of.
No, I don't know how we got here, but we are here and, but let's just,
let's just, we'll go back.
Yeah.
The, um, small language models, right?
The, these are very context sensitive language models.
And so I'm, I'm thinking through, okay, if I had a new API, okay.
And the API that did all kinds of cool magic stuff, right?
How could I build a code generator through that?
And I'm like, big, there's lots of interesting things you could do with that.
Um, Oh my God.
I love that we have animal sounds in our podcast.
Yeah.
I'm going to get this chickens.
This one's annoying me and is about to get kicked up.
One moment.
Kicking.
Show me.
No, no, no.
And the cat is gone.
Testing the boundaries of Alan's no edit policy.
I know.
And what's going to happen with the cats, my cats use my daughter's cats.
I don't, I hate cats.
I don't want one on my own.
You used to kind of beat on the door with their paws to come back in.
So we'll see if that happens later.
She'll start howling and I'm just going to ignore her.
Okay.
Yeah.
Are we done with that?
So I want to back up to, uh, the short answer is for your problem is as a
manager, as a leader, deliberate, you need to create, you need to work your
butt off to create as many opportunities for collaboration and for learning
about each other without adding more calendar, a more meeting time people's
calendars, because as you know, calendar time is the only thing that is totally
finite, uh, you can't create more of it and people are going to get more done.
If they're, if their meetings are, are minimal to get their work done, but you
have to create some opportunities and you can do some things like, um, again,
this puts meetings on the counters.
You can do things like a donut chat where you randomly pair people on your
team, just to talk to each other about stuff.
But I find three minutes at the beginning of a meeting, see how things are going.
Uh, and then if you ever get everyone together, you can go a little bit deeper
and find out a little bit more about where they're from, where they live,
et cetera, I just met with my directs in New York last week.
And we spent some time at the beginning, like, what was your family like?
Where'd you grow up?
Blah, blah, blah, just to get a little bit more information about each other,
to begin to build trust right out of Pat Lincione, but you need to generate
those opportunities, people learn from each other and then give them
collaboration opportunities, make them work together, make them hang
out virtually with each other.
There's of course, there's all kinds of games you can do online, but people
generally fade away from those because they just take more time.
They could be working or, or watching Netflix.
They could become competitive, right?
The right, what you want them to be doing is talking to each other.
Yes.
And then if you ever get them together, which you should, and actually
another way to accelerate that is same way as I took my team together
to New York last week is get us to hang out a little bit because that
accelerates everything out throughout the rest of the year.
We spend a couple of days together, getting to know each other, much
easier to work together, understand how to help each other throughout
the entire rest of the year.
So the other thing I would suggest is get your team together.
I'm not sure what travel budgets are like in this, this world, but
it can just find, but again, if most of your team is in Redmond, just
flying four people out and unfortunately they have to come to Redmond,
but you can just hang out for a couple of days, send them back.
It's relatively cheap.
Whatever that cost is, you know, $10,000, which is a lot of money.
I'm making up a random round number, but you will get that back in
productivity throughout the rest of the year, guarantee it.
Yeah, I'm not certain how I can sell that to the, you remember like safe limits?
I do.
But my argument is if you're going to have remote teams, you need to invest in travel.
Current job, I might've blown my entire travel budget for the year by doing
this little mini offsite, but it's worth it.
It's worth it.
So get the team together.
Okay.
All right, man.
I think that was like for me, the absolute, I mean, you
could have just, we could have just summed it up in five minutes.
It's like, you have to be deliberate.
I'm like, Oh, obviously.
And I can't help.
I can't give a short answer.
So I get the long answer instead.
Sure.
Makes sense.
All right.
It's too much work to do a short answer.
I got another thing to talk about.
And nice.
This is something we will talk about again, the next podcast and the one after
that, and if there's one after that.
Okay.
So, and, and Brent gives me the okay, something we've talked about a little
bit before offline.
So, um, today's Friday.
I gave you this, I gave notice at my job on Monday that I am leaving.
And how did that go?
It went fine.
Um, again, it, and I can be transparent here.
Hasn't been the best fit for me.
They haven't really needed what I, they haven't needed my superpowers very much.
We've talked about this before.
Uh, it's been interesting.
I've learned a lot that people are great.
I've actually really liked it, but it's been hard for me to do what
I'm best at, but that's not why I'm leaving.
Not why I'm leaving.
Why are you leaving now?
Don't make it silly.
So, um, for ever since when I was a child, as you all know, I like to go on my long
hikes, I get therapy from the woods.
Uh, I have an opportunity, meaning I have a permit to, uh, hike the Pacific
Crest Trail and walk from Mexico to Canada.
So I am going to do that.
Okay.
I didn't realize, so listeners, I've been aware of this, um, for a while.
Um, but I didn't realize a permit was necessary.
Who did you get the permit from?
From the Pacific Coast Trail association.
Okay.
And that, that spans all countries.
Dude.
No, I'm in the, you know, California, Oregon and Washington.
Those are all, you said Mexico from the Mexican border to the Canadian border.
Okay.
I will stick my arm into Mexico and then walk north.
And then about four and a half months later, I will stick my arm into
Canada and then I will go home.
Well, that's when, yeah, I'm going to walk home more or less.
Um, the way it works is there's, there's no road at the border there at
the Canadian borders, you have to walk to the border.
There's a little monument there.
You kind of tag that, stick your arm into Canada.
There's no fence.
You can walk right in if you want, but, uh, and then you turn around and you
walk back 30 miles to, um, the closest road where you hope to hitchhike to a
small town where you can get a bus or another hitchhike to a larger town.
So you can get back home.
Oh, you know what?
That's, that's a, that's a problem for later, not a problem for now.
So something I want to do for a long time.
I've been mulling it over for a while.
I think it makes sense for me to take this break now.
So it means you're doing this by yourself.
Yeah.
I mean, there'll be a couple hundred other hikers doing the trail, several hundred,
but I'm not going with anyone.
And there's a reason for that is, uh, there's a thing they say in long distance
hiking is hike your own hike.
And some days I may want to go 10 miles, sit on a rock and
stare at the sunset for six hours.
Some days I may, you know what, I feel good.
I'm going to walk 30 miles.
I don't, you know, I like, I have hiked other people and I do
like it for a short term, but I really want to go at my own rate.
And not have to worry about someone else.
I just, so yeah, I'm going to walk.
Um, there'll be other people there I'll talk with, but, uh, yeah.
So what was I going to say?
Something I want to do for a long time.
Um, this is a good time for me to do it.
I do need a break from my job.
And so I'm going to take a four and a half month mental health break where
I just kind of walk every day.
I'll be professionally homeless.
I'll be living out of a tent every night.
Just that tent moves, uh, 15 to 20 or 25 miles down the trail every day.
So what I was saying was that means two things.
One is that, that what I just said, I'm homeless for five and a half
months while I'm paying mortgage here.
Um, and then I'll be back in mid-September, which means
you'll be back in mid-September.
I got to find a job in October.
Okay.
And I don't know what that is.
I'm of course open to coming back to NBC.
I may or may not.
I think it's, it depends on a lot of things I have.
I told a few close friends, right?
I wouldn't come work here.
I wouldn't make any, like I would not make any plans at all.
I'm not.
I wouldn't even think about thinking about making plans.
So I talked to him.
I believe the world's going to change.
Yes.
By the time I finished Donald Trump may have cut down all the
forests I'm walking through, but someone told me, it's like, yeah, I
worried about leaving a job in this economy.
I was talking to a friend of mine about this.
I said, dude, if you can walk 2,600 miles, you can find a job in this
economy and they're right.
And again, I don't need to look, I like being a VP.
I like being, you know, leading strategy for an organization.
I like executive coaching, which things I've done in this role in the past.
There's a lot of things I like about these, you know, senior
management, uh, software roles, but in America where healthcare is a
privilege and not a right, you know, I may do something totally
different, uh, if it has good health insurance, but we'll see.
And I'll figure that out in October.
I, I, it makes zero sense for me to think about it before them.
Now I could do all this.
I could break my leg on the third day and then, uh, everything continues
on and on and on.
Uh, I don't think that's going to happen.
Uh, but no, if you break, if I break my leg, I'm going to take some
fricking duct tape, wrap it around, real tight and keep going.
That'll make a good story.
I mean, what else are you going to do?
Like you have like the locator safety stuff.
Yeah.
So if you break your leg, they'll, they'll be able to find what,
what bears swallowed you.
This, this don't, the black bears don't need anything.
I have a little device that tracks where I am.
It's in satellite messages is great.
And you have like solar chargers.
No, I bring dude.
I just have a normal lightweight, like battery pack charger.
And then, um, you pass through towns every like three to seven days and
you recharge that and you're good to go.
I have something.
Let me, I hope it's relevant to our conversation.
So this is brand new.
So I haven't let my team, by the time this podcast comes out, folks at work will
know enough people know that it's not that big of a deal and nothing's going to
change, but, uh, I thought I'd just throw it out there for the listeners.
Cause we're, what that means for the podcast.
A third thing it means is that we're going to take a break from the
podcast for a while while I'm doing my thing and we will not do the podcast.
While I'm gone, I have the podcast recording equipment and the ability to
upload.
So Brent's not going to do it without me.
Uh, one of these, not the next one, maybe the one after that and possibly
the one after that will be the last AB testing podcast for a while.
All right.
What are you showing me, Brent, for our podcast audience?
Okay.
First off, actually, let me hold on.
Oh God.
Here he goes again.
He's going to go get the cat.
And this is great podcast material where Brent grabs stuff to show.
I'm sure.
Yeah.
Yay.
Podcast material.
I'll describe until now.
Uh, so I've had this for years.
Okay.
Goal zero by Sherpa.
It's a, it's a battery pack comes with attachments like this one.
Okay.
A light.
But the cool thing about it is this.
Oh, solar.
That's solar dude.
That stuff is so heavy.
I'm not, I mean, you were going to say something like that, but you, you
pinned this onto the back of your, your, I assume you're going to have a
how much is that way?
Uh, it weighs at least a pound.
At least too much.
Do you know how, guess how much do my pack plus my tent sleeping bag, first aid
kit, um, everything, guess how much my pack weighs without food or water on it?
Like fully loaded.
Uh, you have a sleeping bag.
Yeah.
Do you have a sleeping pad?
I have a sleeping bag, a pad, a tent, uh, a puffy jacket, uh, uh, um, fleece
hoodie, uh, some long underwear to sleep in first aid, electronics, including,
you know, a couple of these, these battery chargers, um, phone.
I'm going to go with seven.
Okay.
No more than that, but 11.
It's not very heavy.
A pound is huge at that level.
I don't want to carry an extra pound for charging.
So not going to happen, but I'm keeping it pretty light.
Um, but that's not much.
If you pick up like a 10 pound weight, you know, that's pretty much.
Well, we'll talk.
Well, and then it's the weight of the pack as well.
You're bringing like baby powder or petroleum jelly.
For what?
Uh, the chafing you're going to have.
Let it bleed.
It'll, it'll scab up.
You'll be fine.
Callous baby.
Callous.
Yeah.
The last, last week Alan went twice as slow because he had to walk bowlegged.
I've done enough hundred mile hikes that I feel pretty confident about.
That it's just doing 26 of those back to back.
Oh yeah.
And well, if you put it that way, it's yeah, it's nothing.
Yes.
Sure.
Nothing.
Absolutely nothing.
So, um, yeah, so, uh, for our next few podcasts, if you're on our Slack
group, um, at what you can go to modern testing.org and join that Slack group.
Uh, happy to take questions about the hike.
Happy to take questions about the break.
Happy to take questions about, uh, what's next in October.
I won't know those answers and I will probably.
A couple folks have asked how I'm going to document this.
So, uh, I already made a Google sheet because I can have an offline one and
Excel is kind of a big fat pig.
Uh, I'm going to keep pretty good data on my mileage elevation, a lot of things.
So they can, so I can geek out on the data when I get back.
Um, I'm thinking, but that's not what the people want, Alan.
What do they want?
They want to be able to, to, to track your progress.
Yeah.
So I think I may do like, like some people do like 15 to 20 minute videos
for every day of the hike.
And those people are far more ambitious than I am.
I'm thinking like one YouTube short for every day of the hike.
Uh, sure.
Or I don't know.
I would be interested in you doing like a location share in
some sort of public thing.
You know what?
I can do that because I have four of my little, uh, satellite tracking
device I showed you, you can see where I am at any point and I can share that link
out to, and I'll share that in our slack groups.
If our slack group, you can go there.
You will know where I am at any point.
You can watch me trickle north.
That would be fun.
Yeah.
We can do that.
Cause I don't think I'm the kind of person who would try and stalk or anything.
Like, um, so like if you knew exactly where I was, you can come find me,
which is weird, but I don't think our listeners are those people.
So I'm good.
Please don't come stalk me and track me now without warning me.
Cause that'd be weird.
But yeah, you can watch me trickle.
Yeah.
I don't know how they warn you.
So I guess that means like, please don't come stock out.
Yeah.
I'm going to go code of honor here.
Please don't come stalk me.
Yeah.
There you go.
Okay.
All right.
So I think that's probably a good place to hang it up for the day because I
don't have any other topics to talk about.
No, me neither.
Okay.
Once again, this is episode four 17 of the E B testing podcast.
It is two 17.
Oh, did I say four 17?
You did.
Well today's, let's say it's pie day.
It is Friday.
Yeah.
Nice.
All right.
Well, I'm Alan.
I'm Brent.
We'll see you later.
Bye.
I want.