Welcome to AVE Testing Podcast, your modern testing podcast.
Your hosts, Alan and Brent, will be here to guide you through topics on testing, leadership,
agile, and anything else that comes to mind.
Now, on with the show.
I just did an interpretive dance for Brent.
Yes.
The intro.
And it was a sarcastic interpretive dance.
No.
And I'm like, you know, it may be time for Alan to record a new version of that.
You just didn't know.
You just didn't know what it was all about until now.
When I originally made that, that's exactly what I did.
I documented the choreography and that is what it is.
Welcome to AVE Testing.
I'm Alan.
I'm Brent.
Brent's the other guy over there, generally stinky, is what we call him.
It's a long story.
We talk about that on a previous podcast.
Our producers will look that up for you and let you know we don't have any producers.
So you get us.
Brent, how have you been?
It's review time.
So yet there's that.
Start off with a good pick me up.
Does Microsoft still do the connects things?
Like, is that a thing?
Good.
That's good.
They were done poorly when I was there, but I do like the idea of check-ins multiple
times per year.
So, it's tell me.
Tell me what's on your...
The Connect has a look of pain, disgust, angst, and a slight bit of horror on his face.
Please tell me what you're thinking.
The connects, when we started at Microsoft, right?
They weren't connects.
They were reviews.
And then there was an easy one and then there was the one that sucked.
Yep.
Right?
Then the Connect thing came in and said, hey, we found out through studies slash experience
slash experimentation.
Slash people leaving.
That checking in more frequently is better.
Oh my God.
Right?
What?
And then they're like, oh, and since you're checking in more frequently, right, you should
do this and you should do that and you should do this and manage this Microsoft message.
And so now it has kind of slowly creeped back into what it was.
So that's unfortunate.
And so...
Welcome.
Welcome, great cat to the E.E.N.E.
and it's a podcast.
My dog was crying on the floor a minute ago.
She'll probably cry again.
So let me...
Let's talk about that for a minute.
We can get back to what's been going on.
And maybe this is the whole podcast of the topic, topic of the podcast.
I don't know.
But Review Season Interesting.
Wait, can you do that?
No.
Oh, I did that.
Nice little purr into the microphone.
That was great.
So, current employer, NBC Universal, has one performance review a year, which I find not
good.
It's hard.
Well, what happens?
Let's talk about what happens when you have one performance review a year.
And this is documented.
It goes back to the whole reason that the connect in the first place is...
And plus, a bunch of researchers come out and say, boy, does it put a whole lot of pressure
and anxiety around that performance review.
And again, if you're managing stuff well and you're remembering to give people feedback
and talking to them about what's going on and remembering the mantra of no surprises
at review time, it can be okay.
But it puts a lot of pressure on the manager to remember to do that.
And again, it's the manager's job and they should.
So given that my philosophy of work is to, again, align on the goals of the organization
and what we need to get done.
I do whatever the fuck I want.
And so in this case, my team, I told them that for a couple of reasons, once a year is just
not cool until we get better at giving feedback and remembering to care about this stuff because
it's really easy to fall into that trap of managing the work for the people.
So we do four times a year.
We have the main one in Feb.
Then every three months, we have...
I just don't...
There's no documentation.
There's no...
I don't check follow up, but I do it with my directs.
And so I think by modeling, they do it farther.
It's have a career discussion.
Have a discussion around whether it's...
And it can be different every time.
I didn't mind different, but have a deeper discussion around hopes and dreams.
Have a deeper discussion around feedback.
Have a discussion around really tying purpose to the work, going back to Dan Pink.
And that does two things.
One, it's better for the manager to get used to giving that feedback.
Maybe it's the same thing to two different angles.
It normalizes getting feedback.
It normalizes having that more serious discussion.
It normalizes having one-on-ones that aren't just about status reports, which I freaking
hate.
So it brings a lot of value and practice in that, especially I have some new managers
on the team.
It helps them learn how to manage better in the long run.
It's very low key.
Again, no requirements, but just getting folks to have those conversations is really important
to me.
Did we bring over the Unity questions?
No.
And the Unity questions went away.
Oh.
Why is your job...
Well, actually, indirectly.
Why is your job?
Why is it important?
What have you done?
Something like that.
I think it was with the Unity questions.
But I like that.
We had three queues, three questions, three times a year.
What I've done, and again, first perf review was in last Feb that I was a part of.
So we've done...
This is our third set since then.
We're going to do November career discussions, and then we'll have the big gnarly scary one
in February.
But I usually put a little bit of framing around each of them.
This one is, let's have a discussion around tying purpose to your work.
So this really goes back to that first question.
Why is your job important?
How does what you do support the goals of the company?
Last time it was more around where do you want to go in your career and what are the
skills that I need to find an opportunity for you to practice in order to get there?
And those are things that come up.
I document all this in our shared Slack channel.
And it just...
To me, it's real easy to get caught up, especially in our world where there's a lot
of cognitive load due to far too many things going on at once.
Taking a little bit of time every three months.
And of course, there's reflection that comes after that.
It gives us a basis for future discussions.
But just to have a more serious discussion around, let's just take a step back from
all of the daily bullshit.
Let's just talk about you and your career, why it's important, where you want to go.
Let's just make sure we're aligned on that.
And then we'll go back to the daily bullshit going forward.
But we have a conversation and some documentation on that that we keep, that we can use
to refer to.
And we go, hey, I have an opportunity that I think will help you do this thing we
talked about two months ago.
What do you think?
So to me, yeah, go ahead.
I think that's fantastic.
That's because you love me, Brent.
I do love you.
Well, love, love.
Yeah.
You know what?
It's all the same.
For the people in my life, I'm good with tolerate.
It's mine.
I know who I am.
I know what I do.
It's OK.
Yeah, no, it's I realized the other day that at some point in time, just in the last couple
of years, I have shifted into that that age where you go, I'm fucking old and I no longer
give a fuck.
Right.
It's just like, yeah, this is who I am.
If you don't like it, great.
Like, don't talk to me about it.
Don't waste any further of my time.
Right.
Yeah.
You know what?
I'm older than you and I'm not there.
Sometimes I don't give a shit, but actually, 95 percent of the time I do.
And I forget how old I am because I feel so young at heart and I feel like I have so
much more in me, but also the calendar says otherwise.
Well, there is.
So what I described is sort of like my home persona at work.
Right.
The one of the problems and I do still go into work at least three days a week.
And one of the problems at work is you're surrounded by these 20 something to 30 somethings.
And it's just natural for for you to forget you're not the same age as everyone that's
around you.
Right.
So until things like, oh, yeah, he's basic and totally simping on so and so.
And I'm like, what the hell did you just say?
It's I'm going to be at a loss in four years when when when my last teenager finally
leaves home and I lose my ability to it in near real time, interpret the quote unquote
English around me.
Now, going back to your topic, I think that's that's very base to be a brand.
Thanks. I I think it would be fantastic.
So one of the reasons why Microsoft created the more frequent feedback program right was
because they did the research and they found that it was the benefit.
OK, but the problem is if the people who have to execute it don't understand the benefit
or or worse don't care, there are seeing that there are far too many managers and far too
fewer leaders in management positions.
I had a conversation about this earlier.
So you are on to something because this is true.
Up and down at Microsoft over the years.
But as you know, managing people, being a manager is a whole different job than being a
frontline engineer.
Yes. And being a manager of managers is a whole different job.
Yeah. And we put people into these roles and rather than give them coaching and
training and the skills that they need to be successful, instead, we give them a
handshake and good luck.
So Microsoft, we now do a whole crapload of training.
OK, well, good for you.
So now, so tell me about this because I think that's important.
It is important. And I don't know if that training is tactical or it's around like the
growing humans part, which I feel oftentimes is missing in business.
But please go on because you want to talk.
Yeah. The way I would interpret the training is there.
Like the coaching habit.
OK, that was required training and that was fantastic.
And the reason why it was fantastic is because within the training is part of
training people. Why?
Why you as a manager care, right?
It's creating that intrinsic motivation.
But that type of training is super rare.
If you don't care beforehand, like you're it's you're going to come up or you're going
to view it as this is an action that legal is forcing on us.
Right. Or HR.
And well, what do you think about checking on this stuff before someone comes a manager?
Like I and you see this happen.
It happens a lot less now, given that there are generally fewer manager roles growing,
as there were like years ago when they were booming.
But a lot of times people would want to take on management for no other reason than
they felt like it was a promotion.
Yeah. And how do we.
So maybe there's a little bit of work we need to do.
And I'll talk about how I've been this in the past, but I'm going to put it to you
first. How do you figure out if people are becoming managers for the right reason and
making sure those people go into management because they want to eventually,
the pinnacle, according to Maxwell, grow more leaders.
Ah, I have a very high bar for for someone who wants to be a leader.
Tell me.
Or manager.
And it's essentially OK.
Let me give you let me give you my short speech and I have another mitigation as well
around promotions.
Because I am not trying to construct managers.
I'm trying to construct leaders and the leaders who I will put into a management
position. Honestly, my heuristic is do they want the job?
And if the answer is no, that's my first bar.
Well, OK.
Then I'm going to ask that I want to know why.
So no, it's just the first step.
But if if the answer is no, and the reason why is because of a sense of responsibility,
that they're going to be in a position that could potentially screw up a bunch of
people and their families, that's exactly the person I want in that role.
Good.
It's one that recognizes the importance of the role.
It's so important to check.
And I want to go back to, again, the three things that Gallup over years of
surveys has shown have the most to do with employee engagement.
Feedback.
Know why your job is important and know your manager cares about you.
So if you can get an idea of someone's going into management because we can coach
on feedback, but you but they care about what someone's career looks like.
Give them the feedback and coaching and guidance to get there and tie purpose to
their work.
If there's interest in those things, they're probably going to be pretty good.
It's going to be hard.
Talk about that in a minute.
But but but good call out.
Yeah.
On so this often happens in promotion discussions.
So I'll share I'll share with people.
Brent Brent, thanks.
People listen to the podcast.
Anyway, keep talking.
I'll share with Alan.
Yeah.
Because I don't think like over the years you've heard most of my management
philosophies, but I don't think you've heard this one, but we'll find out shortly.
So, you know how at Microsoft we have ladder levels, but we also have these
things called bands, right?
And a band is sort of an aggregation of levels.
Yeah.
Right.
So it's someone.
One band, one level, one title may contain multiple levels.
Right.
So as an example, we have a band that's simply known as the one band and that
will have people in 59 or 60.
And then the two band has 60 levels, 61 and 62, et cetera, et cetera, et cetera.
Yep.
And just a little bit of context.
So the reason was Microsoft had original ladder levels, which were like nine,
10, 11, should could be, could be four or five, six or one, two, three at another
company when they changed them.
They wanted to make the numbers so vastly different.
People would not confuse one set with another.
So that's why you're an inter-level software engineer at Microsoft.
There's a level 59 general.
Yes.
Um, and there are, there are ladder levels lower than 59, but they're
generally not in development roles.
Yeah.
I was hired at what would be the equivalent of a level 57.
Oh, I was hired at as a 10.
I don't, I don't remember the mapping.
Well, La-Dee-Dah.
Guess who, guess who got more levels?
This guy.
Uh, as far as I recall, we're now tied.
No, cause I started lower.
I got, I got more than you cause I started lower and got there.
You started at 57 and what do we think a 10 is?
I'm just thinking through how many levels do I have to do?
And then I'm willing to do that.
So a 10 was a 61.
Was it?
Okay.
Oh, yeah.
You suck.
No, I'm going to, I'm going to go a 10 is a 59.
All right.
There you go.
The next two.
You're good.
Story time continues.
Okay.
So for, for me as a manager, my ICs are generally going to be, my individual
contributors are going to be in one of four bands and those are the one, two,
then senior, then principal.
Okay.
And I have a little speech.
Around exit and entrance criteria.
Cause when we go on a cross band, things happen.
Okay.
The level one band, basically to get into it, you have to pass the interview.
That's, it's, it's, that's it.
Um, but to get out of it, you have to show, um, that you have mastered the ability.
You have to show two things.
Number one, that you have mastered the ability to independently learn.
And number two, that you have a, that you have the capability to independently
execute, okay.
So far, so good.
Now, similarly with the, the two band, the two bands role is to construct autonomy.
To get out of it, you have to show that you have mastered independent execution,
but you have to show the capability of leadership.
And then similarly, um, senior band, you have to master leadership, but show
the capability of ownership.
And when I talk about ownership here, I mean, um, you're going to own
a small part of the business.
Uh, and the principal band, you are expected to get a task from an executive.
Hey, Brent, I need you to go move this KPI or go solve this problem.
It's, it's like maximum ambiguity and it's your job to own that part of the business.
And sometimes it involves sucky things.
So if you haven't mastered leadership, it's going to be really hard.
Now, um, on leadership, people will often ask me, okay, what do you mean leadership?
Like, like, because there's so many people that view leadership and manager.
Ascentonyms.
And I say, no, no, there is, they are absolutely not synonyms.
And I, I tell them this and I'll do this.
Um, no, cause you'll give me a crappy, you'll give me an answer that doesn't go
the way I want and I'll say, okay, let me share with you how I know if someone's
a leader, okay.
And it's very simply this, they have followers.
Yeah.
Okay.
This is not a circular definition.
I would have given you that answer.
That's all right.
I know.
It's not a circular definition as a lot of people will do.
No, that's a key thing.
They have followers.
Now, the hard thing is what is a follower?
Are you asking me?
Yeah.
I can get after it.
It's a topology.
What do you want the answer to be?
Cause I want to, I w I have a followup on this, but I don't want to, I don't
want to play along.
What's a follower.
If I say a leader has followers, what is a follower?
Someone who has someone who has a leader.
Okay.
So yeah, that that's the, the tautological, stupid, circular answer.
You can do better than this.
I know the executive lobotomy hasn't fully stuck.
Oh, I am.
I am practically brain dead.
Um, okay.
What is the difference between a direct report and a follower?
A follower follows you because they want to.
Okay.
Why?
Because now you're, you're massively overlapping with the levels of
leadership I want to talk to because they want to, because of, because
they believe in what you're doing for the organization.
They believe that you can achieve results with them.
Or whether they believe that your path is beneficial, right?
Whether it's intrinsically or extrinsically, it doesn't frigging matter.
But they believe that that's the path for that.
Okay.
Um, so it is a lot easier to be a manager than a leader, but, uh, I
won't move someone into a manager role unless they are also a leader and
have shown the ability to, to acquire followers versus what is often the
case, like we've seen bullies.
No, I, a person that does what you want them to do out of
fear is not a follower.
Oh, no, no, not at all.
Not at all.
It's in there.
Actually, I don't even want to say it's in their better interest
to follow because if you're a bully, right, you're threatening them.
Right.
The, but in getting that idea into a future leader's head around what is
a follower and what it means, and it's about influence, not, um, not
an organizational change, um, can be difficult, but the more I stick
with it and stay consistent.
I have had a number of people, um, be successful, um, making that shift
and that shift sustains them through the rest of the levels.
Cause it starts sitting in their mindset.
Like it's just as hard getting people to understand ownership because like,
I don't know when you went into the principal band, I don't know if
you hit the same sort of system shock I did.
It's, it's, it's not a linear progression.
Like, like up until around senior, there's sort of this obvious thing, but
no, getting over into, into principle is we trust that we can leave you alone
and that you'll do high ROI things for the business.
Yeah.
And that's your, for me, that was, I spent many years doing that.
He's having to do that next box.
It's before on windows CE, that on stupid link project, but that was my thing.
I just liked to figure out people trusted me to figure out what the right
thing to do was and get it done.
Yep.
And yeah, but absolutely right.
And then I've seen people at principal struggle.
I want to go back to levels of leadership, but the quick thing on principle
is, um, I heard someone say once I keep up the principle.
I keep telling people what to do, but they don't do it.
And if it, well, um, I'll give you one guess where the problem is and it's not then.
Yeah.
So I, you're, I know we've talked about it before on the podcast.
I want to go a little more deeply than we have, because it aligns
really well with what you just said.
And John Maxwell wrote this book called the five, I think it's called
the five levels of leadership.
Please don't type and look it up.
Type, type, type, type, type.
So the first thing he talks about is putting people, your first level of
leadership is that you are in a position of leadership.
People follow you because they have to.
Yeah.
No, that's okay.
Fine.
Again, you don't look, I get it.
I get it.
He calls that the five levels of leadership and that's fine.
Holy, but listen, think of you and I both can name people managing today.
That are managing their team and demanding their respect because they're
in that position of leadership and haven't done Jack squat other than that.
That's true.
A single higher level.
But that's true.
But I hope that the way this progresses level two and five have nothing to do
with having been a manager.
Can I kind of finish before you get in here with all the bullshit?
So you're in a position of leadership.
I'm never going to make it.
People follow because they have to.
These leaders who stay in this position either aren't leaders anymore or they
focus on rules, control and compliance.
Maybe a manager at McDonald's can get away with this for a longer time.
Nothing against McDonald's except for that one where Trump was.
Then people give you permission at level two, people give you permission to lead them.
These leaders are beginning to build those relationships with their teams.
They're fostering trust.
They're building a foundation.
This is where we want people to start rather than level one.
We want to start.
And again, no matter what, Brent, I'm promoting you to a lead.
Briefly, it may be a day, but briefly when I started a new company, I am in a position of
leadership.
I am at level one as quickly as possible.
I have to get to level two because level one sucks for everyone.
It exists.
I'm in a position like here's the new guy in charge.
Okay.
I don't know him.
Why would I give him permission to follow me?
After permission, it's production.
People follow you because of what you've done for the organization.
So again, at this level of leadership, you're focusing, you have the relationships built.
You're focusing on like you get the team aligned around achieving organizational goals.
So they follow you.
You deliver results together.
At people four, people follow you.
Level three is probably different.
The organization at level four, people follow you because what you have done for them.
So these people are they follow you.
This is we're getting into probably if you want to call these managers, they're probably
managers and managers, but they don't have to be.
Their focus is on developing people.
And I talk a lot in my blog at angerweasel.substack.com plug.
I need a little jingle for that.
I'll write one sometime.
People at this level are sorry, I lost my train of thought when I gave the plug.
I manage the people, not the work.
And we know so many managers are focused on managing the work.
Give people a framework they can work in and then let them succeed.
So at this level four, it's all about creating that culture of self-sufficiency,
autonomy, giving people going.
And then finally, not all leaders get here.
And Maxwell calls this out.
This is where we want to get to at level five.
Not only are people following you because of who you are and what you represent, but the
key thing leaders at level five do is they develop more leaders.
Their focus purely on not purely, primarily on culture and values and making sure that
the people that are reporting to them or the organization themselves are becoming better
leaders because of all kinds of other stuff going on.
Very complex.
Not very many leaders get here.
I don't know very many leaders that are there, but it's where we should all strive to be.
It's, you get how these advance and how they get more difficult as you go up.
But it's a nice little, it's probably too long to go.
I mean, the book's like a gazillion pages and I just kind of summarized it in five
minutes and badly.
So I don't know.
To me, it's really stuck because especially those first couple of levels, you have to
move from a position of leadership and I've worked for people talking to you, Peter.
Oh, God damn it.
Alex has Alex.
Alan has frozen.
I don't know if he can hear me.
I will sit here and hopefully remember.
I was taking a screenshot of his face though.
That's funny.
Do you hear me?
I do.
You know, this was not a Riverside thing.
I'm not sure where you lost me.
I have to kind of, I was on a roll.
I'm never going to get it back.
Um, my wonderful Xfinity internet just puked and it's weird.
It almost always pukes during this hour on a Friday and it's fairly consistent the
rest of the time.
I don't know what's going on.
My wifi stayed up hot five bars the whole time, although now it tells me it's off.
So I don't know what's going on.
Do you hear me?
All right.
I do.
This is weird.
Okay.
That was just my Mac getting caught up.
So I don't know what's going on, but we're back.
And I was talking about five levels of leadership.
And then what was I talking about before Comcast cut me off?
I don't know.
You are on a pretty good roll though.
All right.
Well, we're never going to know where that goes because I have the
attention span of piss.
Um, I wrote down notes though.
Oh, why don't you refresh me and we'll just go from here.
You know, listeners, you get what you pay for.
Here we go.
Tell me your problem.
Stinky.
Yeah.
I have, I like the order.
Um, yeah, my only problem is that he calls it the first level of leadership.
It should be the zero.
I know.
I know he's not a, he's not a software guy Maxwell.
So tech people count in zeros.
I don't know.
Was that loud?
That in my house or yours?
That was in your house.
Okay.
Hold on.
All right.
Let's see where the cat went.
No cats right there.
All right.
What wasn't the cat?
It's probably the daughter.
Ah, no, hold on, man.
I'm going to, I'm going to keep things you done.
You good.
Oh, well, no.
So I wrote down, okay.
I did it in an, in alliteration.
So level zero is people.
Level one is permission.
Level two is production.
Level three is personal and level four is propagation.
It's funny.
I believe Maxwell calls them, he also gives them peace.
But I think he uses, if I remember right, I'll look it up in the book.
Someone asked Chad GPT, position, permission, production, people and pinnacle.
Sure.
I think I've told you before that I went pretty far in my younger years and take
one though, and that's right.
And now it's weird because I still, I marvel over the fact that chronologically
I am older than you, but I'm just younger.
Anyway, go on.
Maybe I'm Benjamin Button.
And the horse you rode it on is what I'm currently thinking.
All right.
The, but, uh, so it's different in, in different styles.
Uh, but the style of take one though, I went through, right.
So you, you know, that the ultimate in is a black belt and you can get
multiple degrees in black belt, but, uh, the color belts, what you are in, when you,
when you, um, up to getting to black.
And in my particular style, uh, the color belts were intended to represent sort of
the growth of a plant from, from a white seed all the way up to sort of the red
belt, which is the last color belt before black and red represents the
beginning of death and black indicates is dead, is dead.
But, um, the reason for that symbolism though, is not directly dead because
when a plant dies, it spreads its seeds.
So most, um, most martial arts that I'm familiar with, right.
They will actually tell you, no, actually the color belt, like the destination isn't
black, the color belts are, we're pounding into you all the pre-reqs
necessary for you to be actually begin your martial arts training.
Martial arts training really is intended to begin at the, uh, once you get your
black belt, um, anyway, it's a neat story that somehow, somewhat related to your
leadership story, like on the propagation thing.
Well, this was all the answer to how's it going, Brent?
It was.
And there's actually one other thing that I, that like our little, our
little brief unexpected intermission share, or made me remember.
Um, I have officially decided to take exactly the same journey you did about
four, five, six, 18 years ago.
And that is, um,
I was just out of high school
on November, at the end of next week, no later than the end of the next week.
I will be waving bye-bye to Xfinity.
Oh, you mean to cable TV?
No.
Xfinity.
All right.
I kind of get my Xfinity highly subsidized, so I'm sticking with it.
I am shifting over to Zipli.
Nice.
So, um, yeah, I just get Xfinity super cheap.
So, uh, I, I, and the fact that it goes out during the podcast, you know,
maybe it's great.
You get what you pay for.
Yeah.
I realized like in the last year, um, so I have like the,
the super duper package and I'm like, okay, really?
In the last year I shifted over.
I'm not watching broadcast TV.
I'm all, no, the only things I watch are on, on the streaming channel.
Nobody watches broadcast TV.
It's a dying business.
Yeah.
I say working for a company that delivers broadcast TV, but they'll
figure it out eventually.
Oh no.
Well, I think, I think that move has already happened, right?
Yeah.
Netflix, their lowest offering is with ads, right?
Yep.
And we were like, okay.
Now they just need a live stream nightly news show per market.
Yeah.
I wonder how far I had to do a thing.
We should start that.
I do not want to go into this deeply.
I do not want to, but I have to mention, I had to do a little, um, uh,
what would I call it?
Uh, little survey for a thing I'm going to in a few weeks.
And I had to, the question was something around, write out a fictional news
headline that captures how the world has changed by 2030, something like that.
Or I said it's 2030, write a fictional news line about how the world has changed.
And I will tell you what I wrote cause there's nothing in here, but going
into why broadcast may be dying again, I don't know how right I am, but I'm just
going to read this to you is the headline I wrote was AI driven newsroom set new
standard major media outlets operate with 80% fewer human reporters focusing
on real time, hyper personalized content streams.
So what you do is you log into Netflix, you click news and you get your
personal content stream based on a bunch of stuff has been curated for you.
So news is sort of delegated to the masses and it comes to you based on your
preferences, kind of just like tick tock.
But, uh, anyway, that was my, that was my idea for the future.
Just a mess.
I don't think we're too far away from that.
Maybe 2030 is too long.
Yeah.
I mean, I could think about how to implement that.
And I debated leaving people get so freaked out about AI taking jobs.
I debated leaving off that part, but I also wanted to put it in there.
But anyway, a little thing now we've talked about AI in the podcast.
We got that part done.
Uh, I did, um, uh, a trap ton of travel.
I went to New York for two weeks, hang out with my daughter, stopped in
Bozeman on the way home to take care of my nephews for a week, got back home.
I'm here for two weeks.
I'm going back to New York a week after that.
And, uh, man, just too much going on.
I'm looking forward to the slow.
Well, holiday's coming up.
Is that going to be slow for you or, um, it depends if I survive the election.
Okay.
So I have a question for you on that one.
Yes.
Like, like the, cause that could be a double entendre.
Right.
Cause given your business, it's really more of the first one, given that this
is like, you know, at unity, we had code freezes for, uh, like, uh, Christmas,
uh, dads and grads days that would have huge spikes would be very, we would
never freeze, but we'd be careful around deployments and changes, uh, in the day
who would have spikes and add traffic.
Microsoft had not really code freezes, but dads and grads and holidays and
things were, were sale just to make sure stuff was up, uh, news like Olympics
is big elections, huge, and the election cycle may take a lot longer here.
And a matter of just keeping, keeping news stations, all local news stations
all over the country, national news stations up, uh, getting, uh, web-based
news also up quickly and updated and all that stuff.
It's, um, it's going to be a little zippity doodah here for a while.
And in some, some years, you know, in a, in a normal year, you know, like
when we were kids, the election cycle may take three or four days or out
around elections, a bunch of news comes in, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah,
no matter what happens in this election, no matter what happens, the news is
going to go batshit for two weeks, minimum, minimum.
Now, like we should be taking bets.
Like how long before we actually know who's president?
Oh, see there.
We're going to know on November 6th, we're going to know whether getting the rest of
the country, I mean, getting people that don't have critical thinking to know
will take the remaining two weeks.
A lot.
We didn't know on the day of the election last time.
We knew the next day.
We did know the next day, late in the next day, but the next day.
Yeah.
Well, we're going to see what happens.
But anyway, yeah, we better, we are running out of time here in the
palatial studios of A.B.
testing.
I have one interesting thing.
I wasn't going to say anything, but we had a little bit of a of a audio
issue at the beginning and I had to do the thing right, unplug and plug back
in the USB connector to my audio device.
And that worked great.
But then when it did that, I didn't notice that it changed my
microphone input to my laptop, which is fine.
That works out pretty well.
It's a little more tinny, but I can fix it in EQ and post.
But then just to make things more fun, after my computer, after the
after Xfinity, crap the bed and I had to reconnect.
When I reconnected, it connected back to my good microphone.
So now our listeners get two different microphones, which I get the blend
and post production and see what happens.
So, you know what?
Either it sounds awful.
And again, I hope you enjoyed your time with this anyway, or it sounds great
and you marvel over my audio awesomeness.
Or no, no more ors or it doesn't.
It's a dichotomy.
It doesn't have to look what would sound great mean it to me.
It's either it sounds awful or it doesn't.
Well, I'm an unfortunate audio file, so I will know.
But if the rest of people, yeah, whatever.
Do you think?
All right, man, I am kind of know who I am.
I'm not Brent's cat, so I must be Alan.
And I also am not Brent's cat, so I must be Alan.